<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211; Search Berg</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 13:01:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Happy 4th of July From the Team at Search Berg</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-4th-of-july-from-the-team-at-search-berg/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-4th-of-july-from-the-team-at-search-berg/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 13:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1691</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; It’s time to set your SEO toolkit aside for the weekend and immerse yourself in the social distancing-friendly 4th of July fun and festivities! Deck your home out with red, white, and blue décor, bake a classic 4th of July cake, and hold your family close as you celebrate 244 years of independence. We’d like to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-4th-of-july-from-the-team-at-search-berg/">Happy 4th of July From the Team at Search Berg</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It’s time to set your SEO toolkit aside for the weekend and immerse yourself in the social distancing-friendly 4<sup>th</sup> of July fun and festivities! Deck your home out with red, white, and blue décor, bake a classic 4<sup>th</sup> of July cake, and hold your family close as you celebrate 244 years of independence.<span id="more-1691"></span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1692" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Happy-4th-of-July-From-the-Team-at-Search-Berg.png" alt="graphic design wishing people a happy Fourth of July" width="624" height="453" /></p>
<p>We’d like to wish you a blissful 4<sup>th</sup> of July from the team at Search Berg, including our SEO specialists, content marketing experts, social media management team, and paid marketing professionals. Whether you have a family BBQ party in your backyard or spend the day watching 4<sup>th</sup> of July-themed movies and playing board games with your loved ones, we’re sure you’ll find a creative way to make this holiday just as fun!</p>
<p>Our team is hopeful that America’s collective efforts will prove to be fruitful and allow Juneteenth to be recognized as a national holiday by next year. As strong proponents of the Black Lives Matter movement, we believe that true independence should be marked by the day everyone became free.</p>
<p>In our push for racial equity and justice, we hope to see change so we can proudly celebrate independence and freedom for all, especially the Black community, which has been marginalized for decades and centuries.</p>
<p>Stay safe, practice social distancing, and have a memorable weekend!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-4th-of-july-from-the-team-at-search-berg/">Happy 4th of July From the Team at Search Berg</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-4th-of-july-from-the-team-at-search-berg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Achievement Alert! Search Berg Successfully Completes 30,000 Projects!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-successfully-completes-30000-projects/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-successfully-completes-30000-projects/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Jensen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 14:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; We kicked off 2019 with the announcement of reaching 20,000 projects! And we haven’t slowed down since then! As May 2020 comes to a close, the Search Berg team has now cranked it up a notch—or two!—successfully completing 30,000 projects! We’ve worked with countless businesses—big and small—in a wide range of industries and locations [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-successfully-completes-30000-projects/">Achievement Alert! Search Berg Successfully Completes 30,000 Projects!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1533" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/1-1.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="640" /></p>
<p>We kicked off 2019 with the <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-completes-20000-projects/">announcement of reaching <strong>20,000 projects</strong></a>! And we haven’t slowed down since then!</p>
<p>As May 2020 comes to a close, the <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/">Search Berg</a> team has now cranked it up a notch—or two!—successfully completing <strong><em>30,000 projects</em></strong>!</p>
<p>We’ve worked with countless businesses—big and small—in a wide range of industries and locations to deliver excellent results that help improve sales, brand identity, and customer engagement.</p>
<p>From helping local businesses in Seattle and Orlando to closely monitoring the web presence of established corporations in New York and Seattle, our team has delivered exceptional results across the nation!</p>
<h2>A Glimpse of Our Quick and Impressive Results</h2>
<p>Our content-driven SEO strategies have enabled us to help clients reach their goals and set new targets that would’ve otherwise seemed like a fanciful pipe dream to them.</p>
<p>Our quantifiable on-page and off-page SEO services have enabled businesses in the automotive, education, construction, travel, health, real estate, shopping, and technology industries to establish impressive web presences.</p>
<p>Each of the 30,000 projects we’ve tackled has helped clients:</p>
<ul>
<li>Increase Revenue</li>
<li>Reduce Customer Attrition Rates</li>
<li>Climb SERPs and Attract Quality Traffic</li>
<li>Generate More Leads</li>
<li>Improve User Experience</li>
<li>Build Brand Credibility</li>
<li>Increase Conversion Rates</li>
<li>Reduce Bounce Rates</li>
<li>Increase Audience Engagement and Retention</li>
<li>Decrease Cost Per Acquisition</li>
<li>Increase Website Referrals</li>
<li>Break Into New Markets</li>
</ul>
<p>And the list doesn’t stop there!</p>
<p>Our powerful and innovative strategies continue to help our clients improve rankings and expand their business in new ways. With over 10 years under our belt, we’ve continued to devise unique and cutting-edge strategies that help our clients create an unbeatable web presence.</p>
<p>Each project is assigned a dedicated project manager to ensure seamless execution and continual monitoring. As the goals are periodically assessed and checked off, the project manager ensures a quick turnaround so you don’t have to wait for results.</p>
<p>Our <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/money-back-guarantee/">100% money-back guarantee</a> is a testament to our experience and confidence in helping your brand tap into the digital landscape efficiently, speedily, and successfully.</p>
<h2>Our Award-Winning Strategy</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1534" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/2-1.jpg" alt="" width="960" height="685" /></p>
<p>While we completed 30,000 projects in 2020, we also celebrated a string of other accomplishments.</p>
<p>We were recently named the <a href="https://clutch.co/profile/searchberg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Top Small Business SEO Company of 2020</a> and the <a href="https://clutch.co/profile/searchberg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Top WordPress Developers of 2020</a> by Clutch. Good Firms also honored us by deeming our team the <a href="https://www.goodfirms.co/companies/view/4668/search-berg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Top SEO Services Company</a>.</p>
<p>Our holistic approach has helped us publish 150,000+ content pieces and 22,800+ infographics and videos. Our meticulous <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/how-it-works/">SEO process</a> includes exhaustive keyword research to ensure customers reap the benefits of an SEO-friendly web presence.</p>
<p>With over 1,000 satisfied customers, we don’t plan on stopping any time soon! Our individualized and flexible SEO packages help clients pick the best services for their projects, thereby ensuring they reach their goals.</p>
<p>Clients can opt for a wide range of strategies within the following categories:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-services/">SEO and Lead Generation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/ppc-marketing/">Paid Marketing</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/v1/content-marketing/">Content Marketing</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/web-design-and-development/">Website Design and Development</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/v1/social-media-management/">Social Media Management</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/v1/reputation-management/">Reputation Management</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Kick-start your project by <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/v1/free-proposal/">requesting a proposal and free SEO audit report</a> or giving us a call at <a href="tel:8554444777">855-444-4777</a>. Our representatives will assiduously review your site and prepare an in-depth analysis to help you get started!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-successfully-completes-30000-projects/">Achievement Alert! Search Berg Successfully Completes 30,000 Projects!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-successfully-completes-30000-projects/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Search Berg Wishes You a Happy New Year!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/search-berg-wishes-you-a-happy-new-year/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/search-berg-wishes-you-a-happy-new-year/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Solomon Winston]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 09:39:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1418</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>2019 was fun—and we at Search Berg can’t wait for the New Year, with its new possibilities and successes. We’d like to wish you a great New Year, and we hope it’s as full of possibilities and opportunities as 2019 was. 2019 was a great year for SEO—and an even better one for Search Berg. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/search-berg-wishes-you-a-happy-new-year/">Search Berg Wishes You a Happy New Year!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1420" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/image001.jpg" alt="Happy New Year" width="624" height="457" /></p>
<p>2019 was fun—and we at Search Berg can’t wait for the New Year, with its new possibilities and successes. We’d like to wish you a great New Year, and we hope it’s as full of possibilities and opportunities as 2019 was.</p>
<p>2019 was a great year for SEO—and an even better one for Search Berg. At the turn of this decade, we want to extend our gratitude to all the clients who trusted us with their businesses, the vendors who placed their faith in us, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/white-label-seo-services.html">our white label partners</a> with their unwavering support, our loyal fans, our affiliates, and the super-skilled battalion at Search Labs who have helped us break yet another record for Search Berg in 2019.</p>
<p>The next decade will be no different: more records will be set and broken and set again, because the future’s looking great for SEO!</p>
<p>Here are some of the great things we did in 2019:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-completes-20000-projects/">20,000 completed SEO projects</a></li>
<li>5,064 new content pieces written</li>
<li>2,280 videos and infographics created</li>
<li>We were the 2019 winner for Bark’s Certificate of Excellence</li>
<li>Hundreds of satisfied clients!</li>
</ul>
<p>The New Year and the new decade come bearing a lot of promises for our clients worldwide and for us. We are excited to dive right into all that 2020 holds for us: so, thank you for supporting us and stay tuned—we’ll still be around and working when the fireworks begin!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/search-berg-wishes-you-a-happy-new-year/">Search Berg Wishes You a Happy New Year!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/search-berg-wishes-you-a-happy-new-year/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Holidays From Search Berg!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-holidays-from-search-berg-2/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-holidays-from-search-berg-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Harper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 14:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1412</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Christmas and Holiday festivities are finally upon us! It&#8217;s time to gather around loved ones and soak in the holiday magic in all its glory. Team Search Berg would like to wish everyone a very Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays! Here&#8217;s to hoping the next year (and decade!) is just as blissful and celebratory. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-holidays-from-search-berg-2/">Happy Holidays From Search Berg!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1416" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/HOLIDAYS.png" alt="" width="669" height="446" /></p>
<p>The Christmas and Holiday festivities are finally upon us! It&#8217;s time to gather around loved ones and soak in the holiday magic in all its glory.</p>
<p>Team Search Berg would like to wish everyone a very Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays! Here&#8217;s to hoping the next year (and decade!) is just as blissful and celebratory.</p>
<p>See you in 2020.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-holidays-from-search-berg-2/">Happy Holidays From Search Berg!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-holidays-from-search-berg-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet Olivia, The Newest Member To Our Editorial Team!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/meet-olivia-the-newest-member-to-our-editorial-team/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/meet-olivia-the-newest-member-to-our-editorial-team/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 08:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a few months, I’ll be marking 7 years of managing all content on SearchBerg.com and the company blog. I am amazed at the speed at which Search Berg has grown. What started off as a small business, has expanded and evolved into a network of departments specializing in every internet marketing discipline in use [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/meet-olivia-the-newest-member-to-our-editorial-team/">Meet Olivia, The Newest Member To Our Editorial Team!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a few months, I’ll be marking 7 years of managing all content on SearchBerg.com and the company blog.</p>
<p>I am amazed at the speed at which Search Berg has grown. What started off as a small business, has expanded and evolved into a network of departments specializing in every internet marketing discipline in use today; comprising of talented, hardworking individuals, each of whom has made invaluable contributions to making <a href="https://www.searchberg.com">Search Berg</a>, an award winning company.</p>
<p>The Search Berg blog has been one of our success stories and managing it has been an amazing experience for me. That too, in addition to my primary responsibility as the Senior Account Manager at Search Berg. Well after 7 years, I am happy to say that now I have some help!</p>
<p>I am really excited to introduce the newest addition to our community. Everyone please say hello to Olivia Glynn, our new editor at Search Berg! She just recently joined our Digital Marketing team.</p>
<p>You will be seeing her in action on blog as she talks about some of the trending and emerging demands of Internet Marketing and more importantly how businesses can capitalize on it to generate revenue and increase clientele.</p>
<h2>A Little About Olivia</h2>
<p>Olivia studied Marketing and Advertising, with a minor in Computer Sciences along the way from NYU. After graduating, she went on to intern at a digital marketing agency where she got her first-hand experience with SEO as she helped with strategy formulation and implementation.</p>
<p>Seeking to evolve her career, she has recently joined Search Berg and will be contributing to our marketing strategies as well as the company blog. Olivia will be also interacting with our numerous clients and helping them achieving online solutions just like are many hundreds of other clients. Olivia’s specialty is Content Marketing, Paid Search and Web Design.</p>
<p>We’re really excited to have her onboard. Everyone please join me in welcoming Olivia. I look forward to seeing her posts on the blog as I reshuffle my work to devote more time to Sales and Lead Generation. Good to have you onboard Olivia.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/meet-olivia-the-newest-member-to-our-editorial-team/">Meet Olivia, The Newest Member To Our Editorial Team!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/meet-olivia-the-newest-member-to-our-editorial-team/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Search Berg awarded the 2019 Certificate of Excellence by Bark</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/search-berg-awarded-the-2019-certificate-of-excellence-by-bark/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/search-berg-awarded-the-2019-certificate-of-excellence-by-bark/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 15:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1178</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Another feather in the cap for Search Berg! The leading internet marketing company has recently been awarded the 2019 Certificate of Excellence by Bark, a popular review site. This recognition is one amongst many accolades Search Berg has achieved in its almost decade long career, gaining an impressive clientele along the way. One Milestone after [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/search-berg-awarded-the-2019-certificate-of-excellence-by-bark/">Search Berg awarded the 2019 Certificate of Excellence by Bark</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Another feather in the cap for Search Berg! The leading internet marketing company has recently been awarded the <a href="https://www.bark.com/en/company/search-berg/ld80G/">2019 Certificate of Excellence</a> by Bark, a popular review site. This recognition is one amongst many accolades Search Berg has achieved in its almost decade long career, gaining an impressive clientele along the way.</p>
<h2>One Milestone after Another</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com">Search Berg</a> has worked with thousands of clients, completing an array of diverse projects over the course of almost 10 years. We first passed 10,000 SEO projects back in 2016; a landmark by all standards for us at that time. Since then, we’ve never looked back and just last December, we completed 20,000 SEO projects; an unthinkable achievement. All the hard work, and dedication that went into accomplishing this staggering feat, has paid off and we want to take this opportunity to thank our clients for making this possible. It must be mentioned that Search Berg is also the recipient of the <a href="https://www.sitejabber.com/resources/sitejabber/what-are-the-customer-choice-awards/">Site Jabber Customer Choice Award</a> for SEO in 2017 and 2018, 2 years in a row.</p>
<h2>Taking The Next Step – A True Mark of Excellence.</h2>
<p>Awards like the Certificate of Excellence only encourage us to pursue digital marketing more passionately. Our digital marketing experts are constantly looking at the Google ranking algorithm trends; coming up with new solutions and strategies to cater to the ever changing, ever complex needs of clients today.</p>
<p>In 2019, we plan to take digital marketing to the next level. We are offering industry specific SEO. Our experts have specialty in over 30 industries including <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-for-healthcare.html">Healthcare</a>, travel, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/finance-mortgage-seo.html">finance</a>, lifestyle, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-for-hvac.html">HVAC</a>, and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-for-real-estates.html">real estate</a>. Each project is handled by team of experts with industry-specific knowledge and skills to create high ranking SEO content for the client.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/internet-marketing.html">Get in touch</a> with the company for a full description of their services or request a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/free-proposal.html">free audit report</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/search-berg-awarded-the-2019-certificate-of-excellence-by-bark/">Search Berg awarded the 2019 Certificate of Excellence by Bark</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/search-berg-awarded-the-2019-certificate-of-excellence-by-bark/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Achievement Alert! Search Berg Completes 20,000 Projects!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-completes-20000-projects/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-completes-20000-projects/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 09:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1173</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What better way to start a new year than by celebrating a new achievement! Search Berg is venturing into 2019 with confidence, after a very successful and rewarding 2018. Having worked with thousands of clients over the past 10 years, we are proud to say that as of January 2019, we have successfully completed more [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-completes-20000-projects/">Achievement Alert! Search Berg Completes 20,000 Projects!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What better way to start a new year than by celebrating a new achievement!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com">Search Berg</a> is venturing into 2019 with confidence, after a very successful and rewarding 2018. Having worked with thousands of clients over the past 10 years, we are proud to say that as of January 2019, we have successfully completed more than twenty thousand internet marketing projects for our clients! That’s right, 20,000!</p>
<p>This is a monumental feat and we couldn’t be happier. The amount of growth we have experienced both in terms of employees and clients has been staggering. Just two years ago, the company successfully managed 10,000 projects. It just goes to prove that our results-driven digital marketing strategies are being appreciated and accepted by clients who continue to work with us year after years. Some of our clients have been with us for 5 years!</p>
<h2>Search Berg: A Success Story</h2>
<p>We at Search Berg have accomplished numerous goals and crossed several milestones. One of the biggest contributors to our success is the trustful relationships that we have built with our clients by making sure that our clients see quantifiable, tangible results for their respective marketing campaigns. With the amalgamation of our creative SEO and expertise in accordance with the client’s vision, Search Berg has produced not just exceptional projects but also establishes a loyal clientele.</p>
<p>In addition to completing 20,000 projects, Search Berg has also gained international recognition for other rewards. We were awarded the <a href="https://www.sitejabber.com/resources/sitejabber/what-are-the-customer-choice-awards/">Site Jabber Customer Choice Award</a> in 2017 and 2018 respectively, 2 years in a row! We are ranked the #1 <a href="https://clutch.co/profile/searchberg"><strong>digital marketing agency in New York</strong></a> by Clutch.</p>
<h2>Delivering Tomorrow’s Solutions Today!</h2>
<p>When you talk about Search Berg SEO, you are talking about an SEO process designed to first and foremost, give clients peace of mind.</p>
<p>There are no contractual obligations. No hidden fees.</p>
<p>Our SEO is 100% white-hat meaning it conforms to Google guidelines for building links.</p>
<p>Our clients get full access to the <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/dashboard.html"><strong>Client Dashboard</strong></a> where they can monitor rankings, analyze web traffic, review work done and manage their entire project; all from one platform.</p>
<p>And then to top it off, our SEO comes with a 100% money back guarantee.</p>
<p>You simply can’t go wrong with Search Berg.</p>
<p>Our services and results aren’t restricted to a particular industry or region. We have clients worldwide and our clients are as diverse in their industry as their projects. We have worked with healthcare services, law firms, real estate, HVAC companies, bail bonds providers, and remodeling businesses, authors, retail businesses and many more.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/internet-marketing.html">Get in touch</a> with the company for a full description of their services or to hire their services.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-completes-20000-projects/">Achievement Alert! Search Berg Completes 20,000 Projects!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-completes-20000-projects/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy New Year From Search Berg!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-new-year-from-search-berg/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-new-year-from-search-berg/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 11:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1124</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Team Search Berg would like to wish everyone a very happy, prosperous, joy-filled 2019! 2018 was an amazing year for us and we want to take this opportunity to thank our clients, affiliates, fans, vendors, white label partners, and the talented folks here at Search Labs for making 2018 a record breaking year for Search [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-new-year-from-search-berg/">Happy New Year From Search Berg!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Team <a href="http://www.searchberg.com">Search Berg</a> would like to wish everyone a very happy, prosperous, joy-filled 2019!</p>
<p>2018 was an amazing year for us and we want to take this opportunity to thank our clients, affiliates, fans, vendors, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/white-label-seo-services.html"><strong>white label partners</strong></a>, and the talented folks here at Search Labs for making 2018 a record breaking year for Search Berg.</p>
<p>Here are a few noteworthy mentions for 2018.</p>
<ul>
<li>Successfully completed 15000 SEO projects</li>
<li>Ranked #1 <a href="https://clutch.co/profile/searchberg"><strong>Digital Marketing Agency by Clutch</strong></a></li>
<li>Ranked in Top 10 Web Design Agency in New York by Upcity</li>
<li>Ranked in <a href="https://upcity.com/local-marketing-agencies/profiles/search-berg"><strong>Top 15 Local SEO Companies in New York by Upcity</strong></a></li>
</ul>
<p>We are looking forward to the new year celebrations and some well-earned time off with family and friend! Once again thank you for supporting Search Berg.</p>
<p>See you in 24 hours, next year.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-new-year-from-search-berg/">Happy New Year From Search Berg!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-new-year-from-search-berg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Holidays From Search Berg!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-holidays-from-search-berg/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-holidays-from-search-berg/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 14:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1116</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; Team Search Berg is looking forward to some well-earned time off with family and friends and to enjoy the Christmas and Holiday festivities! We would like to wish everyone, our fans, followers and supporters, our partners, our affiliates, everyone we have worked with and worked for, a very Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays! See [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-holidays-from-search-berg/">Happy Holidays From Search Berg!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Team Search Berg is looking forward to some well-earned time off with family and friends and to enjoy the Christmas and Holiday festivities!</p>
<p>We would like to wish everyone, our fans, followers and supporters, our partners, our affiliates, everyone we have worked with and worked for, a very Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays!</p>
<p>See you in 2019</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-holidays-from-search-berg/">Happy Holidays From Search Berg!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/happy-holidays-from-search-berg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>We have revamped our YouTube channel! Subscribe Today!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/our-youtube-channel-has-been-revamped-subscribe-today/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/our-youtube-channel-has-been-revamped-subscribe-today/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 14:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1088</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Come check us our on YouTube and subscribe to our channel! We’ve recently revamped our YouTube profile and added new videos and playlists for our viewers. https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCpY7HKS4FIbwsQGE0ASP2YA/featured The newest attraction to our video collection is Profession based SEO. After successfully completing over 15,000 projects, Search Berg now has an exceptional command over certain industry clients [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/our-youtube-channel-has-been-revamped-subscribe-today/">We have revamped our YouTube channel! Subscribe Today!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Come check us our on YouTube and subscribe to our channel! We’ve recently revamped our YouTube profile and added new videos and playlists for our viewers.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCpY7HKS4FIbwsQGE0ASP2YA/featured">https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCpY7HKS4FIbwsQGE0ASP2YA/featured</a></p>
<p>The newest attraction to our video collection is <strong>Profession based SEO</strong>. After successfully completing over 15,000 projects, Search Berg now has an exceptional command over certain industry clients when it comes to taking them to the first page in Google and generating massive traffic! Be it a small business like locksmith, or a large scape organization like law firms, Search Bergh has brought them online success which is why we enjoy such a high client retention ratio for these industries.</p>
<p>Be sure to check out our Profession Based SEO playlist and browse through all videos.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1102" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Youtube-Playlists.png" alt="" width="1200" height="847" /></p>
<p>If you are wanting a video for your website, take a minute to explore the different type of videos Search Berg can create for you! From Facebook Banners to super high quality voice-over videos, our extremely talented Promotional Media team is ready to make that perfect video for that that you can proudly share on FaceBook and with your friends, colleagues, clients, and potential leads!</p>
<p>We will be adding more videos to the collection every week. Be sure to subscribe to our channel by clicking on the SUBSCRIBE button and also click on the ring icon to get the latest video updates as soon as they go live!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/our-youtube-channel-has-been-revamped-subscribe-today/">We have revamped our YouTube channel! Subscribe Today!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/our-youtube-channel-has-been-revamped-subscribe-today/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
