<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Seattle SEO firm &#8211; Search Berg</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/tag/seattle-seo-firm/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 14:31:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Top 10 SEO Trends That Could Transform Your Seattle Business’s Online Presence</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-seo-trends-that-could-transform-your-seattle-businesss-online-presence/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-seo-trends-that-could-transform-your-seattle-businesss-online-presence/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Jensen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 14:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seattle SEO firm]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2018</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Is your Seattle business stuck in a rut? Here are the top SEO trends to help you rank higher, generate more leads, and give your sales a boost!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-seo-trends-that-could-transform-your-seattle-businesss-online-presence/">Top 10 SEO Trends That Could Transform Your Seattle Business’s Online Presence</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Contents</h2>
<p><a href="#_Toc50394623">What Is SEO and Why Does Should It Matter for Your Seattle Business?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc50394624">What Are the Biggest Trends in SEO?</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc50394625"> Artificial intelligence: BERT</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50394626"> The Knowledge Graph</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50394627"> Quality and Optimized Content</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50394628"> Video Marketing is King</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50394629"> Compartmentalizing Keyword Research</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50394630"> Voice Search is Here to Stay</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50394631"> Link Building Is the New Brand Building</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50394632"> Local Content Maximizes Outreach</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50394633"> MMM: Make the Move to Mobile!</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50394634"> Revisit and Optimize Old Content</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc50394635">The Final Word</a></p>
<p>With a population of <strong><u>3.98 million</u></strong> and <strong><u>over 100,000 small businesses</u></strong>, the Seattle metropolitan area is brimming with economic activity. Some call it <a href="http://choosewashingtonstate.com/why-washington/our-strengths/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">the Washington advantage</a>.</p>
<p><span id="more-2018"></span></p>
<p>Whether you run a small business or recently launched a lucrative startup, you’re positioned at the center of it all: <em>impressive</em> potential growth.</p>
<p>Ah, the caveat. There’s always one, isn’t there?</p>
<p>While Seattle boasts a wide range of industries and offers countless opportunities to businesses, <strong><u>the competition is cut-throat</u></strong>.</p>
<p>And it’s easy to see why. Over the past few years, Seattle’s economy has “<a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/business/economy/the-seattle-area-economy-defies-an-easy-peg-and-thats-a-huge-strength/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">punched above its weight</a>,”diversifying tremendously.</p>
<p>When it comes to running a successful business, marketing is key. There’s no way around it. And while offline marketing may have been the name of the game in the 2010s, things are much different now.</p>
<p>Currently, <strong><u>over 79% of Americans shop online</u></strong>.</p>
<p>As internet accessibility and use become more common across the nation, people are increasingly connecting with businesses on the web.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc50394623"></a>What Is SEO and Why Does Should It Matter for Your Seattle Business?</h2>
<h2><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/SEO-services-for-Seattle-businesses.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2020 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/SEO-services-for-Seattle-businesses.jpg" alt="SEO services for Seattle businesses" width="701" height="480" /></a></h2>
<p>If your Seattle business has a mediocre to nonexistent online presence, you’ll fail to target, engage, and convert potential customers online.</p>
<p>So how do you turn things around and become more visible on the web? You let <strong><u>search engine optimization (SEO)</u></strong> do the trick.</p>
<p>SEO strategies are designed to help your products/services and content:</p>
<ul>
<li>Rank higher on Google search engine result pages (SERPs)</li>
<li>Get more traffic</li>
<li>Get more clicks</li>
<li>Get more conversions</li>
<li>Boost sales</li>
<li>And repeat!</li>
</ul>
<p>As your web pages actively circulate the World Wide Web, you can only imagine how many web users will engage with them—purchase your products/services, sign up for exclusive emails, create an account on your website, check out your blog page, etc.</p>
<p>Remember the fierce competition we talked about earlier?</p>
<p><strong><em><u>This</u></em></strong> is how you beat it.</p>
<p><strong><em><u>This</u></em></strong> is how you stand out and gain an edge in your respective industry.</p>
<p>Curious about which SEO techniques are trending in Seattle? We’ve rounded up the latest 2020 SEO trends by Seattle SEO experts to help you kick things off.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc50394624"></a>What Are the Biggest Trends in SEO?</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc50394625"></a>1.Artificial intelligence: BERT</h3>
<p>AI has been a catalyst in the evolution of SEO. In October of 2019, <a href="https://blog.google/products/search/search-language-understanding-bert" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Google introduced</a> us to Bidirectional Transformers for Language Understanding (BERT)—a neural network-based technique for NLP (natural language processing).</p>
<p>This breakthrough meant that Google could now process words in connection with other related words, instead of one-by-one in isolation.</p>
<p>And so, BERT models has the capacity to process “the full context of a word by looking at the words that come before and after it”—ultimately understanding the <em>intent behind search queries</em>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/BERT-search-example.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2021 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/BERT-search-example.png" alt="SEO trend BERT example" width="1437" height="628" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><b>Source: </b></strong><a href="https://blog.google/products/search/search-language-understanding-bert/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofolow noreferrer"><strong><u><b>Google</b></u></strong></a></p>
<p>So what does this mean for your Seattle businesses trying to optimize for SEO?</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<div class="left"><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2061" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cta-icon1.png" alt="" width="123" height="123" /></div>
<div class="right">
<h3><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-seattle/">Refocus your efforts on creating quality, engaging content with the sole purpose of solving a reader’s needs.</a></h3>
</div>
</div>
<p>Remember E-A-T (Expertise, Authoritativeness, and Trustworthiness)? Google wants to make sure that your website meets these expectation if they’re going to recommend you (read: rank you).</p>
<p>It’s not just about getting the <em>relevant</em> information (oh no); it’s about giving out <em>accurate </em>information (which is basically YMYL or <strong>Your Money or Your Life</strong>)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/SEO-trend-EAT-YMYL.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2023 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/SEO-trend-EAT-YMYL.jpg" alt="SEO trend: EAT and YMYL" width="601" height="401" /></a></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc50394626"></a>2. The Knowledge Graph</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Knowledge-Graph.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2024 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Knowledge-Graph.png" alt="Knowledge Graph example" width="1355" height="832" /></a></p>
<p>Launched in 2012, Google’s Knowledge Graph allows your potential website visitors to gain quick access to important information while at the same time, presenting trust and authority signals.</p>
<p>Several businesses don’t claim their knowledge graph. Let’s say you own a dental clinic in Seattle. And your knowledge graph doesn’t provide the information you want your potential patients to know about your clinic. The contact number is outdated; the images are low-res; the timings are inaccurate.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<div class="left"><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2062" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cta-icon2.png" alt="" width="146" height="140" /></div>
<div class="right">
<h3><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/gmb-optimization/">You can claim your brand and make specific requests—like updating the featured image, panel title, and social profiles within the knowledge graph panel.</a></h3>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc50394627"></a>3.Quality and Optimized Content</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.google.com/search/howsearchworks/algorithms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">Google’s algorithm</a> is in a league of its own. It expertly processes search queries and helps users find <em>exactly what they’re looking for</em> in the least amount of time possible.</p>
<p>To facilitate this, Google recently made some big changes to SERP results.</p>
<p>Let’s say you ran the search:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Google-search-ebook-publishing-services-Seattle.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2026 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Google-search-ebook-publishing-services-Seattle.png" alt="Google search for ebook publishing services in Seattle " width="714" height="59" /></a></p>
<p>Pretty standard, right? You’d probably expect an array of regular search results displayed based on their relevance.</p>
<p>Not quite.</p>
<p>While the results will be based on their relevance to your search, they won’t necessarily follow the same format. Instead, you’ll find a crop of unique search results, including the “people also ask” section, “people also search for” section, “see results about” section, and video carousel, among others.</p>
<p>Here’s a closer look:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/3-1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2027 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/3-1.png" alt="Google SERP packages" width="689" height="266" /></a><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/4-1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2028 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/4-1.png" alt="Google SERP packages" width="678" height="489" /></a><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/5-1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2029 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/5-1.png" alt="Google SERP packages" width="472" height="338" /></a><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/6-1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2030 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/6-1.png" alt="Google SERP packages" width="693" height="375" /></a></p>
<p>While these search packages are extremely beneficial for users, they’re also a goldmine for businesses.</p>
<p>Take a quick look at the packages one more time. Not only are they concise, they’re also <em>more</em> engaging and clickable than regular search results.</p>
<p>Google didn’t introduce this idea out of nowhere; it was based on meticulous forethought, research, and prediction.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, the results were in line with the projections. <strong><u>10% of clicks</u></strong> that were previously earned by organic entries started going to these packages. As their popularity continues to increase today, people are more likely to engage with these features to get quick, relevant, and brief answers to their queries.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s what you need to do to maximize your chances of snagging one of these coveted spots and generate more traffic.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Start by creating diverse content that covers a wide range of industry-relevant topics. This is a great way to appear in the “people also ask” and “people also search for” packages.</li>
<li>Your <a href="https://moz.com/beginners-guide-to-seo/on-page-seo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">on-page SEO efforts</a> should be top-tier. While title tags and Meta descriptions are essential for regular search results, they’re also non-negotiable for Google’s new search packages.</li>
<li>Cover <strong><em><u>all</u></em></strong> the bases to rank higher on each SERP element.</li>
</ul>
<p>The outcome? An out pour of traffic that helps your Seattle business grow in the long run.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style4">
<div class="inner">
<h3>Get Quality Content that <span class="orange">Engages</span>, <span class="orange">Connects</span> and <span class="orange">Converts!</span></h3>
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-new-york/">Start Now</a></p>
<p>In just under <span class="orange">$199!</span></p>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc50394628"></a>4.Video Marketing is King</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/video-marketing-stats-seo-trends.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2031 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/video-marketing-stats-seo-trends.jpg" alt="SEO trend: video marketing" width="601" height="301" /></a></p>
<p><strong><em><u>Video content is the next big thing</u></em></strong>.</p>
<p>There’s a reason why Google displays the video carousel for the large majority of Google searches: it generates clicks faster than Usain Bolt runs a 100-meter race—and no, that’s not hyperbole; we mean it.</p>
<p>While text- and image-based content is powerful in its own right, video content is a whole new ballgame—one that’s tricky to navigate but worth it.</p>
<p>Think about it; would you rather pore over a long-form article or breeze through a short, engaging, and entertaining video?</p>
<p>The latter, right?</p>
<p>Your customers will most likely share the same sentiment.</p>
<p>Whether you offer legal support, run a beauty supply store, stock modern furniture, or provide home restoration services, creating a compelling video is a great way to engage and retain customers.</p>
<p>They’re less likely to get bored, zone out, and click off your site. Within a matter of minutes, you’ll manage to impart your message and most likely earn a conversion.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/video-content-Seattle-businesses-YouTube.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2032 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/video-content-Seattle-businesses-YouTube.png" alt="video content by Seattle businesses on YouTube" width="583" height="440" /></a></p>
<p>Now, creating a video isn’t the only step. You need to go the extra mile and <strong><u>optimize it</u></strong>—to boost visibility and maximize your chances of ranking higher.</p>
<p>When you’re uploading a video on your website:</p>
<ul>
<li>Make sure you choose the right placement</li>
<li>Insert a video transcript</li>
<li>Use high-ranking keywords in the title and description</li>
<li>Use a witty, eye-catching, and unique <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbescoachescouncil/2018/12/26/why-your-call-to-action-needs-to-be-clear-and-compelling/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">CTA (call-to-action)</a> in the beginning and toward the end of the video to prompt action.</li>
</ul>
<p>And that’s not all.</p>
<p>You can also upload your videos on external platforms—including YouTube, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and Vimeo. Use relevant categories with high search volume to reach more people.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc50394629"></a>5.Compartmentalizing Keyword Research</h2>
<p>Keyword research is one of SEO’s most prized golden rules that will never lose its relevance or efficacy.</p>
<p>While keywords are still just as important today as they were a few years ago, there have been some changes.</p>
<p>If you’re looking to transform your Seattle business’s online presence, you may want to give your current keyword research strategy a quick look-over.</p>
<p>Here’s what you need to check.</p>
<p><em>Are you using the same old bulk of keywords for each project? </em></p>
<p><em>Are your keywords lacking in diverseness? </em></p>
<p>While these slip-ups may seem negligible, they can drastically impact your rankings.</p>
<p>Owing to the segmentation of Google SERP results, your keywords should target <strong><em><u>each</u></em></strong> section—including the <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-googles-local-3-pack-and-how-can-you-use-it-to-rank/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google 3-Pack</a>, additional packages (revisit Section 1), and organic search results.</p>
<p>You should have a different set of keywords for each search element. Example:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/seo-trend-local-search-Google-3-pack.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2034 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/seo-trend-local-search-Google-3-pack.png" alt="Local SEO trend, Google 3 pack" width="952" height="888" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/example-organic-search-paid-search.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2035 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/example-organic-search-paid-search.png" alt="example of organic search and paid search" width="1131" height="784" /></a></p>
<p>For instance, maximize your chances of appearing in the “people also ask” section by using industry-specific self-help keywords.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/example-people-also-ask-search.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2036 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/example-people-also-ask-search.png" alt="example of people also ask search" width="1079" height="415" /></a></p>
<p>If you offer <strong>chiropractic services in Seattle</strong>, focus on long-tail keywords like:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>What does a chiropractor do?</em></li>
<li><em>Are chiropractors safe?</em></li>
<li><em>When should you see a chiropractor?</em></li>
<li><em>Do I need a massage or chiropractor?</em></li>
</ul>
<p>And so on.</p>
<div class="pro-tip">
<div class="left">
<h3>Depending on your industry,</h3>
<p>your keyword research strategy will vary. However, your method will be more or less the same.</p>
</div>
<div class="right"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2063" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/pro-tip-icon3.png" alt="" width="141" height="130" /></div>
</div>
<p>Of course, don’t lose sight of location-specific keywords.</p>
<p>From pulling out the big guns (<strong>“Seattle”</strong>) to using district- and neighborhood-specific keywords <strong>(“North Seattle,” “Greenwood,” “Roosevelt,”</strong> etc.), make sure you cover all the bases.</p>
<p>While your keyword research strategy should be comprehensive, the keyword implementation process should be selective.</p>
<p>The last thing you want to do is over stuff keywords and risk getting penalized by Google.</p>
<p>If you’re struggling to use high-ranking keywords right, get in touch with keyword specialists. They’ll take care of everything for you so you’re all set.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc50394630"></a>6. Voice Search is Here to Stay</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Google-voice-search-statistics.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2038 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Google-voice-search-statistics.png" alt="Google’s voice search statistics" width="938" height="293" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><b>Source: </b></strong><a href="https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/consumer-insights/consumer-trends/google-app-voice-search/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><strong><u><b>Think With Google</b></u></strong></a></p>
<p>2020 has been a <em>great</em> year for <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2019/10/16/why-you-should-optimize-for-voice-search-now-to-stay-ahead-of-your-competition/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow">voice search</a>.</p>
<p>According to research, there were an astounding <strong><u>33 million voice search queries</u></strong> in 2017.</p>
<p>As of today, <strong><u>20% of all searches</u></strong> on mobile are voice-based.</p>
<p><em>“Google, where can I find furniture in Seattle?”</em></p>
<p><em>“Google, what are the best sushi restaurants near me?”</em></p>
<p><em>“Alexa, where’s the closest hospital?”</em></p>
<p><em>“Alexa, make a list of the best dentists near me.”</em></p>
<p><strong><u>Easy, quick, convenient. </u></strong></p>
<p>If you take another look at the four search queries above, you’ll notice that they’re <em>slightly</em> longer than the average text-based search query. While we tend to cut to the chase when manually typing something, we’re more generous with our words when speaking.</p>
<p>In addition, it was found that over 20%of voice search queries consisted of a combination of roughly 25 words:</p>
<table style="height: 124px;" width="664">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="104">how</td>
<td width="105">what</td>
<td width="107">where</td>
<td width="106">when</td>
<td width="104">why</td>
<td width="98">who</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="104">best</td>
<td width="105">top</td>
<td width="107">good</td>
<td width="106">new</td>
<td width="104">easy</td>
<td width="98">free</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="104">homes</td>
<td width="105">recipe</td>
<td width="107">list</td>
<td width="106">find</td>
<td width="104">types</td>
<td width="98">I</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="104">the</td>
<td width="105">is</td>
<td width="107">can</td>
<td width="106">make</td>
<td width="104">does</td>
<td width="98">do</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>This is exactly what you need to take into consideration when optimizing your content for voice search.</p>
<p>Here’s how you can optimize your content for voice search:</p>
<ul>
<li>Use conversational long-tail keywords to ensure your content shows up for voice searches. Use this strategy for regular content (blogs, articles, etc.) and product/service pages.</li>
<li>Try to incorporate more industry-specific questions and answers into your content. This is a neat trick to engage curious web users who aren’t necessarily looking to purchase anything. By finding the answer to a regular query on your page, they could end up making a purchase, reading your blog, or interacting with your social media pages.</li>
</ul>
<p>As long as it’s a conversion, it’s a win!</p>
<div class="blog-cta style4">
<div class="inner">
<h3>Transform your <span class="orange">Seattle</span> business’s online presence!</h3>
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-new-york/"> Get a FREE Proposal Now!</a></p>
<p>Or Call <a href="tel:855-444-4777">855-444-4777</a> now.</p>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc50394631"></a>7.Link Building Is the New Brand Building</h2>
<p>Link building is the process of earning hyperlinks back to your site (also known as “backlinks”) from reputable websites with high domain authority, i.e. great rankings on SERPs.</p>
<p>Let’s say Forbes decides to write an article on credit repair. During their research process, they stumble across a value-added blog that covers the top credit repair strategies of 2020.</p>
<p><em>This blog just so happens to be your content.</em></p>
<p>Forbes is more than impressed. In fact, they end up referencing a strategy from your blog to supplement their article. While doing so, they use <strong>anchor text </strong>that redirects readers to <em>your</em> blog.</p>
<p><em>This</em> is how referencing works in the world of online content.</p>
<p>While Forbes manages to include great insights in their article, you reap the benefits of an influx in traffic.</p>
<p>And not just regular traffic; <em>High-quality leads with high purchase intent</em>.</p>
<p>The outcome? Impressive conversions and better chances of ranking higher on Google!</p>
<p>To help you understand how you can leverage link building for your Seattle business’s success, check out this video:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="What is Back-Linking and Why is it Important for YOUR Business? - Search Berg" width="969" height="545" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GwiI6V1eyQg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>With an impressive domain rating score of 93, Forbes is a digital powerhouse. A backlink from Forbes is akin to earning an Olympic gold medal.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Forbes-domain-authority-93.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2039 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Forbes-domain-authority-93.png" alt="Forbes-domain-authority-93" width="589" height="578" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Here’s how you can boost your link building capabilities and earn high-quality backlinks from the who’s who of your industry:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Create engaging, value-added, and unique content that’s <em>a cut above the rest</em>. This is a great way to ensure people sit through your content and absorb its value without clicking off.It’s <em>also</em> a great way to ensure potential link building partners engage with your content.</li>
<li>Guest blog on credible, high domain authority sites.</li>
<li>Identify and fill content gaps to maximize clicks, not just impressions.</li>
<li>Connect with Seattle-based influencers on social media or other online publications. Get them to link back to you.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a name="_Toc50394632"></a>8.Local Content Maximizes Outreach</h2>
<ul>
<li>72% of customers who perform a local search visit the store</li>
</ul>
<p>46% of all Google searches are for local products/services/content</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/local-search-stat.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2040 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/local-search-stat.jpg" alt="local search statistics" width="601" height="301" /></a></p>
<p>While you may have created winning content, if it’s not optimized for local search, you’re doing your business no favors.</p>
<p>Engaging customers in New York when your products/services are exclusively available in Seattle will end up taking a toll on your rankings, reducing conversions, and negatively affecting sales.</p>
<p><em>So how do you turn things around?</em></p>
<p>You <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-master-local-seo-in-2020/">leverage <strong>local SEO</strong></a>.</p>
<p>While creating a separate strategy is recommended, it’s not required.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s how you can win at local SEO without starting from scratch:</strong></p>
<p>Take your existing SEO roadmap and incorporate local optimization tactics into each strategy. For instance, you could specifically target local companies when implementing your link building strategy.</p>
<p>Let’s say you offer interior design services. While targeting global and nationwide companies like Architectural Digest, Elle Décor, and IKEA is a great way to get started, it’s not enough.</p>
<p>Give the strategy a local touch by adding more companies to the list—<em>specifically companies that are based in Seattle</em>.</p>
<p>Keep in mind that these businesses <strong><u>shouldn’t</u></strong> be direct competitors. You can establish link building partnerships with businesses that sell interior doors or offer roof repair services in Seattle. This way, you’re not taking away from your business.</p>
<p>We also suggest creating local product/service pages to target customers across Seattle.</p>
<p>Here are some examples to whet your inspiration:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/local-content-Google-search-results-Seattle.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2041 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/local-content-Google-search-results-Seattle.png" alt="Google search results for local content in Seattle" width="684" height="544" /></a></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc50394633"></a>9.MMM: <u>M</u>ake the <u>M</u>ove to <u>M</u>obile!</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/mobile-page.jpg"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2042 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/mobile-page.jpg" alt="Website responsiveness" width="601" height="301" /></a></p>
<p><em>When was the last time you checked your phone?</em></p>
<p>If it isn’t already in your hand, probably 2–3 hours ago, right?</p>
<p>To drive the point home, smartphones have quickly transformed from a luxury to a necessity.</p>
<div class="pro-tip">
<div class="left">
<h3>As online shopping continues</h3>
<p>to increase during the COVID-19 pandemic, people are increasingly looking for products/services on their phones.</p>
</div>
<div class="right"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2064" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/pro-tip-icon4.png" alt="" width="150" height="149" /></div>
</div>
<p>And this doesn’t just include the younger generation. Baby Boomers have also jumped on the bandwagon, and this trend is only expected to crystallize more over the next few years.</p>
<p>It’s simple: <strong><u>M</u>ake the <u>M</u>ove to <u>M</u>obile!</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/mobile-friendly-webpages-Seattle-SEO-trends.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2044 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/mobile-friendly-webpages-Seattle-SEO-trends.png" alt="mobile-friendly webpages for Seattle businesses" width="682" height="537" /></a></p>
<p>Optimizing your website for mobile will help you attract customers who’d rather shop using their phones than their computers/laptops/tablets, etc.</p>
<p>And trust us, that number is <em>pretty</em> high.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<div class="left"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2065" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cta-icon3.png" alt="" width="100" height="155" /></div>
<div class="right">
<h3><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/website-speed-optimization/">Make sure your website runs seamlessly across all smartphones. In addition, ensure easy scrolling, reduce page load speed, and keep the navigation user-friendly.</a></h3>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc50394634"></a>10.Revisit and Optimize Old Content</h2>
<p>Once you’ve created and posted content, revisiting it sounds counterproductive to most. And we get why.</p>
<p>Focusing your efforts on upcoming content instead of rehashing the past definitely sounds like a good way to go about things. But it’s not.</p>
<p>Google is constantly upping the game by releasing new updates and making changes to their algorithm. Keeping up with the latest SEO developments is essential. It’ll help you create updated content and maximize your chances of ranking higher.</p>
<p>However, the work doesn’t end up.</p>
<p>Revisit old content periodically and make changes to ensure relevance. Update the keywords, edit the image alt text, tweak tags, shorten and simplify the URL, and make additional changes.</p>
<p>The outcome?</p>
<p>Google will <strong>crawl, index, and rank</strong> your web pages better. This will go <em>a long way</em> in elevating your rankings and boosting your online presence!</p>
<p>In many cases, you may find that your old content is irrelevant, outdated, or simply not accurate anymore. In these cases, you can delete certain pages accordingly.</p>
<p>You’ll also notice that older pieces—especially those posted way back in the day—don’t resonate with your brand anymore. Perhaps your brand identity evolved.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<div class="left"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2066" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cta-icon4.png" alt="" width="147" height="138" /></div>
<div class="right">
<h3>Taking a walk down memory lane—or should we say “content” lane—will help keep your web pages optimized, spruced up, and consistent.</h3>
</div>
</div>
<h2>The Final Word</h2>
<p>In this blog, we walked you through the top SEO trends for Seattle businesses.</p>
<p>From emphasizing the importance of creating content with SERP structure in mind to breaking down the significance of link building, we navigated <strong><u><b>the biggest trends in SEO</b></u></strong> to a tee.</p>
<p>When it comes to implementing these strategies, getting help from Seattle SEO experts is a <em><i>great</i></em> way to give yourself a head start.</p>
<p>If you’re wondering about how to go about SEO, as a leading <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-seattle/"><strong><u><b>Seattle SEO firm</b></u></strong></a>, we specialize in helping clients rank higher, generate more leads, and increase sales by leveraging SEO. Our SEO specialists cover all the bases—<strong><u><b>on-page SEO, off-page SEO, and technical SEO</b></u></strong>.</p>
<p>For more on SEO and PPC future trends in Seattle, stay tuned to our blog!</p>
<p>We’re ready when you are! All you have to do is call <a href="tel:855-444-4777"><u>855-444-4777</u></a> or fill out the form below and we’ll take care of the rest!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-seo-trends-that-could-transform-your-seattle-businesss-online-presence/">Top 10 SEO Trends That Could Transform Your Seattle Business’s Online Presence</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-seo-trends-that-could-transform-your-seattle-businesss-online-presence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
