<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>SEO &#8211; Search Berg</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/category/seo/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 17:12:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>10 Best CMS for a Successful Website</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Jensen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 09:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a quest to design a website for your business, it&#8217;s likely that you&#8217;ve come across the term &#8220;CMS&#8221; a few times. A CMS or Content Management System can make setting up and running your website incredibly straight-forward. In this blog, you&#8217;ll discover the top 10 Content Management Systems out there to support your website, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/">10 Best CMS for a Successful Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a quest to design a website for your business, it&#8217;s likely that you&#8217;ve come across the term &#8220;CMS&#8221; a few times. A CMS or Content Management System can make setting up and running your website incredibly straight-forward.</p>
<p><span id="more-2621"></span></p>
<p>In this blog, you&#8217;ll discover the top 10 Content Management Systems out there to support your website, factors to consider when choosing a CMS, and how the best CMS can boost your SEO.</p>
<p>Because of various CMS platforms, you’re left wondering: which CMS should I use?</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s start by defining <strong><em>what a CMS is</em></strong> and how it helps you build your website effectively.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Do you want a killer, professionally designed website that drives sales? Fill out the form below to get in touch with us.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2>Contents</h2>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181237">What is a CMS?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181238">10 Best CMS Software for 2021</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181239"> WordPress</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181241"> Drupal</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181243"> Joomla</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181244"> Magento</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181246"> HubSpot</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181248"> BigCommerce</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181250"> Shopify</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181251"> Squarespace</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181253">Wix</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181254"> Weebly</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181255">What Factors Do You Need to Consider When Choosing a CMS?</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181256"> Pricing Features that are Right for You</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181257"> Stellar Support</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181258"> Which Content Management System Will Support Your SEO Best?</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181259"> Ease of Personalization and Design</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181260"> Website Security</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181261"> Easy Website Migration Capabilities</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181262">The Best Content Management Systems for SEO &amp; Why</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181263"> WordPress</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181264"> Drupal</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181265"> Magento</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181266"> Hubspot</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181267"> Shopify</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181268">Wrapping Up!</a></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68181237"></a>What is a CMS?</h2>
<p>A CMS, or Content Management System, is a system that allows you to create a website without actually writing any code such as HTML or Java.</p>
<p>Ok, clear so far. Now why do we use CMS?</p>
<p>Without Content Management Systems, those businesses that wanted to create websites would need to rely on experienced coders or learn the languages ourselves. Thankfully, we have Content Management Systems (CMS) at our disposal.</p>
<p>So, a CMS like WordPress makes the process of not only designing, but also <em>managing websites</em> significantly easier and more streamlined.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68181238"></a>10 Best CMS Software for 2021</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181239"></a>1. WordPress: Cost &#8211; $0</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2634" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog2-1.png" alt="wordpress" width="1899" height="804" /><br />
<a href="https://www.searchberg.com/wordpress-seo/">WordPress</a> is the most widely used CMS platform for websites. Using WordPress, you can create any kind of website, including a company website, personal portfolio, online store, etc.</p>
<p>There are many benefits of WordPress. In terms of design freedom, WordPress has thousands of designs available for users to download and use, whether they&#8217;re directly from WordPress or third party WordPress theme websites like <a href="https://themeforest.net/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">ThemeForest</a>.</p>
<p>In addition to being free, WordPress is also great for SEO. It allows you to easily create tags, update URLs and categories, and add separate plug-ins to improve your website&#8217;s SEO.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg" alt="WordPress CMS features from their website's home page." width="730" height="651" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2637" /></p>
<p>The only downside is you&#8217;ll need to purchase your own domain through a domain hosting platform like <a href="https://www.bluehost.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">BlueHost</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181241"></a>2. Drupal: Cost &#8211; $0</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2632" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-9.png" alt="Drupal" width="1891" height="672" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/drupal-seo/">Drupal</a> is super helpful if you have a huge amount of data you want to add on your website. It&#8217;s helpful for this purpose because it can handle extreme customization requirements and data.</p>
<p>It has an in-built user system where you can manage what users can and cannot do. It has a vast array of themes available and you can increase Drupal&#8217;s functions using modules. It has previously installed automation tools for SEO as well.</p>
<p>While you will need a hosting provider, <a href="https://www.drupal.org/hosting" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">here</a> is a list of providers that support Drupal users.</p>
<p>Drupal is also trusted by the following trusted brands.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2631" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-8.png" alt="Six trusted brands known to use Drupal for their websites, promoting it as one of the best CMS software." width="1063" height="477" /></p>
<p>You should know that because the interface is designed to handle complex tasks fit for developers, Drupal is less beginner-friendly relative to WordPress. In addition, its themes can also be pricey.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181243"></a>3. Joomla: Cost &#8211; $0</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2630" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-7.png" alt="The Jooma CMS home page showing three options: to download, use, and learn Joomla." width="1259" height="846" /></p>
<p>As with WordPress and Drupal, you&#8217;re going to need to buy a domain separately. While <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/joomla-seo/">Joomla</a> is also a veteran in the CMS game like WordPress, it&#8217;s equipped to handle large amounts of data and tasks that it can be daunting for beginners. In addition, it features a built-in user access system that allows you to regulate actions of registered users.</p>
<p>If you choose to go with Joomla and have little web development experience, you&#8217;d benefit from hiring a developer to handle building your website.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181244"></a>4. Magento: Cost &#8211; Free, Kind Of.</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2629" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog2.png" alt="Magento" width="1895" height="812" /><br />
Magento is a CMS specifically designed for e-commerce platforms. While there are some standard SEO functions, you&#8217;ll need to download a good extension for more abilities. One example of these extensions is the free Creare SEO 2.0 extension.</p>
<p>While you can certainly access Magento for free using the software Magento OpenSource, you also have the option of paying Magento to manage it on their end. This can start from two grand USD per month.</p>
<p>While Magento is a highly secure, powerful CMS, it&#8217;s not forgiving to beginners and will need you to have technical knowledge or someone on your team who does.</p>
<p>If you own a B2B Ecommerce store and are looking to improve your conversions, check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/11-ways-to-triple-your-b2b-ecommerce-conversions/">11 Ways To Triple Your B2B Ecommerce Conversions.</a></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181246"></a>5. HubSpot: Cost &#8211; $300/mo</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2628" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-6.png" alt="HubSpot" width="1709" height="902" /><br />
Among other benefits, HubSpot provides 24 hour website security and support. The CMS works for users whether you&#8217;re a beginner or a developer because you have the option to write code directly or use the drag-and-drop features.</p>
<p>For that price point, it should be easy to use!</p>
<p>As a bonus, you&#8217;ll also get SEO recommendations and easy A/B testing capabilities in your website.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181248"></a>6. BigCommerce: Cost &#8211; $30/mo</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2627" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-5.png" alt="BigCommerce" width="1894" height="808" /><br />
<a href="https://www.searchberg.com/bigcommerce-seo/">BigCommerce</a> is also specifically for ecommerce stores, as implied by its name. The biggest selling point for BigCommerce is that it allows you to sell products through your own ecommerce website and big ecommerce marketplaces like Amazon and Ebay.</p>
<p>You can either obtain a free domain name from BigCommerce which will have their brand name in the URL or you can purchase a custom domain.</p>
<p>BigCommerce does lack a little in the design department, but you can integrate your BigCommerce site with WordPress to resolve that issue.</p>
<p>The $30 covers a lot for starting companies and sole proprietors, but BigCommerce also has <strong><em>big</em></strong>-ger options with more features for larger organizations.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve ever wondered what CMS big companies use, if it&#8217;s an ecommerce company then it&#8217;s likely BigCommerce.</p>
<p>If you make more than 50,000 USD in sales per year, then you&#8217;ll automatically be bumped up to the more pricey plan which is about $250 per month, so keep that in mind for your expenses.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181250"></a>7. Shopify: Cost &#8211; $29/mo</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2626" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-4.png" alt="The Shopify home page which shows their slogan that anyone, anywhere can start a business online" width="1245" height="614" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/shopify-seo/">Shopify</a> is a simple, drag-and-drop, beginner-friendly CMS for ecommerce. It&#8217;s very straightforward and allows you to accept payments through multiple ways, including Shopify Payments and PayPal.</p>
<p>Additionally, Shopify has apps you can install to your store that make it easy to increase your features. For example, if you&#8217;re dropshipping products, you can import reviews from your third-party supplier&#8217;s website using apps.</p>
<p>While it has a more pricey option of around $300 per month that has more features, unlike BigCommerce, it doesn&#8217;t automatically upgrade your plan.</p>
<p>Shopify&#8217;s main advantage is its simplicity because it handles hosting, security, and site maintenance. These crucial benefits of Shopify leave you free to go out and get customers.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181251"></a>8. Squarespace: cost &#8211; starting at $16/mo</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/squarespace-seo/">Squarespace</a> is great for less technical users who just want to create a basic website. So, personal websites, portfolio websites, and even company websites are easily made using Squarespace.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2625" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-3.png" alt="Squarespace's company message &quot;Simple tools for big ideas&quot; echoing the consensus that it is indeed a simple tool for beginners and non-complex website requirements." width="544" height="383" /></p>
<p>They&#8217;re not the best for ecommerce stores because it&#8217;s so simple that your operation won&#8217;t be heavy-weight, per se.</p>
<p>If you require more robust functionality in your website, though, Squarespace isn&#8217;t your best option.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181252"></a>9. Wix: Cost &#8211; Starts From $14/mo</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2624" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-2.png" alt="wix.com" width="1687" height="890" /></p>
<p style="text-align: right;">&#8211; wix.com</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/wix-seo/">Wix</a> is an incredible platform for beginners who want to make a website. With their subscription, you can pay monthly or annually, and their drag-and-drop features make constructing a website significantly stream-lined.</p>
<p>You should remember, though, that with its simplicity and user-friendliness come some costs. For example, once you choose a designated template for your website, you can&#8217;t change it.</p>
<p>The good thing is that each theme is adaptable to mobiles, tablets, and desktops, so there&#8217;s no bad template options here even if you get pigeon-holed into one template style.</p>
<p>The ecommerce options for Wix will also be limited because it only accepts certain payment pathways like PayPal.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181254"></a>10. Weebly: Cost &#8211; Free and $5 and up.</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2623" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-1.png" alt="Weebly homepage displaying their templates and pricing buttons." width="1240" height="726" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/weebly-seo/">Weebly</a> is also a solid CMS to use. It allows its users simple drag-and-drop features and is user-friendly. Its mobile-responsive templates have calmed many a business owner regarding their mobile rankings on Google.</p>
<p>Weebly does give the option for SEO, but there are more expansive CMS out there for SEO. If you already have a Weebly CMS for your website, it might help to hire a Weebly-specific SEO specialist to help you maximize your website&#8217;s potential.</p>
<p>Users of Weebly have had issues with exporting their content or migrating from this CMS to other platforms.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Take control and build more a responsive website. With our <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/cms-migration/" style="text-decoration:underline;">website migration services</a>, move to a new CMS platform!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2>What Factors Do You Need to Consider When Choosing a CMS?</h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Our list and each CMS features won&#8217;t mean much if you don&#8217;t know what your needs are, so this section is designed to help you concretize what criteria to look out for in your ideal CMS.</p>
<p>After all, what features should the best CMS include?</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181256"></a>1. Pricing Features that are Right for You</h3>
<p>Some CMS will work with your website using a subscription model where you pay the company a certain amount per month. But there are certainly others that are free of cost.</p>
<p>However, even with the free options, you can still have costs that come out when you need to link it with external applications or software for specific website features you may want to incorporate.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181257"></a>2. Stellar Support</h3>
<p>The best CMS for you needs to have a responsive and supportive customer support team. If you&#8217;re waiting for customer support representatives to get back to you for days or weeks on end regarding an issue with your website, your website and its traffic will.</p>
<p>So make sure the CMS you choose has a high-quality, reliable, and trust-worthy support team that other users can vouch for.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181258"></a>3. Which Content Management System Will Support Your SEO Best?</h3>
<p>Does the CMS feature easy ways for you to manage your website&#8217;s SEO?</p>
<p>Will it allow you to make changes for your SEO using the CMS directly or will you need to go the long route and get a coder?</p>
<p>The best CMS platform will make SEO easier and more efficient for you, not harder.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181259"></a>4. Ease of Personalization and Design</h3>
<p>Since the CMS is what you&#8217;ll use to design your website, your baby, you&#8217;ll naturally want it to look impressive and well-designed.</p>
<p>Some CMS platforms are definitely more outdated than others in terms of design. But a few are extremely good for designing the perfect website for your business or even your personal portfolio. To this end, there should be a wide array of website templates and designs for you to choose the one you want.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181260"></a>5. Website Security</h3>
<p>Some CMS platforms will take care of your website&#8217;s security for you, while when using others you&#8217;ll need to do it yourself.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181261"></a>6. Easy Website Migration Capabilities</h3>
<p>The best kind of CMS platform will not keep you if you want to migrate to a different platform. Instead, it will make the process of exporting your data to another CMS platform streamlined and easy.</p>
<p>After all, what is it they say—<em>if you love something, let it go? </em>So the best CMS software will allow you to move your website wherever you please.</p>
<h2>The Best Content Management Systems for SEO &amp; Why</h2>
<p>So you design a website, but what is the use of this website if it doesn’t make your products and services <em>visible</em>? We’re talking about the SOE value of various CMS platforms.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s evaluate the top contenders based purely on their SEO capabilities and tool kits.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181263"></a>1. WordPress</h3>
<p>WordPress has a massive array of themes and plugins that allow you to optimize your site for SEO. These benefits and unique advantages of WordPress allow it to be one of the most popular CMS used in the world today.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181264"></a>2. Drupal</h3>
<p>Drupal&#8217;s modules work similarly to WordPress&#8217;s plugins in that they support your SEO efforts in addition to in-built tools.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181265"></a>3. Magento</h3>
<p>Magento is a powerful CMS for e-commerce because it has a wide array of functionality. It also includes good resources and features on its website to help its users take full advantage of SEO. It&#8217;s more developer-friendly than beginner-friendly overall, though, so keep that in mind.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181266"></a>4. Hubspot</h3>
<p>Hubspot&#8217;s CMS Hub will give you automatically generated recommendations for SEO. It will even give you keyword recommendations in each part of your web page. It has many robust SEO features which you can have access to for $300/month.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181267"></a>5. Shopify</h3>
<p>We recommend <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/shopify-seo/">Shopify</a> in this list in case you&#8217;re a beginner and your domain is ecommerce. If your main target is to make sales through ecommerce, then Shopify is your best bet for SEO.</p>
<p>Shopify&#8217;s benefits are plentiful.</p>
<p>We recommend this CMS because Shopify&#8217;s interface is built for ecommerce SEO, so you&#8217;d have all the tools you need to spruce up your ecommerce store&#8217;s SEO. For its price point of $29/month, Shopify delivers on a lot of fronts in the ecommerce SEO department. Also, once you get some great sales, you can always upgrade to the plan that has even more functionality.</p>
<p>To really nail your SEO for ecommerce, be sure to check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-conversion-rate-optimization-hacks-you-should-know/">10 Conversion Rate Optimization Hacks You Should Know</a>.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Want to transform your website to be responsive and drive sales? Fill out the form below for our expert <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/web-design-and-development/" style="text-decoration:underline;">web design and development services</a>.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form4" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject4" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name4" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website4" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email4" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number4" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country4" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha4();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68181268"></a>Wrapping Up!</h2>
<p>And that&#8217;s all, folks! We’ve covered the best content management systems, choosing the best CMS for you, and the right CMS that will get you the most juice out of your SEO efforts.</p>
<p>As one of the leading digital marketing agencies in the U.S., we provide high-quality <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/web-design-development-services/">web design services</a> that&#8217;ll transform your website to be responsive and produce sales.</p>
<p>For more information about our services, call <a href="tel:8554444777">855-444-4777</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/">10 Best CMS for a Successful Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is a Good Website Domain Authority and How Can You Increase Yours?</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Harper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 11:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Website SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;re reading this blog, chances are, you&#8217;ve come across the term Domain Authority (DA) a couple of times. But what is Domain Authority? What does it mean for your website’s performance? To help you understand the concept and increase the Domain Authority of your website, we’ve created this comprehensive guide. Want to increase your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/">What is a Good Website Domain Authority and How Can You Increase Yours?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;re reading this blog, chances are, you&#8217;ve come across the term <strong>Domain Authority (DA) </strong>a couple of times. But what <em>is </em>Domain Authority? What does it mean for your website’s performance?</p>
<p><span id="more-2574"></span></p>
<p>To help you understand the concept and increase the Domain Authority of your website, we’ve created this comprehensive guide.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Want to increase your Domain Authority? We know how to get you there! Fill out the form to get great results!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2>Table of Contents</h2>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680080">What is Domain Authority?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680081">So, What Is A Good Domain Authority?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680082">How is Domain Authority Calculated?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680083">How to Increase Domain Authority of Your Website?</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680084"> Accept Only High-Quality, Relevant Backlinks</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680085"> Create a Link Building Strategy</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680086"> Guest Post to boost your Domain Authority</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680087"> Build Domain Authority with Content Syndication</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680088"> Create high-value content that fellow bloggers will want to link to</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680089"> Research your competitor&#8217;s strategies and consider writing power blogs</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680090"> Make sure to work on your on-page SEO</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680091">Update older content</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680092">Optimize images</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680093">Optimize meta tags and descriptions </a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680094">Use keywords naturally</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680095">Use both internal and external links</a></p>
<ol start="8">
<li><a href="#_Toc65680096"> Fix up your Technical SEO</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680097"> Social Signals</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680098"> Mobile Friendliness</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680099">Wrapping Up!</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc65680080"></a>What is Domain Authority?</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2589" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-14.png" alt="What is Domain Authority?" width="750" height="544" /></p>
<p>Created by Moz, Domain Authority is a ranking metric—an aggregated number—that indicates how <em>authoritative</em> your website is. The higher your website’s domain authority, the more easily it can rank for your target keywords.</p>
<p>Furthermore, Moz states that a website’s DA is calculated by assessing aspects like linking root domains and the number of total links into a DA score.</p>
<p>DA is scored on a scale of 1–100, with 1 being the lowest performing and 100 being the highest. New websites that have very little to no authority typically start out with a DA of 1. The top websites on the internet, including <u><a href="https://www.apple.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Apple</a></u>, <u><a href="https://www.youtube.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">YouTube</a></u>, and <u><a href="https://www.google.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Google</a>,</u> have DAs of 100.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680081"></a>So, What Is A Good Domain Authority?</h3>
<p>DA below 40 is considered poor; 40–50 is considered average; 51–60 is good; anything above 60 is excellent.</p>
<p>So clearly, scoring high when it comes to Domain Authority should definitely be on your business’s bucket list. But instead of focusing on getting the highest possible DA and competing with giants like Apple and Google, look at your competitors. Your goal should be to develop a higher domain authority than them.</p>
<p>Small businesses, for example, have a relatively lower DA overall, making it easier for competitors to scope out the landscape and improve their authority.</p>
<p>The next logical question is, how <em>do</em> you get high domain authority relative to your competitors?</p>
<p>There are many factors, and in this comprehensive blog, we’ll cover them all in depth.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680082"></a>How is Domain Authority Calculated?</h3>
<p>Domain Authority is calculated using the total number of backlinks you receive, including root domains (among a host of other metrics). It defines the ranking capabilities of an entire website for any page it creates, including but not limited to blog posts.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s important to note that <strong>Domain Authority</strong> is different from <strong>Page Authority (PA)</strong>. So what is Page Authority? While PA measures the ranking strength and capabilities of a single web page on a website, DA showcases the strength of the <em>entire website</em>, indicating the likelihood of a web page ranking when you create one. While different, PA largely depends on Domain Authority because they ultimately rely on the same factors.</p>
<p>So without further ado, let&#8217;s get to our comprehensive ways to increase your site&#8217;s Domain Authority.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc65680083"></a>How to Increase Domain Authority of Your Website?</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680084"></a>1. Accept Only High-Quality, Relevant Backlinks</h3>
<p>Your backlinks are arguably the most important factor in improving your Domain Authority score.</p>
<p>Backlinks are created when other websites hyperlink to your website. These links can send traffic to your websites, improve rankings, and increase your Domain Authority.</p>
<p>To better understand backlinks, check out our YouTube video <u><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GwiI6V1eyQg" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">What is Backlinking And Why is it Important for YOUR Business</a></u>.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GwiI6V1eyQg" width="730" height="411" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So your goal with backlinks is to make sure that they’re all high-quality and relevant to your site. Luckily, you can remove irrelevant, spammy backlinks that will harm your domain authority in the long run using the <u><a href="https://search.google.com/search-console/disavow-links?utm_source=wmx&amp;utm_medium=deprecation-pane&amp;utm_content=disavow-links-main" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Disavow tool</a></u>, courtesy of Google.</p>
<p>Way over your head? You can get in touch with a professional SEO company that can run a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/backlink-audit/">backlink audit</a> for you to take care of that.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2588" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-13.png" alt="screenshot of Disavow tool from Google for backlinks which helps improve website Domain Authority by removing irrelevant, low-quality links" width="1075" height="538" /></p>
<p>If only high-quality, relevant websites are able to link to your website, Google’s bots are more likely to trust your website’s domain authority. The industry-standard rule is that do-follow links are better than no-follow links. This is because do-follow links transfer greater &#8220;SEO juice&#8221; from the linking site to yours compared to no-follow links.</p>
<p>No follow links aren&#8217;t bad to have by any means—you just want to try to target more do-follow links because they’ll give you more SEO bang for your buck. Once you audit your current links and regularly remove the “trash” links, so to speak, you can focus on building more high-quality, relevant backlinks.</p>
<p><em><strong>Pro tip </strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>If you’re running a small business, submit your site for local roundups. These include “best XYZ” lists and/or directories that accept submissions. These are easy backlinks for you to grab for your business.</strong></em></p>
<p>Another hack is to collaborate with local businesses that have a similar customer demographic as you. In this way, you can build mutually beneficial links that are relevant to your mutual customers. You can even work with small businesses that you already have a professional relationship with whose customer demographics would be interested in your product or service. There are more ways to build high-quality links, though.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>We’ve helped hundreds of businesses increase their Domain Authority. Become one of them today!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680085"></a>2. Create a Link Building Strategy</h3>
<p>Now that you know you want to maintain only high quality, high authority links and are well aware of how to disavow unwanted links, you need a strategy to build wanted links.</p>
<p>The first most important building block to any great promotion strategy is having something of note or value to say in your industry. The second is to promote this content using every marketing channel at your disposal.</p>
<p>So once you&#8217;ve created in-depth blogs (we will get into details about <strong><em>how </em></strong>to create linkable content in a future point), send it to your email list and promote it on your social media channels. Don&#8217;t underestimate organic reach even if you don&#8217;t have a sizable following yet. Use hashtags that are relevant to your industry and content to get more eyeballs on your content.</p>
<p>The next step once you&#8217;ve squared away what you can do on your own is to reach out to the big boys. Or, at least, the <em>bigger </em>boys in your industry. As long as their website has a similar or greater authority as yours, you should contact them for a backlink. You want to be subtle as opposed to making demands when you contact them. Make sure you do your research regarding their brand beforehand. If the person&#8217;s audience isn&#8217;t relevant to yours, then there&#8217;s no point reaching out.</p>
<p>Express gratitude for the content they publish. Here, it can help to link to a specific blog that resonated with you, one that is similar in topic to the content you are seeking to build a link with. You can then say in your email or message that you also wrote a new blog about *insert similar topic interest* and that you thought they might enjoy it as someone who writes about said topic/s.</p>
<p>You can end your email or message by saying that your blog/guide/article/etc. might make a helpful addition to their page. End the message on a positive note and send it off. If they like your content and think it would help their audience to read it, they will happily link to it. Many will accept, a lot will say no, and some won&#8217;t even respond. That is part of the game of link building.</p>
<p>Another key way to proactively build links is to strategically guest post.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680086"></a>3. Guest Post to boost your Domain Authority</h3>
<p>Guest posting is when you write a piece that is to be published on a third party website instead of your own. A guest post is many times more efficient and effective at boosting your current DA score than only creating content on your native website is.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2587" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-12.png" alt="screenshot of example guest post page for the photography niche" width="1195" height="891" /></p>
<p>With guest posting, you will have many opportunities to link your website in your content or Author Bio yourself. Studies have shown that people are more likely to click on links within a blog while they are still gaining information rather than afterwards, once they have captured said information.</p>
<p>Both ways, however, provide a high quality backlink to your website from a reputable, high DA site that is sure to also boost your own DA. This is important because these links will be on high authority websites that you&#8217;ve found in your niche, showing Google that you are a thought leader in your industry.</p>
<p>In addition, since the new people that will read your post are already interested in your niche, this further improves the chances of them coming to your blog and linking back to <em>your</em> posts.</p>
<p>You can find guest posting websites by searching &#8220;*insert niche* guest posting websites&#8221; on Google.<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2586" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-11.png" alt="Screenshot of Google search to find relevant guest posting sites" width="1042" height="696" /></p>
<p>Yet another way is to locate them using key phrases such as &#8220;write for us&#8221;, &#8220;submit a post&#8221;, &#8220;submit a blog&#8221;, etc.</p>
<p>A final note on guest posts is to make sure that the links being provided to you are &#8220;<strong><em>do follow</em></strong>&#8221; and not &#8220;<em>no follow</em>&#8220;. <u>A do follow link will help your rankings directly</u> by communicating the link to search engines, while a no follow link will not communicate this.</p>
<p><em><strong>Pro Tip</strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>Since guest posting is a time intensive process, don&#8217;t mass produce content to be guest posted everywhere; instead, be more strategic about which websites will give you the biggest bang for your buck.</strong></em></p>
<p>While this information about no follow backlinks can persuade you to avoid no follow links altogether, chances are, you will get them at some point. There&#8217;s no need to remove them as long as they are from a relevant website in your niche.</p>
<p>They still provide referral traffic (which influences your rankings), brand awareness, and greater social media shares and engagement. So while no follow links may not directly impact your rankings and DA, they do indirectly help so there’s no harm to keep relevant no follow links as part of your website&#8217;s backlink portfolio.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680087"></a>4. Build Domain Authority with Content Syndication</h3>
<p>Content syndication is when you publish a singular piece of content on <em>multiple websites</em>. Note that this is separate from guest posting because, instead of creating entirely new content on a website, you are instead reposting it by giving the third party website permission to do so.</p>
<p>You can do this on your own using blog posting websites like <a href="http://www.linkedin.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a> and <a href="http://www.medium.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Medium</a>, and even forum websites such as <a href="https://www.quora.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Quora</a> and <a href="http://www.reddit.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Reddit.</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2585" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-10.png" alt="screenshot of LinkedIn blogs site where content can be reposted and linked back to your website to improve your backlinks and hence, Domain Authority" width="1146" height="890" /></p>
<p>You can also reach out to websites that will republish with your permission. To find these, search &#8220;republish with permission&#8221; and add the topic you are covering in your piece or even your niche as a whole so you can explore.</p>
<p>When you do find these web sources where you can republish with permission, you want to reach out to them communicating the value their site will receive through republishing your specific content piece.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680088"></a>5. Create high-value content that fellow bloggers will want to link to</h3>
<p>There’s a reason we keep saying that <em><u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/why-content-driven-seo-is-a-lucrative-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2019-and-beyond/">Content is King</a>. </u></em>That’s because it truly is, fit with a bombastic gold crown and silver scepter.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2584" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-9.png" alt="A content marketer is typing on their laptop writing high-quality content to improve their website’s SEO and Domain AuthorityA content marketer is typing on their laptop writing high-quality content to improve their website’s SEO and Domain Authority" width="962" height="642" /></p>
<p>The truth is, you can follow every single SEO advice and tactic in the proverbial book, but, ultimately, having good SEO clears the path for a site visitor to come to your content. So if your content isn’t helpful, engaging, or even interesting, you’re going to get stuck with a high bounce rate and very minimal to <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2020/03/04/the-secret-to-high-search-engine-rankings-quality-content/?sh=2b42b5b070c5" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">no conversions</a></u>.</p>
<p>People are searching for answers to their pain-points and concerns on the internet. If you’re the one to be able to provide them with answers in a way that makes sense to them, they’ll be grateful and are more likely to remember your site as a future resource.</p>
<p>Good content is helpful to build trust with your prospect. Trust leads to higher site visits, lower bounce rates, greater dwell time, and greater conversions. Yet another awesome benefit of creating high-quality content, though, is that authoritative blogs within your niche will also find it valuable.</p>
<p>Because your blog explains, teaches, or provides some sort of resource to them in an easily digestible manner, they’ll be incentivized to link back to your blog as a citation in one of their pieces. Therefore, your go-to strategy to increase your DA should be to regularly release high-value content for your niche.</p>
<p><em><strong><u>Pro Tip</u></strong></em></p>
<p><em>Provide valuable content that you can use is to create media-rich content such as infographics, graphs, and charts that break down complex topics in your niche into a simple picture.</em></p>
<p>One final tip we will impart here for content is if you&#8217;re wondering what kind of content to create that fills a gap, you might want to check out the content your competitors are creating and figure out what&#8217;s missing. Therein lies your opportunity.</p>
<p>To learn more about writing great content, be sure to check out our blog: <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-to-write-a-blog-that-ranks/">How To Write A Blog That Ranks</a></u>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680089"></a>6. Research your competitor&#8217;s strategies and consider writing power blogs</h3>
<p>If you do your research thoroughly, you&#8217;ll discover the keywords your competitors are targeting. Based on this, you’ll know what’s missing in your content marketing strategy <em>and </em>what you need to beat in order to rank.</p>
<p>Check what kind of sites are already linking to their web page. Are you able to build a Franken-blog that is the MOST comprehensive one out of all these competitors? This kind of blog, also known as a power blog, can be highly sought after by readers because it is a one-stop shop for everything they need to know about a topic. A power blog in this way can help your blog stand out.</p>
<p>If you still need convincing here, be sure to read our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-reasons-why-you-need-power-blog-posts-for-your-website-blog/">5 Reasons Why You Need Power Blog PostsFor Your Website Blog</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680090"></a>7. Make sure to work on your on-page SEO</h3>
<p>In addition to your off-page SEO, which includes setting up backlinks, it’s also important to work on your <em>on-page SEO </em>to increase your domain authority.</p>
<h4><a name="_Toc65680091"></a>Update older content</h4>
<p>The most important factor in your on-page SEO is to make sure your content is up to date and relevant to today’s audiences. If your blog has lost relevance, it will result in an increased bounce rate, which ultimately affects your overall SEO efforts, rankings, and domain authority.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2583" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-8.png" alt="A screenshot of a recent Search Berg blog updated for relevancy in 2021" width="699" height="337" /></p>
<h4><a name="_Toc65680092"></a>Optimize images</h4>
<p>A feature not enough people with websites are aware of is that you can actually add more text at the back-end of every image on your website.</p>
<p>You can do this by updating the image’s file name and the associated Alt Text. The point of these fields is to show the text to the viewer about what’s happening in the image in case it doesn’t load, or your visitor is visually impaired. You can simply describe what your image contains and, where relevant, insert your target keywords in the Alt text.</p>
<h4><a name="_Toc65680093"></a>Optimize meta tags and descriptions</h4>
<p>Each page on your website will have a section in the HTML region to optimize your meta tags and descriptions.<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2582" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-7.png" alt="Meta tags and descriptions shown in search results, which, when optimized, improve website Domain Authority and SEO" width="952" height="656" /></p>
<p>In a nutshell, these are the titles and descriptions that appear on Google when you search a term.</p>
<p>So if you leave your meta tags and descriptions up to chance, Google will phrase them at random. Since this is the equivalent of your store’s front sign, i.e., the first thing any of your prospects from Google search results will see, it’s worth optimizing for keywords and readability.</p>
<p>To discover more detailed tactics on tackling meta tags and descriptions, you can learn it all in our blog <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-meta-tags-affect-your-websites-seo/">How Meta Tags Affect Your Website’s SEO</a></u>.</p>
<h4><a name="_Toc65680094"></a>Use keywords naturally</h4>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2581" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-6.png" alt="Visual demonstration of web SEO and Domain Authority" width="750" height="544" /></p>
<p>The number one practice that you want to avoid like the plague is keyword stuffing. Keyword stuffing is essentially when a keyword is “stuffed” into a site’s meta data, backlinks, web pages, etc., in an attempt to game the system and unfairly rank higher.</p>
<p>This may have worked very briefly a long, long time ago, but since <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnrampton/2017/01/28/seo-keyword-ratio-guide-how-to-not-kill-your-seo/?sh=5bef0bcd599a" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">the Hummingbird Update</a>, Google and its robots which crawl your website have gotten very smart. Not only do they catch on if your website includes keyword stuffing, but they also penalize your website by rapidly reducing its rankings. So the best policy is to play the game by Google’s rules and win. This means using your target keywords naturally where they are relevant in your blog and web content.</p>
<p>The more you place your keywords based on relevancy, the greater its readability becomes, and therefore, the longer your reader is likely to stay engaged.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680095"></a>Use both internal and external links</h3>
<p>Internal links are important because they create a web of interconnected pages on your website through links. The more coiled and well-connected the <em>web</em> is, the better Google’s <em>Spiders </em>can crawl it.</p>
<p>Who doesn’t love a good spider pun?</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2580" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-5.png" alt="A spider web is shown with a spider crawling it to illustrate that increasing internal links help Google's spiders crawl your website more easily, improving your domain authority." width="962" height="642" /></p>
<p>Internal links build a high-quality network between your web pages the Spiders can index on Google.</p>
<p>Building internal links also helps you &#8220;pass on&#8221; some of the authority you&#8217;ve gained from a reputable page to other specific web pages on your site for which your goal is to rank.</p>
<p>External links help when they are relevant because it shows you are linking to note-worthy blogs and websites related to your topics. The idea is: if you’re commenting about relevant topics within your niche, then your commentary must by proxy also be somewhat relevant.</p>
<p>For further on-page SEO tips to keep your visitor on your website longer, you can check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-to-improve-website-bounce-rate/">10 Proven Tips to Drastically Reduce Website Bounce Rate</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680096"></a>8. Fix up your Technical SEO</h3>
<p>Your technical SEO is the foundation upon which your rankings, domain authority, and everything you&#8217;re doing for your website, stand on. You need to have your website registered on Google Search Console. Once you&#8217;ve registered, submit a file known as the &#8220;xml sitemap&#8221; of your website to Google Search Console.</p>
<p>This is the equivalent of giving Google a &#8220;cheat sheet&#8221; map to send its crawlers through your website. You want these crawlers all over your website because once they are, they can index your web pages.</p>
<p>Indexing your pages means that they become part of the Google Search results. Once you&#8217;ve completed these steps, you can actually test your pages for crawlability.</p>
<p>This can be done using the Fetch tool within Google Search Console. The <a href="https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2011/08/submit-urls-to-google-with-fetch-as" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Fetch as Google bot</a> feature in your Google Search Console dashboard allows you to submit new and updated URLs to Google for sped-up indexing and to check whether your site pages can be crawled by Google&#8217;s bots.</p>
<p>To check the status of existing pages that you&#8217;ve already been in the process of indexing, you can use Google&#8217;s <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/9012289" rel="nofollow">URL Inspection Tool</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2579" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-4.png" alt="A screenshot of a Google tool to help with technical SEO and heighten domain authority" width="962" height="395" /></p>
<p>Crawlability problems, in particular, are frustrating because they mean that even if all the right elements on your website are in place, you are still missing out on some SEO juice that can impact your domain authority score.</p>
<p>Thus, it&#8217;s important to regularly audit your website for crawlability problems including problematic redirects, links that don&#8217;t work, 404 pages, irrelevant or outdated content links, etc.</p>
<p>Another major focus area to improve your DA should be social signals.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680097"></a>9. Social Signals</h3>
<p>Social signals are social media engagements and shares. They’re important because they indicate to Google that your content is creating buzz and is relevant within your niche.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2578" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-3.png" alt="Worldwide social media penetration statistics to demonstrate its importance in the world today and how it can be instrumental in bettering a website's Domain Authority" width="958" height="651" /></p>
<p>While Google has maintained that Social Signals are not an official ranking factor, there’s a huge correlation between pages that rank well and their social media presences. High-ranking pages have great social media presence and engagement metrics.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2577" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-2.png" alt="Screenshot of Searchberg Facebook page" width="1153" height="897" /></p>
<p>This means building your brand and/or small business&#8217;s presence on social media is an integral step to take if you want to secure a high Domain Authority.</p>
<p>Whether you start with <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-to-get-more-followers-on-linkedin/">LinkedIn</a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/top-10-ways-to-grow-a-small-business-through-facebook/">Facebook</a>, or <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-to-unleash-the-power-of-instagram-to-promote-your-brand/">Instagram</a>, the key is to build your brand and engage with your customers in a meaningful way. Take the key principles from our content section in this blog and apply them here. You want to provide value, and on social media, this can be as simple as bringing positivity to someone&#8217;s newsfeed.</p>
<p>To learn more in-depth strategies for each social media platform stated previously, be sure to check out the links above. To binge-learn how to create high-quality social media content for your business and improve your engagement, here’s a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/category/social-media-management/">list</a> of our social media marketing blogs for businesses to help you out.</p>
<p>Specifically to improve your SEO and therefore, DA, we suggest reading our blog Social Media and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-and-seo-how-to-use-social-media-to-improve-seo-rankings/">SEO: How to Use Social Media to Improve SEO Rankings</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680098"></a>10. Mobile Friendliness</h3>
<p>Making sure your website is mobile friendly is important for three key reasons:</p>
<ol>
<li>Mobile friendly sites are easier to use, providing a more high quality user experience</li>
<li>They are looked upon more favorably by Google&#8217;s ranking system</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Thus, they are more likely to secure backlinks, so it&#8217;s a key way to improve your site&#8217;s Domain Authority.</li>
</ul>
<p>Since <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/groupthink/2015/05/15/can-your-business-survive-googles-mobile-geddon/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Mobilegeddon</a> in 2015, Google has cracked down on websites which are not friendly to use on a mobile device or smartphone and rewards those sites that are.</p>
<p>So if a website is easy to use on a smartphone or a tablet, then Google notices and ranks that site higher in the search results for the site&#8217;s target keywords.</p>
<p>If it&#8217;s not, however, then the algorithm punishes the site by reducing its rankings and pushing its web pages lower in search results.</p>
<p>You can easily measure your website&#8217;s mobile friendliness capabilities using the Google <a href="https://search.google.com/test/mobile-friendly" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Mobile Friendly Test Tool.</a><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2576" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-1.png" alt="screen shot of mobile friendly test tool through Google to help improve mobile friendliness and increase Domain Authority" width="1188" height="875" /></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc65680099"></a>Wrapping Up!</h2>
<p>In this blog, we dove into the deep end to learn all about website DA and how to increase domain authority.</p>
<p>While many of these tips can easily be performed by an everyday Joe who is just learning about domain authority and discovering the world of SEO, it will definitely speed things up and prevent errors if you consult with professionals who have been in the game for a long time.</p>
<p>We, at <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/">Search Berg</a>, can help you <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/high-domain-authority/">increase your website&#8217;s domain authority today</a>. Call us at <a href="tel:855-444-4777">855-444-4777</a> to kick-start your domain authority score and SEO rankings or fill out the form below!</li>
</ol>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/">What is a Good Website Domain Authority and How Can You Increase Yours?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Algorithm Updates That Changed SEO</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-algorithm-updates-that-changed-seo/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-algorithm-updates-that-changed-seo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 09:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Google&#8217;s Ranking System includes the use of multiple advanced algorithms that sort through billions of web pages per second to deliver the most relevant information to users.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-algorithm-updates-that-changed-seo/">Google Algorithm Updates That Changed SEO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google&#8217;s Ranking System includes the use of multiple advanced algorithms that sort through billions of web pages per second to deliver the most relevant information to users.<span id="more-2562"></span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/searchberg_revised-01-1-min1.jpg"  alt="Google's Ranking System includes the use of multiple advanced algorithms that sort through billions of web pages per second to deliver the most relevant information to users."  width="730" height="5008" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2569" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-algorithm-updates-that-changed-seo/">Google Algorithm Updates That Changed SEO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-algorithm-updates-that-changed-seo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Meta Tags Affect Your Website’s SEO</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-meta-tags-affect-your-websites-seo/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-meta-tags-affect-your-websites-seo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dennis Nguyen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 13:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wondered what Meta Data or Tags in SEO are or how on Earth they even help your site’s SEO rankings? There’s a ton of buzz in the SEO world around the use of Meta Tags. Today, we want to help you discover Meta Tags; we’ll provide you with a comprehensive guide to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-meta-tags-affect-your-websites-seo/">How Meta Tags Affect Your Website’s SEO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wondered what Meta Data or Tags in SEO are or how on Earth they even help your site’s SEO rankings?</p>
<p><span id="more-2517"></span></p>
<p>There’s a <strong><u>ton</u></strong> of buzz in the SEO world around the use of Meta Tags. Today, we want to help you <strong>discover Meta Tags</strong>; we’ll provide you with a <strong>comprehensive guide</strong> to navigating Meta Tags in order to<em> boost your site’s SEO</em> rankings.</p>
<p>Let’s start by defining Meta Tags.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Struggling to understand how Meta Tags can skyrocket your website’s rankings? We’ve been in the game long enough to know what works and what doesn’t. Fill out the form to get great results!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Catalog</h2>
<p><a href="#_Toc19666">What Exactly Are Meta Tags, Anyway?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc6364">So Why Are Meta Tags Important For Your Site’s Ranking?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc30419">Essential Meta Tags To Fill To Boost Your Webpages’ SEO</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc16285"> Title Tags</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc607"> Meta Description Tags</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc21287"> Image Description Tags</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc1114"> No follow attributes</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc31246"> Robots Meta Tag</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc24895"> Social Media Meta Tags</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc26160">The 4 codes or puzzle pieces to control how your page appears on social media are as follows:</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc11645">Best Tools For Meta Tag Optimization</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc1065"> Yoast Optimization Plugin</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc11676"> BuzzStream Meta Tag Extractor</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc20302">Wrapping Up!</a></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc19666"></a>What Exactly Are Meta Tags, Anyway?</h2>
<p>Meta Tags serve in your site’s HTML code provide search engines with data about your site and its pages. They are invisible, akin to a Russian Babushka doll; they <strong><u>provide data about data</u></strong>.</p>
<p>This data, in turn, helps search engines like Google not only rank your site appropriately based on keyword usage and search relevance, but also to display snippets in search results.</p>
<p>By <em>“invisible</em>,” we mean that Meta Tags won’t appear on the website itself, but are present within the site’s source code.</p>
<p>Some examples of Meta Tags include the <strong>&lt;title&gt;</strong> and <strong>&lt;description&gt;</strong> tags.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc6364"></a>So Why Are Meta Tags Important For Your Site’s Ranking?</h2>
<p>As stated above, Meta Tags help your site rank on SERPs and display snippets in search results, which are both crucial SEO functions. But in addition to these functions, <strong>Meta Tags act as the “cover” of your website</strong>, and you can bet a reader<em> will </em>judge a book (read: site) by this cover.</p>
<p>Acclaimed Digital Marketers even goes as far as to say that <strong><em>without Meta Tags, you literally cannot rank organically</em></strong>. They function as the foundation of SEO and should be one of the first things you attend to when setting up your site.</p>
<p>Truthfully, the tiny investment of time that goes into making this change to your site can be a game-changer, because 93% of all online experiences begin with a search engine. So naturally you want to <strong>speak the search engine’s language</strong> and <strong>communicate</strong> what your web page is about to it!</p>
<p>Secondly, they act as a metaphorical website cover not just in search engines, but also on social media and email. Do you ever notice how when you paste a link somewhere on social media or in an email, it suddenly looks very presentable with large titles, and even a picture comes up?</p>
<p>That’s the <em>power </em>of Meta Tags.</p>
<p>Meta tags ultimately affect your site’s rankings because they can help a user find relevant pages on your site. It is crucial to add your core keyword/s in your Meta Tags. Title tags, for instance, should include relevant keywords that your target customer may be searching for.</p>
<p>To reinforce how Meta Tags fit into your complete marketing strategy, we have created a helpful comprehensive <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-a-blog-that-ranks/">infographic</a> to illustrate each aspect of your plan, including but not limited to using Meta Tags.</p>
<p>So now that you know the awesome powers of using Meta Tags in your webpages, you may be wondering what types of Meta Tags are key for you to pay attention to.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Want to rank your web pages and take full advantage of Meta Tags? We know how to make it happen.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>While there are many, many types of Meta Tags, we have compiled the most essential ones in this list:</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc30419"></a>Essential Meta Tags To Boost SEO Rankings</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc16285"></a>Title Tags</h3>
<p><strong>What is a Meta Title in SEO?</strong></p>
<p>Title tags provide you with a bird’s eye view of what your page is about and are inserted in the &lt;head&gt; of your webpage. A hack for writing your title tag is to simply use your H1. In fact, Google actually <a href="https://support.google.com/news/publisher-center/answer/9607104?hl=en&amp;ref_topic=9606945" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">recommends</a> this practice (slight differences notwithstanding) because it creates consistency for the user.</p>
<p>You can optimize your HTML Meta title tags for SEO by:</p>
<ul>
<li>Making sure that each page on your website has a <strong>unique title</strong> that<strong> communicates that page’s content</strong> in a concise manner.</li>
<li>Since longer title tags get cut off by the SERP’s, make sure they are between<strong> 50-60 characters</strong> in length.</li>
<li><strong>Prioritize your most important keywords </strong>first and use those in the beginning of your title tags. The more<strong> naturally inserted in the sentence or title</strong>, the better. Unnatural usage or stuffing the Meta Tag can be both detrimental to SEO and off-putting to the reader.</li>
</ul>
<p>You can change the title tag either directly in the source code of your site or if you have a Content Management System like <em>WordPress</em>, it can be as simple as <strong>changing the title </strong>of your webpage.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc607"></a>Meta Description Tags</h3>
<p>Do Meta Description Tags Matter and how important is it for SEO? <strong>A</strong>s the name implies, allow you to describe a page’s content. They serves as a succinct overview of what the reader can expect if they were to click on your webpage in the search engine.</p>
<p>The <strong><em><u>more accurate the description</u></em></strong><em><u>,<strong> the happier the user </strong></u></em>will be when they read content, because it was exactly what it said on the tin.</p>
<p>The Meta Name Description resides in the<strong>&lt;head&gt;</strong> of a webpage and usually shows up in the snippet when your page ranks for a keyword.</p>
<p>The HTML source code for this tag would look something like this:</p>
<p><strong>&lt;head&gt;<br />
&lt;meta name=”description” content=”This is what your description will look like. If a user finds it relevant to their search, they click through to your page.”&gt;<br />
&lt;/head&gt;</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>While it is true that a description tag does not directly correlate with SEO, make no mistake because it still helps with SEO.</p>
<p>A good, relevant description <strong>massively increases click-throughs</strong> to your site’s page.</p>
<p>Secondly, if the description matches your site’s content it can also significantly reduce your site’s bounce rate. The description element is the <strong>largest bit of keyword real-estate</strong> you get in your snippet, so be sure to take full advantage of it.</p>
<p>For even more killer best practices for using Meta Tags for your webpages, go through <a href="https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/344233" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">this article</a> on <em>Entrepreneur </em>as well.</p>
<p>Fun fact: you may have noticed that when you search keywords on a search engine, the keywords that match those that are searched for become <strong>bold</strong> in the SERP.</p>
<p>This can help your site stand out in terms of informing a user what they can hope to find in your site.</p>
<p>You can optimize your Meta Description Tags For Keywords on Google by:</p>
<ul>
<li>Write up a <strong>unique meta description for each page</strong> that you wish to rank which clearly informs the reader what content lies on the other side of their click.</li>
<li>Keep it between<strong> 150-160 characters</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>Insert the important keywords</strong> you wish to rank for in the description, naturally. No stuffing!</li>
</ul>
<h3><a name="_Toc21287"></a>Image Description Tags</h3>
<p>Have you ever wondered <em>why</em> we need to add descriptions to images? Aren’t <strong>images</strong> meant to be <strong>viewed </strong>rather than <strong><em>described</em></strong>?</p>
<p>Well, for one, it <strong><em><u>helps search engines understand what the image is of</u></em></strong>, so it can guide the relevant audience to it.</p>
<p>Secondly, the<strong> alt text</strong> in a description is <strong>crucial</strong> for those who are <strong>visually impaired</strong> to be able to understand what the image is of.<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2520" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/blog2-2.png" alt="concept illustration image Alt Text Description For SEO" width="1124" height="667" /></p>
<p>Again, Google itself <a href="https://www.searchenginejournal.com/google-image-publishing-guidelines/252149/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">recommends this practice</a> to help search engines understand what the pictures in your post are about and how they are relevant to the topic at hand and keywords you want to target.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc1114"></a>No follow attributes</h3>
<p>Have you ever come across black hat link building tactics like stuffing a bunch of irrelevant links in a post just for the sake of building links?<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2519" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/blog2-1.png" alt="concept illustration no follow attributes for SEO Meta Tags" width="750" height="544" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Google has been <strong>seriously</strong> and <strong>mercilessly cracking down</strong> on such webpages, causing SEO rankings to hurtle far beneath the ground.</p>
<p>When you put <strong>contextually relevant links</strong> to <strong>enhance</strong> the reader’s experience, Google looks at this as you giving a vote of confidence to that link. It automatically considers this as a<strong> do-follow</strong> link.</p>
<p><em>Some</em> links on your website, such as those in your<em> comments section</em>, you want to make <strong>no-follow </strong>so they do not hurt your <strong>credibility</strong> in Google’s eyes. Therefore, it is key to both pay attention to where you link to as well as how.</p>
<p>The main <strong><em>red-flag links</em></strong> that you want to place no-follow restrictions on would be:</p>
<ol>
<li>Any paid or sponsored links</li>
<li>Links that you do not trust or look<em> spammy</em></li>
<li>Internal links that have little to no content and therefore don’t make sense to crawl, such as registration and sign in pages on your website.</li>
</ol>
<h3><a name="_Toc31246"></a>Robots Meta Tag</h3>
<p>This is another means for telling Google and other search engines <strong>not to crawl or index a page. </strong></p>
<p>The meta robots tag<strong> Content=”no index”</strong> indicates to search engines to not index a particular page and consequently all the links present on this same page become no-follow links automatically.</p>
<p>Like with no follow links, <strong><u>it makes little sense to index pages that have little content</u></strong>. This Meta Tag also applies to pages on your site that are currently under construction.</p>
<p>If the internet were a bakery, you wouldn’t send a <strong><em>half-done cake</em></strong> out for display to your customers, would you?</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc24895"></a>Social Media Meta Tags</h3>
<p>Have you ever considered why some accounts’ social media posts look absolutely professional and consistent in how their<strong> links display</strong> in each and every social media post?</p>
<p>The “<strong>secret sauce software”</strong> that many of these companies and individual users is known as <strong><u>Open Graph.</u></strong></p>
<p><strong>Open Graph</strong> is a protocol for how your site’s web page will appear on a social media post.</p>
<p>It allows <strong>you</strong> to control what content is displayed when your website is linked to social media websites, including Facebook, LinkedIn &amp; Twitter (If <strong>Twitter Cards</strong> are not present).</p>
<p>You accomplish this by adding <strong>little codes</strong> in the source code for each page on your site.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc26160"></a>The 4 codes or puzzle pieces to control how your page appears on social media are as follows:</h2>
<ol>
<li>og:title: This is your page’s title. Generally this will be the same title as your web page &lt;title&gt;tag, unless for some reason you wish to display it differently.</li>
<li>og:type: The “type” of website you have. For this you can generally just write “website”.</li>
<li>og:image: This is where you would place the URL of the image that you want representing your content on your site’s web page. It should be a high quality picture that can be used by the social networks to come up in its feeds.</li>
<li>og:url: This should be the URL of the current page.</li>
</ol>
<p>Using these 4 puzzle pieces, you just need to bring them together and insert your <strong>page title, website type, image URL &amp; URL</strong> of the page itself. Here is an example template:</p>
<p>&lt;meta property=&#8221;og:title&#8221;content=&#8221;Your Site’s Page Title&#8221;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&#8221;og:type&#8221;content=&#8221;website&#8221;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&#8221;og:image&#8221;content=&#8221;https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2017/08/16/18/35/pug-2648774_960_720.jpg&#8221;/&gt;&lt;meta property=&#8221;og:url&#8221;content=&#8221;https://www.searchberg.com&#8221;/&gt;</p>
<p>You might want to visit the image link above<em> purely</em> for entertainment value.</p>
<p><strong>Twitter Cards</strong> offer similar enhancements but are<strong> purely for Twitter</strong>. You might also want to test the web page’s URLs to see if they display the way that you want to on social media.</p>
<p>While you definitely want to make sure you optimize the way your social media content is presented to your prospects, this is <strong><u>no substitute for good, quality content.</u></strong> A bag full of coal wrapped nicely is still a bag full of coal. To help you create <em>killer</em> content we’ve created<a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-and-seo-how-to-use-social-media-to-improve-seo-rankings/"> this blog post </a>to help you connect with your audience, engage with them and make your content easily shareable, among other social media goals.</p>
<p>All this jargon related to source codes can be overwhelming at first.</p>
<p>What if: <strong>you understand <u>absolutely nothing </u>about web development or source codes?</strong></p>
<p>Luckily, for those of us who aren’t very interested in going through the site’s backend for Meta Tag optimization, there are some <strong>very good and easy to use tools available. </strong></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc11645"></a>Best Tools For Meta Tag Optimization</h2>
<p>Now that you have a basic understanding of Meta Tags and how they can be helpful, let’s talk about<strong> applying your newly acquired knowledge</strong> for Meta Tag Optimization.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc1065"></a>Yoast Optimization Plugin</h3>
<p><em>Yoast</em> is basically one of the most popular search engine optimization plug-ins out there. Using Yoast, you will have easy access to the back-end controls for all of the pages and blogs you put up. Yoast, in this way, <u>facilitates Meta Tag optimization, increasing social sharing, SEO optimization, and other metadata options. </u></p>
<p>Absolutely <strong><em><u>no coding necessary</u></em></strong><u>.</u></p>
<h3><strong><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2518" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/blog2.png" alt="Yoast SEO plugin for Meta Title And Description Tags" width="828" height="390" /></strong></h3>
<h3><a name="_Toc11676"></a><strong>BuzzStream Meta Tag Extractor</strong></h3>
<p><strong>This is a great hack to spy on what Meta Tags your competitors are using. You essentially go on</strong> <a href="http://tools.buzzstream.com/meta-tag-extractor" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">BuzzStream’s Meta Tag Extractor</a>, copy-paste a list of your competition’s URLs, and it spits out their Meta Tag information.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc20302"></a>Wrapping Up!</h2>
<p>To boost your site’s rankings, make sure to pay attention to these <strong><u>small but crucial</u></strong> elements.</p>
<p><strong>Little changes definitely add up</strong> in the world of SEO.</p>
<p>Now you know the essential information to use Meta Tags effectively for your site’s success. Call <strong><a href="tel:855-444-4777">855-444-4777</a></strong> and let’s get to work to <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/">increase your rankings</a>!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-meta-tags-affect-your-websites-seo/">How Meta Tags Affect Your Website’s SEO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-meta-tags-affect-your-websites-seo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Difference Between Organic and Paid Search</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-difference-between-organic-and-paid-search/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-difference-between-organic-and-paid-search/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 08:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pay Per Click]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Do you sell products/services online? If so, you should have a strong grasp on the difference between organic and paid search. As an online business, your primary goal is to reach a wide audience and maximize conversions. Both organic and paid search help you do just that! They boost your online visibility, improve your SERP [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-difference-between-organic-and-paid-search/">The Difference Between Organic and Paid Search</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do you sell products/services online? If so, you should have a strong grasp on the difference between organic and paid search. <span id="more-2473"></span><br />
As an online business, your primary goal is to reach a wide audience and maximize conversions. Both organic and paid search help you do just that! They boost your online visibility, improve your SERP rankings, and help you generate more traffic. Sounds like the perfect mix?<br />
In this infographic, we dive deeper and walk you through the differences between organic and paid search. We cover their position, cost, ranking, and speed. We also discuss some genius tips to improve both organic and paid search campaigns. Let’s get right into it!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2474" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SearchBerg_revised-01-min.jpg" alt="Difference between organic and paid search" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-difference-between-organic-and-paid-search/">The Difference Between Organic and Paid Search</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-difference-between-organic-and-paid-search/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Get More Followers on LinkedIn</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-followers-on-linkedin/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-followers-on-linkedin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 06:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2439</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>With an astounding 675 million monthly users, LinkedIn is a gold mine for businesses in 2021. The mega networking platform isn’t just your regular go-to for employment purposes; it’s also a game-changing marketing tool. If you’ve already dipped your toes in the LinkedIn marketing water, you’re on the right track. But simply creating a business [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-followers-on-linkedin/">How to Get More Followers on LinkedIn</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With an astounding <strong><u>675 million monthly users</u></strong>, LinkedIn is a gold mine for businesses in 2021. The mega networking platform isn’t just your regular go-to for employment purposes; it’s also a <em>game-changing</em> marketing tool.</p>
<p>If you’ve already dipped your toes in the LinkedIn marketing water, you’re on the right track. But simply creating a business profile isn’t enough. You <em>have</em> to go the extra mile and leverage LinkedIn marketing tips to grow your <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/setup/new/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">company page</a>.</p>
<p>In this blog, we want to walk you through top-tier strategies to get more followers on LinkedIn. We’ll cover the basics, dive into the deep end, and get into the nitty-gritty.</p>
<p>By the end of this blog, you’ll have a firm grasp on how to engage followers on LinkedIn like a seasoned pro. Let’s jump right into it!</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Struggling to revive your LinkedIn follower count? We’ve been in the game long enough to know what works and what doesn’t. Fill out the form to get great results!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2>Contents</h2>
<ul class="toc_list">
<li><a href="#_Toc61021480">Ways to Get More Followers on LinkedIn</a>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021481"> Create a Winning Company Page from the Get-Go</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021482"> Use the <em>Right</em> Hashtags the <em>Right</em> Way!</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021483"> Include High-Quality Images in Your Posts</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021484"> Don’t Sideline the Importance of Engaging Videos</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021485"> Share Value-Added, Insightful, and Compelling Content</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021486"> Make the Most of Polls</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021487"> Highlight Your Company’s Accomplishments</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021488"> Create Special Posts for Major Events, Holidays, and Trends</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021489"> Encourage Your Employees to Join the Action</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021490"> Actively Participate in LinkedIn Groups</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021491"> Use LinkedIn Sponsored Ads</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021492"> Promote Your LinkedIn Page on Social Media and Your Website</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021493">Wrapping Up! </a></li>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc61021480"></a>Ways to Get More Followers on LinkedIn</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021481"></a>1. Create a Winning Company Page from the Get-Go</h3>
<p>When getting started with LinkedIn marketing, many companies have a razor-sharp focus on optimization. As they should!</p>
<p>However, jumping straight into optimization without taking care of the basics is <em><u>not</u></em> the right way to go. If your company page isn’t up-to-date, optimization simply won’t do the trick.</p>
<p>Start by creating a strong foundation and working your way upwards. Let’s take a quick look at how you can do that with an example.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2441" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-1.png" alt="DELL’s LinkedIn Page as example of a Winning Company Page " width="1119" height="367" /></a></p>
<p>Dell’s LinkedIn company page checks off all the fundamental boxes.</p>
<p>High-quality profile picture and cover image? Check.</p>
<p>Accurate industry and location? Check.</p>
<p>Concise and catchy subheading? Check.</p>
<p>Once you take a closer look, you begin to realize that <em>they haven’t stopped there</em>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-2.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2442" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-2.png" alt="DELL’s LinkedIn Page as example of a Winning Company Page " width="542" height="527" /></a></p>
<p>The “overview” section is replete with to-the-point information.</p>
<p><em>“What does this have to do with getting more followers?”</em> you may ask.</p>
<p>As a professional platform, LinkedIn has set a high standard for its users. They don’t expect subpar, incomplete nuggets of information. Instead, they’re looking to <em>connect</em> with companies that are <strong><u>on top of their game</u></strong>.</p>
<p>If your company page is incomplete, your lack of interest in comprehensiveness will reflect poorly on your business as a whole. Ultimately, it may cost you your follower count. As a rule of thumb, make sure your company page is updated with <strong><u>accurate information</u></strong>. Avoid going overboard; the descriptions should be concise and the images professional. Anything too flashy or verbose will do more harm than good.</p>
<p>We also recommend adding the <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/1593/affiliated-linkedin-pages?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">“affiliated pages” section</a> to your profile.</p>
<p>Here’s how this section appears on Dell’s company page:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-3.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2443" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-3.png" alt="DELL’s LinkedIn Page as example of a Winning Company Page " width="299" height="444" /></a></p>
<p>As a parent page, you can link child pages, i.e., companies that are closely associated with your business and owned by you. If you’re a small business or a startup, you can choose to forgo this option.</p>
<p>Ultimately, covering <em><u>as many bases as possible</u></em> will help you make a great first impression on professionals who are looking to interact with your brand. A professional, clean, and comprehensive company page will go a long way in adding a touch of legitimacy to your business.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021482"></a>2. Use the <em>Right</em> Hashtags the <em>Right</em> Way!</h3>
<p>Is your company page up and running? Great.</p>
<p>It’s time to turn your attention to <strong><u>optimization</u></strong>. Optimization is your golden ticket to engaging a wide audience on LinkedIn. And while there are many ways to optimize your profile (we’ll cover all of them shortly), using hashtags is still one of the most effective strategies in 2021.</p>
<p>If you’ve been navigating the digital marketing industry for a while now, you’re probably familiar with the importance of using the right keywords in your content.</p>
<p>Hashtags are like <em>keywords</em> for your LinkedIn company page. Yes, this means you should have a stellar “hashtag research” (akin to “keyword research”) strategy in place.</p>
<p>If you’re new to LinkedIn, you can use the platform’s in-built hashtag recommendations.</p>
<p>Let’s say you’re sharing an engaging article that covers the benefits of link building.</p>
<p>Once you start typing a relevant hashtag, you’ll get recommendations accordingly.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-4.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2444" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-4.png" alt="how to use hashtags on LinkedIn posts " width="525" height="372" /></a></p>
<p>If you’re completely unsure of which hashtags to use, LinkedIn will do the job for you. The platform will pick up on keywords used in the post, and display a set of relevant hashtags accordingly.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-6.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2446" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-6.png" alt="how to use hashtags on LinkedIn posts " width="522" height="365" /></a></p>
<p>If you’re just starting off, you can rely on LinkedIn’s impressive hashtag prowess. However, for more advanced hashtag research, we recommend consulting LinkedIn marketing pros. They’ll create a customized hashtag strategy for each post, resulting in optimal reach.</p>
<p>Go for <strong><u>3–5 hashtags</u></strong> in each post. Too little and you won’t reach your target audience; too much and the LinkedIn algorithm will work to your detriment.</p>
<p>Now, when it comes to standing out from the massive competition on LinkedIn, you <em><u>need</u></em> to think outside the box. In addition to having a strong hashtag strategy in place, we also suggest letting your creative juices flow.</p>
<p>Sounds vague?</p>
<p>Here’s what we’re talking about. Head over to Puma’s LinkedIn company page and you’ll notice that they’ve sprinkled a specific hashtag across every other post: #PumaFam.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-7.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2447" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-7.png" alt="how to customize hashtags on LinkedIn posts " width="541" height="442" /></a></p>
<p>Here’s another glimpse of the catchy hashtag in action:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-8.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2448" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-8.png" alt="how to customize hashtags on LinkedIn posts " width="540" height="462" /></a></p>
<p>Creating a whip-smart, memorable, and standout hashtag for your company is a great way to set yourself apart from the hundreds of companies in your industry and city/state.</p>
<p>Whether you create a hashtag for your audience, your products/services, or your brand, you’ll manage to get an edge in your competitive industry.</p>
<p>Over time, <strong><u>the hashtag will catch on</u></strong>.</p>
<p>As your followers use it, it’ll build momentum and <a href="https://medium.com/@steve_fabrik/forget-boring-branding-the-elements-of-brand-recall-strategy-e08c2105269b" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">increase brand recall</a>.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Want to grow your LinkedIn business page and get more followers? Let’s make it happen.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021483"></a>3. Include High-Quality Images in Your Posts</h3>
<p>A whopping <strong><u>87.5% of marketers</u></strong> state that they use visual elements in online content.</p>
<p>Over the years, the human attention span has dropped to a measly <em><a href="https://time.com/3858309/attention-spans-goldfish/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">eight seconds</a></em>. In comparison, a goldfish has an attention span of <em>nine seconds</em>—one second more than ours!</p>
<p>Here’s where we’re going with this: we don’t like paying attention to things that don’t excite us.</p>
<p>Five pages of continuous text? Boring.</p>
<p>A dull concept illustration? Next.</p>
<p>A set of statistics with no visual elements? Pass.</p>
<p>What <em>does</em> excite us, however, is <strong><a href="https://neilpatel.com/blog/visual-content-you-need-to-use-in-your-marketing-campaign/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">engaging visual content</a></strong>.</p>
<p>Content with high-quality images and videos does much better than content that entirely lacks visual elements. In essence, if your LinkedIn posts feature chunky bites of text without images or videos, you can wave your followers goodbye.</p>
<p>How can you undo the damage? Befriend gripping visuals and don’t let that friendship turn sour.</p>
<p>Let’s take a quick look at brands who walk the visual talk on LinkedIn.</p>
<p>iRobot’s LinkedIn posts feature stunning images that not only instantly catch your eye, but also compel you to engage with the content. The content itself features the perfect mix of high-quality images—enough to make you want to stay put till the very end.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-9.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2449" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-9.png" alt="LinkedIn posts with stunning images" width="541" height="516" /></a></p>
<p>A closer look and you’ll notice that they’ve also used a hashtag that fits perfectly. While we have to deduct a few points for the low hashtag usage (remember: use 3–5 as a general rule of thumb), the engaging image <em>more than makes up for it</em>.</p>
<p>While using the right images in each post is important, we also recommend ensuring that your company page is replete with pictures that pack a powerful punch.</p>
<p>Here’s what we mean by this. Each company page features a section entitled “company photos.” Some businesses make the mistake of uploading little to no images in this section. So when a LinkedIn user clicks on your profile and browses through the “company information” section, all they’ll see is a bunch of text. If there are no visual elements supplementing the text, you can imagine what’ll happen next: the user will “bounce”.</p>
<p><strong><u>What do you do to set things right? </u></strong></p>
<p>Here’s what McDonalds did:<a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-10.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2450 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-10.png" alt="LinkedIn posts with stunning images" width="540" height="249" /></a></p>
<p>And Apple:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-11.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2451" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-11.png" alt="LinkedIn posts with stunning images" width="542" height="249" /></a></p>
<p>And Dell:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-12.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2452" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-12.png" alt="LinkedIn posts with stunning images" width="540" height="249" /></a></p>
<p>Just to reiterate, make sure you upload a set of relevant, engaging, and high-quality images that satiate your audience’s visual thirst.</p>
<p>This is a great way to increase engagement on your LinkedIn company page and, of course, get more followers.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021484"></a>4. Don’t Sideline the Importance of Engaging Videos</h3>
<p>As another form of visual content, <strong><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2020/06/01/three-reasons-video-marketing-is-important-on-social-media-in-2020/?sh=58a80a456e55" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">videos are imperative</a></strong>. Maybe more so than images since they stimulate an additional sense: hearing. LinkedIn pages that feature high-quality videos do much better than pages that don’t. But this is where things get a little tricky—especially for startups and small businesses that don’t have a lot of (<em>or any</em>) video content ready to go.</p>
<p>If you’re unprepared, consider getting help from a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/video-design-services/">professional video design team</a>.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4Fk48tDAVCQ" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Once you’re equipped with a set of high-quality videos, start featuring them on your LinkedIn company page. Each profile incudes a “recently posted videos” section that shows up right after the “about” section.</p>
<p>Here’s a glimpse:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-13.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2453" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-13.png" alt="LinkedIn posts with engaging videos" width="541" height="233" /></a></p>
<p>By default, this section displays the most recently posted video, and features a “+ more videos” tab for LinkedIn users who wish to engage with additional video content.</p>
<p>Once you click on this tab, the rest of the videos uploaded on your page show up.</p>
<p>This is what Walmart’s video panel looks like:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-14.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2454" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-14.png" alt="LinkedIn posts with engaging videos" width="877" height="533" /></a></p>
<p>Quite a visual treat, right?</p>
<p>If you take a closer look, you’ll notice that the engagement on each video is <em>pretty impressive</em>. Lots of views, and a plethora of “like,” “celebrate,” “love,” and “support” reactions.</p>
<p><strong><u>That’s the power of video content, in a nutshell</u></strong>.</p>
<p>A power-packed mix of explainer videos, testimonial videos, company culture videos, product demonstration videos, and behind-the-scenes videos will breathe life into your LinkedIn profile. The outcome? A steady increase in LinkedIn company page followers.</p>
<p>Over time, this LinkedIn marketing tip will help you grow your company page and actively engage your target audience.</p>
<p>If you’ve already uploaded high-quality videos on YouTube (or any other video sharing platform), and engaged an impressive audience there, you don’t have to re-upload them on LinkedIn. Simply embed the video so you can steadily increase views, likes, and comments on YouTube. This is a great way to grow your YouTube page and increase ad revenue via AdSense.</p>
<p>Here’s an example from LARQ’s LinkedIn company page:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-15.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2455" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-15.png" alt="LinkedIn posts with engaging videos" width="541" height="533" /></a></p>
<p>As stated earlier, make sure you use 2–5 hashtags in <em>every</em> post, whether it links to a blog, video, or infographic. We’re continually doubling down on this because it’s absolutely imperative. Hashtags are just as important on LinkedIn as they are on Twitter, so take special care to incorporate them into every post.</p>
<p>By combining the power of strong visuals (images and videos) and the right hashtags, you’ll manage to reach, engage, and convert a wide audience.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021485"></a>5. Share Value-Added, Insightful, and Compelling Content</h3>
<p>Content has always been at the forefront of any social media or networking platform. If you want your company page to strike a chord with your audience, you <em>have</em> to share <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-the-ultimate-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2020/">engaging content</a> that achieves its purpose.</p>
<p>Remember, people won’t hit the “follow” button if your posts doesn’t resonate with them. Your page should <strong><u>inform, inspire, and excite your audience</u></strong>.</p>
<p>Start by creating a customized content marketing plan for your LinkedIn page. Incorporate different types of content into the mix—blogs, articles, guest posts, press releases, infographics, and instructographics.</p>
<p>Once you have a set of value-added and optimized content ready to go, write an equally compelling LinkedIn post to supplement your content.</p>
<p>Patricia Hartmann, a writer in Ojai, California, creates the perfect segue into one of her blogs:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-16.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2456" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-16.png" alt="Sharing Value-Added, Insightful, Compelling Content on LinkedIn to gain followers" width="545" height="578" /></a></p>
<p>Keeping the current context in mind, she focuses on inspiring her audience by helping them break away from the ongoing uncertainty, chaos, and stress triggered by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p><strong>Recommended Read: </strong><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/8-ways-to-adjust-your-seo-strategy-amid-the-ongoing-covid-19-pandemic/">8 Ways to Adjust Your SEO Strategy Amid the Ongoing COVID-19 Pandemic</a></p>
<p>Starbucks used a similar approach on New Year’s Eve:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-17.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2457" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-17.png" alt="Sharing Value-Added, Insightful, Compelling Content on LinkedIn to gain followers" width="541" height="497" /></a></p>
<p>Ultimately, your content should <em><u>make an impact</u></em>. Avoid cookie-cutter content strategy. The more creative you can get, the better. And, of course, keep optimization in mind at all times.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021486"></a>6. Make the Most of Polls</h3>
<p>Over the past few years, polls have taken LinkedIn by storm, and it’s easy to see why. They’re quick. They’re engaging. They’re exciting. The best part? You can leverage polls for <em><u>a wide range of purposes</u></em>.</p>
<p>Whether you’re trying to get feedback on a newly-launched product or curious about where your audience stands with respect to something like remote working, creating a quick poll is a great way to double down on engagement.</p>
<p>Netflix’s smart poll earned a whopping 13,633 votes because of the compelling question and equally impressive options.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-18.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2458" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-18.png" alt="Using polls to increase followers on LinkedIn" width="541" height="399" /></a></p>
<p>Let’s be real; if we could, we’d immediately hit one of those four options depending on our Netflix viewing history.</p>
<p>There’s something about polls that <em>compels people to participate</em>, which is exactly why they’re so popular on LinkedIn.</p>
<p>We strongly recommend posting <strong><u>1–2 polls every other week</u></strong>.</p>
<p>However, make sure you’re not posting polls <em>just for the sake of it</em>. If you don’t have a great idea in mind, it’s better to skip your weekly poll than to post one that’s too dull to engage people.</p>
<p>Here’s another great example to help you get inspired:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-19.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2459" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-19.png" alt="Using polls to increase followers on LinkedIn" width="537" height="444" /></a></p>
<p>What makes this specific poll even better is the unique way it brilliantly prompts further engagement in the comments. This is how you check off <em><u>all the boxes</u></em>! Not only did this post receive a plethora of votes, but it also earned a decent amount of comments.</p>
<p>Follow suit and you’ll be taken aback by how rapidly you manage to increase your LinkedIn followers.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021487"></a>7. Highlight Your Company’s Accomplishments</h3>
<p>Whether you run a small business or recently launched a startup, we’re sure you’ve accomplished certain milestones along the way—both big and small. Many businesses manage to check off 1–2 accomplishments within the first few month of inception!</p>
<p>If you have something to show off, <em><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2020/06/02/14-tips-for-showing-off-awards-and-accolades-without-bragging/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">show it off</a></em>.</p>
<p>Be proud of your company’s performance and growth, and don’t shy away from announcing it on LinkedIn. You’ll manage to present your business in a flattering light, and engage more people.</p>
<p>Tesla frequently posts its accomplishments, and this strategy always works in their favor.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-20.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2460" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-20.png" alt="tesla" width="541" height="291" /></a></p>
<p>18,385 reactions and 402 comments. Now, <em>that’s</em> engagement. Showcase your company’s achievements accordingly and you’ll manage to climb the rungs of LinkedIn. You don’t have to highlight awards. You can also announce the number of projects you closed, especially if your company exceeded its goals. If a certain product did exceptionally well, highlight that. If you earned a noteworthy mention by an industry giant, highlight that. If your customer satisfaction (CSAT) score improved by leaps and bounds, highlight that.</p>
<p>In essence, drawing attention to your company’s successes will help you build a great reputation and get more followers on LinkedIn.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021488"></a>8. Create Special Posts for Major Events, Holidays, and Trends</h3>
<p>Struggling to increase engagement on your LinkedIn company page? Take a quick look at your recent posts. Did you create a custom post for New Year’s? Christmas? Black Friday? Cyber Monday? If you didn’t, make sure you double down on major events, holidays, and trends in 2021. Covering important occasions will help you connect with your audience and watch your follower count go up.</p>
<p>Here are some <em><u>great</u></em> examples to help you get inspired:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-21.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2461" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-21.png" alt="1" width="546" height="533" /></a> <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog3.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2462" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog3.png" alt="2" width="541" height="593" /></a></p>
<p>Plan ahead to ensure you don’t miss out on an important event or holiday. Since you can’t plan trends in advance, make sure you have a team ready to create content for trends that develop within a matter of hours. This will help you stay on top of things!</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021489"></a>9. Encourage Your Employees to Join the Action</h3>
<p>When it comes to growing your business via LinkedIn, your company page isn’t the only page that should be spruced up and optimized at all times.</p>
<p>We touched upon Puma’s custom hashtag (#PUMAFam) earlier. If you browse through the hashtag on LinkedIn, you’ll come across <em>a plethora of posts</em>, and not all of them come from their company page!</p>
<p>In fact, their managers and employees have also joined the action to keep the momentum going.</p>
<p>Here’s a glimpse:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-22.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2463" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-22.png" alt="puma" width="539" height="853" /></a></p>
<p><em><u>This</u></em> is team effort at a glance. And when it comes to succeeding on LinkedIn, you can’t run a tight ship on your own. You <em><u>have</u></em> to recruit the rest of your team to help grow your company page and crystallize your online presence on the mega platform.</p>
<p>Encourage your team to share frequent posts that reflect your company in a positive light. They can share behind-the-scenes images, repost your company’s posts, and help custom hashtags do even better. You can also request them to engage with your posts to improve their reach. Collectively, these strategies will go a long way in helping your company page grow.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021490"></a>10. Actively Participate in LinkedIn Groups</h3>
<p>Looking to connect with likeminded individuals in your industry? And we don’t mean your competitors, we mean thought leaders and industry insiders who are passionate about the same products/services/ideas/strategies. If you’re nodding your head in the affirmative, make sure you join relevant LinkedIn groups.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-23.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2464" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-23.png" alt="groups" width="771" height="485" /></a></p>
<p>As you engage in niche-specific conversations, you’ll manage to reflect your company’s expertise and <a href="https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/310427" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">create awareness for your brand</a>.</p>
<p>You can also start your own group and share your content (blogs, articles, etc.). It’s a little more work, but <em><u>it’s worth it</u></em>. As the group gains momentum, you’ll marvel at how much traffic it generates for your company page.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021491"></a>11. Use LinkedIn Sponsored Ads</h3>
<p>If you’re still frowning upon your LinkedIn follower count, it’s time to let the professionals take care of things for you. Over the years, LinkedIn sponsored ads have become a go-to for thousands of companies across the platform. You can choose from a wide range of ads depending on the specific goal you want to reach. Whether you want to prompt more visits to your page, increase reach, or boost conversions, you can select the right ads accordingly.</p>
<p>Take your time to acclimatize to the purpose of each ad. Once you have a good grasp on the ins and outs of LinkedIn advertising, you’ll manage to make an informed decision that pays off in the long run!</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021492"></a>12. Promote Your LinkedIn Page on Social Media and Your Website</h3>
<p>While you can take several measures to promote your LinkedIn profile on the platform itself, you also need to branch out into other platforms.</p>
<p>Sharing your LinkedIn profile on social media is a great way to target a different audience that wouldn’t normally discover your company page on LinkedIn. In addition, we recommend linking your LinkedIn page on the “home” and “contact” pages of your website.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc61021493"></a>Wrapping Up!</h2>
<p>In this blog, we delved deep into the top LinkedIn marketing tips that can help you increase followers in 2021. Some are straightforward, some require a little assistance, and some can only be implemented by professionals (e.g., LinkedIn advertising).</p>
<p>Depending on where you stand, get a good grasp on your requirements and head in the right direction accordingly.</p>
<p>When it comes to LinkedIn marketing, <strong><u>consistency is the name of the game</u></strong>. Post high-quality, engaging, and optimized content <em>on a regular basis</em> and you’ll manage to steadily increase your LinkedIn followers.</p>
<p>If you’re ready to get started, we can help. Give us a call at <a href="tel:8554444777">855-444-4777</a> to kick-start your <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/linkedin-marketing/">LinkedIn marketing strategy</a>!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-followers-on-linkedin/">How to Get More Followers on LinkedIn</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-followers-on-linkedin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blog vs. Article: What Is the Difference?</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/blog-vs-article-what-is-the-difference/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/blog-vs-article-what-is-the-difference/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivia Glyn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 05:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Our SEO experts get asked this a lot! When we begin working with businesses that really want to get on top of SERPs, part of our game plan is content marketing. Blogs and articles make up a major part of it. So we wanted to really break this down. It’s safe to say that content [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/blog-vs-article-what-is-the-difference/">Blog vs. Article: What Is the Difference?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our SEO experts get asked this <em>a lot!</em> When we begin working with businesses that really want to get on top of SERPs, part of our game plan is <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/content-marketing/"><u>content marketing</u></a>. Blogs and articles make up a major part of it. <span id="more-2384"></span></p>
<p>So we wanted to really break this down. </p>
<p>It’s safe to say that <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/content-marketing/"><u>content marketing</u></a> is still being touted as the crème de la crème of digital marketing. But where should you start: blogs or articles? What’s the difference between writing a blog and writing an article? And does it even matter?</p>
<p>We have to admit; in the last few years or so, the lines differentiating blog posts and articles have blurred. But these lines do exist.</p>
<p>One of the best ways to getting started is understanding the difference between article and blog writing. We’ll walk you through each key difference so you can customize your content marketing strategy accordingly.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Want to get more traffic on your blogs and articles? Fill out the form here and let’s get started:</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2>Contents</h2>
<ul class="toc_list">
<li><a href="#_Toc59543709"><u>What is the Difference Between Blogs and Articles?</u></a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc59543710"><u>Where Are They Posted?</u></a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc59543713"><u>What Is the Length?</u></a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc59543716"><u>What Is the Content Style?</u></a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc59543719"><u>What Is the SEO Strategy</u></a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc59543722"><u>What Is the Scope?</u></a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc59543725"><u>Wrapping Up!</u></a></li>
</ul>
<h2><strong><b>What is the Difference Between Blogs and Articles?</b></strong><strong><b> </b></strong></h2>

<table id="tablepress-1" class="tablepress tablepress-id-1">
<thead>
<tr class="row-1 odd">
	<th class="column-1">HIGH-CONVERTING KEYWORDS</th><th class="column-2">	STRONGER HIGH-CONVERTING KEYWORDS</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody class="row-hover">
<tr class="row-2 even">
	<td class="column-1">For attorneys: “<u>Build</u> a strong case”</td><td class="column-2">For attorneys: “Build a strong case <u>in Los Angeles</u>”</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-3 odd">
	<td class="column-1">For web developers: “<u>Create </u>an interactive website”</td><td class="column-2">For web developers: “Create an interactive website <u>in less than $100</u>”</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-4 even">
	<td class="column-1">For realtors: “<u>Buy </u>your dream home”</td><td class="column-2">For realtors: “Buy your dream home <u>in SoHo</u>”</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-5 odd">
	<td class="column-1">For door manufacturers: “<u>Replace </u>your front doors”</td><td class="column-2">For door manufacturers: “Replace your front doors <u>and get a transom for free</u>” </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<!-- #tablepress-1 from cache -->
<h2><strong><b>Where Are They Posted?</b></strong></h2>
<p>The biggest difference in the blog post vs. article or ‘what makes a blog different from an article’ debate is <em><i>where they’re posted</i></em>.</p>
<h3><strong><b>Blogs</b></strong></h3>
<p>Blogs are posted on a company’s own blog page as opposed to a third-party platform. In essence, if your site features written content that’s supplemented by images and/or videos, it’s classified as a blog, not an article.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/HEH.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2389" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/HEH.png" alt="HEH blogs published on their website" width="471" height="733" /></a></p>
<p>So what is the purpose of a blog? They’re posted on your site and give readers a glimpse into expert industry insight and recommendations. The idea is to create authority, increase lead generation and overall SEO value.</p>
<p>When you write blogs, you typically include key internal and external links that sort of connect your blog to other relevant pages and services that your readers might be interested in.</p>
<p>That way, you’re keeping them <em><i>engaged </i></em>longer to elicit a desired response—a purchase of a product/service, a call, etc. You’re essentially trying to convert them from a <strong><u><b>reader</b></u></strong> to a <strong><u><b>customer</b></u></strong>.</p>
<p><strong><b>Blogs are super important from a </b></strong><strong><em><b><i>conversation point of view</i></b></em></strong><strong><b>. </b></strong></p>
<h3><strong><a name="_Toc59543712"></a>Articles</strong></h3>
<p>Unlike blogs, articles can be posted anywhere <em><u><i>but</i></u></em> on your own site. As a rule of thumb, we recommend choosing third-party websites that (a) are in the same niche, (b) are non-competitors, and (c) have a high <a href="https://moz.com/learn/seo/domain-authority" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>domain authority (DA)</u></a>.</p>
<p>But wait, this doesn’t add up. Why would anyone contribute free content to another website, even if it isn’t a direct competitor?</p>
<p>Well, articles are posted with the intent of targeting high-quality, <em><u><i>varied</i></u></em> traffic.</p>
<p>Let’s say your blog page isn’t doing too well: it doesn’t have a high DA, which is resulting in less-than-impressive reach. In this case, posting articles is a great way to ride on another site’s coattails, so to speak. If they have a stellar DA, you’ll manage to engage a wide audience and rank higher on SERPs.</p>
<p>This article generally includes a CTA (call-to-action) that redirects readers to your site. It’s a win-win: you get high-quality traffic while nudging potential customers in your site’s direction for more conversions.</p>
<p><strong><b>Articles are super important from a </b></strong><strong><em><b><i>lead generation point of view</i></b></em></strong><strong><b>. </b></strong></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc59543713"></a><strong><b>What Is the Length?</b></strong></h2>
<p>Now that you have a good grasp on the basics, let’s dive into the intricacies. Over the years, blogs and articles have become very similar when it comes to length. Let’s call this a kind of convergence. Previously, articles were long and detailed (generally longer than 300 words) while blogs were short and to the point. Today, however, this demarcation has become increasingly blurred.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc59543714"></a><strong><b>Blogs</b></strong></h3>
<p>Blogs are divided into two main categories based on length: <strong><u><b>short-form blogs</b></u></strong> and <strong><u><b>long-form blogs</b></u></strong>. In other words, you have full rein here; there are no rules.</p>
<p>Short-form blogs typically range from 400–800 words whereas long-form blogs are longer than 2000 words.</p>
<p>Now, choosing the right length comes down to your target audience and brand identity. We strongly recommend working with a content marketing team to dive deeper into your audience’s preferences. Are they interested in short, engaging, and witty blogs? Do they prefer long, insightful, and industry-rich blogs? Based on these insights, create a customized strategy.</p>
<p>Track each blog’s performance to gauge which blog length performs better than the others. Finalize your strategy and don’t forget to update it on a monthly or bimonthly basis as you collect fresh insights.</p>
<p><strong><b>Recommended Read: </b></strong><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-a-blog-that-ranks/"><u>How to Write a Blog That Ranks</u></a></p>
<h2><strong><b>Articles</b></strong></h2>
<p>Today, articles can be as short as 400 words or as long as 3000 words. Like blogs, there are no strict requirements you need to adhere to when it comes to length. Consult the website you’re partnering with beforehand. In some cases, certain websites only accept articles of a specific length.</p>
<p>To avoid facing rejection once your articles have been written and edited, get a strong grasp on the guidelines. If anything looks off, feel free to submit your articles to another website.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Double down on informative and engaging blogs and articles!<br />Our article and blog writers can help!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc59543716"></a><strong><b>What Is the Content Style?</b></strong></h2>
<p>As a rule of thumb, make sure your blogs and articles have impeccable grammar, syntax, punctuation, and spelling. In addition, no matter what style you pick, your content should be unmistakably engaging.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc59543717"></a><strong><b>Blogs</b></strong></h3>
<p>While you have complete leeway to switch things up, blogs are generally more informal and laid back than articles. Stick to a casual and conversational writing style. This is a great way to establish a connection with your audience.</p>
<p>Remember, you’re not just writing blogs to increase traffic and boost conversions; you’re <em><i>also</i></em> focused on <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbescoachescouncil/2019/04/25/13-effective-methods-to-help-you-build-a-strong-brand-identity/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>improving your brand identity</u></a>. Since blogs are posted on your site, they’re an extension of your business. In essence, they reflect your brand identity.</p>
<p>If you opt for a formal and sophisticated style, chances are, your content will fail to resonate with your audience. Go for a casual tone to engage and retain your audience in the long run. Of course, you can still incorporate facts and figures into your blogs, so long as you don’t bore your audience.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Buzzfeed-article.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2390" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Buzzfeed-article.png" alt="Buzzfeed article" width="624" height="321" /></a></p>
<p>Strike the perfect balance between “informing” and “engaging” your audience. Over time, this balance will help you write winning blogs that keep your audience coming back for more!</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc59543718"></a><strong><b>Articles</b></strong></h3>
<p>Since articles aren’t directly posted on your site, they can take on a more professional and formal tone. However, too much of anything can do more harm than good. Retain the balance we discussed earlier to ensure new visitors don’t click off the article halfway through.</p>
<p>As compared to blogs, articles also make use of facts and figures more frequently. Cite credible research to increase the value of your article. If a web user has never engaged with your business, they’ll feel more compelled to give your site a visit if your article is replete with unique industry insights and research.</p>
<p>Take a look at <a href="https://www.searchenginewatch.com/2020/07/24/what-google-says-about-nofollow-sponsored-and-ugc-links-in-2020-does-it-affect-your-seo-rankings/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>this article</u></a> published on Search Engine Watch by Joseph Dyson, one of our Lead Generation experts. The tone is formal and informative, yet engaging.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nofollow.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2391" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/nofollow.png" alt="nofollow, sposored and ugc links - post by one of Saerch Berg's lead generation expert Joseph Dyson" width="624" height="263" /></a></p>
<p>And here’s how the article ends; it’s super simple and non-promotional.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/simple-and-non-promotional.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2392" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/simple-and-non-promotional.png" alt="simple and non-promotional - Joseph's Author bio" width="624" height="108" /></a></p>
<p>Having said that, you can always change your tune if you’d like. While blogs and articles have unique content styles, there’s still lots of room for improvisation. If you want your articles to be more informal and laid back, feel free to do just that!</p>
<p><strong><u><b>However, retain an air of professionalism amid the informality. </b></u></strong></p>
<p>Remember, your articles will be a “first impression” of sorts for many people. With blogs, you’re engaging an audience that’s already familiar with your business. With articles, you’re targeting <em><i>an entirely new audience</i></em>. In essence, your articles should exude an air of credibility. This is a great way to ensure new web users take you seriously.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc59543719"></a><strong><b>What Is the SEO Strategy? </b></strong></h2>
<p>We also want to talk about the difference between blogs and articles in terms of SEO. No matter what content you’re producing, you should have a razor-sharp focus on optimization. If you fail to double down on on-page SEO, your content will rank poorly on SERPs, resulting in not-so-great traffic generation and weak conversions.</p>
<p>Whether you’re writing blogs or articles, go all out on optimization. Use high-ranking keywords, Meta descriptions, title tags, headings, alt text, and URLs.</p>
<p>In addition, incorporate high-quality internal and external links into your content. This will help you redirect readers to your own content and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-advanced-link-building-tips-and-tricks-to-boost-your-seo/"><u>generate more backlinks</u></a>. As you boost your link building potential, you’ll also manage to increase your DA. Needless to say, sites with a high DA (Forbes, Entrepreneur, Medium, Inc., etc.) consistently appear among the top search results.</p>
<p>The outcome? A massive inflow of traffic. As you follow suit, you’ll increase your audience and grow your business in the long run.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc59543720"></a><strong><b>Blogs</b></strong></h3>
<p>While both blogs and articles should be optimized similarly, use more internal links in your blogs. You can’t always use this strategy when working on articles, especially if the third-party platform has a specific set of restrictions.</p>
<p>In addition, you may not be able to use certain on-page SEO strategies for articles. If you face these restrictions, make sure you actively incorporate these sidelined optimization strategies into your own blogs.</p>
<p>We also recommend using technical SEO strategies like increasing the speed of your blog page.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc59543721"></a><strong><b>Articles</b></strong></h3>
<p>When optimizing articles, use local keywords to target the right audience. While this is also a great strategy for blogs, it’s all the more important for articles as you have little control over who engages with your content.</p>
<p>Local keywords will help you target web users who are close to your business and can actually buy your products/services. The more specific you can get with your SEO efforts, the better.</p>
<h2><strong><b>What Is the Scope?</b></strong></h2>
<p>While you may feel compelled to cover multiple aspects of different topics in depth, that may not be possible, especially if you’re working on a shorter blog/article. Sidelining the scope can work to your detriment in this case.</p>
<h3><strong><b>Blogs</b></strong></h3>
<p>Focus is important. Don’t digress. For instance, if you’re writing a blog on the most popular wrought iron doors of the year, focus on a handful of properties like aesthetic appeal, functionality, maintenance, and durability. Sticking to the plan will help you cover important details as opposed to superficially touching upon a plethora of bases.</p>
<p>In general, blogs are <em><u><i>more specific</i></u></em>—even if you’re opting for a long-form blog. You want to demonstrate industry insight.</p>
<h3><strong><b>Articles</b></strong></h3>
<p>As stated earlier, posting an article is akin to making a first impression on web users. You’re targeting new people who know next to nothing about your business. As a rule of thumb, you want to give them <em><i>an overview</i></em> of your industry insight.</p>
<p>While you can use the same strategy for blogs, we recommend adopting a different approach this time around. Demonstrate variegated insight by giving your audience an overarching view of your industry insight and expertise.</p>
<p>A great way to go about this is to quickly gloss over all your products/services in the CTA. Remember, your blog readers already know about your products/services; they frequently read your blogs. Web users who engage with your articles, however, don’t know these particularities.</p>
<p>If you’re a criminal defense lawyer, include your practice areas in the CTAs for your articles. This will give new readers a quick overview of what your business is all about. In short, don’t hesitate to cover more bases!</p>
<h1><a name="_Toc59543725"></a><strong><b>Wrapping Up!</b></strong></h1>
<p>There’s no denying that content marketing is a great way to actively engage your target audience, boost conversions, retain customers, and dominate the digital realm. Businesses that understand the difference between blogs and articles have a better shot at appearing on the first SERP (search engine result page) and attracting a ton of high-converting traffic.</p>
<p>If you’re new to content marketing, we recommend <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-the-ultimate-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2020/">creating a content marketing strategy</a> that comprises both <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog-writing-services/"><u>blogs</u></a> and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/article-writing/"><u>articles</u></a>.</p>
<p>Still have questions? We’ve love to hear what you have to say! If you’re ready to kickstart your article writing or blogging campaign, call <a href="tel:855-444-4777"><strong><u><b>855-444-4777</b></u></strong></a> now or fill out the form below and let’s talk!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/blog-vs-article-what-is-the-difference/">Blog vs. Article: What Is the Difference?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/blog-vs-article-what-is-the-difference/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Social Media and SEO: How to Use Social Media to Improve SEO Rankings</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-and-seo-how-to-use-social-media-to-improve-seo-rankings/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-and-seo-how-to-use-social-media-to-improve-seo-rankings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Harper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 08:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contents How Does Social Media Affect SEO Rankings? 5 Tips To Use Social Media To Boost SEO Move Away From Creating and Sharing Mediocre Content Master the Art of Social Media Optimization Make Your Content Shareable Connect With Your Audience Leverage Social Media to Craft a Pristine Brand Identity What Are The Best Social Media [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-and-seo-how-to-use-social-media-to-improve-seo-rankings/">Social Media and SEO: How to Use Social Media to Improve SEO Rankings</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Contents</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203060">How Does Social Media Affect SEO Rankings?</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203061">5 Tips To Use Social Media To Boost SEO</a>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203062"> Move Away From Creating and Sharing Mediocre Content</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203063"> Master the Art of Social Media Optimization</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203064"> Make Your Content Shareable</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203065"> <em>Connect</em> With Your Audience</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203066"> Leverage Social Media to Craft a Pristine Brand Identity</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203067">What Are The Best Social Media Sites For SEO?</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203068">Wrapping Up!</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Is on-page SEO the only way to boost Google rankings?</p>
<p>Is there a link between social media marketing and SEO?</p>
<p>In this blog, we want to talk about how social media optimization can help you become more visible on the web.</p>
<div class="blog-cta" style="padding: 0;background: none;height: auto;min-height: inherit;">
<div class="inner">
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/social-media-management/">View Our Social Media Management Services</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc57203060"></a>How Does Social Media Affect SEO Rankings?</h2>
<p>Over <strong><u>4.57 billion people</u></strong> use social media around the world.</p>
<p><strong>Now, let’s get to the question that’s on everyone’s mind: Is social media marketing one of Google’s ranking factors?</strong></p>
<p>So, for most of this blog, we’re going to talk about how you can leverage your presence on social sites to boost your online presence. But it’s important to note that social media marketing <em>isn’t a direct element of SEO; </em>in fact, it <em>supports</em> elements that impact SEO.</p>
<p>For example: sharing engaging posts on Facebook, Twitter, etc., can make your content shareable, which increases your content’s visibility, which <em>in turn boosts Google rankings.</em></p>
<p>So if a blog was shared over 10,000 times and generated over 1 million likes and 30,000 comments, it may bag the first spot on Google for several of its keywords.</p>
<p>There’s absolutely no denying that social media and SEO have a meaningful and powerful link. Now let’s jump right into how you can leverage that!</p>
<div class="blog-cta style2">
<div class="inner">
<h3>Consult Our Experts For A Social Media SEO Plan.</h3>
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/contact-us/">Get a Free Proposal!</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc57203061"></a>5 Tips To Use Social Media To Boost SEO</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc57203062"></a>1. Move Away From Creating and Sharing Mediocre Content</h3>
<p>Curious about how many U.S. businesses have a social media marketing strategy in place?</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/203513/usage-trands-of-social-media-platforms-in-marketing/#:~:text=In%202017%20it%20was%20calculated,to%2091%20percent%20in%202019.&amp;text=Everyone%20knows%20that%20social%20media,to%20a%20powerful%20marketing%20tool." target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">90%</a></strong><strong>.</strong> And it’s easy to see why.</p>
<p>While taking things into your own hands may sound compelling, it’s very likely that you’ll fall short of the high standard set by the leading brands today.</p>
<p>Most top-tier businesses have a winning social media SEO strategy that helps them speedily climb ranks.</p>
<p>Take a quick look at Longines’ simple yet unmistakably engaging Facebook post:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe loading="lazy" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FLongines%2Fposts%2F10158707841863399&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=773&amp;appId" width="552" height="773" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>From using their signature hashtag to reach the intended audience to painting a vivid picture of the client’s admiration for Longines watches, this post makes <u>a lasting impression</u> on the audience.</p>
<p>And the more it resonates with people, the greater the likes, shares, page views, and sales.</p>
<p>These factors collectively play a fundamental role in increasing your search visibility and improving your rankings.</p>
<p>Nordstrom’s social media posts expertly follow the same recipe of creativity, uniqueness, and storytelling at its best:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe loading="lazy" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FNordstrom%2Fposts%2F10159194091224837&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=754&amp;appId" width="552" height="754" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>When it comes to using social media for SEO success, you have to stand out from the crowd by creating and sharing content that’s <em>a cut above the rest</em>.</p>
<p>An experienced social media marketing team will help you post gripping, moving, and impactful content that compels casual social media users to get immersed in your brand’s story and visit your website.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc57203063"></a>2. Master the Art of Social Media Optimization</h3>
<p>You’ve heard about content optimization.</p>
<p>You’re also familiar with webpage optimization.</p>
<p><em>But what on earth is social media optimization?</em></p>
<p>This is where social media and SEO cross paths. In essence, social media optimization is the process of “optimizing” your social media activity to build a wide audience and become more visible on SERPs.</p>
<p>How do you go about this?</p>
<p>Here’s a roundup of the top strategies:</p>
<ul>
<li>Use high-ranking hashtags for your industry and location</li>
<li>Set up your profile on the leading social media platforms (Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, YouTube, and Pinterest)</li>
<li>Integrate your social media links in your site architecture</li>
<li>Post high-quality content on a regular or semi-regular basis</li>
<li>Post media-rich content (e.g., blogs with engaging images or concept illustrations, infographics, videos, etc.)</li>
<li>Determine the optimal posting times for your business based on your demographic</li>
<li>Optimize your social media profile by posting a professional cover photo and profile photo, writing an engaging bio, and using an uncomplicated username</li>
<li>Monitor your campaign and make changes accordingly</li>
</ul>
<p>As you optimize your pages, you’ll engage more social media users and increase your chances of <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-marketers-guide-to-the-powerful-benefits-of-consistent-link-building/">establishing link building partners</a>.</p>
<p><u>This is one of the most impressive boons of social media optimization</u>!</p>
<p>As more non-competitor businesses come across your profile and engage with your content, they’ll become familiar with your presence in the industry.</p>
<p><em>The outcome?</em></p>
<p>Better chances of earning a lucrative backlink from high-DA businesses.</p>
<p>And it should come as no surprise that high-quality backlinks are <strong><u>power-packed juice shots</u></strong> for fatigued rankings! If you’re stuck at the back end of SERPs, you’ll manage to climb your way to the middle and eventually the top.</p>
<p>But leveraging social media sites for SEO isn’t enough. Make sure you turn to on-page SEO strategies as well.</p>
<p><strong>Recommended Read: </strong><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-likes-on-facebook-in-2020/">How to Get More Likes on Facebook in 2020</a></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc57203064"></a>3. Make Your Content Shareable</h3>
<p>Sure, you’ve created a winning social media campaign. You’ve also written the perfect social media post to get your content out in the open with a bang!</p>
<p>But did you make the post <em>shareable</em>?</p>
<p>While every social media post features a “share” button, it’s very likely that your audience won’t use it unless they’re prompted to. And losing potential shares will ultimately cause your SEO efforts to self-destruct.</p>
<p>Go for damage control ASAP.</p>
<p>Here’s an example:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We now have plenty of Feather Edge Panel in stock for immediate collection or delivery!!!!</p>
<p>Call us now on 01553760000 or email us sales@timberservices.com</p>
<p>Please share!! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/featheredgepanel?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">#featheredgepanel</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/kingslynn?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">#kingslynn</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/timber?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">#timber</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/instock?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">#instock</a> <a href="https://t.co/vvnjXUcfu2" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/vvnjXUcfu2</a></p>
<p>— Timber Services Ltd (@ServicesTimber) <a href="https://twitter.com/ServicesTimber/status/1326128127349829635?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">November 10, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>Requesting your audience to “share” your posts is a great way to prompt action and <strong><u>get the most out of your social media content</u></strong>.</p>
<p>You can also experiment with different CTAs like “visit our website for more,” “feel free to give us a call,” “check out our services/products,” and “sign up for our newsletter,” among others.</p>
<p>Make sure you prioritize creativity; the more <u>unique</u> and <u>compelling</u> your posts, the better the outcome!</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc57203065"></a>4. <em>Connect</em> With Your Audience</h3>
<p>Social media isn’t a lecture hall; it’s a seminar room that involves active discussion.</p>
<p>If you plan on posting content and exiting until it’s time for a new post, you may want to rethink your strategy.</p>
<p>To improve your rankings and get people talking about your products/services, <strong><u>actively converse</u></strong> with your audience and initiate mini conversations between them.</p>
<p>Let’s take a look at how Starbucks puts this strategy into play:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe loading="lazy" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FStarbucks%2Fposts%2F10158957429378057&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=609&amp;appId" width="552" height="609" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>If you scroll down, you’ll notice that they’ve engaged with the large majority of people who have left a comment. And the responses aren’t lackluster and generic; they’re <strong>witty, creative, and a breath of fresh air!</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2346 aligncenter" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/blog2-13.png" alt="comments" width="463" height="201" /></p>
<p>And if you so much as enter “pumpkin cream” on Google, Starbucks shows up as the second most relevant search result.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2345 aligncenter" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/blog2-12.png" alt="how to use social media for SEO" width="713" height="364" /></p>
<p>This, in a nutshell, is a masterclass in how to use social media for SEO. It shows you how social signals help your SEO strategy succeed.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc57203066"></a>5. Leverage Social Media to Craft a Pristine Brand Identity</h3>
<p>Branding is at the core of successful SEO.</p>
<p>If your business has a weak brand identity, it’s very likely that your audience will gradually begin to lose interest and turn to your competitors.</p>
<p>Mediocre branding also reduces brand recall, resulting in dwindling audience engagement and retention.</p>
<p><em>So how do you turn things around?</em></p>
<p>You create an <strong><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/sarabliss/2019/02/13/how-to-build-a-brand-through-social-media/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">immaculate brand identity</a></strong> through social media.</p>
<p>Portray your business as an empathetic, attentive, and accommodating brand that actually cares about its audience.</p>
<p>Posting meaningful content, engaging with customers on a frequent basis, responding to queries with care and concern, and going the extra mile to ensure a seamless user experience are a few of the many ways to make a mark in your industry.</p>
<p>When executed with consistency and quality in mind, these strategies will help you become more visible on the web and <strong><u>rank your way to the top SERPs</u></strong>!</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc57203067"></a>What Are The Best Social Media Sites For SEO?</h2>
<p>Believe it or not, there are several dozen social sites you can choose from, but we want to focus on a few popular (read: powerful) ones in this blog:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2344 aligncenter" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/blog2-11.png" alt="Social Media Sites For SEO" width="1079" height="1079" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Source</strong>: <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/272014/global-social-networks-ranked-by-number-of-users/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Statista</a></p>
<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a></strong>: Most brands really overlook this powerhouse social media site. Twitter is huge. It has a great audience (over 330 million monthly active users) that you can tap into.</li>
<p></br></p>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">YouTube</a></strong><strong>: </strong>If video marketing isn’t part of your SEO strategy, it’s time to rethink that plan. 22% of the social media traffic in the U.S. is on this platform.</li>
<p></br></p>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a></strong>: Definitely the most popular, Facebook allows you to direct your advertising to your target audience and attract major traffic straight to your website. In addition to attracting traffic organically, there are paid options like Facebook sponsored content.</li>
<p></br></p>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Instagram</a></strong>: Over a billion people use Instagram on a monthly basis; it’s more than just posting images; think stories, video sharing, etc.</li>
<p></br></p>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a></strong><strong>: </strong>If you’re operating under the B2B model, you need to be on this professional platform. This is where you connect with potential clients, engage with existing customers, and build your brand. 53% of B2B companies that look up clients here have 50% chances of making a purchase from them.</li>
<p></br></p>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pinterest.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Pinterest</a></strong>: The future is imagery. There are over 50 billion pins on the site, with over 175 million users.</li>
<p></br>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc57203068"></a>Wrapping Up!</h2>
<p>And so, with that, you’ve understood more or less about SEO and its relationship with social media. But there’s so much more to it! And we’d love to talk to you about it!</p>
<p>If you want to get your business’s social media marketing off the ground, let’s talk! Call <strong><a href="tel:855-444-4777">855-444-4777</a></strong> now to speak with a strategist or fill out the form below!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-and-seo-how-to-use-social-media-to-improve-seo-rankings/">Social Media and SEO: How to Use Social Media to Improve SEO Rankings</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-and-seo-how-to-use-social-media-to-improve-seo-rankings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SEO for Startups: How to Get Organic Traffic on Your Website Fast</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/seo-for-startups-how-to-get-organic-traffic-on-your-website-fast/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/seo-for-startups-how-to-get-organic-traffic-on-your-website-fast/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Mears]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 08:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2233</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contents Why More Website Traffic? What Is Organic Traffic? How To Drive Traffic To Your Website: 9 Proven SEO Tips Understand Your Target Audience Make Keyword Research a Priority Invest in Link-Building Activities Create Fresh, Value-Added, and Page-Turning Blogs Speed Up Your Website Make Sure Your Website Runs Seamlessly Across All Devices Build Your Website’s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/seo-for-startups-how-to-get-organic-traffic-on-your-website-fast/">SEO for Startups: How to Get Organic Traffic on Your Website Fast</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Contents</p>
<p><a href="#_Toc56687701">Why More Website Traffic?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc56687702">What Is Organic Traffic?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc56687703">How To Drive Traffic To Your Website: 9 Proven SEO Tips</a></p>
<ol start="3">
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ol start="1">
<li><a href="#_Toc56687704">Understand Your Target Audience</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc56687705">Make Keyword Research a Priority</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc56687706">Invest in Link-Building Activities</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc56687707">Create Fresh, Value-Added, and Page-Turning Blogs</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc56687708">Speed Up Your Website</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc56687709">Make Sure Your Website Runs Seamlessly Across All Devices</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc56687710">Build Your Website’s Domain Authority</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc56687711">Improve Your Website’s Security and Encryption</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc56687712">Supercharge Your Social Signals</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc56687713">Got It! Now How To See How Much Traffic A Website Gets?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc56687714">Final Thoughts on How to Get Traffic to Your Website</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc56687701"></a>Why More Website Traffic?</h2>
<p>There are currently <strong>over 4.6 billion people </strong>online right now. In total, web users across the globe are running an astounding <strong>3.8 million searches per minute</strong>.</p>
<p>It takes a couple of seconds to process those numbers and let the <em>sheer power of the internet</em> wash over you. It’s distinct, powerful, and <strong><u>impossible to ignore</u></strong>.</p>
<p>Website traffic is an important factor in driving your sales and ultimately defining your long term growth online.</p>
<p>Wondering how to get traffic on your website?How to <em>increase </em>existing traffic to your website?<em>And </em>how to grow your website organically?There’s always pay-per-click options if you can afford that. If not, there’s plenty you can do to increase <em>organic</em> traffic at a much lower cost. That’s what we want to focus on here, but first…</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc56687702"></a>What Is Organic Traffic?</h2>
<p>Unlike paid search results, organic search results are free, and dominate Google search engine result pages (SERPs).</p>
<p>Here’s a closer look:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2235" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-12-683x1024.png" alt="Organic traffic" width="683" height="1024" /></p>
<p>While paid search results are achieved through pay-per-click advertising, organic search results are, as the name suggests, <u>completely organic</u>.</p>
<p>In essence, it’s impossible for you to “buy” them.</p>
<p>Each time a web user runs a Google search, the Google algorithm gets to work instantly. It <a href="https://moz.com/beginners-guide-to-seo/how-search-engines-operate" rel="nofollow">crawls, indexes, and ranks</a> a wide, wide, <em>wide</em> range of websites based on multiple factors.</p>
<p>If your webpage shows up among the top search results, you’ve done your job and pleased the algorithm gods. And as the competition becomes fiercer every day, failing to impress the algorithm gods isn’t an option.</p>
<div class="pro-tip">
<div class="left">
<h3>If your startup</h3>
<p>doesn’t show up on the first page, you’ll struggle to get your business seen by prospective customers.</p>
</div>
<div class="right"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2258" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/pro-tip-icon.png" alt="" width="146" height="146" /></div>
</div>
<p>Over time, poor reach will translate to poor engagement, conversions, and profit. Trust us, you don’t want to go down that rabbit hole, especially as an up-and-coming business that’s still putting down roots.</p>
<p><em>“How do I get my company to come up on Google search?”</em></p>
<p>You leverage <strong><u>SEO for startups</u></strong>.</p>
<p>If you’re just getting started, here’s how to get traffic to your website fast.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc56687703"></a>How To Drive Traffic To Your Website: 9 Proven SEO Tips</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc56687704"></a>1.Understand Your Target Audience</h3>
<p>While focusing on Google algorithm should be <em>one</em> of your top priorities, it shouldn’t be the only one.</p>
<p>The novelty and rush of launching a startup can compel you to push the “optimization” button with full force. And there’s nothing wrong with that; in fact, it’s <em>exactly what you should be doing</em>. However, many startups tend to shift the focus from their target audience to Google’s algorithm. If you’re guilty of doing this, <em>stop</em> and <em>re-strategize</em> before the damage begins to manifest.</p>
<p>Take the time to <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2019/10/24/targeting-your-audience-how-understanding-conventional-behaviors-can-help-marketers/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">understand your target audience</a> before you start looking into how Google crawls, indexes, and ranks websites.</p>
<p>If you don’t have a foundational understanding of user intent and preferences, your SEO strategy will lack relevance and be all over the place.</p>
<p>Here’s how you can get started:</p>
<ul>
<li>Narrow down your demographic and dive deep into their search intent, interests, and preferences.</li>
<li><strong>Put yourself in their shoes:</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>What would you search for?</p>
<p>What kind of content would you be interested in?</p>
<p>What trends would you like to keep up with?</p>
<p>As you do this, make sure your products/services are <em>at the center</em> of your brainstorming process.</p>
<p>Let’s say you sell supplements for women in Los Angeles; you’re very likely to come up with the following search queries:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2237" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-14.png" alt="suplement1" width="722" height="85" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2238" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog2.png" alt="suplement2" width="718" height="85" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2239" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog3.png" alt="suplement3" width="715" height="83" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2240" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog4.png" alt="suplement4" width="714" height="84" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2241" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog5.png" alt="suplement5" width="719" height="84" /></p>
<p>The better you understand your target audience, the more relevant your list of search queries will be.</p>
<p>Make sure you take relevant national holidays (International Women’s Day, in this case), trends, pop culture references, news, entertainment stories, etc. into account.</p>
<p>The goal is to determine what your audience wants instead of obliviously turning to SEO. Once you have a good grasp on how your potential customers <em>think</em>, you’ll excel at SEO.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc56687705"></a>2.Make Keyword Research a Priority</h3>
<p>Keywords are to SEO what lemons are to lemonade: indispensable.</p>
<p>How do you grow your website organically? You need a stellar keyword research strategy in place.</p>
<p>Luckily, you’re halfway there.</p>
<p>Now that you understand your target audience to a tee, compile a list of relevant keywords, i.e. industry-specific search queries that lead customers to your business.</p>
<p>As a startup, you should focus on the following types of keywords:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Short-tail keywords:</strong> Short keywords comprising three words or less (e.g. “salon in Manhattan”)</li>
<li><strong>Long-tail keywords:</strong> Long keywords comprising 3+ words (e.g. “best tech support in Michigan”)</li>
<li><strong>LSI (Latent Semantic Indexing) keywords:</strong> Keywords that are conceptually related to a topic (e.g. if you’re talking about interior design, LSI keywords may be décor, living room, wall colors, etc.)</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s important to note that LSI keywords can be either short-tail or long-tail.</p>
<p>If your products/services are restricted in a specific area, make sure you use <u>local phrases</u> to target local customers. The last thing you want to do is target businesses in Florida when your IT support firm is based in Washington.</p>
<p>Using local keywords will help Google compartmentalize your business.</p>
<p>The outcome?</p>
<p>You’ll rank higher for relevant local searches and manage to eliminate uninterested buyers in regions where your products/service are unavailable.</p>
<p>If you’re creating your own list of keywords (more on this later), use <strong>Google Trends</strong> to gauge their popularity.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2242" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-15-351x1024.png" alt="Trends" width="351" height="1024" /></p>
<p>In addition to “interest over time,” you’ll also manage to get an overview of “interest by sub region,” “related topics,” and “related queries.”</p>
<p>We strongly recommend branching out into <u>industry-relevant trends</u> to ensure your keyword strategy isn’t run-of-the-mill.</p>
<p>If you’re looking to gain a competitive edge in your industry and increase traffic to your website, don’t take things into your own hands and call it a day. Instead, consult <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-keyword-research/">keyword research specialists</a> to receive a list of customized keywords each month.</p>
<p>With extensive experience and expertise, they’re adept at narrowing down the top keywords for your industry. They use cutting-edge software to identify high-volume keywords that increase your chances of ranking higher on SERPs.</p>
<p>Ultimately, a professional keyword research strategy will play a big role in helping you increase website traffic through Google.</p>
<p><strong>For more on Google’s ranking factors, read: <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-8-google-ranking-factors-for-2020/">8 Crucial Google Ranking Factors You Shouldn’t Ignore in 2020</a></strong></p>
<div class="blog-cta style1">
<div class="inner">
<h3>Ready to get more traffic on your website?</h3>
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/free-proposal/">Start ranking with us in less than 30 DAYS!</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<h3><a name="_Toc56687706"></a>3. Invest in Link-Building Activities</h3>
<p>According to recent data, the “link popularity” of a website makes up for 22.33% of Google’s ranking factor. This of course works if the linking websites are <em>trustworthy</em> and <em>credible</em>.</p>
<p>The more credible incoming links you have, the more “authoritative” your website becomes in the eyes of search engines.</p>
<p>To understand how link-building works, check out this video:</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc53510401"></a></h3>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" style="display: block; margin: 0 auto;" title="What is Back-Linking and Why is it Important for YOUR Business?" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GwiI6V1eyQg" width="770" height="433" frameborder="0" align="center" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc56687707"></a>4. Create Fresh, Value-Added, and Page-Turning Blogs</h3>
<p>Posting a blog to your website increases its chances of ranking in Google search results by 434%!</p>
<p>As a startup, you should have a strong focus on <strong><u>visibility</u></strong>.No matter how great your business model may be, if your web pages don’t show up on the first page of Google, you’re pretty much invisible in the digital world.</p>
<p>Creating a winning content marketing strategy is tantamount to placing a microphone to your mouth. It’ll amplify your brand and create lasting echoes that reach <em>everyone</em>—even the back benchers.</p>
<p>They don’t say <strong>“</strong><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-the-ultimate-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2020/"><strong>content is king</strong></a><strong>”</strong> for nothing!</p>
<p>Start off with a small-scale content marketing strategy. While you may feel tempted to try your hand at different types of content, you’ll end up feeling overwhelmed as a new business.</p>
<p>There’s a lot that you need to focus on right now, including funding, infrastructure management, business insurance, etc. Marketing is <em>part of it</em>. Instead of putting all your eggs in one basket, adopt a smart approach and go slow.</p>
<p><strong><u>Focus on blogs for now</u></strong>.</p>
<p>Create value-added, page-turning blogs that rank high on Google SERPs and get your business out there! As you rank among the top organic search results, you’ll get more traffic to your website and increase conversions.</p>
<p>As a startup, <em>that’s exactly what you want</em>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2243" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-16.png" alt="Startups that post blogs" width="801" height="304" /></p>
<p>Turn to <a href="https://trends.google.com/trends/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"><strong>Google Trends</strong></a> to keep up with the whole gamut of industry relevant trends (holidays, events, news bits, etc.).</p>
<p>Occasionally create content around these trends to ensure relevance and keep your audience engaged in the long run.</p>
<p>This is a great way to avoid churning out the same ol’ blogs that lack value and ingenuity.</p>
<p>So how do you grow organic traffic? Think outside the box and let your creative juices run wild! Unique, imaginative, and original blogs is the answer!</p>
<p>Over time, you can begin to experiment with diverse types of content, including articles, press releases, guest posts, infographics, and videos, among others. But for now, stick to creating a <strong>winning blog marketing strategy</strong>.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style1">
<div class="inner">
<h3>Don’t have the time to write engaging blogs?</h3>
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog-writing-services/">Check out our blog samples</a></p>
<p>and sign up for our affordable custom blog services.</p>
</div>
</div>
<h3><a name="_Toc56687708"></a>5. Speed Up Your Website</h3>
<p>Remember the golden ranking factors we touched upon earlier?</p>
<p>Those that make it easier for Google’s algorithm to rank websites on SERPs?</p>
<p>Well, <strong><u>site speed</u></strong> is one of them.</p>
<p>Google uses page speed, among a wide range of other factors, to rank webpages.</p>
<p>Here’s an excerpt:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2245" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-18.png" alt="excrept" width="864" height="162" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Source: <a href="https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2010/04/using-site-speed-in-web-search-ranking.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Google</a></p>
<p>In short, if your website takes too long to load, you can wave high rankings goodbye.</p>
<p>If you’re looking to grow your website traffic, you <em>need</em> to make sure your webpages show up among the top organic search results on Google.</p>
<p>Start by using Google’s very own PageSpeed Insights to determine whether your website passes the <a href="https://web.dev/vitals/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Core Web Vitals assessment</a>. You’ll get an overview of your site’s speed and general user-friendliness so you can work on the weaknesses accordingly.</p>
<p>Toggle between “mobile” mode and “desktop” mode to gauge how well your site performs across each platform.</p>
<p>Here’s a snippet of the performance and speed report for Apple’s desktop site:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2246" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-19.png" alt="Apple" width="736" height="513" /></p>
<p>If you don’t pass the report, your website requires some work.</p>
<p>Focus on reducing page load speed by getting in touch with web development experts.</p>
<p>You can also try the following strategies to speed up your website:</p>
<ul>
<li>Enable compression</li>
<li>Minimize HTTP requests</li>
<li>Use a content delivery network (CDN)</li>
<li>Optimize images for speed</li>
<li>Use faster plugins</li>
<li>Reduce server response time</li>
</ul>
<h3><a name="_Toc56687709"></a>6.Make Sure Your Website Runs Seamlessly Across All Devices</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2247" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-20.png" alt="website runs smoothly" width="801" height="564" /></p>
<p>Web speed isn’t the only technical SEO factor that needs to be taken into consideration to maximize organic search traffic.</p>
<p>If your website doesn’t run seamlessly <em>across all devices</em>, you could be setting yourself up for failure. It’s virtually impossible that your target audience solely uses their desktop to search for products/services online.</p>
<p>Over the past few years, internet use has continued to diversify. Presently, people use a wide range of devices—including desktops, laptops, smartphones, tablets, etc.—to connect with brands online.</p>
<p>So if your website runs smoothly on certain devices but appears ghastly on others, you’ll struggle to boost conversions.</p>
<p><em>And that’s not all.</em></p>
<p>Google uses mobile-friendliness as a <a href="https://developers.google.com/search/mobile-sites/mobile-first-indexing" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">key ranking factor</a>.This means startups that launch mobile-friendly websites rank higher than those that don’t.</p>
<p>Better rankings, greater traffic, excellent conversions, long-term growth… need we go on?</p>
<p>Increase organic search by making sure your website looks <em>and</em> operates optimally across all devices. It’s important to check both web design and development off the list. Skimping on either will take a toll on your rankings.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc56687710"></a>7.Build Your Website’s Domain Authority</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2248" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-21.png" alt="moz" width="701" height="480" /></p>
<p>Created by Moz, Domain Authority (DA) is a measure of how well your website ranks on SERPs.</p>
<p>It takes multiple ranking factors into consideration to calculate your website’s authority.</p>
<p>The score ranges from 0–100, with 0 being and lowest and 100 being the highest. A DA between 40 and 50 is considered average while anything above60 is considered excellent.</p>
<p>To put things into perspective, here’s a glimpse into the DA of some of the top businesses across the globe:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://apple.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Apple</a>: DA = 100</li>
<li><a href="http://adobe.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Adobe</a>: DA = 98</li>
<li><a href="http://time.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">TIME</a>: DA = 94</li>
<li><a href="http://entrepreneur.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Entrepreneur</a>: DA = 92</li>
</ul>
<p>Needless to say, websites with a high DA get more traffic than those with an average or below-average DA.</p>
<p>Can SEO help your startup grow? Absolutely! As a startup, you should have a strong focus on <em>building authority from the get-go</em>.</p>
<ul>
<li>Start by optimizing on-page content, including your blogs, product/service pages, local pages, etc.</li>
<li>Use title tags, Meta description tags, image alt text, canonical tags, and shorter URLs to improve your rankings.</li>
<li>In addition, try your hand at <em>link building</em> to increase organic reach.</li>
</ul>
<p>Link building is the process of acquiring high-quality hyperlinks (also known as “backlinks”) from websites with a high DA. As they link to your webpages in their content, you’ll generate more traffic and get your startup seen by a wide audience.</p>
<p><strong>Recommended Read:</strong><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-advanced-link-building-tips-and-tricks-to-boost-your-seo/">10 Advanced Link Building Tips and Tricks to Boost Your SEO</a></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc56687711"></a>8.Improve Your Website’s Security and Encryption</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2249" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-22.png" alt="Security and Encryption " width="701" height="386" /></p>
<p>In <a href="http://googlewebmastercentral.blogspot.com.au/2014/08/https-as-ranking-signal.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">2014</a>, Google announced that it would be using HTTPS as a ranking signal.</p>
<p>In essence, websites that are secured with HTTPS encryption are <em>more likely</em> to climb to the top rungs of Google SERPs than those that aren’t.</p>
<p>Here’s what you need to do:</p>
<ul>
<li>Start off by getting an SSL certificate to enable an encrypted connection. This will protect user data entered on your website.</li>
<li>Make sure you partner with a reliable and trusted hosting company to ensure optimal security and reduce the risk of a security breach.</li>
<li>Eliminate further security issues by using expertly developed plugins and themes.</li>
</ul>
<p>Not only will these measures help you rank higher on SERPs, but they’ll also protect your startup in its initial stages of inception.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc56687712"></a>9.Supercharge Your Social Signals</h2>
<p>Social signals are metrics that demonstrate the level of engagement and activity on your social media pages. They include, but are not limited to, likes, shares, views, pins, votes, tags, follows, tweets, retweets,etc.</p>
<p>Now, marketing experts have long debated whether social signals affect rankings and organic search or not. If you think about it, excellent social signals equate to a <em>booming</em> social media presence. And if you’ve made it big on social media, it goes without saying that your business has garnered <u>a lot of followers and attention</u>. This popularity in itself will hike up your webpages on SERPs.</p>
<p>But if we take this organic correlation out of the picture, does Google’s algorithm <em>actually</em> care about social signals when ranking webpages?</p>
<p>Well, it does.</p>
<p>Moz has conducted numerous studies (exhibit <a href="https://moz.com/blog/does-google-use-facebook-shares-to-influence-search-rankings" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">A</a> and <a href="https://moz.com/blog/facebook-twitters-influence-google-search-rankings" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">B</a>) to prove that Google does, indeed, use social signals to rank webpages. The increase in inbound links and citations plays a big role in making a business more visible on the web, which, in turn, improves rankings.</p>
<p>Supercharge your social signals by creating social media pages if you haven’t already.</p>
<p>Start with Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram. Over time, you can branch out into Pinterest, LinkedIn, and YouTube, if necessary.</p>
<p>Once you’ve set up your pages, make sure you fill them out to a tee. Don’t skip any important detail and make sure your business information (especially NAP—name, address, and phone number) is consistent across the board.</p>
<p><em>Now comes the fun part.</em></p>
<p>Optimize your pages by posting <em>actively and regularly</em>.</p>
<p>Don’t post for the sake of posting. If you share unengaging and lackluster content, you’ll struggle to engage and retain customers. Instead, share compelling, value-added, and original posts to get people talking about your startup for all the right reasons.</p>
<p>We also suggest sharing your blogs (and other types of content, if you have any) to send some link juice their way.</p>
<p>Actively engage with your followers by responding to comments, messages, and tags.The more friendly, attentive, and empathetic you are, the better the chances of building a wide customer base.</p>
<p>As a startup, <em>retention</em> should be one of your main focus. If a strategy strikes a chord with your audience, zone in on it to ensure customer satisfaction.</p>
<p>As you generate more traffic, increase conversions, and ensure audience retention, your startup will enjoy booming success!</p>
<div class="blog-cta style2">
<div class="inner">
<h3>Grow your startup by building a wide audience!</h3>
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/free-proposal/">Request a free proposal and get started now!</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc56687713"></a>Got It! Now How To See How Much Traffic A Website Gets?</h2>
<p>There are a few ways; if you own a website, it’s fairly simple. You can install Google Analytics for free. Click on <em>Overview </em>to see pretty accurate results of your overall web traffic.</p>
<p>Now, if you <em>don’t </em>own the website; let’s say you’re trying to get to know your competition (great move!), then try out:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.similarweb.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">SimilarWeb</a>: You can check out stuff like the website’s total visits, pages per visit, average visit duration and bounce rate.</li>
<li><a href="https://ahrefs.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Ahrefs</a>: This one’s more accurate and extensive. You can review monthly total visits, top ranking keywords; you can even break down pages that receive the highest traffic. Pretty cool, right!</li>
</ol>
<h2><a name="_Toc56687714"></a>Final Thoughts on How to Get Traffic to Your Website</h2>
<p>In this blog, we walked you through a step-by-step guide to growing your startup by leveraging SEO for small businesses.</p>
<p>We covered everything from understanding your target audience to using the <em>right</em> keywords for excellent local reach. We help you increase website traffic through search engines like Google and Bing.</p>
<p>If you’re ready to give SEO a go, we can help you kick things off.</p>
<p>At Search Berg, we offer expert <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/small-business-seo/">small business SEO services</a> to startups struggling to get seen online.</p>
<p>Our online marketing specialists analyze your business model, industry, and target audience to create a customized strategy that helps you hit the ground running! Call <a href="tel:855-444-4777"><strong>855-444-4777</strong></a> now or fill out the form below to start driving traffic to your website!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/seo-for-startups-how-to-get-organic-traffic-on-your-website-fast/">SEO for Startups: How to Get Organic Traffic on Your Website Fast</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/seo-for-startups-how-to-get-organic-traffic-on-your-website-fast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is SEO? A Beginner’s Guide</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-search-engine-optimization-seo/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-search-engine-optimization-seo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 14:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2164</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Each time a web user searches for a business in your industry on Google, they receive a ton of results. If your product/service page shows up among the first few results, great! You’ll earn a click and potential conversion. However, if it shows up on the second, third, or eighteenth page, you may not even get [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-search-engine-optimization-seo/">What is SEO? A Beginner’s Guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Each time a web user searches for a business in <strong><em><u><b><i>your</i></b></u></em></strong> industry on Google, they receive a ton of results. If your product/service page shows up among the first few results, great! You’ll earn a click and potential conversion. However, if it shows up on the second, third, or eighteenth page, you may not even get an impression.<span id="more-2164"></span></p>
<p><em>So how do you turn things around?</em></p>
<p>How do you boost your website on Google SERPs?</p>
<p>How do you make sure your business shows up among the top search results and generates impressive traffic?</p>
<p>You turn to SEO (search engine optimization).</p>
<p><em>But what is SEO and how does it work?</em></p>
<p>SEO is the process of <em><i>optimizing</i></em> your content to ensure it <strong><u><b>ranks higher on Google</b></u></strong>.</p>
<p>So the next time a local web user looks up “digital marketing company in NY,” “best SEO company in New York,” or similar products/services in your industry, <strong><em><u><b><i>your</i></b></u></em></strong> business will show up among the top search results and bag impressive sales.</p>
<p>As SEO specialist, we dive deeper into the process of SEO and cover how your business can benefit from it. We walk you through how we can help you get traffic, calls, conversions and sales…all with the power of SEO.</p>
<p>Learn everything you need to about search engine optimization quickly to boost your website on Google!</p>
<p>Call us at <a href="tel:855-444-4777"><strong><u><b>855-444-4777</b></u></strong></a><strong><b> </b></strong>to speak with our <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-services/">SEO experts</a> to kick start your SEO campaign! Or <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/contact-us/"><u>request a quote and get a FREE SEO Audit Report</u></a>!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><iframe loading="lazy" title="What is SEO | Importance of SEO | SEO Services | Hire SEO Experts - Search Berg" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cWhpgjdwyyk" width="770" height="433" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-search-engine-optimization-seo/">What is SEO? A Beginner’s Guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-search-engine-optimization-seo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
