<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Content Marketing &#8211; Search Berg</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/category/content-marketing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 14:17:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to Write Content That Converts Leads into Customers</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-content-that-converts-leads-into-customers/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-content-that-converts-leads-into-customers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 13:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=3204</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While converting curious web users into leads is important, it’s not enough. Sure, you’ve managed to turn casual web browsing into serious shopping, but now what? If a web user simply buys your products/services without returning, you’ll struggle to consistently generate revenue over time. Instead of solely focusing on converting browsers into leads, go a step [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-content-that-converts-leads-into-customers/">How to Write Content That Converts Leads into Customers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/how-to-write-content-that-generate-leads.jpg" /><br />
While converting curious web users into leads is important, it’s not enough. Sure, you’ve managed to turn casual web browsing into serious shopping, but now what?</p>
<p>If a web user simply <em><u>buys</u></em> your products/services without <em><u>returning</u></em>, you’ll struggle to consistently generate revenue over time. Instead of solely focusing on converting browsers into leads, go a step beyond by <u>converting leads into loyal customers</u> that stick around in the long run.</p>
<p>The outcome? Consistent brand building, lead generation, coversion, and profit-making. This mix is music to an up-and-coming business’s ears.</p>
<p>How can you achieve it? By <em><u>creating content that converts</u></em>.</p>
<p>We want to make things simpler by breaking down the process of converting leads into customers through content. Let’s dive in!</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Struggling to write high-quality content that converts? Consult our pros by filling out the form below!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contents</strong></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc80048632"><u>How to Write Content That Converts</u> </a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc80048633"><u> Incorporate High-Converting Keywords Into Your Content</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc80048634"><u> It’s All About the CTA (Call-to-Action)</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc80048635"><u>3.Write </u><u>Sales-Driven Content</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc80048636"><u> Showcase Testimonials on Your Web Pages and Social Media Pages</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc80048637"><u> Avoid Inconsistency and Redundancy</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc80048638"><u> Replace Loud Pitches with Softer Nudges</u> </a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc80048639"><u>Wrapping Up</u> </a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><a name="_Toc80048632"></a><strong><b>How to Write Content That Converts</b></strong></h1>
<h2><a name="_Toc80048633"></a><strong><b>1. Incorporate High-Converting Keywords Into Your Content</b></strong></h2>
<p>Many brands wonder why their content fails to generate leads in the long run. They seemingly check off all the boxes by writing engaging, insightful, and industry-specific content.</p>
<p>So, what’s missing? The answer may be right under your nose: <em><u>keywords</u></em>.</p>
<p>This phrase is obnoxiously overused in the world of content, but rightfully so. Keywords are the foundation of high-quality content that drives massive sales.</p>
<p>Using a mix of the right exact match, phrase match, broad match, broad match modifier, and negative match keywords, you can turn <u>web browsers into leads</u> and <u>leads into returning customers</u>.</p>
<p>As a rule of thumb, make sure <strong>60% of the keywords you select</strong> are equipped to drive high conversion rates.</p>
<p>In other words, they should compel your audience to a) take positive action on your site, b) further explore your site, c) return for a purchase at least 1–2 times, and d) continue to return for purchases, subscriptions, etc. in the long run.</p>
<p>Your audience shouldn’t simply buy a product/service and “bounce”; they should feel interested and engaged enough to <em><u>want to stick around</u></em>.</p>
<p>Start by selecting <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/conversion-rate-optimization/"><u>high-CTR (click-through rate) keywords</u></a> that are your top performers. More often than not, these keywords include verbs that prompt action.</p>
<p>Let’s consider an example for more clarity.</p>
<p>Let’s say you provide ecommerce support to startups and up-and-coming businesses. Instead of solely using keywords like “ecommerce services” or “cheap ecommerce solutions,” introduce an actionable verb to the mix.</p>
<p>For instance, keywords like “create an ecommerce strategy” and “consult ecommerce professionals” include verbs (“create” and “consult”) that prompt action.</p>
<p>In other words, they’re <em><u>excellent converters</u></em>.</p>
<p>As web users land on your site and come across more high-converting keywords, they’ll take consistent actions on your site.</p>
<p>This is a great way to keep your target audience on your site for longer, which, in turn, will convert them into long-term customers.</p>
<p>Here are more examples of high-converting keywords to further elucidate this strategy:</p>
<ul>
<li>For attorneys: “<strong><u>Build</u></strong>a strong case”</li>
<li>For web developers: “<strong><u>Create</u></strong>an interactive website”</li>
<li>For realtors: “<strong><u>Buy</u></strong>your dream home”</li>
<li>For door manufacturers: “<strong><u>Replace</u></strong>your front doors”</li>
</ul>
<p>See what we mean? As long as there’s a verb supporting the keyword, you’re on the right track.</p>
<p>Of course, you can further build the keyword to strengthen it even more.</p>
<p>Here’s what we mean:<br />

<table id="tablepress-1" class="tablepress tablepress-id-1">
<thead>
<tr class="row-1 odd">
	<th class="column-1">HIGH-CONVERTING KEYWORDS</th><th class="column-2">	STRONGER HIGH-CONVERTING KEYWORDS</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody class="row-hover">
<tr class="row-2 even">
	<td class="column-1">For attorneys: “<u>Build</u> a strong case”</td><td class="column-2">For attorneys: “Build a strong case <u>in Los Angeles</u>”</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-3 odd">
	<td class="column-1">For web developers: “<u>Create </u>an interactive website”</td><td class="column-2">For web developers: “Create an interactive website <u>in less than $100</u>”</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-4 even">
	<td class="column-1">For realtors: “<u>Buy </u>your dream home”</td><td class="column-2">For realtors: “Buy your dream home <u>in SoHo</u>”</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-5 odd">
	<td class="column-1">For door manufacturers: “<u>Replace </u>your front doors”</td><td class="column-2">For door manufacturers: “Replace your front doors <u>and get a transom for free</u>” </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<!-- #tablepress-1 from cache --></p>
<p>As you build high-converting keywords by adding local search terms and your brand’s USPs to the mix, you’ll increase your chances of converting leads into customers through content.</p>
<p>We recommend incorporating high-converting keywords into <u>different types of content</u> on your site: blogs, product/service pages, the FAQ page, the about page, the contact us page, etc.</p>
<p>This will ensure that your audience takes continual actions, which will ultimately help them learn more about your brand as they go and keep shopping in the long run.</p>
<p>Here are some excellent titles from <a target="_blank" href="https://www.adidas.com/us/blog" rel="noopener"><u>Adidas’ blogs</u></a>. We’ve highlighted the verbs to help you understand how seamlessly their team has incorporated high-converting keywords into the mix!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/how-to-choose-for-legging.jpg" /><br />
<img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/how-to-wear-stan-smith.jpg" /><br />
<img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/how-to-choose-for-rock-climbing.jpg" /><br />
<img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/how-to-break-in-running-shoes.jpg" /></p>
<p>The verbs are strategically followed by their products (leggings, Stan Smith sneakers, climbing shoes, running, shoes).</p>
<p>This is how you check this strategy off the list like a seasoned pro!</p>
<p><strong>Recommended Read: </strong><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/blog-vs-article-what-is-the-difference/"><u>Blog vs. Article: What Is the Difference?</u></a></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc80048634"></a><strong><b>2. It’s All About the CTA (Call-to-Action)</b></strong></h2>
<p>When it comes to creating content that converts, a <a target="_blank" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2020/10/12/planning-your-content-ctas-by-funnel-stage-and-content-type/" rel="noopener"><u>strong CTA (call-to-action)</u></a> isn’t just useful, it’s <em><u>imperative</u></em>.</p>
<p>A CTA is a short text (2–5 lines) that compels web users to take action.</p>
<p>If you’re writing a blog, power blog, article, guest post, or any other type of content that goes on your site or a third-party site, the CTA should generally be included at the end.</p>
<p>If you’re working on a product/service page, the CTA can be included in the form of visual elements.</p>
<p>For social media posts, the CTA can be included in the beginning or towards the end.</p>
<p><em>Here’s the catch</em>.</p>
<p>While CTAs follow a similar rhythm for the most part, they can’t be generic or predictable.</p>
<p>Instead of incorporating a boring CTA into your content, make sure it a) carries conversion potential, b) is engaging, and c) is expertly optimized.</p>
<p>Here’s a closer look at a power-packed CTA from <a target="_blank" href="https://www.adidas.com/us/blog/681805-how-to-break-in-running-shoes-for-maximum-comfort" rel="noopener"><u>Adidas’ recent blog</u></a>:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/screenshots.jpg" /></p>
<p>Notice how the CTA comprises <u>high-converting keywords</u> (“choose” and “find” are the guiding verbs here).</p>
<p>It also includes <u>visual elements</u> that lead web users to Adidas’ relevant collections.</p>
<p>In fact, they’ve gone the extra mile by linking their <u>social media pages and email</u> below (bottom right).</p>
<p><em>This is one hell of a CTA! </em></p>
<p>The keywords are hyperlinked, the visual elements are as eye-catching as it gets, and the transition from the rest of the content to the CTA is seamless.</p>
<p>The goal is to compel your audience to take positive action without them realizing what’s happening.</p>
<p>A cheesy CTA that’s easily detectable can be extremely off-putting. Your audience will know right away that you’re trying to “sell” something.</p>
<p>This isn’t something they should be able to pick up on; the transition should be <u>undetectable and natural</u>.</p>
<p>Adidas gets this balance <em>just right</em>.</p>
<p>If you want to create website content that converts, make sure your CTAs aren’t overly promotional. They should also be expertly optimized using the right keywords (refer to the first section of this blog for more insight) and internal links.</p>
<p>Your goal is to prompt positive action without making it painfully obvious. It takes a while to get this roundabout content writing style just right.</p>
<p>If you’re struggling, we recommend consulting a team of <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog-writing-services/"><u>professional content writers</u></a>.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Got the CTA or keyword blues? Our content marketing pros can help. Fill out the form below to start converting leads into customers through content!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc80048635"></a><strong><b>3.Write </b></strong><strong><b>Sales-Driven Content</b></strong></h2>
<p>We’ve covered the basics: keywords and CTAs; they form the foundation of good content.</p>
<p>However, creating “good content” atop a firm foundation is the bulk of the job.</p>
<p>One misstep and you could end up damaging the foundation and going back to square one.</p>
<p>In other words, <em><u>this is where the real work begins</u></em>.</p>
<p>If you write unengaging, boring, and banal content, your audience will “bounce,” thereby increasing your site’s <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-improve-website-bounce-rate/"><u>bounce rate</u></a>.</p>
<p>At the very most, you’ll manage to convert web users into leads. However, you’ll struggle to convert leads into loyal customers that stick around in the long run.</p>
<p>To check this important box off the list, write <strong><u>sales-driven content</u></strong>.</p>
<p>Not only that, but your content should also be highly engaging, value-added, and insightful.</p>
<p>As the name suggests, sales-driven content is content that <u>generates massive sales</u>. It’s written with the intention of <em>informing, engaging</em>, and <em>converting</em> your target audience.</p>
<p>Start off by taking a deep dive into your audience’s interests and preferences. This is the first step to writing content that converts.</p>
<p>As you understand what your audience is looking for, you’ll manage to choose the right topics for your content.</p>
<p>We strongly recommend sectioning off your audience demographically.</p>
<p>For instance, if you run an apparel store, identify the specific age groups you create clothing for. As you split these groups into different categories, you can work on creating content for each category.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://blog.ae.com/" rel="noopener"><u>American Eagle</u></a> does this brilliantly. As a result, their content isn’t generic; it’s actually highly specific.</p>
<p>The outcome? They’ve managed to convert <em>each demographic</em> into long-term customers.</p>
<p>Here’s an example of their recent blog:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/aejeans.jpg" /></p>
<p>Notice how they’ve targeted their younger demographic, i.e., teenagers who are returning to school this year.</p>
<p>Once you’ve sectioned off your audience, start selecting relevant themes, topics, events, and social media trends that pique their interest. In other words, look for ideas to create content that they’ll actually read.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.tonal.com/blog/" rel="noopener"><u>Tonal’s relevant blogs</u></a> are a great example of putting this strategy into practice the right way!</p>
<p>Instead of choosing generic topics, they delved deeper and carefully selected topics that their audience was actually interested in.</p>
<p>For instance, they wrote an <a target="_blank" href="https://www.tonal.com/blog/for-patrick-curreri-being-strong-is-about-more-just-himself/" rel="noopener"><u>insightful, empowering, and deeply moving blog during Pride Month</u></a>.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/brand-celebration.jpg" /></p>
<p>The brand also celebrated and emphasized the true meaning of independence by <a target="_blank" href="https://www.tonal.com/blog/celebrating-juneteenth/" rel="noopener"><u>posting a powerful blog on Juneteenth</u></a>.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/celebrating-juneteenth.jpg" /></p>
<p>Writing content on topics that resonate with your audience shows that you care about their interests, representation, and using your platform for good.</p>
<p>Today, people are increasingly looking for brands that go the extra mile to <em><u>value customers</u></em>, not just generate massive revenue.</p>
<p>As a brand, you should have a razor-sharp focus on showing your audience that they’re more than just a number to you.</p>
<p>As you build a strong brand identity, you’ll simultaneously manage to convert leads into customers.</p>
<p>Your audience will feel <em>acknowledged, accepted, celebrated</em>, and <em>included</em>.</p>
<p>This feeling makes customers feel special. It shows them that brands care about who they are and what they stand for.</p>
<p>As you create content for different demographics, you’ll manage to capture their interests and show them that you’re committed to offering more than just a great product/service.</p>
<p>This extra step is also known as “<u>humanizing the content</u>”, i.e., adding an element of humanness and empathy to web content.</p>
<p>When combined with high-converting CTAs and keywords, humanized content helps brands rank higher, generate more traffic, convert web users into leads, and convert leads into customers.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://postmates.com/blog/" rel="noopener"><u>Postmates</u></a> is also known for creating content that <em><u>centers their audience</u></em>. Here’s a glimpse of their audience-centric blogs:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/stophating-asianhate.jpg" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/international-women-day.jpg" /></p>
<p><strong>Recommended Read: </strong><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-a-blog-that-ranks/"><u>How To Write A Blog That Ranks</u></a></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc80048636"></a><strong><b>4.Showcase Testimonials on Your Web Pages and Social Media Pages</b></strong></h2>
<p>According to research, a whopping <u>84% of web users trust online reviews</u>. That’s a lot by any measure.</p>
<p>In fact, <u>80% of people change their minds after reading a positive or negative review</u>.</p>
<p>As an up-and-coming or even established business, you can actualize impressive growth by <em>doubling down on testimonials</em>.</p>
<p>Here’s why this is so important.</p>
<p>Presently, large majority of brands have a separate testimonial page that lists their online reviews.</p>
<p>While this is a great approach, it’s not enough.</p>
<p>The human attention span is incredibly low: <em>a measly eight seconds</em>.</p>
<p>It’s unlikely that your customers will explore every single page on your site.</p>
<p>In most cases, customers never end up on the testimonial page, which delays the process of trusting a brand.</p>
<p>Undo the damage by showcasing your testimonials on multiple pages across your site, especially your product/service pages and blogs.</p>
<p>If you explore <a target="_blank" href="https://www.nike.com/" rel="noopener"><u>Nike’s product pages</u></a>, you’ll notice that <em>each page</em> features reviews for the respective product. Here’s an example:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/nike-shoes.jpg" /></p>
<p>A lot of brands use a similar approach for non-product/service pages.</p>
<p>Let’s say you manufacture sporting equipment and choose to write a blog on the best footwear for an arduous hike.</p>
<p>As you showcase some products that you have in stock, you can include reviews for each product towards the end of the blog.</p>
<p>This is a great way to compel your audience to buy said products.</p>
<p>Testimonials are <a target="_blank" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/theyec/2019/08/21/why-reviews-are-essential-and-how-to-generate-positive-reviews-for-your-business/" rel="noopener"><em><u>extremely powerful</u></em></a>. They carry the ability to form a person’s opinion and eliminate doubt.</p>
<p>By incorporating them into web content and even social media content, you can nudge your audience in the right direction: potentially buying your products/services and becoming long-term customers.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.lacoste.com/" rel="noopener"><u>Lacoste</u></a> is known for frequently replying to and retweeting posts from customers. While these aren’t “reviews” in the traditional sense, they still count as testimonials.</p>
<p>By interacting with these posts, Lacoste expertly ensures that they gain more traction.</p>
<p>Here’s an example:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/twitter-post.jpg" /></p>
<p>The tweet will show up on Lacoste’s page since they’ve responded to it. It’ll also gain more traction as it earned a response from a verified page.</p>
<p>Lacoste’s social media marketing team has an <em>excellent understanding</em> of how the Twitter algorithm works. By using it to their benefit, they’re brilliantly showcasing positive online reviews on social media!</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.target.com/" rel="noopener"><u>Target</u></a> is known for using the same approach:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/twitter-post-reply.jpg" /></p>
<p>Whether customers appreciate your products, services, in-store shopping experience, customer support team, or any other facet of your brand, consider it a win and highlight it!</p>
<p>As more customers interact with flattering social media posts or web reviews, they’ll become loyal customers that stick around in the long run.</p>
<p>This is a tried-and-tested way of converting leads into customers through content (both web content and social media content).</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Need high-converting content for your web or social media pages? Do things the right way: the Search Berg way. Fill out the form below to get started!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form4" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject4" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name4" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website4" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email4" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number4" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country4" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha4();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc80048637"></a><strong><b>5. Avoid Inconsistency and Redundancy</b></strong></h2>
<p>Many brands are guilty of falling into the all-too-familiar traps of inconsistency and redundancy.</p>
<p>As you start creating content, you may reach a point when you <em>simply can’t think of new topics</em>.</p>
<p>When this situation arises, some brands become inconsistent with content creation (i.e., they start posting less frequently) while others resort to redundancy (i.e., they recycle the same ideas and present them differently).</p>
<p>These avenues can be <u>extremely dangerous</u> for your brand, especially if you start relying on both of them at once.</p>
<p>The sooner you identify these habits, the better.</p>
<p>As you start undoing the damage in due course, you can prevent customer attrition/loss.</p>
<p>If you take action a little too late, you may have already lost a significant number of customers.</p>
<p>It’s important to note that consistently creating fresh content is one of the easiest ways to convert leads into customers. This is why nipping inconsistency and redundancy in the bud is so important.</p>
<p>If you’re short on ideas, turn to <a target="_blank" href="https://www.google.com/imghp?hl=EN" rel="noopener"><u>Google Images</u></a> for help!</p>
<p>Let’s say you offer massage therapy services in Atlanta, Georgia. As you enter “massage therapy” in the search bar, Google will fetch a lot of suggestions for you.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/google-search.jpg" /></p>
<p>These tags are <em><u>closely related</u></em> to your search query. In other words, web users are actively searching for these terms as they’re looking up “massage therapy” on Google.</p>
<p>Use these suggestions to your advantage by building new connections and creating fresh, relevant, and engaging content.</p>
<p>This strategy is extremely useful because you’re relying on <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-algorithm-updates-that-changed-seo/"><u>Google’s whip-smart algorithm</u></a>, which already knows what’s relevant and what’s not.</p>
<p><em>It’s doing the work for you! </em></p>
<p>Instead of manually searching for new topics that may not be as relevant, you can opt for this route to find the most relevant topics for new content.</p>
<p>Once you’ve used up all your connections, click on individual tags to unearth a plethora of new terms.</p>
<p>This cycle is never-ending. It’s one of the best ways to write new content that doesn’t bore your audience.</p>
<p>In addition to employing this strategy, we also recommend reaching out to your audience for help.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.plm.automation.siemens.com/global/en/products/simcenter/" rel="noopener"><u>Simcenter</u></a>, a branch of the renowned brand <a target="_blank" href="https://www.siemens.com/" rel="noopener"><u>Siemens</u></a>, recently reached out to their audience on Twitter. They requested more insight into the specific kind of content their audience was seeking: videos, infographics, live webinars, or blogs.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/slim-center.jpg" /></p>
<p>You can leverage the same strategy but <em><u>get a tad more specific</u></em>!</p>
<p>Ask your audience to list the specific topics they’d love to read content on.</p>
<p>Make use of Twitter’s inbuilt features (polls, etc.) to further increase engagement.</p>
<p>You can also keep the post more open-ended by requesting your audience to share their ideas in the comments.</p>
<p>This is a great way to feed two birds with one scone!</p>
<p>Not only will you manage to fill your proverbial “content marketing” bags with new ideas, but you’ll also get a chance to increase your social media engagement.</p>
<p>It’s a win-win!</p>
<p>Here are some more great examples to help you start off on the right foot:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/crypto-mena.jpg" /><br />
<img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/build-your-future.jpg" /><br />
<img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/kucoin.jpg" /></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc80048638"></a><strong><b>6. Replace Loud Pitches with Softer Nudges</b></strong></h2>
<p>Think back to marketing in the 2010s.</p>
<p>Whether you were watching a TV commercial, reading a blog, or browsing through a company’s products/services, you would have been bombarded with statements like:</p>
<ul>
<li>“What are you waiting for? Buy now before it’s too late!”</li>
<li>“You can’t miss out on our sale! We’ve got the best toasters in town, grab ‘em now!”</li>
<li>“$20 off? Go, go, go! It doesn’t get better than this, start shopping now for the best in interior décor!”</li>
</ul>
<p>While these pitches may not seem too loud at first, they can easily overwhelm you once you come across two, three, five, or <em>even ten</em> each day.</p>
<p>This was marketing in the 2010s in a nutshell. It was loud, excessively promotional, cheesy, and downright gimmicky.</p>
<p>In the 2020s, we’ve transitioned from loud pitches to softer nudges. While you may think the latter aren’t as effective, they’re actually better at converting leads into customers.</p>
<p>Today, people are on the hunt for content that <em>informs, educates</em>, and <em>solves their problems</em>.</p>
<p>Flashy lights, gaudy props, cheesy headlines, and an excessive sense of urgency aren’t appreciated anymore.</p>
<p>Instead, customers would rather read content that includes practical insights, useful tips, and fresh ideas.</p>
<p>As a rule of thumb, steer clear of loud pitches. They do more harm than good and may compel your audience to start looking elsewhere.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.dyson.com/newsroom/overview" rel="noopener"><u>Dyson’s blogs</u></a> are a great example of putting value over heavy promotion.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/blog-screenshots.jpg" /></p>
<p>You can still include a well-placed CTA in your content. However, focus on writing quality content to make <em>a great impression</em> on your audience.</p>
<p>Not only will people stick around until the very end, but they’ll also take positive action in response to the great content that was provided.</p>
<p>And if your content features testimonials towards the end, well, you’ve checked off all the boxes!</p>
<h1><a name="_Toc80048639"></a><strong><b>Wrapping Up</b></strong></h1>
<p>In this blog, we walked you through six steps to writing content that converts. As you put these strategies into practice, make sure you <em><u>prioritize quality every step of the way</u></em>.</p>
<p>When woven into content strategically and seamlessly, soft nudges can compel action and convert leads into loyal customers.</p>
<p>As you work towards <a target="_blank" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/theyec/2019/12/23/five-strategies-for-developing-a-strong-brand-identity/" rel="noopener"><u>strengthening your brand identity</u></a>, you’ll also manage to retain customers who were considering partnering with a different brand.</p>
<p>At Search Berg, our content marketing team has extensive experience in writing high-converting content that generates leads and drives sales.</p>
<p>We’re committed to helping you stand out in your industry and make big splashes through high-quality content.</p>
<p>If you’re ready to get started, we can help. Give us a call at <a href="tel:8554444777"><u>855-444-4777</u></a> to kick-start your <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/content-marketing/"><u>content marketing strategy</u></a>!</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Writing content that converts can be tricky; let us step in and achieve the results you’re aiming for! Fill out the form below to get started.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form4" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject5" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name5" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website5" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email5" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number5" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country5" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha5();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-content-that-converts-leads-into-customers/">How to Write Content That Converts Leads into Customers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-content-that-converts-leads-into-customers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Best CMS for a Successful Website</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Jensen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 09:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a quest to design a website for your business, it&#8217;s likely that you&#8217;ve come across the term &#8220;CMS&#8221; a few times. A CMS or Content Management System can make setting up and running your website incredibly straight-forward. In this blog, you&#8217;ll discover the top 10 Content Management Systems out there to support your website, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/">10 Best CMS for a Successful Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a quest to design a website for your business, it&#8217;s likely that you&#8217;ve come across the term &#8220;CMS&#8221; a few times. A CMS or Content Management System can make setting up and running your website incredibly straight-forward.</p>
<p><span id="more-2621"></span></p>
<p>In this blog, you&#8217;ll discover the top 10 Content Management Systems out there to support your website, factors to consider when choosing a CMS, and how the best CMS can boost your SEO.</p>
<p>Because of various CMS platforms, you’re left wondering: which CMS should I use?</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s start by defining <strong><em>what a CMS is</em></strong> and how it helps you build your website effectively.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Do you want a killer, professionally designed website that drives sales? Fill out the form below to get in touch with us.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2>Contents</h2>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181237">What is a CMS?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181238">10 Best CMS Software for 2021</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181239"> WordPress</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181241"> Drupal</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181243"> Joomla</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181244"> Magento</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181246"> HubSpot</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181248"> BigCommerce</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181250"> Shopify</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181251"> Squarespace</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181253">Wix</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181254"> Weebly</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181255">What Factors Do You Need to Consider When Choosing a CMS?</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181256"> Pricing Features that are Right for You</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181257"> Stellar Support</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181258"> Which Content Management System Will Support Your SEO Best?</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181259"> Ease of Personalization and Design</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181260"> Website Security</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181261"> Easy Website Migration Capabilities</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181262">The Best Content Management Systems for SEO &amp; Why</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181263"> WordPress</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181264"> Drupal</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181265"> Magento</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181266"> Hubspot</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181267"> Shopify</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181268">Wrapping Up!</a></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68181237"></a>What is a CMS?</h2>
<p>A CMS, or Content Management System, is a system that allows you to create a website without actually writing any code such as HTML or Java.</p>
<p>Ok, clear so far. Now why do we use CMS?</p>
<p>Without Content Management Systems, those businesses that wanted to create websites would need to rely on experienced coders or learn the languages ourselves. Thankfully, we have Content Management Systems (CMS) at our disposal.</p>
<p>So, a CMS like WordPress makes the process of not only designing, but also <em>managing websites</em> significantly easier and more streamlined.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68181238"></a>10 Best CMS Software for 2021</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181239"></a>1. WordPress: Cost &#8211; $0</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2634" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog2-1.png" alt="wordpress" width="1899" height="804" /><br />
<a href="https://www.searchberg.com/wordpress-seo/">WordPress</a> is the most widely used CMS platform for websites. Using WordPress, you can create any kind of website, including a company website, personal portfolio, online store, etc.</p>
<p>There are many benefits of WordPress. In terms of design freedom, WordPress has thousands of designs available for users to download and use, whether they&#8217;re directly from WordPress or third party WordPress theme websites like <a href="https://themeforest.net/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">ThemeForest</a>.</p>
<p>In addition to being free, WordPress is also great for SEO. It allows you to easily create tags, update URLs and categories, and add separate plug-ins to improve your website&#8217;s SEO.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg" alt="WordPress CMS features from their website's home page." width="730" height="651" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2637" /></p>
<p>The only downside is you&#8217;ll need to purchase your own domain through a domain hosting platform like <a href="https://www.bluehost.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">BlueHost</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181241"></a>2. Drupal: Cost &#8211; $0</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2632" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-9.png" alt="Drupal" width="1891" height="672" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/drupal-seo/">Drupal</a> is super helpful if you have a huge amount of data you want to add on your website. It&#8217;s helpful for this purpose because it can handle extreme customization requirements and data.</p>
<p>It has an in-built user system where you can manage what users can and cannot do. It has a vast array of themes available and you can increase Drupal&#8217;s functions using modules. It has previously installed automation tools for SEO as well.</p>
<p>While you will need a hosting provider, <a href="https://www.drupal.org/hosting" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">here</a> is a list of providers that support Drupal users.</p>
<p>Drupal is also trusted by the following trusted brands.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2631" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-8.png" alt="Six trusted brands known to use Drupal for their websites, promoting it as one of the best CMS software." width="1063" height="477" /></p>
<p>You should know that because the interface is designed to handle complex tasks fit for developers, Drupal is less beginner-friendly relative to WordPress. In addition, its themes can also be pricey.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181243"></a>3. Joomla: Cost &#8211; $0</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2630" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-7.png" alt="The Jooma CMS home page showing three options: to download, use, and learn Joomla." width="1259" height="846" /></p>
<p>As with WordPress and Drupal, you&#8217;re going to need to buy a domain separately. While <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/joomla-seo/">Joomla</a> is also a veteran in the CMS game like WordPress, it&#8217;s equipped to handle large amounts of data and tasks that it can be daunting for beginners. In addition, it features a built-in user access system that allows you to regulate actions of registered users.</p>
<p>If you choose to go with Joomla and have little web development experience, you&#8217;d benefit from hiring a developer to handle building your website.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181244"></a>4. Magento: Cost &#8211; Free, Kind Of.</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2629" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog2.png" alt="Magento" width="1895" height="812" /><br />
Magento is a CMS specifically designed for e-commerce platforms. While there are some standard SEO functions, you&#8217;ll need to download a good extension for more abilities. One example of these extensions is the free Creare SEO 2.0 extension.</p>
<p>While you can certainly access Magento for free using the software Magento OpenSource, you also have the option of paying Magento to manage it on their end. This can start from two grand USD per month.</p>
<p>While Magento is a highly secure, powerful CMS, it&#8217;s not forgiving to beginners and will need you to have technical knowledge or someone on your team who does.</p>
<p>If you own a B2B Ecommerce store and are looking to improve your conversions, check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/11-ways-to-triple-your-b2b-ecommerce-conversions/">11 Ways To Triple Your B2B Ecommerce Conversions.</a></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181246"></a>5. HubSpot: Cost &#8211; $300/mo</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2628" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-6.png" alt="HubSpot" width="1709" height="902" /><br />
Among other benefits, HubSpot provides 24 hour website security and support. The CMS works for users whether you&#8217;re a beginner or a developer because you have the option to write code directly or use the drag-and-drop features.</p>
<p>For that price point, it should be easy to use!</p>
<p>As a bonus, you&#8217;ll also get SEO recommendations and easy A/B testing capabilities in your website.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181248"></a>6. BigCommerce: Cost &#8211; $30/mo</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2627" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-5.png" alt="BigCommerce" width="1894" height="808" /><br />
<a href="https://www.searchberg.com/bigcommerce-seo/">BigCommerce</a> is also specifically for ecommerce stores, as implied by its name. The biggest selling point for BigCommerce is that it allows you to sell products through your own ecommerce website and big ecommerce marketplaces like Amazon and Ebay.</p>
<p>You can either obtain a free domain name from BigCommerce which will have their brand name in the URL or you can purchase a custom domain.</p>
<p>BigCommerce does lack a little in the design department, but you can integrate your BigCommerce site with WordPress to resolve that issue.</p>
<p>The $30 covers a lot for starting companies and sole proprietors, but BigCommerce also has <strong><em>big</em></strong>-ger options with more features for larger organizations.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve ever wondered what CMS big companies use, if it&#8217;s an ecommerce company then it&#8217;s likely BigCommerce.</p>
<p>If you make more than 50,000 USD in sales per year, then you&#8217;ll automatically be bumped up to the more pricey plan which is about $250 per month, so keep that in mind for your expenses.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181250"></a>7. Shopify: Cost &#8211; $29/mo</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2626" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-4.png" alt="The Shopify home page which shows their slogan that anyone, anywhere can start a business online" width="1245" height="614" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/shopify-seo/">Shopify</a> is a simple, drag-and-drop, beginner-friendly CMS for ecommerce. It&#8217;s very straightforward and allows you to accept payments through multiple ways, including Shopify Payments and PayPal.</p>
<p>Additionally, Shopify has apps you can install to your store that make it easy to increase your features. For example, if you&#8217;re dropshipping products, you can import reviews from your third-party supplier&#8217;s website using apps.</p>
<p>While it has a more pricey option of around $300 per month that has more features, unlike BigCommerce, it doesn&#8217;t automatically upgrade your plan.</p>
<p>Shopify&#8217;s main advantage is its simplicity because it handles hosting, security, and site maintenance. These crucial benefits of Shopify leave you free to go out and get customers.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181251"></a>8. Squarespace: cost &#8211; starting at $16/mo</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/squarespace-seo/">Squarespace</a> is great for less technical users who just want to create a basic website. So, personal websites, portfolio websites, and even company websites are easily made using Squarespace.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2625" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-3.png" alt="Squarespace's company message &quot;Simple tools for big ideas&quot; echoing the consensus that it is indeed a simple tool for beginners and non-complex website requirements." width="544" height="383" /></p>
<p>They&#8217;re not the best for ecommerce stores because it&#8217;s so simple that your operation won&#8217;t be heavy-weight, per se.</p>
<p>If you require more robust functionality in your website, though, Squarespace isn&#8217;t your best option.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181252"></a>9. Wix: Cost &#8211; Starts From $14/mo</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2624" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-2.png" alt="wix.com" width="1687" height="890" /></p>
<p style="text-align: right;">&#8211; wix.com</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/wix-seo/">Wix</a> is an incredible platform for beginners who want to make a website. With their subscription, you can pay monthly or annually, and their drag-and-drop features make constructing a website significantly stream-lined.</p>
<p>You should remember, though, that with its simplicity and user-friendliness come some costs. For example, once you choose a designated template for your website, you can&#8217;t change it.</p>
<p>The good thing is that each theme is adaptable to mobiles, tablets, and desktops, so there&#8217;s no bad template options here even if you get pigeon-holed into one template style.</p>
<p>The ecommerce options for Wix will also be limited because it only accepts certain payment pathways like PayPal.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181254"></a>10. Weebly: Cost &#8211; Free and $5 and up.</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2623" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-1.png" alt="Weebly homepage displaying their templates and pricing buttons." width="1240" height="726" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/weebly-seo/">Weebly</a> is also a solid CMS to use. It allows its users simple drag-and-drop features and is user-friendly. Its mobile-responsive templates have calmed many a business owner regarding their mobile rankings on Google.</p>
<p>Weebly does give the option for SEO, but there are more expansive CMS out there for SEO. If you already have a Weebly CMS for your website, it might help to hire a Weebly-specific SEO specialist to help you maximize your website&#8217;s potential.</p>
<p>Users of Weebly have had issues with exporting their content or migrating from this CMS to other platforms.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Take control and build more a responsive website. With our <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/cms-migration/" style="text-decoration:underline;">website migration services</a>, move to a new CMS platform!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2>What Factors Do You Need to Consider When Choosing a CMS?</h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Our list and each CMS features won&#8217;t mean much if you don&#8217;t know what your needs are, so this section is designed to help you concretize what criteria to look out for in your ideal CMS.</p>
<p>After all, what features should the best CMS include?</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181256"></a>1. Pricing Features that are Right for You</h3>
<p>Some CMS will work with your website using a subscription model where you pay the company a certain amount per month. But there are certainly others that are free of cost.</p>
<p>However, even with the free options, you can still have costs that come out when you need to link it with external applications or software for specific website features you may want to incorporate.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181257"></a>2. Stellar Support</h3>
<p>The best CMS for you needs to have a responsive and supportive customer support team. If you&#8217;re waiting for customer support representatives to get back to you for days or weeks on end regarding an issue with your website, your website and its traffic will.</p>
<p>So make sure the CMS you choose has a high-quality, reliable, and trust-worthy support team that other users can vouch for.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181258"></a>3. Which Content Management System Will Support Your SEO Best?</h3>
<p>Does the CMS feature easy ways for you to manage your website&#8217;s SEO?</p>
<p>Will it allow you to make changes for your SEO using the CMS directly or will you need to go the long route and get a coder?</p>
<p>The best CMS platform will make SEO easier and more efficient for you, not harder.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181259"></a>4. Ease of Personalization and Design</h3>
<p>Since the CMS is what you&#8217;ll use to design your website, your baby, you&#8217;ll naturally want it to look impressive and well-designed.</p>
<p>Some CMS platforms are definitely more outdated than others in terms of design. But a few are extremely good for designing the perfect website for your business or even your personal portfolio. To this end, there should be a wide array of website templates and designs for you to choose the one you want.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181260"></a>5. Website Security</h3>
<p>Some CMS platforms will take care of your website&#8217;s security for you, while when using others you&#8217;ll need to do it yourself.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181261"></a>6. Easy Website Migration Capabilities</h3>
<p>The best kind of CMS platform will not keep you if you want to migrate to a different platform. Instead, it will make the process of exporting your data to another CMS platform streamlined and easy.</p>
<p>After all, what is it they say—<em>if you love something, let it go? </em>So the best CMS software will allow you to move your website wherever you please.</p>
<h2>The Best Content Management Systems for SEO &amp; Why</h2>
<p>So you design a website, but what is the use of this website if it doesn’t make your products and services <em>visible</em>? We’re talking about the SOE value of various CMS platforms.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s evaluate the top contenders based purely on their SEO capabilities and tool kits.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181263"></a>1. WordPress</h3>
<p>WordPress has a massive array of themes and plugins that allow you to optimize your site for SEO. These benefits and unique advantages of WordPress allow it to be one of the most popular CMS used in the world today.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181264"></a>2. Drupal</h3>
<p>Drupal&#8217;s modules work similarly to WordPress&#8217;s plugins in that they support your SEO efforts in addition to in-built tools.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181265"></a>3. Magento</h3>
<p>Magento is a powerful CMS for e-commerce because it has a wide array of functionality. It also includes good resources and features on its website to help its users take full advantage of SEO. It&#8217;s more developer-friendly than beginner-friendly overall, though, so keep that in mind.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181266"></a>4. Hubspot</h3>
<p>Hubspot&#8217;s CMS Hub will give you automatically generated recommendations for SEO. It will even give you keyword recommendations in each part of your web page. It has many robust SEO features which you can have access to for $300/month.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181267"></a>5. Shopify</h3>
<p>We recommend <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/shopify-seo/">Shopify</a> in this list in case you&#8217;re a beginner and your domain is ecommerce. If your main target is to make sales through ecommerce, then Shopify is your best bet for SEO.</p>
<p>Shopify&#8217;s benefits are plentiful.</p>
<p>We recommend this CMS because Shopify&#8217;s interface is built for ecommerce SEO, so you&#8217;d have all the tools you need to spruce up your ecommerce store&#8217;s SEO. For its price point of $29/month, Shopify delivers on a lot of fronts in the ecommerce SEO department. Also, once you get some great sales, you can always upgrade to the plan that has even more functionality.</p>
<p>To really nail your SEO for ecommerce, be sure to check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-conversion-rate-optimization-hacks-you-should-know/">10 Conversion Rate Optimization Hacks You Should Know</a>.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Want to transform your website to be responsive and drive sales? Fill out the form below for our expert <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/web-design-and-development/" style="text-decoration:underline;">web design and development services</a>.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form4" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject4" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name4" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website4" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email4" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number4" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country4" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha4();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68181268"></a>Wrapping Up!</h2>
<p>And that&#8217;s all, folks! We’ve covered the best content management systems, choosing the best CMS for you, and the right CMS that will get you the most juice out of your SEO efforts.</p>
<p>As one of the leading digital marketing agencies in the U.S., we provide high-quality <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/web-design-development-services/">web design services</a> that&#8217;ll transform your website to be responsive and produce sales.</p>
<p>For more information about our services, call <a href="tel:8554444777">855-444-4777</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/">10 Best CMS for a Successful Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Write A Blog That Ranks</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-a-blog-that-ranks/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-a-blog-that-ranks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 12:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There’s no denying that content marketing can be challenging. And we know the backbone of every content marketing strategy is blogging. Wondering how to start a blog? The question on every business owner’s mind should in fact be: how to write a blog that ranks.  Because sure, you can shell out content every day or [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-a-blog-that-ranks/">How To Write A Blog That Ranks</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There’s no denying that content marketing can be challenging. And we know the backbone of every content marketing strategy is <strong><b>blogging</b></strong>.</p>
<p>Wondering how to start a blog?<span id="more-2295"></span></p>
<p>The question on every business owner’s mind should in fact be: how to write a blog <strong><em><u><b><i>that ranks.</i></b></u></em></strong><strong><em><u><b><i> </i></b></u></em></strong></p>
<p>Because sure, you can shell out content every day or so—generic, 200-words blogs with no focus and zero keywords. They’re not going to add value; they’re not going to solve your target audiences’ questions; they won’t augment your brand; and <u>they’re not going to rank</u>.</p>
<p>If you’re going to invest time in a blogging strategy, it doesn’t matter what industry you’re in; you need to know how to write a <em><i>good</i></em> blog, how to <em><i>structure</i></em> a blog post, the ideal word count for a blog, and how to <em><i>drive traffic to your blog</i></em>!</p>
<p>These are <em><i>key</i></em> elements.</p>
<p>In this infographic, our blog experts talk about some tips for writing successful blogs.</p>
<p>If you’re struggling to get your blogs off the ground, call us at <a href="tel:855-444-4777"><strong><u><b>855-444-4777</b></u></strong></a> now and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog-writing-services/"><u>hire a blog writing service</u></a> that can ensure you get the traffic, leads and conversions!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog-writing-services/"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-2296 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/SearchBerg_revised-01-1.jpg" alt="Tips on how to write a blog that ranks high on search engines " /></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-a-blog-that-ranks/">How To Write A Blog That Ranks</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-a-blog-that-ranks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Content-Driven SEO Is the Ultimate Digital Marketing Strategy for 2020</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-the-ultimate-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-the-ultimate-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivia Glyn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 07:45:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contents Engaging Content Helps Drive Quality Traffic to Your Website. 3 Leverage Optimized Content to Improve Online Visibility and Climb SERPs. 7 Speed Up Buyers’ Journeys. 9 … And Put Your Sales on Autopilot! 11 Give Your Domain Authority a Much-Needed Boost 12 Cut Your Customer Attrition Rate and Bounce Rate By Half 14 Establish [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-the-ultimate-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2020/">Why Content-Driven SEO Is the Ultimate Digital Marketing Strategy for 2020</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2>Contents</h2>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc50027197"> Engaging Content Helps Drive Quality Traffic to Your Website. 3</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50027198"> Leverage Optimized Content to Improve Online Visibility and Climb SERPs. 7</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50027199"> Speed Up Buyers’ Journeys. 9</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50027200"> … And Put Your Sales on Autopilot! 11</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50027201"> Give Your Domain Authority a Much-Needed Boost 12</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50027202"> Cut Your Customer Attrition Rate and Bounce Rate By Half 14</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50027203"> Establish a Winning Social Media Presence. 16</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc50027204"> Envision and Actualize Long-Term Business Growth. 17</a></li>
</ol>
<p><strong><u><b>60%</b></u></strong> of marketers make sure they create at least one piece of content every day.</p>



<p><em><i>Why? </i></em></p>



<p>Because a whopping <strong><u><b>70%</b></u></strong> of people prefer getting informed about products/services/trends through content.</p>



<p><span id="more-1607"></span></p>



<p>If you’re new to the world of digital marketing, we’re sure you’ve grown sick of seeing the phrase “content is king” plastered across blogs and social media platforms.</p>



<p>And we don’t blame you.</p>



<p>But while it may sound cheesy and hackneyed, its meaning runs deep. Try your hand at <u><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>leveraging SEO</strong></span></u> while leaving content out of the mix and you’ll soon notice that you’ve taken on a task that’s impossible to accomplish.</p>
<p><strong><em>“How important is content in a digital marketing strategy?”</em></strong></p>
<p>More than you may think.</p>



<p>Simply put, content and SEO go hand in hand. Sideline one, and you’ll put your business at risk of low conversions, high customer attrition, and massive revenue loss.</p>



<p>As one of the most effective and fast-acting digital marketing strategies of 2020, content-driven SEO is a <em><i>recipe for success</i></em> any way you look at it.</p>



<p>But despite its rapid and consistent efficacy, many companies fail to create winning content-driven digital marketing strategies.</p>



<p><em>The outcome?</em></p>



<p>They’re confronted with countless hurdles that prevent them from achieving KPI targets and they experience long-term issues that impede business growth.</p>



<p><strong><em><b><i>“Alright, I get the gist of it. But what’s in it for me?”</i></b></em></strong></p>



<p>If you’ve been following our blog for a while now, you may have stumbled across our previous blog on <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-a-lucrative-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2019-and-beyond/"><strong><u><b>the importance of content-driven SEO in 2019</b></u></strong></a>.</p>



<p>We suggest getting a quick refresher to familiarize yourself with the content-driven SEO landscape of 2019.</p>



<p>Juxtapose the blogs so you can identify divergences and draw parallels between each section. This will help you take note of the changes that have occurred since, so you can tweak your strategy accordingly.</p>



<p>Let’s dive in!</p>



<h2><strong><b>1. Engaging Content Helps Drive Quality Traffic to Your Website</b></strong></h2>



<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1622" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/graphic-design-that-reads-‘engaging-content’-and-displays-two-women-producing-content.png" alt="graphic design that reads ‘engaging content’ and displays two women producing content" width="624" height="442" /></figure>
</div>



<p>Companies that post an average of 16 blogs a month drive <strong><u><b>3.5 times more traffic</b></u></strong> to their website than those that post 0–4 blogs each month.</p>



<p>While you may have employed a plethora of <u>actionable SEO strategies</u>, overlooking the importance of content could end up doing more harm than good.</p>



<p>It’s no surprise that a whopping <strong><u><b>50%</b></u></strong> of marketers admit that <u>curated content</u> has played a big role in boosting organic traffic to their website!</p>



<p><a href="https://blog.jostle.me/blog" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>Jostle’s</u></a> frequent, high-quality, and expertly optimized blogs are a great example of content-driven SEO done right. Notice how multiple blogs are uploaded on the same day without compromising quality, creativity, and relevance.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1609" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/optimized-blogs.png" alt="screenshot of value-added and engaging blogs by Eventbrite" width="644" height="179" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img class="wp-image-1608" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/expertly-optimized-blogs.png" alt="expertly optimized blogs" /></figure>
</div>



<p>The gripping titles, eye-catching blog thumbnails, and informative content each play a big role in allowing Jostle to boast an impressive domain rating of 61.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1610" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/jostle.png" alt="Jostle’s domain rating" width="626" height="223" /></figure>
</div>



<p>And while leveraging blogs is a great way to drive high-quality traffic to your website, it’s equally important to make the most of other forms of content.</p>



<p>In addition to blogs, you should be focusing on creating compelling, unique, and optimized:</p>



<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/article-writing/"><u>Articles</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/video-content-services/"><u>Videos</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/infographics/"><u>Infographics</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/guest-blogging/"><u>Guest blogs</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/press-release-writing/"><u>Press releases</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/product-description-writing-services/" rel="nofollow"><u>Product web pages</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/service-page-writing-services/"><u>Service web pages</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/regional-page-writing-services/"><u>Regional web pages</u></a></li>
</ul>



<p>Optimize the content by diving into the deep end of <strong><b>keyword research</b></strong>.</p>



<p>We suggest using <u><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Google Keyword Planner</span></u> to identify and incorporate relevant keywords into your content.</p>



<p>Simply enter words or phrases closely associated with your business to find the right keywords for your content.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1611" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/keyword-research.png" alt="screenshot of the Google Keyword Planner" width="571" height="210" /></figure>
</div>



<p>Focus on short-tail keywords, long-tail keywords, geo-targeting keywords, and LSI (latent semantic indexing) keywords to increase quality traffic to your website.</p>



<p>We suggest paying special attention to long-tail keywords, as they have a <a href="https://www.smartinsights.com/search-engine-optimisation-seo/seo-analytics/comparison-of-google-clickthrough-rates-by-position/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><strong><u><b>3–5%</b></u></strong></a> higher click-through rate than generic keywords.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img class="wp-image-1612 aligncenter" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/geo-targeting-keywords.png" alt="geo-targeting keywords" /></figure>
</div>



<p>Incorporating <a href="https://neilpatel.com/blog/html-tags-for-seo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>optimized HTML tags</u></a> into your content will go a long way in generating more traffic and increasing the visitor-to-lead conversion rate.</p>
<p>Ultimately, impactful content ensures your visitors stay on your website longer. These strategies will help you do just that!</p>



<h2><strong><b>2. Leverage Optimized Content to Improve Online Visibility and Climb SERPs</b></strong></h2>



<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1613" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/graphic-design-displaying-Google-search-results.png" alt="concept illustration of top Google search results being analyzed by a marketer" width="624" height="624" /></figure>
</div>



<p>Whether you’re a seasoned marketing specialist or recently began testing <strong><u><b>the waters of digital marketing</b></u></strong>, we’re sure you’re well-acquainted with the importance of climbing SERPs by now.</p>



<p>But let’s dive a little deeper.</p>



<p>The first five organic search results on Google receive <strong><u><b>67.6%</b></u></strong> of all clicks.</p>



<p><em><i>Why? </i></em></p>



<p>Because a whopping <strong><u><b>75%</b></u></strong> of people never scroll past the first page on Google.</p>



<p>Understandable, right? Who has the time to?</p>



<p>But this is probably where you’re subconsciously hurting your brand.</p>



<p>If you haven’t implemented a content-driven SEO strategy yet, the chances are that your web pages are showing up on the 8<sup>th</sup>, 9<sup>th</sup>, or even <em><i>30</i></em><em><sup><i>th</i></sup></em> SERP.</p>



<p>Active content creation is a great way to undo the damage by climbing SERPs and giving your online visibility a much-needed boost. In fact, websites with blogs have an astounding <strong><u><b>434%</b></u></strong> more search engine-indexed pages!</p>



<p>Leverage high-quality blogs, articles, press releases, videos, and infographics to boost audience engagement and retention. As your product/service pages and content pages begin to climb SERPs, you’ll manage to target a wide, localized, and quality audience.</p>



<p>Over time, this will reduce uninterested visitors and allow you to build a strong network of quality leads that are more likely to invest in your products/services as opposed to dillydally around.</p>



<h2><strong><b>3. Speed Up Buyers’ Journeys</b></strong> <img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1614 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/graphic-design-demonstrating-online-order-confirmation.png" alt="concept illustration of online order confirmation" width="624" height="624" /></h2>



<p>With over <strong><u><b>61%</b></u></strong> of American consumers admitting that they’ve made a purchase after reading a blog, leveraging content is a surefire way to <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesbusinesscouncil/2020/03/27/what-to-know-about-the-buyers-journey-and-customer-life-cycle-and-how-to-use-them-both/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>speed the buyers’ journey</u></a>.</p>



<p>Potential customers are <em><i>actively</i></em> on the lookout for engaging, value-additive, and succinct information that helps them make a decision.</p>



<p>Let’s say your company designs and manufactures high-quality and visually striking tote bags. While you may have uploaded high-definition pictures on your website, producing little to no content around the product will dramatically reduce the chances of a potential purchase.</p>



<p>Instead, writing an engaging and optimized product description is a great way to increase the chances of attracting interested customers and speeding up the buyer’s journey.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.katespade.com/products/molly-falling-flower-large-tote/767883647844.html?cgid=ks-handbags-totes" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>Kate Spade’s</u></a> descriptive and engaging—albeit precise—product description is the <em><i>perfect</i></em> example of powerful content that paints a picture in the reader’s mind.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1615" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/albeit-precise.png" alt="screenshot of Kate Spade’s descriptive and engaging product description for a tote bag" width="589" height="581" /></figure>
</div>



<p>Top it off with an engaging and informative blog titled “6 Versatile Ways to Use a Tote Bag” to further expedite the buyer’s journey!</p>



<h2><strong><b>4. … And Put Your Sales on Autopilot!</b></strong></h2>



<p><em>Struggling to boost sales?</em></p>



<p>Leveraging content-driven SEO is one of the most effective ways to not only grow sales, but also put them on autopilot!</p>



<p>Whether you create visually dynamic infographics or write value-added blogs, you’ll notice a gradual and steady increase in revenue and profits.</p>



<p>If your content strikes a chord with your audience, they’re more likely to share it with friends/family on social media or messaging platforms. This is a great way to expand your audience and organically target new demographics!</p>



<p>We recommend leveraging video content to further increase your chances of receiving quality shares.</p>



<p>According to research, <strong><u><b>92%</b></u></strong> of users who engage with a video on their mobile phones share it with others. In fact, video content generates <strong><u><b>1,200%</b></u></strong> more shares than text and image content.</p>



<p>While leveraging the latter is important, incorporating the former into your digital marketing strategy is <em><i>imperative</i></em>.</p>



<p>As you focus on creating unique, value-added, and optimized content, you’ll reap the benefits of consistent revenue gain that helps your brand grow in the long run.</p>



<h2><strong><b>5. Give Your Domain Authority a Much-Needed Boost</b></strong></h2>



<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1616" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/graphic-design-displaying-web-analytics-on-a-tablet.png" alt="concept illustration of web analytics displayed on a tablet" width="624" height="624" /></figure>
</div>



<p>Domain authority (DA) is a popular search engine ranking score that determines your website’s rank on Google SERPs.</p>



<p>The score ranges from 0–100. DA between 40–50 is considered average, DA between 50–60 is considered good, and DA over 60 is considered excellent.</p>



<p>Reputable websites like <a href="https://www.forbes.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>Forbes</u></a>, <a href="https://www.entrepreneur.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>Entrepreneur</u></a>, <a href="https://www.glassdoor.com/index.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>Glassdoor</u></a>, <a href="https://www.architecturaldigest.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>Architectural Digest</u></a>, and <a href="https://www.elledecor.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>Elle Décor</u></a> have an impressive DA between 80–95. Not only does this give them an edge over competitors, but it also means people are more likely to perceive them as trustworthy sources of information.</p>



<p>This means increased traffic, higher SERP rankings, and <em><i>better</i></em> sales!</p>



<p>While there are many ways to improve your website’s DA, producing impactful, optimized, and engaging content is the most effective.</p>



<p>Instead of creating content that superficially covers the basics of an industry-relevant topic, go <em><i>all </i></em>in!</p>



<p>This means taking the time to research industry trends so you can produce content that informs the reader.</p>



<p>This is a great way to build a consistent audience, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-link-building-and-why-does-my-business-need-it/"><u>attract high-quality backlinks</u></a>, and give your website’s DA a much-needed boost. Over time, you’ll manage to become a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/8-reasons-to-protect-your-brands-online-reputation-during-the-covid-19-pandemic/"><strong><u><b>reputable and trustworthy</b></u></strong></a> voice in the industry.</p>



<p>We suggest browsing through the content of key competitors in your industry. Focus on both established and up-and-coming businesses.</p>



<p>For instance, if you recently started an online tech support business, identify key local and global players in the industry. Your research should generally include <a href="https://www.bestbuy.com/site/services/geek-squad/pcmcat138100050018.c?id=pcmcat138100050018" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>Geek Squad</u></a>, <a href="https://www.bask.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>Bask</u></a>, <a href="http://mynerds.com/tech-support.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>My Nerds</u></a>, <a href="https://totaltechcare360.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>Total Tech Care 360</u></a>, <a href="https://www.techtous.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>Tech to Us</u></a>, and <a href="http://www.iyogi.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>iYogi</u></a>, among others.</p>



<p>Work closely with an SEO and content marketing specialist to analyze their current content marketing strategy.</p>



<p>This will help you plan ahead and leverage winning content-driven SEO so you can hit the ground running!</p>



<h2><strong><b>6. Cut Your Customer Attrition Rate and Bounce Rate By Half</b></strong></h2>



<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1617" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/graphic-design-displaying-web-analytics-on-a-computer-screen.png" alt="concept illustration of web analytics on a computer screen" width="624" height="416" /></figure>
</div>



<p>Nobody likes the thought of losing potential customers.</p>



<p>And while losing the odd customer here and there isn’t too bad for business, you know you’re dealing with a serious problem if the numbers keep plummeting… consistently.</p>



<p>Creating content that informs <em><i>and</i></em> enthralls your audience is a genius way to cut your customer attrition rate and bounce rate by half.</p>



<p>As your audience is greeted by a visually engrossing blog page that features high-quality blogs and infographics, they’re more likely to stick around. And if you continue to post gripping content, you’ll <em><i>master</i></em> the art of <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/nickmorgan/2016/05/31/how-to-improve-audience-retention-with-five-simple-techniques/#1090405c46dd" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)"><u>audience retention</u></a>!</p>



<p>But while consistency is important, creativity is equally essential.</p>



<p>Take special care to avoid falling into the all-too-familiar abyss of complacency and stagnancy.</p>



<p>Instead, retain a laser-sharp focus on keeping quality and ingenuity intact.</p>



<p>We also suggest producing high-quality press releases to keep customers informed about recent updates, fresh milestones, and notable events. Keeping your audience in the loop will go a long way in helping them feel involved and informed about the brand’s key happenings.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img class="wp-image-1618 aligncenter" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/loyal-customers.png" alt="loyal customers" /></figure>
</div>



<p>We strongly recommend focusing on <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/local-seo-in-2019-heres-what-you-need-to-primarily-focus-on/">local SEO</a> for your content—especially press releases—to ensure you target local customers. This is all the more important if your products/services are only available in selected regions.</p>



<p>Find out more about how you can optimize and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-optimize-google-my-business-listing-and-leverage-it-for-more-sales/">leverage Google My Business</a> to tap into your local audience and boost sales.</p>



<h2><strong><b>7. Establish a Winning Social Media Presence</b></strong></h2>



<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1619" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/graphic-design-displaying-a-phone-screen-surrounded-by-social-media-icons.png" alt="concept illustration of social media marketing" width="624" height="624" /></figure>
</div>



<p>According to research, a whopping <strong><u><b>73%</b></u></strong> of customers are influenced by a brand’s social media page as they make a purchasing decision.</p>



<p>Simply put, <u>social media matters</u> <em><i>more</i></em> than you may think.</p>



<p>And while you may have created impressive, updated, and interactive Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and Pinterest pages, kicking things off is only half the battle.</p>



<p>It’s equally important to ensure you actively share your social media pages to establish and maintain a winning social media presence.</p>



<p>Content-driven SEO is a great way to give your social media pages a quick shout-out. Whether you <u>give a nod to your Instagram page</u> in the call-to-action (CTA) or <u>seamlessly slide in a Facebook link</u> within the first few paragraphs, you’ll manage to boost your social media traffic.</p>



<p>We also suggest creating a YouTube page (<a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/youtube-seo-smart-digital-marketing-in-2019-to-expand-your-audience-promote-your-business-and-strengthen-your-brand/"><u>more on how to optimize YouTube videos here</u></a>) and linking your social media pages accordingly.</p>



<p>Here’s what the links should look like:</p>



<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1620" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/links-should-look-like.png" alt="Chick-fil-A’s eye-catching, simple, and effective YouTube page" width="624" height="160" /></figure>
</div>



<p>Of course, leaving your page in a state of limbo will wash your efforts down the drain.</p>



<p>Instead, create and share <u>SEO-friendly video content</u> on a weekly or monthly basis (or more if you can!).</p>



<p>You can also include links to YouTube videos in your blogs, articles, and infographics. Cross-linking will go a long way in helping you sustain an active social media presence!</p>



<h2><strong><b>8. Envision and Actualize Long-Term Business Growth</b></strong></h2>



<p>As the ultimate digital marketing strategy for 2020, content-driven SEO swiftly unlocks the portals to long-term business growth.</p>



<p>Simply put, sidelining optimized content can put your business at risk of losing relevance and reputability over the years. Instead, optimized content keeps your business on the map while consistently widening your audience base and boosting visibility.</p>



<p>It’s no surprise that over <strong><u><b>56%</b></u></strong> of businesses admit that they want to increase their content creation spending!</p>



<p>In fact, <strong><u><b>62%</b></u></strong> of companies have approximately 5,000 employees that work on producing daily content.</p>



<p><em>Sounds like a debatable investment?</em></p>



<p>We can help simplify <em><i>and</i></em> economize things.</p>



<p>As one of the leading digital marketing agencies in New York, Seattle, Orlando, San Diego, and Washington DC, we offer <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/content-marketing/">award-winning content-driven SEO services</a>.</p>



<p>Our content marketing team will analyze your current strategy and tweak it accordingly so you can reap the benefits of powerful content that keeps your audience engrossed.</p>



<p>We’ve published a whopping 150,000 content pieces and created over 22,800 infographics and videos so far!</p>



<p>Our affordable content-driven digital marketing services start at $0.06 per word so you don’t have to worry about breaking the bank.</p>



<p>Call <a href="tel:8554444777"><strong><u><b>855-444-4777</b></u></strong></a> to request a free quote and get started!</p>



<p>We also offer expert <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/ppc-marketing/"><u>paid marketing</u></a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/web-design-development-services/"><u>website design and development</u></a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/social-media-management/"><u>social media management</u></a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/reputation-management/">reputation management</a>, and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service/"><u>link building</u> services</a> across the globe.</p>

<div> </div>
<div> </div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-the-ultimate-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2020/">Why Content-Driven SEO Is the Ultimate Digital Marketing Strategy for 2020</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-the-ultimate-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Content-Driven SEO Is a Lucrative Digital Marketing Strategy for 2021 and Beyond</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-a-lucrative-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2019-and-beyond/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-a-lucrative-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2019-and-beyond/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Jensen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 14:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; With search engines like Google updating their algorithms frequently every year, it’s becoming increasingly difficult for website owners to develop digital marketing strategies that can stand the test of time. In order to devise strategies that produce actual business results, it’s important to map out your site’s structure and map out your objectives. SEO [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-a-lucrative-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2019-and-beyond/">Why Content-Driven SEO Is a Lucrative Digital Marketing Strategy for 2021 and Beyond</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>With search engines like Google updating their algorithms frequently every year, it’s becoming increasingly difficult for website owners to develop digital marketing strategies that can stand the test of time.</p>
<p>In order to devise strategies that produce actual business results, it’s important to <strong>map out your site’s structure and map out your objectives.</strong></p>
<p>SEO and content marketing are taken as two important yet separate strategies to drive marketing and engagement efforts, but this is the wrong way to view them because they are very much intertwined with one another.</p>
<p>Many business owners and bloggers believe that by doing content marketing that they reduce their need for SEO.</p>
<p>But since the two go hand in hand, this <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/media-network/media-network-blog/2013/may/10/google-content-marketing-seo" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">concept</a> is a misconception.</p>
<p>The reason why important content marketing efforts take off for a business is that they involve the meticulous use of SEO.</p>
<p>Essentially, while you are doing content marketing, the best practice is to implement the technical side of SEO into your content pieces as you generate them.</p>
<p>Without SEO, your content doesn&#8217;t reach the Google SERP for your keywords, and without good, regularly uploaded content, your SEO efforts are in vain.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1386" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/5072962.jpg" alt="digital marketing strategies" width="1000" height="946" /></p>
<p>In recent years, we have seen several digital marketing strategies come in and go out of trend.</p>
<p>However, in the constantly shifting online marketing landscape, there is one thing that has remained constant: <em>content is king, making content marketing its queen.</em></p>
<p>As website owners compete for the top spots on SERPs, content-driven SEO is becoming an increasingly important priority for businesses, both small and large.</p>
<p>You see, content is <em>the reason</em> why people visit a website, and it is through content that you connect with your audience and potential customers.</p>
<p>Therefore, when developing your content for SEO, it’s important to think about the questions your target audience is asking, and answer them in an engaging, compelling way.</p>
<h2>The Correlation between Content Marketing and SEO&#8217;s Importance For Your Business</h2>
<p><u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/content-marketing.html" rel="noopener">Content marketing</a></u> is a subcategory of digital inbound marketing which involves transitioning a website visitor through the sales funnel by offering them informative, helpful, and engaging content pieces.</p>
<p>Search engine optimization, or SEO as it’s more commonly known as, is the process of optimizing the website to perform better on the search engine results pages.</p>
<p>Although the two appear to be quite different to each other, they are more closely linked than you may think.</p>
<p>It’s not only possible to devise a content marketing strategy for SEO, but it’s also highly beneficial.</p>
<p>As the algorithms of search engines have evolved and changed, they have become increasingly partial to content driven SEO – that is, fresh unique content of a certain length, with just the right amount of keyword integration, and on specific pages.</p>
<p>A content-driven SEO strategy is a perfect balance of content creation and the other, more technical SEO factors.</p>
<p>Let’s take a look at why content-driven SEO will always be an evergreen digital marketing strategy.</p>
<h2>Content-Driven SEO Targets Quality Traffic</h2>
<p>One of the most notable advantages of content-driven SEO is that it’s an inbound digital marketing strategy.</p>
<p>In contrast to conventional “outbound” online advertising channels that take an “in your face” approach, inbound marketing doesn’t involve reaching out to consumers whether they’re interested in what you have to say or not.</p>
<p>Inbound marketing strategies focus on making it easier for potential consumers to find you when they need relevant information.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1390" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Traditional-outbound-marketing.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="250" /></p>
<p>On the other hand, inbound marketing takes a more <strong>“consumer-centric”</strong> approach.</p>
<p>Instead of disturbing consumers while they’re watching a video or reading an article, inbound marketing involves making valuable information easily accessible and creating valuable resources for the consumer.</p>
<p>Content-driven SEO makes it easy for consumers to find you when they’re looking for the type of services or products you offer.</p>
<p>Not only is this much more convenient for the consumers, but it also draws in more qualified leads for your business, which in turn, translates into better conversion rates.</p>
<p>In fact, according to the report from a recent studies, the majority of marketers say that inbound practices generated the highest quality leads for their sales teams.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1387" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/23765528.jpg" alt="Content-Driven SEO" width="1000" height="702" /></p>
<h2>More Content=More Keyword Opportunities=Better SEO</h2>
<p>A huge part of SEO is keyword usage. This involves finding and researching keywords that are relevant to your niche and then communicating their importance within your content marketing efforts.</p>
<p>The only way to actually use the keywords you garner as a result of your SEO efforts is to be strategic and analytical regarding how you use them in your web pages and content.</p>
<p>Naturally, if you instead choose to follow the black hat practice of stuffing keywords into your content, Google will find out and crack down on your site, punishing it severely in the SERP for your keywords.</p>
<p>There is definitely such a thing as excessively optimizing for keywords.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t beat a horse after it&#8217;s dead because Google will possess the horse&#8217;s body and drag your rankings down to hell&#8217;s gates.</p>
<p>Search engines like Google don’t “see” websites like us humans do.</p>
<p>While we can understand a website for what it is by looking at the pictures on the web pages, search engines have no way of determining a website’s purpose until those words are expressly written somewhere.</p>
<p>Content-driven SEO enables you to go further than the text descriptions on pictures and small paragraphs of homepage copy, where the space you have for keywords is restricted.</p>
<p>Through using blog posts, guides, articles and other forms of written content, you can utilize more keywords that are related to what your business is about – as well as what consumers are searching for.</p>
<p>For instance, if you sell auto supplies on your website, you may want to rank well for keywords relevant to tires.</p>
<p>And rather than attempting to stuff a variety of tire-related keywords and phrases into a small page or space, you can write a very natural blog post on “What Tires are best for Winter Driving” or create a guide for buying the right type of tires for your vehicle.</p>
<p>In addition to being informative and engaging, this type of content also provides you with a great opportunity to utilize keywords and boost your rankings in SERPs.</p>
<p>Furthermore, according to a <u><a href="http://blog.serpiq.com/how-important-is-content-length-why-data-driven-seo-trumps-guru-opinions/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">study</a></u> by SerpIQ, pages that rank the highest on Google’s SERPs tend to also have the most amount of content.</p>
<p>But is long-form content always better?</p>
<p>Well, not necessarily.</p>
<p>While content length is certainly prioritized by search engines, it’s not prioritized as much as quality. A content piece could by 10,000 words, but it would be completely useless if it didn’t contain the relevant information.</p>
<p>Just think about the last instance you used Google search to find an answer or an online tutorial.</p>
<p>How long did it take to find a page that answered your question in a detailed manner?</p>
<p>Chances are you found it almost instantly.</p>
<p>SEO has come a long way since those early days. It’s much more evolved now and takes factors into consideration other than just keyword density.</p>
<p>Therefore, by developing fresh and unique content that makes your audience go “wow!”, you have a better chance of climbing to the top spots in SERPs.</p>
<h2>Content Ensures Your Visitors Stay On Your Website Longer</h2>
<p>Let’s assume that a user is directed to one of your web pages by a search engine, can’t find what they’re looking for, and leaves at once without even looking at any other page. In the world of digital marketing, this is what you call a “bounce”. The percentage of visitors who do this on each of your web pages is factored into your site’s bounce rate.</p>
<p>Metrics such as the bounce rate are factored into your website’s overall SEP profile by Google. If one of your web pages have a higher than normal bounce rate, Google will think there’s something wrong with it, and will most likely stop ranking it high on its SERPs. The right content, however, can help you fight a high bounce rate.</p>
<p>For instance, let’s assume that your homepage has a very high bounce rate and you think the underlying problem is that consumers don’t know where to start learning about your services or products. To rectify this problem, you can add some content that introduces your business, add a few internal links, or even suggest where they could get started. This will reduce confusion, send them to other pages, and keep them on your website for longer. In this case, content allows you to solve three problems instead of just one!</p>
<p>As we discussed above, content that doesn’t solve the problems of your target audience, bores them, or doesn’t make its point quickly, will just drive visitors away. So, remember: while content length is certainly important, it’s also important not to waste your visitors’ time!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1388" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/25838476.jpg" alt="content length is certainly important" width="1000" height="832" /></p>
<h2>Unique Content Can Help You Climb SERP Rankings</h2>
<p>There’s one more area where content marketing and SEO often overlap: they focus on finding content that has never been done before and try to rank high for it.</p>
<p>When you take a content-driven approach to SEO, you can concentrate not only on developing a beneficial content marketing strategy for SEO purposes but also on creating fresh and unique content that enhances your brand’s domain authority.</p>
<p>This focus on fresh content helps you not only engage users who are looking for your specific content topics, but also other creators.</p>
<p>This helps you a lot with the automatic generation of backlinks.</p>
<p>According to SEO, the greater your number of high-quality, high domain authority backlinks, the better.</p>
<p>Ask yourself: why would people want to link to your web pages?</p>
<p>Perhaps, because you are creating high-quality content that helps them make their points in their blogs, and therefore, they actually want to link back to your blog.</p>
<p>This helps them provide their audience with a high authority source in the niche that provides helpful information for the topic at hand.</p>
<p>So outstanding content in this way is positively correlated with garnering high-quality high domain authority backlinks to your website.</p>
<p>While you do have the option to have temporary collaborations in which sources link back to your website, the only way to have continued backlink success is to have solid, timeless content on your website.</p>
<p>This timeless content will be referred to by people regardless of when you post it or whom you have worked with for backlink creation because they will naturally want to link to it.</p>
<p>It can be argued that since SEO also has technical aspects to it, such as optimizing the robots.txt file, it is different from content marketing.</p>
<p>But the fact remains that all technical efforts are created to clear the path between Google&#8217;s robots and what?</p>
<p>Fresh, helpful content.</p>
<p>Therefore, content and SEO are very much interlinked. Like Yin and Yang, one without the other is simply ineffective.</p>
<p>The right people do not see a blocked pathway to good content.</p>
<p>And a clear path to null or awful content is ignored by the right people, if not everyone who views it.</p>
<p>As long as you keep creating fresh, never-seen-before content that’s relevant you your enterprise and industry, these unique pieces will keep on helping you in occupying the top ranks in SERPs, rank higher for a wider range of keywords, and reach a larger audience.</p>
<p>So if either your SEO or Content Marketing approach is suffering, it&#8217;s likely that the other is also suffering by proxy and as a result of the first suffering.</p>
<p>To fix this, it is key to take an audit of how your site is currently performing.</p>
<p>There are two audits necessary for this purpose.</p>
<p>The first would be an exhaustive <strong>technical audit</strong>, in which you see what is working effectively and what is not.</p>
<p>Are all your URLs working? Is there duplicate content somewhere? Are your Meta Tags and Meta Descriptions for each page all in order? Have you made sure that the pages you don&#8217;t want Google bots to index from your site, such as a registration page, have been marked as such in the source code? How are your page loading speeds performing? Is your website mobile and tablet friendly?</p>
<p>You get the picture.</p>
<p>The second type of audit you will need to run on your site is a <strong>content audit</strong>.</p>
<p>The surprising thing that many sites find is that a lot of their content, especially old and outdated content, is no longer being visited.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s essentially wasted space that&#8217;s being taken up on your website that you are expecting results from, but people visiting your actual site couldn&#8217;t care less about it.</p>
<p>The way to fix this problem is to whip out your metaphorical vacuum cleaner and clean out the pointless content taking up space on your website.</p>
<p>Remember that you are also putting SEO efforts into these old pieces which simply aren&#8217;t performing, so you&#8217;re wasting your precious SEO juice and resources.</p>
<p>Once you have accomplished this removal of outdated and irrelevant content, you are only left with solid, contemporary blogs that are not only applicable to the readers of the present day but also are performing well for your website.</p>
<p>To figure out if the content is performing, check whether the information is still applicable and whether you are generating sufficient leads from that page on your website.</p>
<p>Using a content audit in this way can help to streamline your efforts and cast a smaller net in order to catch your fish.</p>
<p>For the many reasons outlined in this blog post, your SEO and Content Marketing efforts need to be intertwined so that they can be mutually beneficial.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you are a business owner and have separate departments for Content Marketing and SEO, it is vital that they regularly communicate and come up with strategies together.</p>
<p>If you are a sole proprietor or blogger and doing it on your own, it is thus important that you prioritize both in order to optimize your rankings on Google&#8217;s SERP.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1389" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Conclusion.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="250" /></p>
<p>Actually, your primary objective when devising a content marketing strategy shouldn’t be SEO gains; instead, it should be exposing your brand to a wider audience, establishing it as a domain authority, and establishing trust with your audience.</p>
<p>An award-winning digital marketing and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/small-business-seo.html">small business SEO</a> firm, Search Berg specializes in providing effective <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/guest-blogging.html">blogging</a> and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/high-da.html">publication services</a>. If you’re looking for quality content marketing services, get in touch with our representatives today!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-a-lucrative-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2019-and-beyond/">Why Content-Driven SEO Is a Lucrative Digital Marketing Strategy for 2021 and Beyond</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-a-lucrative-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2019-and-beyond/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Content Comprehensiveness for SEO – Are You Content With Your Content?</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/content-comprehensiveness-are-you-content-with-your-content/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/content-comprehensiveness-are-you-content-with-your-content/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 16:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contents What is Content Comprehensiveness? A Complete Guide to Content Comprehensiveness User Intent In-Depth and Long-Form Content Subtopics and Question Mining Trends and YMYL Content Comprehensives for SEO: How Should I Get Started?   By now, the phrase “content is king” has become a chant in SEO circles. It’s omnipresent, unavoidable, and when it really [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/content-comprehensiveness-are-you-content-with-your-content/">Content Comprehensiveness for SEO – Are You Content With Your Content?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Contents</h2>
<p><a href="#_Toc52786271">What is Content Comprehensiveness?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc52786272">A Complete Guide to Content Comprehensiveness</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc52786273">User Intent</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc52786274">In-Depth and Long-Form Content</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc52786275">Subtopics and Question Mining</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc52786276">Trends and YMYL</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc52786277">Content Comprehensives for SEO: How Should I Get Started?</a></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p>By now, the phrase <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-a-lucrative-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2019-and-beyond/">“content is king”</a> has become a chant in SEO circles. It’s omnipresent, unavoidable, and when it really comes to it, no one knows what it means.</p>
<p>While everyone knows in the abstract that Google <em>rewards </em>high-quality web content and <em>penalizes </em>subpar content, what does that really entail?</p>
<p>How does the algorithm decide between gold and lumps of coal?</p>
<p>To parse all of this systematically, it’s time to talk about content comprehensiveness for SEO!</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc52786271"></a>What is Content Comprehensiveness?</h2>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1665 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/content-comprehensiveness.png" alt="graphic design displaying an individual writing comprehensive web content" width="534" height="356" /></p>
<p>Now it’s unfortunate, but Google’s actually quite coy about what they mean by this term. We have a hunch that it has a lot to do with not revealing how their secret sauce algorithm works. Actually, let’s append an ‘s’ to the end of algorithm.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1666" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Hummingbird.png" alt="Hummingbird" width="624" height="130" /></p>
<p>The one that’s important to this article is Hummingbird. When it launched in 2013, it was hailed as groundbreaking in the way it leveraged machine learning. It allowed pages to rank even if they didn’t contain the <em>exact</em> keyword that people were searching for, focusing instead on the <em>intent </em>of the user.</p>
<p>It also penalized <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnrampton/2017/01/28/seo-keyword-ratio-guide-how-to-not-kill-your-seo/" rel="”nofollow”">keyword stuffing</a> and employed natural language processing capabilities to gain a rudimentary understanding of content quality.</p>
<p>In a nutshell, Google built Hummingbird from the ground up to ensure that all of a user’s needs were satisfied when they search for a keyword. This includes related keywords, how in-depth the content is, and how a site serves other content that users may want.</p>
<p>That being established, how do you go about making sure your content is as comprehensive as possible? We’re glad you asked!</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc52786272"></a>A Complete Guide to Content Comprehensiveness</h2>
<p>Did you see what we did with this title? Not only is it a nifty alliteration, but it’s also a great way to indicate to Google that this guide will give users everything they want.</p>
<p>If we went with “<em>A Guide to Content Comprehensiveness,</em>” it would not only sound generic (and remember, Google <em>loathes </em>generic content), it would also suggest that it’s just a basic guide, or that it doesn’t cover everything a user may need to know.</p>
<p>Remember, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2020/02/27/15-best-practices-for-producing-quality-engaging-content/" rel="”nofollow”">high-quality content</a>, according to Google, covers more than just the one keyword a searcher types in.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc52786273"></a>User Intent</h2>
<p>Let’s use an example to make sense of all this. Let’s say you’re an aspiring academic, looking to write a paper on Postcolonial Studies. Your professor told you that a professor who goes by the name of Edward Said is the who’s who of the field.</p>
<p>When you search his name on Google, a bunch of results show up; in fact, let’s take a look at what does crop up:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1667" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Edward-Said.png" alt="Edward Said" width="606" height="342" /></p>
<p>So, <em>what kind </em>of article did Google serve up?</p>
<p>The first two results are both overviews of who Edward Said is and what his work was on. This is because Google knows that a user who was already familiar with his work would search something more specific.</p>
<p>Don’t buy into almighty Google’s omniscience?</p>
<p>Here’s an example of another query we could have used:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1668" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Edward-Said-imperialism.png" alt="Edward Said imperialism" width="621" height="439" /></p>
<p>The difference here is that we searched for a specific <em>concept </em>that the author has talked about. This indicates to Google that you’re more well versed with his work, and it provides us with both a link to his book and deep dives of him talking on YouTube.</p>
<p>This is what Google calls a <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbescommunicationscouncil/2018/07/06/how-to-leverage-user-intent-for-online-searches-in-your-seo-strategy/" rel="”nofollow”">user’s intent</a>.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc52786274"></a>In-Depth and Long-Form Content</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1669 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/long-form.png" alt="an individual working on long-form content on a laptop" width="535" height="357" /></p>
<p>Now, let’s see what kind of <a href="https://www.lehigh.edu/~amsp/2004/09/introduction-to-edward-said.html" rel="”nofollow”">content the first page</a> provides.</p>
<p>The first thing you’ll notice is that it’s a <em>long </em>article. That’s a great place to start. Don’t be afraid to churn out <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/sachinkamdar/2016/02/29/the-benefits-of-long-form-content/#545fc79dce64" rel="”nofollow”">long-form content</a> when it’s required.</p>
<p>If you cover all the bases in your blog or article, it’ll <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-changing-seo-landscape-how-to-keep-up-with-content-marketing-tactics-in-2018-in-order-to-rank-your-content-high-and-ahead-of-your-competitors-for-your-target-audience/">rank a lot higher</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1670" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/blog-or-article.png" alt="blog or article" width="624" height="130" /></p>
<p>Whether you’re focusing on guest blogging or writing engaging product descriptions, incorporating SEO into your <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-content-marketing.html">content marketing strategy</a> will help your brand stand out from the crowd and climb SERPs.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc52786275"></a>Subtopics and Question Mining</h2>
<p>One of the things the first result Google serves for “<em>postcolonial studies edward said</em>” does is that it covers a broad range of topics a user may want to learn about after learning about this author. It talks about people he was writing in reaction to (Rudyard Kipling, etc.) and other authors that talk about similar themes (Malcolm X, Frantz Fanon, etc.).</p>
<p>To Google, these are useful subtopics that not only make the page sound like an authority on the topic, but also give users a much broader spectrum to work with that will best serve their needs. These subtopics come from having a basic understanding of what questions a user might ask after reading a content piece.</p>
<p>So how are you supposed to predict what are useful subtopics and questions?</p>
<p>By using SEO keyword tools of course!</p>
<p>Two free ones that are very useful are <a href="https://keywordseverywhere.com/" rel="”nofollow”">Keywords Everywhere</a> and <a href="https://answerthepublic.com/" rel="”nofollow”">Answer the Public</a>. Both allow you query-specific keywords you want to be listed for, and provide you with related keywords, questions people who search for those keywords are asking for, as well as which ones you should prioritize based on search volume.</p>
<p>If there are too many keywords, you can even use them as ideas for future content, to make your website a true one-stop for customers. This greatly <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/get-ranked-high-in-2018-detailed-list-of-proven-seo-techniques/">increases rankings</a> as well.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc52786276"></a>Trends and YMYL</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1671 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/trens.png" alt="graphic design illustrating an individual producing high-quality and optimized web content on their laptop" width="450" height="450" /></p>
<p>What else do you need to keep in mind?</p>
<p>Well, there are also trends and YMYL content.</p>
<p>For example, if you’re looking to buy a 4K OLED TV, Google will hold articles that give advice regarding one to a much higher standard. This is because these types of articles actually influence people to spend money.</p>
<p>YMYL stands for “your money, your life,” and Google doesn’t want to serve pages which will cause a customer any kind of financial loss. A good way to get ranked for such pages is to quote actual experts, or get a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/">guest post</a> written by someone who’s an established name in the industry.</p>
<p>Now it’s a known fact that <a href="https://www.tomsguide.com/us/when-best-time-buy-tv,news-27059.html" rel="”nofollow”">TV sales skyrocket during the holiday season</a>. It’s important to write specific content that’s geared toward this trend.</p>
<p>For example, you could feature a post on “The Best 4K OLED TV Deals This Holiday Season.” This topic not only covers 4K OLED TVs, but also keeps the seasonality of buying trends in mind.</p>
<p>To go back to the title of the article, it’s comprehensive!</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc52786277"></a>Content Comprehensives for SEO: How Should I Get Started?</h2>
<p>As one of the leading content marketing agencies across the US, we’re equipped with the resources and expertise to help you kick things off the right way. If you’ve been struggling to create a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-the-ultimate-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2020/">winning content marketing strategy</a>, we’ll take you under our wing and help your business hit the ground running.</p>
<p>Our SEO content writers have extensive experience in producing focused and comprehensive content that keeps readers engrossed while covering all the bases.</p>
<p>Our <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-content-marketing.html">SEO content marketing mix</a> includes high-quality and optimized:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/article-writing/">Articles</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog-writing-services/">Blogs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/guest-blogging/">High DA (Domain Authority) Guest Blogs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/infographics/">Infographics</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/press-release-writing/">Press Releases</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/product-description-writing-services/">Product Descriptions</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/service-page-writing-services/">Service Pages</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/regional-page-writing-services/">Regional Pages</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/video-content-services/">Video Content</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/web-copywriting-services/">Web Copywriting</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Call <a href="tel:8554444777">855-444-4777</a> to get started with content comprehensiveness! We’ll walk you through how content comprehensiveness can help SEO and create a winning strategy.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/content-comprehensiveness-are-you-content-with-your-content/">Content Comprehensiveness for SEO – Are You Content With Your Content?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/content-comprehensiveness-are-you-content-with-your-content/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
