<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Guest Blogging &#8211; Search Berg</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/category/guest-blogging/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 17:12:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>What is a Good Website Domain Authority and How Can You Increase Yours?</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Harper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 11:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Website SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;re reading this blog, chances are, you&#8217;ve come across the term Domain Authority (DA) a couple of times. But what is Domain Authority? What does it mean for your website’s performance? To help you understand the concept and increase the Domain Authority of your website, we’ve created this comprehensive guide. Want to increase your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/">What is a Good Website Domain Authority and How Can You Increase Yours?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;re reading this blog, chances are, you&#8217;ve come across the term <strong>Domain Authority (DA) </strong>a couple of times. But what <em>is </em>Domain Authority? What does it mean for your website’s performance?</p>
<p><span id="more-2574"></span></p>
<p>To help you understand the concept and increase the Domain Authority of your website, we’ve created this comprehensive guide.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Want to increase your Domain Authority? We know how to get you there! Fill out the form to get great results!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2>Table of Contents</h2>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680080">What is Domain Authority?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680081">So, What Is A Good Domain Authority?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680082">How is Domain Authority Calculated?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680083">How to Increase Domain Authority of Your Website?</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680084"> Accept Only High-Quality, Relevant Backlinks</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680085"> Create a Link Building Strategy</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680086"> Guest Post to boost your Domain Authority</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680087"> Build Domain Authority with Content Syndication</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680088"> Create high-value content that fellow bloggers will want to link to</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680089"> Research your competitor&#8217;s strategies and consider writing power blogs</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680090"> Make sure to work on your on-page SEO</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680091">Update older content</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680092">Optimize images</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680093">Optimize meta tags and descriptions </a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680094">Use keywords naturally</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680095">Use both internal and external links</a></p>
<ol start="8">
<li><a href="#_Toc65680096"> Fix up your Technical SEO</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680097"> Social Signals</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680098"> Mobile Friendliness</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680099">Wrapping Up!</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc65680080"></a>What is Domain Authority?</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2589" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-14.png" alt="What is Domain Authority?" width="750" height="544" /></p>
<p>Created by Moz, Domain Authority is a ranking metric—an aggregated number—that indicates how <em>authoritative</em> your website is. The higher your website’s domain authority, the more easily it can rank for your target keywords.</p>
<p>Furthermore, Moz states that a website’s DA is calculated by assessing aspects like linking root domains and the number of total links into a DA score.</p>
<p>DA is scored on a scale of 1–100, with 1 being the lowest performing and 100 being the highest. New websites that have very little to no authority typically start out with a DA of 1. The top websites on the internet, including <u><a href="https://www.apple.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Apple</a></u>, <u><a href="https://www.youtube.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">YouTube</a></u>, and <u><a href="https://www.google.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Google</a>,</u> have DAs of 100.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680081"></a>So, What Is A Good Domain Authority?</h3>
<p>DA below 40 is considered poor; 40–50 is considered average; 51–60 is good; anything above 60 is excellent.</p>
<p>So clearly, scoring high when it comes to Domain Authority should definitely be on your business’s bucket list. But instead of focusing on getting the highest possible DA and competing with giants like Apple and Google, look at your competitors. Your goal should be to develop a higher domain authority than them.</p>
<p>Small businesses, for example, have a relatively lower DA overall, making it easier for competitors to scope out the landscape and improve their authority.</p>
<p>The next logical question is, how <em>do</em> you get high domain authority relative to your competitors?</p>
<p>There are many factors, and in this comprehensive blog, we’ll cover them all in depth.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680082"></a>How is Domain Authority Calculated?</h3>
<p>Domain Authority is calculated using the total number of backlinks you receive, including root domains (among a host of other metrics). It defines the ranking capabilities of an entire website for any page it creates, including but not limited to blog posts.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s important to note that <strong>Domain Authority</strong> is different from <strong>Page Authority (PA)</strong>. So what is Page Authority? While PA measures the ranking strength and capabilities of a single web page on a website, DA showcases the strength of the <em>entire website</em>, indicating the likelihood of a web page ranking when you create one. While different, PA largely depends on Domain Authority because they ultimately rely on the same factors.</p>
<p>So without further ado, let&#8217;s get to our comprehensive ways to increase your site&#8217;s Domain Authority.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc65680083"></a>How to Increase Domain Authority of Your Website?</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680084"></a>1. Accept Only High-Quality, Relevant Backlinks</h3>
<p>Your backlinks are arguably the most important factor in improving your Domain Authority score.</p>
<p>Backlinks are created when other websites hyperlink to your website. These links can send traffic to your websites, improve rankings, and increase your Domain Authority.</p>
<p>To better understand backlinks, check out our YouTube video <u><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GwiI6V1eyQg" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">What is Backlinking And Why is it Important for YOUR Business</a></u>.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GwiI6V1eyQg" width="730" height="411" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So your goal with backlinks is to make sure that they’re all high-quality and relevant to your site. Luckily, you can remove irrelevant, spammy backlinks that will harm your domain authority in the long run using the <u><a href="https://search.google.com/search-console/disavow-links?utm_source=wmx&amp;utm_medium=deprecation-pane&amp;utm_content=disavow-links-main" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Disavow tool</a></u>, courtesy of Google.</p>
<p>Way over your head? You can get in touch with a professional SEO company that can run a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/backlink-audit/">backlink audit</a> for you to take care of that.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2588" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-13.png" alt="screenshot of Disavow tool from Google for backlinks which helps improve website Domain Authority by removing irrelevant, low-quality links" width="1075" height="538" /></p>
<p>If only high-quality, relevant websites are able to link to your website, Google’s bots are more likely to trust your website’s domain authority. The industry-standard rule is that do-follow links are better than no-follow links. This is because do-follow links transfer greater &#8220;SEO juice&#8221; from the linking site to yours compared to no-follow links.</p>
<p>No follow links aren&#8217;t bad to have by any means—you just want to try to target more do-follow links because they’ll give you more SEO bang for your buck. Once you audit your current links and regularly remove the “trash” links, so to speak, you can focus on building more high-quality, relevant backlinks.</p>
<p><em><strong>Pro tip </strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>If you’re running a small business, submit your site for local roundups. These include “best XYZ” lists and/or directories that accept submissions. These are easy backlinks for you to grab for your business.</strong></em></p>
<p>Another hack is to collaborate with local businesses that have a similar customer demographic as you. In this way, you can build mutually beneficial links that are relevant to your mutual customers. You can even work with small businesses that you already have a professional relationship with whose customer demographics would be interested in your product or service. There are more ways to build high-quality links, though.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>We’ve helped hundreds of businesses increase their Domain Authority. Become one of them today!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680085"></a>2. Create a Link Building Strategy</h3>
<p>Now that you know you want to maintain only high quality, high authority links and are well aware of how to disavow unwanted links, you need a strategy to build wanted links.</p>
<p>The first most important building block to any great promotion strategy is having something of note or value to say in your industry. The second is to promote this content using every marketing channel at your disposal.</p>
<p>So once you&#8217;ve created in-depth blogs (we will get into details about <strong><em>how </em></strong>to create linkable content in a future point), send it to your email list and promote it on your social media channels. Don&#8217;t underestimate organic reach even if you don&#8217;t have a sizable following yet. Use hashtags that are relevant to your industry and content to get more eyeballs on your content.</p>
<p>The next step once you&#8217;ve squared away what you can do on your own is to reach out to the big boys. Or, at least, the <em>bigger </em>boys in your industry. As long as their website has a similar or greater authority as yours, you should contact them for a backlink. You want to be subtle as opposed to making demands when you contact them. Make sure you do your research regarding their brand beforehand. If the person&#8217;s audience isn&#8217;t relevant to yours, then there&#8217;s no point reaching out.</p>
<p>Express gratitude for the content they publish. Here, it can help to link to a specific blog that resonated with you, one that is similar in topic to the content you are seeking to build a link with. You can then say in your email or message that you also wrote a new blog about *insert similar topic interest* and that you thought they might enjoy it as someone who writes about said topic/s.</p>
<p>You can end your email or message by saying that your blog/guide/article/etc. might make a helpful addition to their page. End the message on a positive note and send it off. If they like your content and think it would help their audience to read it, they will happily link to it. Many will accept, a lot will say no, and some won&#8217;t even respond. That is part of the game of link building.</p>
<p>Another key way to proactively build links is to strategically guest post.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680086"></a>3. Guest Post to boost your Domain Authority</h3>
<p>Guest posting is when you write a piece that is to be published on a third party website instead of your own. A guest post is many times more efficient and effective at boosting your current DA score than only creating content on your native website is.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2587" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-12.png" alt="screenshot of example guest post page for the photography niche" width="1195" height="891" /></p>
<p>With guest posting, you will have many opportunities to link your website in your content or Author Bio yourself. Studies have shown that people are more likely to click on links within a blog while they are still gaining information rather than afterwards, once they have captured said information.</p>
<p>Both ways, however, provide a high quality backlink to your website from a reputable, high DA site that is sure to also boost your own DA. This is important because these links will be on high authority websites that you&#8217;ve found in your niche, showing Google that you are a thought leader in your industry.</p>
<p>In addition, since the new people that will read your post are already interested in your niche, this further improves the chances of them coming to your blog and linking back to <em>your</em> posts.</p>
<p>You can find guest posting websites by searching &#8220;*insert niche* guest posting websites&#8221; on Google.<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2586" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-11.png" alt="Screenshot of Google search to find relevant guest posting sites" width="1042" height="696" /></p>
<p>Yet another way is to locate them using key phrases such as &#8220;write for us&#8221;, &#8220;submit a post&#8221;, &#8220;submit a blog&#8221;, etc.</p>
<p>A final note on guest posts is to make sure that the links being provided to you are &#8220;<strong><em>do follow</em></strong>&#8221; and not &#8220;<em>no follow</em>&#8220;. <u>A do follow link will help your rankings directly</u> by communicating the link to search engines, while a no follow link will not communicate this.</p>
<p><em><strong>Pro Tip</strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>Since guest posting is a time intensive process, don&#8217;t mass produce content to be guest posted everywhere; instead, be more strategic about which websites will give you the biggest bang for your buck.</strong></em></p>
<p>While this information about no follow backlinks can persuade you to avoid no follow links altogether, chances are, you will get them at some point. There&#8217;s no need to remove them as long as they are from a relevant website in your niche.</p>
<p>They still provide referral traffic (which influences your rankings), brand awareness, and greater social media shares and engagement. So while no follow links may not directly impact your rankings and DA, they do indirectly help so there’s no harm to keep relevant no follow links as part of your website&#8217;s backlink portfolio.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680087"></a>4. Build Domain Authority with Content Syndication</h3>
<p>Content syndication is when you publish a singular piece of content on <em>multiple websites</em>. Note that this is separate from guest posting because, instead of creating entirely new content on a website, you are instead reposting it by giving the third party website permission to do so.</p>
<p>You can do this on your own using blog posting websites like <a href="http://www.linkedin.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a> and <a href="http://www.medium.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Medium</a>, and even forum websites such as <a href="https://www.quora.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Quora</a> and <a href="http://www.reddit.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Reddit.</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2585" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-10.png" alt="screenshot of LinkedIn blogs site where content can be reposted and linked back to your website to improve your backlinks and hence, Domain Authority" width="1146" height="890" /></p>
<p>You can also reach out to websites that will republish with your permission. To find these, search &#8220;republish with permission&#8221; and add the topic you are covering in your piece or even your niche as a whole so you can explore.</p>
<p>When you do find these web sources where you can republish with permission, you want to reach out to them communicating the value their site will receive through republishing your specific content piece.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680088"></a>5. Create high-value content that fellow bloggers will want to link to</h3>
<p>There’s a reason we keep saying that <em><u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/why-content-driven-seo-is-a-lucrative-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2019-and-beyond/">Content is King</a>. </u></em>That’s because it truly is, fit with a bombastic gold crown and silver scepter.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2584" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-9.png" alt="A content marketer is typing on their laptop writing high-quality content to improve their website’s SEO and Domain AuthorityA content marketer is typing on their laptop writing high-quality content to improve their website’s SEO and Domain Authority" width="962" height="642" /></p>
<p>The truth is, you can follow every single SEO advice and tactic in the proverbial book, but, ultimately, having good SEO clears the path for a site visitor to come to your content. So if your content isn’t helpful, engaging, or even interesting, you’re going to get stuck with a high bounce rate and very minimal to <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2020/03/04/the-secret-to-high-search-engine-rankings-quality-content/?sh=2b42b5b070c5" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">no conversions</a></u>.</p>
<p>People are searching for answers to their pain-points and concerns on the internet. If you’re the one to be able to provide them with answers in a way that makes sense to them, they’ll be grateful and are more likely to remember your site as a future resource.</p>
<p>Good content is helpful to build trust with your prospect. Trust leads to higher site visits, lower bounce rates, greater dwell time, and greater conversions. Yet another awesome benefit of creating high-quality content, though, is that authoritative blogs within your niche will also find it valuable.</p>
<p>Because your blog explains, teaches, or provides some sort of resource to them in an easily digestible manner, they’ll be incentivized to link back to your blog as a citation in one of their pieces. Therefore, your go-to strategy to increase your DA should be to regularly release high-value content for your niche.</p>
<p><em><strong><u>Pro Tip</u></strong></em></p>
<p><em>Provide valuable content that you can use is to create media-rich content such as infographics, graphs, and charts that break down complex topics in your niche into a simple picture.</em></p>
<p>One final tip we will impart here for content is if you&#8217;re wondering what kind of content to create that fills a gap, you might want to check out the content your competitors are creating and figure out what&#8217;s missing. Therein lies your opportunity.</p>
<p>To learn more about writing great content, be sure to check out our blog: <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-to-write-a-blog-that-ranks/">How To Write A Blog That Ranks</a></u>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680089"></a>6. Research your competitor&#8217;s strategies and consider writing power blogs</h3>
<p>If you do your research thoroughly, you&#8217;ll discover the keywords your competitors are targeting. Based on this, you’ll know what’s missing in your content marketing strategy <em>and </em>what you need to beat in order to rank.</p>
<p>Check what kind of sites are already linking to their web page. Are you able to build a Franken-blog that is the MOST comprehensive one out of all these competitors? This kind of blog, also known as a power blog, can be highly sought after by readers because it is a one-stop shop for everything they need to know about a topic. A power blog in this way can help your blog stand out.</p>
<p>If you still need convincing here, be sure to read our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-reasons-why-you-need-power-blog-posts-for-your-website-blog/">5 Reasons Why You Need Power Blog PostsFor Your Website Blog</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680090"></a>7. Make sure to work on your on-page SEO</h3>
<p>In addition to your off-page SEO, which includes setting up backlinks, it’s also important to work on your <em>on-page SEO </em>to increase your domain authority.</p>
<h4><a name="_Toc65680091"></a>Update older content</h4>
<p>The most important factor in your on-page SEO is to make sure your content is up to date and relevant to today’s audiences. If your blog has lost relevance, it will result in an increased bounce rate, which ultimately affects your overall SEO efforts, rankings, and domain authority.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2583" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-8.png" alt="A screenshot of a recent Search Berg blog updated for relevancy in 2021" width="699" height="337" /></p>
<h4><a name="_Toc65680092"></a>Optimize images</h4>
<p>A feature not enough people with websites are aware of is that you can actually add more text at the back-end of every image on your website.</p>
<p>You can do this by updating the image’s file name and the associated Alt Text. The point of these fields is to show the text to the viewer about what’s happening in the image in case it doesn’t load, or your visitor is visually impaired. You can simply describe what your image contains and, where relevant, insert your target keywords in the Alt text.</p>
<h4><a name="_Toc65680093"></a>Optimize meta tags and descriptions</h4>
<p>Each page on your website will have a section in the HTML region to optimize your meta tags and descriptions.<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2582" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-7.png" alt="Meta tags and descriptions shown in search results, which, when optimized, improve website Domain Authority and SEO" width="952" height="656" /></p>
<p>In a nutshell, these are the titles and descriptions that appear on Google when you search a term.</p>
<p>So if you leave your meta tags and descriptions up to chance, Google will phrase them at random. Since this is the equivalent of your store’s front sign, i.e., the first thing any of your prospects from Google search results will see, it’s worth optimizing for keywords and readability.</p>
<p>To discover more detailed tactics on tackling meta tags and descriptions, you can learn it all in our blog <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-meta-tags-affect-your-websites-seo/">How Meta Tags Affect Your Website’s SEO</a></u>.</p>
<h4><a name="_Toc65680094"></a>Use keywords naturally</h4>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2581" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-6.png" alt="Visual demonstration of web SEO and Domain Authority" width="750" height="544" /></p>
<p>The number one practice that you want to avoid like the plague is keyword stuffing. Keyword stuffing is essentially when a keyword is “stuffed” into a site’s meta data, backlinks, web pages, etc., in an attempt to game the system and unfairly rank higher.</p>
<p>This may have worked very briefly a long, long time ago, but since <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnrampton/2017/01/28/seo-keyword-ratio-guide-how-to-not-kill-your-seo/?sh=5bef0bcd599a" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">the Hummingbird Update</a>, Google and its robots which crawl your website have gotten very smart. Not only do they catch on if your website includes keyword stuffing, but they also penalize your website by rapidly reducing its rankings. So the best policy is to play the game by Google’s rules and win. This means using your target keywords naturally where they are relevant in your blog and web content.</p>
<p>The more you place your keywords based on relevancy, the greater its readability becomes, and therefore, the longer your reader is likely to stay engaged.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680095"></a>Use both internal and external links</h3>
<p>Internal links are important because they create a web of interconnected pages on your website through links. The more coiled and well-connected the <em>web</em> is, the better Google’s <em>Spiders </em>can crawl it.</p>
<p>Who doesn’t love a good spider pun?</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2580" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-5.png" alt="A spider web is shown with a spider crawling it to illustrate that increasing internal links help Google's spiders crawl your website more easily, improving your domain authority." width="962" height="642" /></p>
<p>Internal links build a high-quality network between your web pages the Spiders can index on Google.</p>
<p>Building internal links also helps you &#8220;pass on&#8221; some of the authority you&#8217;ve gained from a reputable page to other specific web pages on your site for which your goal is to rank.</p>
<p>External links help when they are relevant because it shows you are linking to note-worthy blogs and websites related to your topics. The idea is: if you’re commenting about relevant topics within your niche, then your commentary must by proxy also be somewhat relevant.</p>
<p>For further on-page SEO tips to keep your visitor on your website longer, you can check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-to-improve-website-bounce-rate/">10 Proven Tips to Drastically Reduce Website Bounce Rate</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680096"></a>8. Fix up your Technical SEO</h3>
<p>Your technical SEO is the foundation upon which your rankings, domain authority, and everything you&#8217;re doing for your website, stand on. You need to have your website registered on Google Search Console. Once you&#8217;ve registered, submit a file known as the &#8220;xml sitemap&#8221; of your website to Google Search Console.</p>
<p>This is the equivalent of giving Google a &#8220;cheat sheet&#8221; map to send its crawlers through your website. You want these crawlers all over your website because once they are, they can index your web pages.</p>
<p>Indexing your pages means that they become part of the Google Search results. Once you&#8217;ve completed these steps, you can actually test your pages for crawlability.</p>
<p>This can be done using the Fetch tool within Google Search Console. The <a href="https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2011/08/submit-urls-to-google-with-fetch-as" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Fetch as Google bot</a> feature in your Google Search Console dashboard allows you to submit new and updated URLs to Google for sped-up indexing and to check whether your site pages can be crawled by Google&#8217;s bots.</p>
<p>To check the status of existing pages that you&#8217;ve already been in the process of indexing, you can use Google&#8217;s <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/9012289" rel="nofollow">URL Inspection Tool</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2579" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-4.png" alt="A screenshot of a Google tool to help with technical SEO and heighten domain authority" width="962" height="395" /></p>
<p>Crawlability problems, in particular, are frustrating because they mean that even if all the right elements on your website are in place, you are still missing out on some SEO juice that can impact your domain authority score.</p>
<p>Thus, it&#8217;s important to regularly audit your website for crawlability problems including problematic redirects, links that don&#8217;t work, 404 pages, irrelevant or outdated content links, etc.</p>
<p>Another major focus area to improve your DA should be social signals.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680097"></a>9. Social Signals</h3>
<p>Social signals are social media engagements and shares. They’re important because they indicate to Google that your content is creating buzz and is relevant within your niche.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2578" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-3.png" alt="Worldwide social media penetration statistics to demonstrate its importance in the world today and how it can be instrumental in bettering a website's Domain Authority" width="958" height="651" /></p>
<p>While Google has maintained that Social Signals are not an official ranking factor, there’s a huge correlation between pages that rank well and their social media presences. High-ranking pages have great social media presence and engagement metrics.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2577" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-2.png" alt="Screenshot of Searchberg Facebook page" width="1153" height="897" /></p>
<p>This means building your brand and/or small business&#8217;s presence on social media is an integral step to take if you want to secure a high Domain Authority.</p>
<p>Whether you start with <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-to-get-more-followers-on-linkedin/">LinkedIn</a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/top-10-ways-to-grow-a-small-business-through-facebook/">Facebook</a>, or <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-to-unleash-the-power-of-instagram-to-promote-your-brand/">Instagram</a>, the key is to build your brand and engage with your customers in a meaningful way. Take the key principles from our content section in this blog and apply them here. You want to provide value, and on social media, this can be as simple as bringing positivity to someone&#8217;s newsfeed.</p>
<p>To learn more in-depth strategies for each social media platform stated previously, be sure to check out the links above. To binge-learn how to create high-quality social media content for your business and improve your engagement, here’s a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/category/social-media-management/">list</a> of our social media marketing blogs for businesses to help you out.</p>
<p>Specifically to improve your SEO and therefore, DA, we suggest reading our blog Social Media and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-and-seo-how-to-use-social-media-to-improve-seo-rankings/">SEO: How to Use Social Media to Improve SEO Rankings</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680098"></a>10. Mobile Friendliness</h3>
<p>Making sure your website is mobile friendly is important for three key reasons:</p>
<ol>
<li>Mobile friendly sites are easier to use, providing a more high quality user experience</li>
<li>They are looked upon more favorably by Google&#8217;s ranking system</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Thus, they are more likely to secure backlinks, so it&#8217;s a key way to improve your site&#8217;s Domain Authority.</li>
</ul>
<p>Since <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/groupthink/2015/05/15/can-your-business-survive-googles-mobile-geddon/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Mobilegeddon</a> in 2015, Google has cracked down on websites which are not friendly to use on a mobile device or smartphone and rewards those sites that are.</p>
<p>So if a website is easy to use on a smartphone or a tablet, then Google notices and ranks that site higher in the search results for the site&#8217;s target keywords.</p>
<p>If it&#8217;s not, however, then the algorithm punishes the site by reducing its rankings and pushing its web pages lower in search results.</p>
<p>You can easily measure your website&#8217;s mobile friendliness capabilities using the Google <a href="https://search.google.com/test/mobile-friendly" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Mobile Friendly Test Tool.</a><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2576" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-1.png" alt="screen shot of mobile friendly test tool through Google to help improve mobile friendliness and increase Domain Authority" width="1188" height="875" /></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc65680099"></a>Wrapping Up!</h2>
<p>In this blog, we dove into the deep end to learn all about website DA and how to increase domain authority.</p>
<p>While many of these tips can easily be performed by an everyday Joe who is just learning about domain authority and discovering the world of SEO, it will definitely speed things up and prevent errors if you consult with professionals who have been in the game for a long time.</p>
<p>We, at <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/">Search Berg</a>, can help you <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/high-domain-authority/">increase your website&#8217;s domain authority today</a>. Call us at <a href="tel:855-444-4777">855-444-4777</a> to kick-start your domain authority score and SEO rankings or fill out the form below!</li>
</ol>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/">What is a Good Website Domain Authority and How Can You Increase Yours?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Guest Blogging and How to Get Started with it?</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-guest-blogging-and-why-is-it-important-for-seo/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-guest-blogging-and-why-is-it-important-for-seo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Harper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 15:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Blogging]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contents What Is Guest Blogging? And Why Is Guest Blogging Important for SEO? How to Get Started With Guest Blogging Identify Your Guest Blogging Goals Look for High-Quality Guest Blogging Prospects Google Search Strings Competitor Backlinks Social Media Focus on Relevant Guest Posting Websites Pitch A Guest Post Effectively Do your research Know When to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-guest-blogging-and-why-is-it-important-for-seo/">What is Guest Blogging and How to Get Started with it?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Contents</h2>
<p><a href="#_Toc55839660">What Is Guest Blogging? And Why Is Guest Blogging Important for SEO?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc55839661">How to Get Started With Guest Blogging</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc55839662"> Identify Your Guest Blogging Goals</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc55839663"> Look for High-Quality Guest Blogging Prospects</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#_Toc55839664">Google Search Strings</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc55839665">Competitor Backlinks</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc55839666">Social Media</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#_Toc55839667"> Focus on Relevant Guest Posting Websites</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc55839668"> Pitch A Guest Post Effectively</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#_Toc55839669">Do your research</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc55839670">Know When to Pitch</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#_Toc55839671"> Write a Winning Guest Blog That Checks Off All the Boxes!</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc55839672"> Promote Your Guest Blog Like a Pro</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc55839673"> Track, Track, Track!</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc55839674"> Start Planning Your Next Guest Blogging Campaign</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc55839675">Final Thoughts on Guest Blogging</a></p>
<p>We’ve <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-a-blog-that-ranks/">talked about</a> how consistent blogging can help you build credibility and ranking. In this blog, we want to talk about <em>another </em>content marketing strategy that’s pretty much become a buzz word in 2020: <strong>guest blogging.</strong></p>
<p>If quality traffic and powerful backlinks is your SEO goal, then you need to start talking about <strong>guest blogging</strong> or <strong>guest posting</strong>.</p>
<p>Let’s cut to the chase.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc55839660"></a>What Is Guest Blogging? And Why Is Guest Blogging Important for SEO?</h2>
<p>Guest blogging is the process of writing content for <em>other websites</em>. The blog is published under your business name or your own name on a third-party website.</p>
<p>For the most part, they’re free of cost. So what’s the catch? A lot of websites allow guest posts because they provide <em>insider expertise and analysis</em> to their readers. And <em>because</em> of that, keep in mind—and we cannot stress this enough—guest posts <em>cannot </em>be promotional!</p>
<p>Guest blogging isn’t just another run-of-the-mill content marketing strategy; it’s designed to help your business get a wellness shot that’s <em>packed</em> with visibility potion, ranking tonic, and lead generation elixir.</p>
<p>In short, <u>it’s a revival kit for your business</u>.</p>
<p>Here’s a closer look at why guest blogging is touted as the crème de la crème of modern content marketing strategies:</p>
<ul>
<li>Guest blogging generates 3x more leads close to conversion</li>
<li>Guest blogging boosts direct sales by 75%</li>
<li>Guest blogging generates 5x more valuable backlinks, resulting in better rankings</li>
<li>Guest blogging generates 80% increase in organic and referral traffic</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2306" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/blog2-1.png" alt="Statistics showing why Guest Blogging is important in SEO" width="801" height="293" /></p>
<p>Creating winning content for websites with high domain authority (i.e., great ranking capabilities) is a <em>surefire</em> way to become more visible on the web.</p>
<p>Think about it; you’re probably familiar with websites like <a href="https://medium.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">Medium</a> and <a href="https://www.forbes.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">Forbes</a>. Why?</p>
<p>Because they continually show up among the top search results for just about any search.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2307" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/blog2-2.png" alt="DA1" width="391" height="177" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2308" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/blog3.png" alt="DA2" width="397" height="184" /></p>
<p>These websites are comfortably and firmly seated on the ranking throne because of their impressive DA.</p>
<p>Instead of solely writing blogs for your website and generating fair-to-middling traffic, writing blogs for high-DA websites is a great way to <u>get your content seen by more people</u>.</p>
<p>In this guide, we’ll walk you through the basics of guest blogging so you can create a winning strategy that helps you hit the ground running. We’ll also look at some additional <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/">benefits of guest blogging</a> along the way, so you know exactly what’s in store for you.</p>
<p>Let’s dive in!</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc55839661"></a>How to Get Started With Guest Blogging</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc55839662"></a>1. Identify Your Guest Blogging Goals</h3>
<p>One of the best ways to get started with guest blogging is knowing exactly where you stand.</p>
<p>Typically, it could be one or a combination of the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>You want to increase visibility for your products/services</li>
<li>You want to position yourself as an authoritative voice in your industry</li>
<li>You’re looking to generate backlink opportunities</li>
</ul>
<p>Analyze your business model and performance over the past few months/years. This will help you list clear guest blogging goals and create a strategy that focuses on achieving them.</p>
<p>Make sure you get <em><u>as specific as possible</u></em>. The last thing you want is to execute a guest blogging strategy that simply isn’t right for your business.</p>
<p>If you’re unsure about how to set guest blogging goals, feel free to look into<strong> <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/guest-blogging-services/">professional guest posting services</a>.</strong></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc55839663"></a>2. Look for High-Quality Guest Blogging Prospects</h3>
<p>Once you have a set of well-defined guest blogging goals, you can start looking for the right opportunities for your business.</p>
<p>As a rule of thumb, here are some things to look for when choosing a guest blogging website:</p>
<ul>
<li>High DA</li>
<li>Content that’s relevant to your niche/industry</li>
<li>A wide audience that will be interested in your content and products/services</li>
<li>High-quality blogs with substantial engagement, i.e., likes, comments, shares, etc.</li>
<li>A great reputation (no history of allegations, lawsuits, questionable content, inaccurate claims, etc.)</li>
</ul>
<p>Make sure you’ve already checked your website’s DA in advance.</p>
<p>The score ranges from 0–100; 40–50 is considered <strong>average</strong>, 50–60 is considered <strong>good</strong>, and 60+ is considered <strong>excellent</strong>.</p>
<p>If your DA is less than 40, it goes without saying that you’ll struggle to get a response from websites with exceptional DA.</p>
<div class="pro-tip">
<div class="left">
<h3>Make sure you look for guest blogging</h3>
<p>prospects with a domain rating that doesn’t largely deviate from your score (a difference of 20–30 is acceptable). This will help you get your content approved and gradually improve your DA by generating more backlinks.</p>
</div>
<div class="right"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2328" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/pro-tip.png" alt="" width="133" height="123" /></div>
</div>
<p>Over time, better rankings will equate to an improved domain authority, and you’ll be able to partner with companies like Forbes, Medium, Entrepreneur, Inc.com, Business Insider, and the likes.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s a look at some of the best ways to search for—and actually find—<em>great</em> guest blogging opportunities:</strong></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc55839664"></a>Google Search Strings</h3>
<p>Using customized search strings is easily the most effective way to find the right guest posting prospects for your business.</p>
<p>Enter these search queries on Google (use relevant keywords for your industry):</p>
<ul>
<li>[enter keyword] “guest blog”</li>
<li>[enter keyword] “guest post”</li>
<li>[enter keyword] “submit a guest blog”</li>
<li>[enter keyword] “write for us”</li>
<li>[enter keyword] “contribute to our site”</li>
<li>[enter keyword] “accepting guest blogs”</li>
<li>[enter keyword] “guest blog opportunities”</li>
<li>[enter keyword] “guest blog guidelines”</li>
</ul>
<p>You’ll receive highly-specific, relevant results. Browse through the guest blogs, guidelines, and submission pages to shortlist websites accordingly.</p>
<p>Here’s an example of how you should go about this if you run a financial advising business:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2310" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/blog2-4.png" alt="Submit a guest post" width="714" height="443" /></p>
<p>You can also refine your search by selecting a specific time period for more relevant results. Stick to the past month or past year to find fresh guest blogging opportunities.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2311" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/blog2-5.png" alt="Submit a guest post2" width="716" height="439" /></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc55839665"></a>Competitor Backlinks</h3>
<p>Run a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/backlink-audit/">backlink analysis/audit</a> of your top competitors to receive comprehensive data about their link building partners.</p>
<ul>
<li>Which websites are offering them backlinks?</li>
<li>Do these sites have high DA?</li>
<li>How frequently are the backlinks offered?</li>
</ul>
<p>These insights will not only help you identify great guest blogging sites in your industry, but you’ll also manage to pick up on link building strategies and patterns that help you start off on the right foot.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc55839666"></a>Social Media</h3>
<p>When it comes to exploring opportune guest blogging prospects, social media <em>works wonders</em>.</p>
<p>The large majority of companies promote their guest blogs on popular social media platforms like <strong>Facebook</strong> and <strong>Twitter</strong>. Scouring these platforms for guest posts will help you identify great opportunities and promptly reach out to the relevant professionals.</p>
<p>Follow the same search strategy we mentioned earlier; type in an industry-relevant keyword and follow that up with “guest blog,” “write for us,” “submit a guest blog,” and so forth.</p>
<p>Here’s an example:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Surviving on a rapidly warming <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/1f30d.png" alt="🌍" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> is one of the top economic &amp; social challenges facing us today. Yet as <a href="https://twitter.com/SEforALLorg?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@SEforALLorg</a> research shows, providing <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CoolingforAll?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#CoolingforAll</a> risks a spike in energy demand</p>
<p>New SEforALL guest blog explores passive solutions to help: <a href="https://t.co/PR4TJq1sN8" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://t.co/PR4TJq1sN8</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SDG7?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SDG7</a> <a href="https://t.co/9CjeneTgFj" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/9CjeneTgFj</a></p>
<p>— Damilola Ogunbiyi (@DamilolaSDG7) <a href="https://twitter.com/DamilolaSDG7/status/1323665164202332160?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">November 3, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2312" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/blog2-6.png" alt="guestblogger" width="591" height="642" /></p>
<p>As always, feel free to specify your search requirements by using the search filters or opting for an advanced search. This will help you fetch results in your city/state and look for posts with high levels of engagement (e.g., a minimum number of replies, likes, and retweets). You can also select a certain time period and emphasize specific keywords.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style1">
<div class="inner">
<h3>Struggling to find high-quality guest blogging sites for your industry?</h3>
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/contact-us/">Request a free proposal and get started!</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<h3><a name="_Toc55839667"></a>3. Focus on Relevant Guest Posting Websites</h3>
<p>Sure, you can opt for non-specific websites with all-encompassing content; in fact, that’s recommended. However, make sure you don’t start relying on these sites too much.</p>
<p>Opt for a <strong><u>50:50 ratio</u></strong>, i.e., 50% of your guest blogging partners should be non-specific sites (e.g., Forbes, Medium), whereas the remaining 50% should be industry-specific sites.</p>
<p>For instance, if you run a travel and tourism business, partner with <a href="https://www.goabroad.com/careers" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">Go Abroad</a> (DA = 76), <a href="https://www.hostelbookers.com/blog/travel/write-for-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">Hostel Bookers</a> (DA = 75), <a href="https://www.edreams.com/blog/write-for-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">eDreams</a> (DA = 70), and the likes.</p>
<p>If you offer health services, partner with sites like <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/intl/writers-guidelines" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">Psychology Today</a> (DA = 92).</p>
<p>If you run a restaurant, look into sites like <a href="https://www.thekitchn.com/about/submissions" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">Kitchn</a> (DA = 87) and <a href="https://www.onegreenplanet.org/write-for-us-2/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">One Green Planet</a> (DA = 80).</p>
<p>We’re sure you get the gist by now.</p>
<p>Establishing industry-specific guest blogging partners is a great way to get more leads since the content is right up the audience’s alley.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc55839668"></a>4. Pitch A Guest Post Effectively</h3>
<p>While you may feel tempted to make a pitch then and there, take things slow. Keep these pointers in mind!</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc55839669"></a>Do your research</h3>
<p>Head over to the guest blogging site and familiarize yourself with their brand philosophy, story, mission, and values. This bit of research will come in handy when you’re making a pitch.</p>
<p>In addition, closely examine their content.</p>
<p><em>Do you like the style, tone, and level of research?</em></p>
<p><em>Can you see your content fitting in?</em></p>
<p>This is a two-way street; not only are <strong><u>you</u></strong> learning more about them, but you’re also gauging whether <strong><u>they’re</u></strong> right for you.</p>
<p>Once you’ve gotten a general gist of their brand identity and content, look for their guest blogging guidelines to ensure you <u>make an informed pitch</u>. The last thing you want to do is ask a plethora of questions that are already clearly specified on their guest blogging guidelines page.</p>
<p>Make a great first impression; do your research and make sure it reflects in the way you approach them.</p>
<p>In some cases, certain sites only accept completed guest blogs and want nothing to do with pitches. This is more common among sites with high DA.</p>
<p>Ultimately, the more research you do, the better the outcome. You’ll avoid getting entangled in embarrassing faux pas and ruining your chances of getting approved.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc55839670"></a>Know When to Pitch</h3>
<p>Here are your cues:</p>
<ul>
<li>The website openly advertises that they accept guest posts</li>
<li>The website has listed your business in one of their blogs</li>
<li>The website consistently posts guest blogs</li>
<li>The platform is a credible source in the community/industry</li>
<li>Some of your more successful competitors are posting there</li>
</ul>
<div class="blog-cta style2">
<div class="inner">
<h3>Want more traffic on your website?</h3>
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/guest-blogging/">Get started with Guest Blogging now!</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc55839671"></a>5. Write a Winning Guest Blog That Checks Off All the Boxes!</h2>
<p>Ah, the <em>fun</em> part.</p>
<p>Or the <em>daunting</em> part, depending on how equipped you are to write a guest blog.</p>
<p>With the competition becoming more fierce every day, pulling out all the stops has become imperative.</p>
<p>Today, the large majority of guest blogging companies hire experts to get the job done to a tee.</p>
<p>While you may feel compelled to take care of things yourself, it’s important to note that writing a guest blog isn’t a walk in the park; it requires:</p>
<ul>
<li>Extensive experience</li>
<li>Meticulous research skills</li>
<li>Industry insights</li>
<li>Strong language, grammar, syntax, punctuation, and spelling skills</li>
<li>The ability to write engaging content that draws the reader in from the get-go</li>
</ul>
<p>Start by getting in touch with guest blogging professionals who are adept at writing gripping, industry-specific, and well-researched guest posts.</p>
<p>The overall quality of the blog will go a long way in keeping readers engrossed till the very end and generating more leads.</p>
<p>Since guest blogs can’t be too promotional in nature, they don’t include more than 1–3 backlinks. While you can use more internal links in your own blogs, you can’t do the same with guest blogs.</p>
<p>In most cases, guest blogs only include a single backlink in the “About the Author” section towards the end of the content. So if readers don’t stick around till the very end, your content may not yield the intended results.</p>
<p><em>What are we getting at?</em></p>
<p><strong><u>Complete engagement </u></strong>is essential, and you can’t achieve it without turning to the pros who know the ins and outs of creating page-turning content.</p>
<p>Expert guest blogging writers are adept at writing stellar author descriptions, using opportune backlinks, demonstrating industry-specific expertise, and meeting the hosting website’s requirements.</p>
<p>They also use guest blogging SEO strategies to ensure the content ranks higher on SERPs and helps you generate massive traffic that results in skyrocketing sales.</p>
<div class="pro-tip">
<div class="left">
<h3>Make sure you have</h3>
<p>realistic expectations when planning your first guest blog. It may take a couple of guest blogs to see great results.</p>
</div>
<div class="right"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2329" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/pro-tip2.png" alt="" width="134" height="151" /></div>
</div>
<p>As you partner with more high-DA websites and continue to write multiple guest posts each month (or at least every other month), you’ll notice a significant improvement in web traffic.</p>
<p>Recommended Read: <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-a-blog-that-ranks/">How To Write A Blog That Ranks</a></p>
<div class="blog-cta style2">
<div class="inner">
<h3>Stuck with not-so-great rankings?</h3>
<p><a class="btn" href="tel:855-444-4777">Call 855-444-4777</a></p>
<p>to speak with our guest blogging experts!</p>
</div>
</div>
<h3><a name="_Toc55839672"></a>6. Promote Your Guest Blog Like a Pro</h3>
<p>Submitting a terrific guest blog and sitting on it is tantamount to baking a delectable chocolate cake and watching it sit on your counter for days on end.</p>
<p><em>Promote the guest blog like you would devour the cake! </em></p>
<p>We strongly recommend creating a separate guest blog promotion strategy to ensure you don’t leave any stone unturned.</p>
<p>Actively share your blog on <strong>Facebook</strong>, <strong>Twitter</strong>, <strong>Instagram</strong>, <strong>LinkedIn</strong>, and <strong>Pinterest</strong>.</p>
<p>You can also email the blog to customers who have subscribed to your newsletter/emails.</p>
<p>Here are some great examples of how to do justice to promoting your guest blog:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Got a guest spot on the Cionic blog! Check out my thoughts on building remote teams. <a href="https://t.co/QHIUicXy32" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">https://t.co/QHIUicXy32</a></p>
<p>— raycourtney (@raycourtney) <a href="https://twitter.com/raycourtney/status/1323663348026773505?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">November 3, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Remote Work: 6 Ways to Manage Stress While You Work From Home <a href="https://t.co/n0toIA51FT" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">https://t.co/n0toIA51FT</a> Check out my guest blog post!</p>
<p>— Janice Simon (@JaniceSimon) <a href="https://twitter.com/JaniceSimon/status/1324436566077526022?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">November 5, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" style="border: none; overflow: hidden; margin: 0 auto; display: block;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fgeorginasteytler%2Fposts%2F781992109027550&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=513&amp;appId" width="552" height="513" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc55839673"></a>7. Track, Track, Track!</h2>
<p>No matter how great your guest blogging strategy may be, you’ll struggle to ensure long-term growth if you sideline the importance of tracking.</p>
<p>Ultimately, you want your efforts to yield <em>great</em> results. And you can’t gauge where you stand without tracking your site’s performance.</p>
<p>Closely monitor your site’s rankings, impressions, traffic, leads, and sales. As you periodically assess these metrics, you’ll manage to ascertain which guest blogs are performing better than the others. This will help you replicate certain strategies across the board and focus on writing more guest blogs for certain high-DA sites that bring more traffic to your domain.</p>
<p>In addition, identify content needs and gaps to avoid running the risk of rehashing ideas, topics, and themes. Think outside the box and let your creative juices flow!</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc55839674"></a>8. Start Planning Your Next Guest Blogging Campaign</h2>
<p>Guest blogging rests on the foundation of <strong><u>consistency</u></strong>.</p>
<p>Once you’ve successfully written, submitted, and promoted a set of monthly guest blogs, make sure you start planning your upcoming guest blogging campaign.</p>
<p>In fact, kick-start the process while you’re still promoting blogs from the previous campaign! A head start will help you make timely changes based on the negatives and positives of the last campaign.</p>
<p>Be open to making adjustments; <u>your content should grow with your brand</u>.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc55839675"></a>Final Thoughts on Guest Blogging</h2>
<p><em>“What is guest posting in SEO?”</em></p>
<p><em>“What are the basics of guest blogging?”</em></p>
<p><em>“What are the benefits of guest blogging?”</em></p>
<p>If you started reading this blog with those questions in mind, we’re sure we’ve covered a major chunk of it. Keep in mind; guest blogging is no piece of cake. It’s really challenging for businesses to maintain their blog; let alone gust blogging. So feel free to hire blog outreach services.</p>
<p>As one of the most powerful content marketing strategies, guest blogging works wonders for startups, small businesses, ecommerce companies, and established corporations looking to gain an edge.</p>
<p>Create a winning guest blogging strategy, ensure consistency along the way, track your performance, and make the required adjustments!</p>
<p>Ready to get started? Call <a href="tel:855-444-4777">855-444-4777</a> now or fill out the form below to kick-start your <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/guest-blogging-services/">Guest Blogging</a> project today!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-guest-blogging-and-why-is-it-important-for-seo/">What is Guest Blogging and How to Get Started with it?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-guest-blogging-and-why-is-it-important-for-seo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Benefits of Guest Blogging for Small Businesses Owners</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Harper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 09:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Small Business SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1351</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contents Create Brand Awareness &#38; Enhance Online Exposure Educational Content Call to Action Identify Potential Customers and Sales Opportunities Expand Your Email List Create an Environment of Engagement and External Feedback Broaden Your Online Publication Network Use Guest Posting to Boost Your SEO Spread on Social Media Improve Online Authority Generate Qualified Leads Shorten your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/">5 Benefits of Guest Blogging for Small Businesses Owners</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2></h2>
<h2>Contents</h2>
<p><u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/#_Toc51075632">Create Brand Awareness &amp; Enhance Online Exposure</a></u></p>
<p><u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/#_Toc51075633">Educational Content</a></u></p>
<p><u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/#_Toc51075634">Call to Action</a></u></p>
<p><u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/#_Toc51075635">Identify Potential Customers and Sales Opportunities</a></u></p>
<p><u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/#_Toc51075636">Expand Your Email List</a></u></p>
<p><u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/#_Toc51075637">Create an Environment of Engagement and External Feedback</a></u></p>
<p><u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/#_Toc51075638">Broaden Your Online Publication Network</a></u></p>
<p><u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/#_Toc51075639">Use Guest Posting to Boost Your SEO</a></u></p>
<p><u>Spread on Social Media</u></p>
<p><u>Improve Online Authority</u></p>
<p><u>Generate Qualified Leads</u></p>
<p><u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/#_Toc51075632">Shorten your Sales Cycle</a></u></p>
<p>In today’s tech-focused world, virtually all aspects of our lives are intimately connected with the internet. Businesses, both small and large, rely on the internet to reach out to a worldwide audience and market their products/services. In short, digital marketing has become the new norm.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2103" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/blog1.jpg" alt="concept illustration of the process of guest blogging for SEO" width="1000" height="684" /></p>
<p>Creating online blogs is a marketing technique that is popular among many small and large businesses—and this isn’t surprising. It’s an effective and efficient way to establish yourself as an authority in your industry and draw attention to your offerings. In fact, a survey conducted by HubSpot revealed that blogging is the top content marketing priority for 53% of marketers.</p>
<p>But, just like any other type of blog, it can be quite tricky to maintain a small business blog. It takes a lot of effort and a significant amount of research to draw and capture the attention of today’s highly impatient online consumers.</p>
<p>In order to create a successful blog, you need to have a firm understanding of your target audience, develop a robust blogging schedule, create fresh content that interests readers, and design a visually engaging, user-friendly, and interactive website.</p>
<p>The question on many business owner&#8217;s minds is: does Guest Blogging improve or have benefits for SEO?</p>
<p>While building authority by creating and maintaining a blog is all well and good, a small business (or any sized business really) also requires the support of its peers to succeed—and this is where <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/guest-blogging.html">guest blogging for SEO</a></u> comes in.</p>
<p>You see, it’s not difficult to find websites with big audiences that are willing to help you grow your small business. Collaborating with them by publishing quality guest posts on their platform exposes your businesses to a large audience, and ultimately drives traffic to your website.</p>
<p>Here are five reasons why guest blogging is the key that opens the doors to brand development, customer acquisition, and small business growth.</p>
<h2>Expand on Social Media</h2>
<p>You can also grow your brand presence on social media as a result of guest blogging.</p>
<p>This is one of the biggest pros of Guest Blogging for small businesses and bloggers.</p>
<p>Social media shares definitely follow a domino effect once the sharing ball gets rolling on your content.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you are sending your guest post to a website that gets a fair amount of social media shares, it is likely that your post will get a lot of shares as well.</p>
<p>A hack to triple and even quadruple the number of shares you get through social media through a guest post and otherwise is to embed high-value sharable content within your blog.</p>
<p>This can look like a really helpful infographic.</p>
<p>The best kind of infographics are those that break down complex topics and content into easily digestible and understandable graphics or flow charts.</p>
<p>To get you started on your infographic, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2021/01/25/12-effective-ways-to-use-infographics-for-marketing/?sh=7ee681fb6da1" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">here</a> is an awesome guide to help you create yours today.</p>
<p>The great thing about guest posts is that your page will be linked back to and tagged.</p>
<p>Guest blogging can, in this way, increase not only the social media shares of your content but also increase your follower count and your lead generating efforts.</p>
<p>By getting your work published on a blog that has authority, you are essentially upping your own authority as well because they are referring you as a credible source to their audience.</p>
<p>When you get to create your contributing profile, in order to maximize click-throughs to your social media, make sure to link to your accounts in your bio section.</p>
<p>This way, specific readers who take the time to check out your author bio will actually be able to connect with you or your business via social media, making your posts a regular part of their newsfeeds.</p>
<p>Since you now have them on your social feeds, you want to remind them why they followed you.</p>
<p>The way you do this is by regularly posting high caliber, helpful content for them to digest. Not only does this engage the followers you garnered from the guest blog you posted, but it also helps your organic reach on social media.</p>
<p>Content truly is king, so don&#8217;t forget to keep providing value to stay at the forefront of your audience&#8217;s minds.</p>
<h2>Create Brand Awareness &amp; Enhance Online Exposure</h2>
<p>One of the most significant benefits of guest blogging for small business owners is increased online exposure and brand awareness.</p>
<p>Why do these matter?</p>
<p>Well, nobody will spend money on your business if they don’t know it exists, right?</p>
<p>Simply put, guest blogging gets your name out there and thus benefits your small business&#8217;s SEO.</p>
<p>Considering how intensely competitive the digital marketing environment is today, don’t you think it’s ideal to <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-advanced-link-building-tips-and-tricks-to-boost-your-seo/">earn quality backlinks</a></u> and <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-googles-local-3-pack-and-how-can-you-use-it-to-rank/">climb SERPs</a></u>?</p>
<p>Moreover, notable online marketing experts believe that it takes around 5 to 7 impressions before a consumer is able to remember your brand, which means that in order to make the greatest impact, it’s essential to write relevant guest blogs as frequently as possible.</p>
<p>But how exactly does guest blogging <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbescoachescouncil/2019/10/02/13-budget-friendly-methods-for-increasing-brand-awareness/#6ec8d620320d" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">create brand awareness</a></u> and increase exposure for your business? Well, let us explain through an example. Let’s assume that you have the opportunity to publish a guest blog on a site that has 100,000 followers, and 10,000 of them end up reading your blog. Even if the likelihood of getting redirected traffic from this post to your site is low, you still get the chance to introduce your businesses to thousands of potential consumers.</p>
<p>But how do you increase the chances of acquiring redirected traffic? Well, here’s what you need:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1358" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Targeted-Audience-and-Targeted-Keyword.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="250" /></p>
<h2>Improve your niche-wide authority</h2>
<p>There&#8217;s a formula for transforming your guest content efforts into leads for your business.</p>
<p>Good, helpful content + high authority site within your niche = greater authority within your niche = greater trust among potential customers.</p>
<p>This greater trust comforts the followers of your work to convert from prospects to paying customers/clients.</p>
<p>Guest blogging in this way helps your target audience see you as a credible, reliable source of information to help them solve their pain-points.</p>
<p>Therefore, because of this initial trust, they are more open to the value propositions that you present to them.</p>
<p>A hot lead that trusts your authority will always convert faster than a cold one.</p>
<h2>Increase your qualified leads</h2>
<p>A qualified lead is essentially a lead that is further down the sales process.</p>
<p>They have already expressed interest in your value proposition and therefore need less convincing to convert as opposed to someone who is simply browsing.</p>
<p>To get these qualified leads, the key is to find websites to guest post on that already have a regular and reliable flow of traffic as well as relevancy in your niche.</p>
<p>It is unlikely that you will be able to guest post with a direct competitor but try to find a high authority, a well-respected site within your niche as a whole to post on.</p>
<p>When you post your links within your blog, there is a certain art and finesse to making sure people want to click that big call-to-action button, which leads to your website.</p>
<p>Otherwise, it can very well be perceived as a useless waste of space that took up the reader&#8217;s time without a pay-off rather than the highly converting benefit of Guest Blogging that it can be.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, this approach (or lack thereof) can result in very few click-throughs and leads from the guest post.</p>
<p>The key is to create unity between the CTA you post and the actual page that it leads to.</p>
<p>Make sure both of these are related to the overall content of the guest post you are writing.</p>
<p>This <strong>actionable step</strong> should read in the prospect&#8217;s mind as a <strong>reasonable next step from the guest blog</strong> they just read in order to solve their pain-point.</p>
<p>Use This Content Marketing Opportunity to Shorten Your Sales Cycle</p>
<p>The key here is that rather than waiting for potential customers to show up on your website, you get to help them discover your unique value proposition on a trusted third-party website.</p>
<p>In this way, you get to shorten your sales process for your services and products.</p>
<p>To capitalize on the match between your value proposition and the topic you write about, you need to be very strategic about what you blog about.</p>
<p>Think of yourself as a guest blogging ninja who is there to strike specific key pain-points that are relevant to the solutions you provide (i.e., your services and products).</p>
<h2>Educational Content</h2>
<p>Ensure that the content of your guest blog is <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2019/08/23/how-educational-content-can-lead-to-more-business/#1db341d92617" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">engaging and educational</a></u>.</p>
<p>Discuss trends and insights to become an authoritative voice in the industry and increase your chances of persuading readers to visit your website.</p>
<p>The reason that educational content performs so well is that bridging people&#8217;s gaps in their knowledge helps them to solve problems and understand their pain-points better so that they can tackle them more effectively.</p>
<p>Good educational content provides value.</p>
<p>Engaging and good educational content provides value and builds engagement.</p>
<p>Try to be the professor that enthralls and inspires his or her class to change the way that they think to solve their problems.</p>
<p>The root of most problems is, after all, a mindset difference.</p>
<p>This is a key advantage of Guest Blogging for startups who are still building their name and can exponentially speed up the process.</p>
<p>Empowered with the right knowledge presented to them in the right way, people act differently, and for that mindset shift, a prospect will be grateful.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc51075634"></a>Call to Action</h2>
<p>What’s the point of investing your precious time and resources to create quality content and not get even a single email in return? Make sure you insert a <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbescoachescouncil/2018/12/26/why-your-call-to-action-needs-to-be-clear-and-compelling/#3143b412801b" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">call to action</a></u> in the conclusion of each blog post.</p>
<p>Deciding the specifics of the call to action is up to you—you can either ask the readers to sign up for your newsletter, or simply urge them to leave feedback in the comments section.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2105" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/blog3.jpg" alt="concept illustration of the process of creating brand awareness for local businesses" width="1000" height="699" /></p>
<h2>Identify Potential Customers and Sales Opportunities</h2>
<p>We’ve already mentioned that guest blogging exposes your brand to new audiences, but how exactly does it help generate more leads?</p>
<p>Well, when you offer solutions to readers’ problems through your guest blogs, they start considering you to be an expert in your particular industry or niche.</p>
<p>They will follow you, approach you, and visit your website to gain more information.</p>
<p>Of course, this will expose your products or services to new consumers, and the ones that are interested in your products will make inquiries.</p>
<p>In a nutshell, the higher the generated business leads, the higher the sales—and the higher the sales, the higher the profits.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc51075636"></a>Expand Your Email List</h2>
<p>Emails have long established themselves as a reliable tool for business development and branding. The sheer power that enables you to reach the meticulously managed inbox can be life-altering. Utilize email marketing in an efficient manner and watch how fast your small business grows.</p>
<p>The biggest key to building your email list, which you can even discuss and link in your guest post, is to create an &#8220;opt-in incentive.&#8221;</p>
<p>This is some document, video, training, etc., that provides value to your prospective customer.</p>
<p>Some examples of this are a checklist, an ebook, an exclusive video or video series, etc. Whatever format you choose, the incentive you provide needs to be electrifying and value-adding enough that your prospect will want it to help them solve their problem.</p>
<p>In exchange for this amazing, value-adding piece of content you provide them with, your opt-in form will ask for their email address.</p>
<p>Once they&#8217;ve opted in, and your email marketing software has sent them their opt-in incentive, boom &#8211; you&#8217;ve got a new email subscriber, and your list is primed to grow in this way.</p>
<p>However, there’s one mistake that you should avoid at all costs: <em>spamming.</em></p>
<p>Developing an email list can be quite a tricky undertaking, especially if you’re new on the block. Not every visitor of your website shares their email address or signs up for a newsletter. However, guest blogging can just be the growth catalyst you need to start building an email list.<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1357" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/collaborate-with-established-bloggers.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="250" /></p>
<p>However, it’s essential to make your readers believe that being on your mailing list will provide them with access to valuable information.</p>
<p>In order to achieve this, you need to work on the varied nuances of the blog post, and make sure that it’s the perfect blend of information, sales pitch, and call to action.</p>
<p>Another way of <u><a href="https://neilpatel.com/blog/5-digit-email-lists/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">expanding your email list</a></u> is to ask established bloggers to share their email lists. However, it’s not as simple as it sounds. You need to offer them something in return for this favor. This could be an engaging infographic or a well-written blog post.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc51075637"></a>Create an Environment of Engagement and External Feedback</h2>
<p>An important aspect of devising great digital marketing strategies involves developing unique new ideas or modifying plans to fit current requirements. Another great benefit of guest blogging for small businesses is access to community insights, which can help fine tune those strategies.</p>
<p>Just pull up a well-written blog post on a popular website with <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/high-domain-authority/">high domain authority</a></u>, and you’ll find the comment section filled with the readers’ opinions, experiences and ideas—and this is exactly what guest blogging gives you access to. It helps you to get <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbescommunicationscouncil/2020/01/24/10-ways-your-company-can-benefit-from-encouraging-criticism/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">constructive feedback</a></u> from areas outside your own website.</p>
<p>Put it this way: you come across a person who has constructive, insightful suggestions to a blog post from a website belonging to someone else. This feedback may inspire you to do something that ends up accumulating quality traffic.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2107" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Communication1.jpg" alt="concept illustration of branding efforts" width="937" height="986" /></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc51075638"></a>Broaden Your Online Publication Network</h2>
<p>When it comes to developing a brand, networking is one of the most important components. Just as the adage goes, “<em>It’s not all about what you know, but also who you know.</em>” This statement is as relevant in today’s business landscape as it was 50 years ago.</p>
<p>The key to successful networking is <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/amyblankson/2019/08/15/why-collaboration-is-the-currency-of-the-future/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">collaborating with businesses</a></u> that are capable of helping you build a recognizable brand across their own network. It’s like creating a web of awareness where all the involved parties can potentially help each other. As a matter of fact, this is the underlying idea behind the LinkedIn social media hub.</p>
<p>Publishing guest blogs on other websites allows the creation of networks between website owners and readers alike. Furthermore, these networks often lead to collaborations, which take business relationships to new heights.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc51075639"></a>Use Guest Posting to Boost Your SEO</h2>
<p>Guest blogging is easily one of the most in-demand <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/content-marketing/">content marketing services</a></u> right now. Unsurprisingly, companies are increasing hiring guest blog writers to work on their website. An increasing number of entrepreneurs, businesses, and companies are maximizing the unique benefits of hiring expert guest bloggers, which include generating quality backlinks, boosting authority, improving name recognition, increasing the chances of getting featured on high-traffic platforms, and gaining the trust of a large target audience.</p>
<p>If you’ve been struggling to use guest posting to boost your SEO, we can help you kick things off. As an award-winning digital marketing and <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/small-business-seo.html">small business SEO</a></u> firm, we specialize in helping brands leverage <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/guest-blogging/">guest blogging for SEO</a></u>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/">5 Benefits of Guest Blogging for Small Businesses Owners</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
