<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Search Berg</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 14:17:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to Write Content That Converts Leads into Customers</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-content-that-converts-leads-into-customers/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-content-that-converts-leads-into-customers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 13:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=3204</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While converting curious web users into leads is important, it’s not enough. Sure, you’ve managed to turn casual web browsing into serious shopping, but now what? If a web user simply buys your products/services without returning, you’ll struggle to consistently generate revenue over time. Instead of solely focusing on converting browsers into leads, go a step [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-content-that-converts-leads-into-customers/">How to Write Content That Converts Leads into Customers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/how-to-write-content-that-generate-leads.jpg" /><br />
While converting curious web users into leads is important, it’s not enough. Sure, you’ve managed to turn casual web browsing into serious shopping, but now what?</p>
<p>If a web user simply <em><u>buys</u></em> your products/services without <em><u>returning</u></em>, you’ll struggle to consistently generate revenue over time. Instead of solely focusing on converting browsers into leads, go a step beyond by <u>converting leads into loyal customers</u> that stick around in the long run.</p>
<p>The outcome? Consistent brand building, lead generation, coversion, and profit-making. This mix is music to an up-and-coming business’s ears.</p>
<p>How can you achieve it? By <em><u>creating content that converts</u></em>.</p>
<p>We want to make things simpler by breaking down the process of converting leads into customers through content. Let’s dive in!</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Struggling to write high-quality content that converts? Consult our pros by filling out the form below!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contents</strong></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc80048632"><u>How to Write Content That Converts</u> </a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc80048633"><u> Incorporate High-Converting Keywords Into Your Content</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc80048634"><u> It’s All About the CTA (Call-to-Action)</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc80048635"><u>3.Write </u><u>Sales-Driven Content</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc80048636"><u> Showcase Testimonials on Your Web Pages and Social Media Pages</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc80048637"><u> Avoid Inconsistency and Redundancy</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc80048638"><u> Replace Loud Pitches with Softer Nudges</u> </a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc80048639"><u>Wrapping Up</u> </a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><a name="_Toc80048632"></a><strong><b>How to Write Content That Converts</b></strong></h1>
<h2><a name="_Toc80048633"></a><strong><b>1. Incorporate High-Converting Keywords Into Your Content</b></strong></h2>
<p>Many brands wonder why their content fails to generate leads in the long run. They seemingly check off all the boxes by writing engaging, insightful, and industry-specific content.</p>
<p>So, what’s missing? The answer may be right under your nose: <em><u>keywords</u></em>.</p>
<p>This phrase is obnoxiously overused in the world of content, but rightfully so. Keywords are the foundation of high-quality content that drives massive sales.</p>
<p>Using a mix of the right exact match, phrase match, broad match, broad match modifier, and negative match keywords, you can turn <u>web browsers into leads</u> and <u>leads into returning customers</u>.</p>
<p>As a rule of thumb, make sure <strong>60% of the keywords you select</strong> are equipped to drive high conversion rates.</p>
<p>In other words, they should compel your audience to a) take positive action on your site, b) further explore your site, c) return for a purchase at least 1–2 times, and d) continue to return for purchases, subscriptions, etc. in the long run.</p>
<p>Your audience shouldn’t simply buy a product/service and “bounce”; they should feel interested and engaged enough to <em><u>want to stick around</u></em>.</p>
<p>Start by selecting <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/conversion-rate-optimization/"><u>high-CTR (click-through rate) keywords</u></a> that are your top performers. More often than not, these keywords include verbs that prompt action.</p>
<p>Let’s consider an example for more clarity.</p>
<p>Let’s say you provide ecommerce support to startups and up-and-coming businesses. Instead of solely using keywords like “ecommerce services” or “cheap ecommerce solutions,” introduce an actionable verb to the mix.</p>
<p>For instance, keywords like “create an ecommerce strategy” and “consult ecommerce professionals” include verbs (“create” and “consult”) that prompt action.</p>
<p>In other words, they’re <em><u>excellent converters</u></em>.</p>
<p>As web users land on your site and come across more high-converting keywords, they’ll take consistent actions on your site.</p>
<p>This is a great way to keep your target audience on your site for longer, which, in turn, will convert them into long-term customers.</p>
<p>Here are more examples of high-converting keywords to further elucidate this strategy:</p>
<ul>
<li>For attorneys: “<strong><u>Build</u></strong>a strong case”</li>
<li>For web developers: “<strong><u>Create</u></strong>an interactive website”</li>
<li>For realtors: “<strong><u>Buy</u></strong>your dream home”</li>
<li>For door manufacturers: “<strong><u>Replace</u></strong>your front doors”</li>
</ul>
<p>See what we mean? As long as there’s a verb supporting the keyword, you’re on the right track.</p>
<p>Of course, you can further build the keyword to strengthen it even more.</p>
<p>Here’s what we mean:<br />

<table id="tablepress-1" class="tablepress tablepress-id-1">
<thead>
<tr class="row-1 odd">
	<th class="column-1">HIGH-CONVERTING KEYWORDS</th><th class="column-2">	STRONGER HIGH-CONVERTING KEYWORDS</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody class="row-hover">
<tr class="row-2 even">
	<td class="column-1">For attorneys: “<u>Build</u> a strong case”</td><td class="column-2">For attorneys: “Build a strong case <u>in Los Angeles</u>”</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-3 odd">
	<td class="column-1">For web developers: “<u>Create </u>an interactive website”</td><td class="column-2">For web developers: “Create an interactive website <u>in less than $100</u>”</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-4 even">
	<td class="column-1">For realtors: “<u>Buy </u>your dream home”</td><td class="column-2">For realtors: “Buy your dream home <u>in SoHo</u>”</td>
</tr>
<tr class="row-5 odd">
	<td class="column-1">For door manufacturers: “<u>Replace </u>your front doors”</td><td class="column-2">For door manufacturers: “Replace your front doors <u>and get a transom for free</u>” </td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<!-- #tablepress-1 from cache --></p>
<p>As you build high-converting keywords by adding local search terms and your brand’s USPs to the mix, you’ll increase your chances of converting leads into customers through content.</p>
<p>We recommend incorporating high-converting keywords into <u>different types of content</u> on your site: blogs, product/service pages, the FAQ page, the about page, the contact us page, etc.</p>
<p>This will ensure that your audience takes continual actions, which will ultimately help them learn more about your brand as they go and keep shopping in the long run.</p>
<p>Here are some excellent titles from <a target="_blank" href="https://www.adidas.com/us/blog" rel="noopener"><u>Adidas’ blogs</u></a>. We’ve highlighted the verbs to help you understand how seamlessly their team has incorporated high-converting keywords into the mix!</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/how-to-choose-for-legging.jpg" /><br />
<img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/how-to-wear-stan-smith.jpg" /><br />
<img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/how-to-choose-for-rock-climbing.jpg" /><br />
<img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/how-to-break-in-running-shoes.jpg" /></p>
<p>The verbs are strategically followed by their products (leggings, Stan Smith sneakers, climbing shoes, running, shoes).</p>
<p>This is how you check this strategy off the list like a seasoned pro!</p>
<p><strong>Recommended Read: </strong><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/blog-vs-article-what-is-the-difference/"><u>Blog vs. Article: What Is the Difference?</u></a></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc80048634"></a><strong><b>2. It’s All About the CTA (Call-to-Action)</b></strong></h2>
<p>When it comes to creating content that converts, a <a target="_blank" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2020/10/12/planning-your-content-ctas-by-funnel-stage-and-content-type/" rel="noopener"><u>strong CTA (call-to-action)</u></a> isn’t just useful, it’s <em><u>imperative</u></em>.</p>
<p>A CTA is a short text (2–5 lines) that compels web users to take action.</p>
<p>If you’re writing a blog, power blog, article, guest post, or any other type of content that goes on your site or a third-party site, the CTA should generally be included at the end.</p>
<p>If you’re working on a product/service page, the CTA can be included in the form of visual elements.</p>
<p>For social media posts, the CTA can be included in the beginning or towards the end.</p>
<p><em>Here’s the catch</em>.</p>
<p>While CTAs follow a similar rhythm for the most part, they can’t be generic or predictable.</p>
<p>Instead of incorporating a boring CTA into your content, make sure it a) carries conversion potential, b) is engaging, and c) is expertly optimized.</p>
<p>Here’s a closer look at a power-packed CTA from <a target="_blank" href="https://www.adidas.com/us/blog/681805-how-to-break-in-running-shoes-for-maximum-comfort" rel="noopener"><u>Adidas’ recent blog</u></a>:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/screenshots.jpg" /></p>
<p>Notice how the CTA comprises <u>high-converting keywords</u> (“choose” and “find” are the guiding verbs here).</p>
<p>It also includes <u>visual elements</u> that lead web users to Adidas’ relevant collections.</p>
<p>In fact, they’ve gone the extra mile by linking their <u>social media pages and email</u> below (bottom right).</p>
<p><em>This is one hell of a CTA! </em></p>
<p>The keywords are hyperlinked, the visual elements are as eye-catching as it gets, and the transition from the rest of the content to the CTA is seamless.</p>
<p>The goal is to compel your audience to take positive action without them realizing what’s happening.</p>
<p>A cheesy CTA that’s easily detectable can be extremely off-putting. Your audience will know right away that you’re trying to “sell” something.</p>
<p>This isn’t something they should be able to pick up on; the transition should be <u>undetectable and natural</u>.</p>
<p>Adidas gets this balance <em>just right</em>.</p>
<p>If you want to create website content that converts, make sure your CTAs aren’t overly promotional. They should also be expertly optimized using the right keywords (refer to the first section of this blog for more insight) and internal links.</p>
<p>Your goal is to prompt positive action without making it painfully obvious. It takes a while to get this roundabout content writing style just right.</p>
<p>If you’re struggling, we recommend consulting a team of <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog-writing-services/"><u>professional content writers</u></a>.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Got the CTA or keyword blues? Our content marketing pros can help. Fill out the form below to start converting leads into customers through content!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc80048635"></a><strong><b>3.Write </b></strong><strong><b>Sales-Driven Content</b></strong></h2>
<p>We’ve covered the basics: keywords and CTAs; they form the foundation of good content.</p>
<p>However, creating “good content” atop a firm foundation is the bulk of the job.</p>
<p>One misstep and you could end up damaging the foundation and going back to square one.</p>
<p>In other words, <em><u>this is where the real work begins</u></em>.</p>
<p>If you write unengaging, boring, and banal content, your audience will “bounce,” thereby increasing your site’s <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-improve-website-bounce-rate/"><u>bounce rate</u></a>.</p>
<p>At the very most, you’ll manage to convert web users into leads. However, you’ll struggle to convert leads into loyal customers that stick around in the long run.</p>
<p>To check this important box off the list, write <strong><u>sales-driven content</u></strong>.</p>
<p>Not only that, but your content should also be highly engaging, value-added, and insightful.</p>
<p>As the name suggests, sales-driven content is content that <u>generates massive sales</u>. It’s written with the intention of <em>informing, engaging</em>, and <em>converting</em> your target audience.</p>
<p>Start off by taking a deep dive into your audience’s interests and preferences. This is the first step to writing content that converts.</p>
<p>As you understand what your audience is looking for, you’ll manage to choose the right topics for your content.</p>
<p>We strongly recommend sectioning off your audience demographically.</p>
<p>For instance, if you run an apparel store, identify the specific age groups you create clothing for. As you split these groups into different categories, you can work on creating content for each category.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://blog.ae.com/" rel="noopener"><u>American Eagle</u></a> does this brilliantly. As a result, their content isn’t generic; it’s actually highly specific.</p>
<p>The outcome? They’ve managed to convert <em>each demographic</em> into long-term customers.</p>
<p>Here’s an example of their recent blog:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/aejeans.jpg" /></p>
<p>Notice how they’ve targeted their younger demographic, i.e., teenagers who are returning to school this year.</p>
<p>Once you’ve sectioned off your audience, start selecting relevant themes, topics, events, and social media trends that pique their interest. In other words, look for ideas to create content that they’ll actually read.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.tonal.com/blog/" rel="noopener"><u>Tonal’s relevant blogs</u></a> are a great example of putting this strategy into practice the right way!</p>
<p>Instead of choosing generic topics, they delved deeper and carefully selected topics that their audience was actually interested in.</p>
<p>For instance, they wrote an <a target="_blank" href="https://www.tonal.com/blog/for-patrick-curreri-being-strong-is-about-more-just-himself/" rel="noopener"><u>insightful, empowering, and deeply moving blog during Pride Month</u></a>.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/brand-celebration.jpg" /></p>
<p>The brand also celebrated and emphasized the true meaning of independence by <a target="_blank" href="https://www.tonal.com/blog/celebrating-juneteenth/" rel="noopener"><u>posting a powerful blog on Juneteenth</u></a>.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/celebrating-juneteenth.jpg" /></p>
<p>Writing content on topics that resonate with your audience shows that you care about their interests, representation, and using your platform for good.</p>
<p>Today, people are increasingly looking for brands that go the extra mile to <em><u>value customers</u></em>, not just generate massive revenue.</p>
<p>As a brand, you should have a razor-sharp focus on showing your audience that they’re more than just a number to you.</p>
<p>As you build a strong brand identity, you’ll simultaneously manage to convert leads into customers.</p>
<p>Your audience will feel <em>acknowledged, accepted, celebrated</em>, and <em>included</em>.</p>
<p>This feeling makes customers feel special. It shows them that brands care about who they are and what they stand for.</p>
<p>As you create content for different demographics, you’ll manage to capture their interests and show them that you’re committed to offering more than just a great product/service.</p>
<p>This extra step is also known as “<u>humanizing the content</u>”, i.e., adding an element of humanness and empathy to web content.</p>
<p>When combined with high-converting CTAs and keywords, humanized content helps brands rank higher, generate more traffic, convert web users into leads, and convert leads into customers.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://postmates.com/blog/" rel="noopener"><u>Postmates</u></a> is also known for creating content that <em><u>centers their audience</u></em>. Here’s a glimpse of their audience-centric blogs:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/stophating-asianhate.jpg" /></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/international-women-day.jpg" /></p>
<p><strong>Recommended Read: </strong><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-a-blog-that-ranks/"><u>How To Write A Blog That Ranks</u></a></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc80048636"></a><strong><b>4.Showcase Testimonials on Your Web Pages and Social Media Pages</b></strong></h2>
<p>According to research, a whopping <u>84% of web users trust online reviews</u>. That’s a lot by any measure.</p>
<p>In fact, <u>80% of people change their minds after reading a positive or negative review</u>.</p>
<p>As an up-and-coming or even established business, you can actualize impressive growth by <em>doubling down on testimonials</em>.</p>
<p>Here’s why this is so important.</p>
<p>Presently, large majority of brands have a separate testimonial page that lists their online reviews.</p>
<p>While this is a great approach, it’s not enough.</p>
<p>The human attention span is incredibly low: <em>a measly eight seconds</em>.</p>
<p>It’s unlikely that your customers will explore every single page on your site.</p>
<p>In most cases, customers never end up on the testimonial page, which delays the process of trusting a brand.</p>
<p>Undo the damage by showcasing your testimonials on multiple pages across your site, especially your product/service pages and blogs.</p>
<p>If you explore <a target="_blank" href="https://www.nike.com/" rel="noopener"><u>Nike’s product pages</u></a>, you’ll notice that <em>each page</em> features reviews for the respective product. Here’s an example:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/nike-shoes.jpg" /></p>
<p>A lot of brands use a similar approach for non-product/service pages.</p>
<p>Let’s say you manufacture sporting equipment and choose to write a blog on the best footwear for an arduous hike.</p>
<p>As you showcase some products that you have in stock, you can include reviews for each product towards the end of the blog.</p>
<p>This is a great way to compel your audience to buy said products.</p>
<p>Testimonials are <a target="_blank" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/theyec/2019/08/21/why-reviews-are-essential-and-how-to-generate-positive-reviews-for-your-business/" rel="noopener"><em><u>extremely powerful</u></em></a>. They carry the ability to form a person’s opinion and eliminate doubt.</p>
<p>By incorporating them into web content and even social media content, you can nudge your audience in the right direction: potentially buying your products/services and becoming long-term customers.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.lacoste.com/" rel="noopener"><u>Lacoste</u></a> is known for frequently replying to and retweeting posts from customers. While these aren’t “reviews” in the traditional sense, they still count as testimonials.</p>
<p>By interacting with these posts, Lacoste expertly ensures that they gain more traction.</p>
<p>Here’s an example:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/twitter-post.jpg" /></p>
<p>The tweet will show up on Lacoste’s page since they’ve responded to it. It’ll also gain more traction as it earned a response from a verified page.</p>
<p>Lacoste’s social media marketing team has an <em>excellent understanding</em> of how the Twitter algorithm works. By using it to their benefit, they’re brilliantly showcasing positive online reviews on social media!</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.target.com/" rel="noopener"><u>Target</u></a> is known for using the same approach:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/twitter-post-reply.jpg" /></p>
<p>Whether customers appreciate your products, services, in-store shopping experience, customer support team, or any other facet of your brand, consider it a win and highlight it!</p>
<p>As more customers interact with flattering social media posts or web reviews, they’ll become loyal customers that stick around in the long run.</p>
<p>This is a tried-and-tested way of converting leads into customers through content (both web content and social media content).</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Need high-converting content for your web or social media pages? Do things the right way: the Search Berg way. Fill out the form below to get started!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form4" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject4" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name4" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website4" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email4" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number4" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country4" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha4();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc80048637"></a><strong><b>5. Avoid Inconsistency and Redundancy</b></strong></h2>
<p>Many brands are guilty of falling into the all-too-familiar traps of inconsistency and redundancy.</p>
<p>As you start creating content, you may reach a point when you <em>simply can’t think of new topics</em>.</p>
<p>When this situation arises, some brands become inconsistent with content creation (i.e., they start posting less frequently) while others resort to redundancy (i.e., they recycle the same ideas and present them differently).</p>
<p>These avenues can be <u>extremely dangerous</u> for your brand, especially if you start relying on both of them at once.</p>
<p>The sooner you identify these habits, the better.</p>
<p>As you start undoing the damage in due course, you can prevent customer attrition/loss.</p>
<p>If you take action a little too late, you may have already lost a significant number of customers.</p>
<p>It’s important to note that consistently creating fresh content is one of the easiest ways to convert leads into customers. This is why nipping inconsistency and redundancy in the bud is so important.</p>
<p>If you’re short on ideas, turn to <a target="_blank" href="https://www.google.com/imghp?hl=EN" rel="noopener"><u>Google Images</u></a> for help!</p>
<p>Let’s say you offer massage therapy services in Atlanta, Georgia. As you enter “massage therapy” in the search bar, Google will fetch a lot of suggestions for you.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/google-search.jpg" /></p>
<p>These tags are <em><u>closely related</u></em> to your search query. In other words, web users are actively searching for these terms as they’re looking up “massage therapy” on Google.</p>
<p>Use these suggestions to your advantage by building new connections and creating fresh, relevant, and engaging content.</p>
<p>This strategy is extremely useful because you’re relying on <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-algorithm-updates-that-changed-seo/"><u>Google’s whip-smart algorithm</u></a>, which already knows what’s relevant and what’s not.</p>
<p><em>It’s doing the work for you! </em></p>
<p>Instead of manually searching for new topics that may not be as relevant, you can opt for this route to find the most relevant topics for new content.</p>
<p>Once you’ve used up all your connections, click on individual tags to unearth a plethora of new terms.</p>
<p>This cycle is never-ending. It’s one of the best ways to write new content that doesn’t bore your audience.</p>
<p>In addition to employing this strategy, we also recommend reaching out to your audience for help.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.plm.automation.siemens.com/global/en/products/simcenter/" rel="noopener"><u>Simcenter</u></a>, a branch of the renowned brand <a target="_blank" href="https://www.siemens.com/" rel="noopener"><u>Siemens</u></a>, recently reached out to their audience on Twitter. They requested more insight into the specific kind of content their audience was seeking: videos, infographics, live webinars, or blogs.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/slim-center.jpg" /></p>
<p>You can leverage the same strategy but <em><u>get a tad more specific</u></em>!</p>
<p>Ask your audience to list the specific topics they’d love to read content on.</p>
<p>Make use of Twitter’s inbuilt features (polls, etc.) to further increase engagement.</p>
<p>You can also keep the post more open-ended by requesting your audience to share their ideas in the comments.</p>
<p>This is a great way to feed two birds with one scone!</p>
<p>Not only will you manage to fill your proverbial “content marketing” bags with new ideas, but you’ll also get a chance to increase your social media engagement.</p>
<p>It’s a win-win!</p>
<p>Here are some more great examples to help you start off on the right foot:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/crypto-mena.jpg" /><br />
<img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/build-your-future.jpg" /><br />
<img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/kucoin.jpg" /></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc80048638"></a><strong><b>6. Replace Loud Pitches with Softer Nudges</b></strong></h2>
<p>Think back to marketing in the 2010s.</p>
<p>Whether you were watching a TV commercial, reading a blog, or browsing through a company’s products/services, you would have been bombarded with statements like:</p>
<ul>
<li>“What are you waiting for? Buy now before it’s too late!”</li>
<li>“You can’t miss out on our sale! We’ve got the best toasters in town, grab ‘em now!”</li>
<li>“$20 off? Go, go, go! It doesn’t get better than this, start shopping now for the best in interior décor!”</li>
</ul>
<p>While these pitches may not seem too loud at first, they can easily overwhelm you once you come across two, three, five, or <em>even ten</em> each day.</p>
<p>This was marketing in the 2010s in a nutshell. It was loud, excessively promotional, cheesy, and downright gimmicky.</p>
<p>In the 2020s, we’ve transitioned from loud pitches to softer nudges. While you may think the latter aren’t as effective, they’re actually better at converting leads into customers.</p>
<p>Today, people are on the hunt for content that <em>informs, educates</em>, and <em>solves their problems</em>.</p>
<p>Flashy lights, gaudy props, cheesy headlines, and an excessive sense of urgency aren’t appreciated anymore.</p>
<p>Instead, customers would rather read content that includes practical insights, useful tips, and fresh ideas.</p>
<p>As a rule of thumb, steer clear of loud pitches. They do more harm than good and may compel your audience to start looking elsewhere.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="https://www.dyson.com/newsroom/overview" rel="noopener"><u>Dyson’s blogs</u></a> are a great example of putting value over heavy promotion.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/blog-screenshots.jpg" /></p>
<p>You can still include a well-placed CTA in your content. However, focus on writing quality content to make <em>a great impression</em> on your audience.</p>
<p>Not only will people stick around until the very end, but they’ll also take positive action in response to the great content that was provided.</p>
<p>And if your content features testimonials towards the end, well, you’ve checked off all the boxes!</p>
<h1><a name="_Toc80048639"></a><strong><b>Wrapping Up</b></strong></h1>
<p>In this blog, we walked you through six steps to writing content that converts. As you put these strategies into practice, make sure you <em><u>prioritize quality every step of the way</u></em>.</p>
<p>When woven into content strategically and seamlessly, soft nudges can compel action and convert leads into loyal customers.</p>
<p>As you work towards <a target="_blank" href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/theyec/2019/12/23/five-strategies-for-developing-a-strong-brand-identity/" rel="noopener"><u>strengthening your brand identity</u></a>, you’ll also manage to retain customers who were considering partnering with a different brand.</p>
<p>At Search Berg, our content marketing team has extensive experience in writing high-converting content that generates leads and drives sales.</p>
<p>We’re committed to helping you stand out in your industry and make big splashes through high-quality content.</p>
<p>If you’re ready to get started, we can help. Give us a call at <a href="tel:8554444777"><u>855-444-4777</u></a> to kick-start your <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/content-marketing/"><u>content marketing strategy</u></a>!</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Writing content that converts can be tricky; let us step in and achieve the results you’re aiming for! Fill out the form below to get started.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form4" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject5" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name5" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website5" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email5" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number5" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country5" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha5();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-content-that-converts-leads-into-customers/">How to Write Content That Converts Leads into Customers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-write-content-that-converts-leads-into-customers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Google My Business and How Does It Help Small Businesses?</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-google-my-business-and-how-does-it-help-small-businesses/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-google-my-business-and-how-does-it-help-small-businesses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Video Content]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=3187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There are currently over 400 million small businesses located across the globe. In fact, the accurate figure is expected to be much, much greater. With so many local businesses struggling to engage their target audience, it’s impossible to ignore the thick layer of competition they’re engulfed in. As a small business, you’re competing with thousands of local businesses [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-google-my-business-and-how-does-it-help-small-businesses/">What is Google My Business and How Does It Help Small Businesses?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="What is Google My Business and How Does It Help Small Businesses?" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w4LUqYzm9AI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><br />
There are currently <strong><u>over 400 million</u></strong> small businesses located across the globe. In fact, the accurate figure is expected to be <em>much, much</em> greater.</p>
<p>With so many local businesses struggling to engage their target audience, it’s impossible to ignore the thick layer of <strong>competition</strong> they’re engulfed in.</p>
<p>As a small business, you’re competing with thousands of local businesses in your industry.</p>
<p>Sure, you’ve launched a website. And great, your marketing team is putting out word on social media.</p>
<p>But <em>that’s not enough</em>.</p>
<p>As the competition thickens every day, you have to stand out to your local audience. <strong>Google My Business helps you do just that</strong>.</p>
<p>What is Google My Business? It’s a versatile tool that enables small businesses to <u>engage and convert</u> their local target audience.</p>
<p>Let’s say a web user looks up “the best pizza places near me.” If they’re located in Brooklyn, New York, the top-rated pizzerias in their surrounding area will show up.</p>
<p>If you run a pizza parlor in Brooklyn, you can leverage Google My Business to help <em><u>your</u></em> business show up among the first few search results.</p>
<p>The outcome? More clicks, leads, conversions, and sales.</p>
<p>It’s that simple and quick.</p>
<p>In this video, we break down the basics of Google My Business and walk you through its benefits for small businesses.</p>
<p>Get your business seen today. Call us at <a href="tel:855-444-4777"><strong><u><b>855-444-4777</b></u></strong></a> to speak with our Google My Business experts and start achieving local visibility.</p>
<p>Subscribe now: <a href="https://bit.ly/3kL0Ka4"><u>https://bit.ly/3kL0Ka4</u></a></p>
<p>Check out: <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/gmb-optimization/"><u>https://www.searchberg.com/gmb-optimization/</u></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Stay tuned for more!</p>
<p>Facebook: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/searchberg/"><u>https://www.facebook.com/searchberg/</u></a></p>
<p>Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/searchberg"><u>https://twitter.com/searchberg</u></a></p>
<p>LinkedIn:<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/searchberg"><u>https://www.linkedin.com/company/searchberg</u></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-google-my-business-and-how-does-it-help-small-businesses/">What is Google My Business and How Does It Help Small Businesses?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-google-my-business-and-how-does-it-help-small-businesses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Create Winning Social Media Strategies for Small Businesses</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-create-winning-social-media-strategies-for-small-businesses/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-create-winning-social-media-strategies-for-small-businesses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 14:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=3163</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Up-and-coming businesses can no longer afford to also have a social media marketing strategy; it needs to be their bread and butter. Whether you’re talking customer acquisition or retargeting old customers who’ve lapsed over time, a social media marketing plan allows you to do it all. The big question is, where do you even begin with [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-create-winning-social-media-strategies-for-small-businesses/">How to Create Winning Social Media Strategies for Small Businesses</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3164" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/social-media-attention.png" alt="A graphic depicting a small business social media page calling for attention." width="750" height="544" /></p>
<p>Up-and-coming businesses can no longer afford to <em><i>also </i></em>have a social media marketing strategy; it needs to be their bread and butter.</p>
<p>Whether you’re talking customer acquisition or retargeting old customers who’ve lapsed over time, a social media marketing plan allows you to do it all.</p>
<p>The big question is, where do you even begin with your social media strategy? We’re glad you asked! Here are 14 proven social media advertising strategies for small businesses that you need to take up.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Ready to take your social media presence to the next level? Fill the form below.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Contents</strong></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc70174089"><u>Social Media Marketing Strategies</u><u> That Work! An Essential Guide For Small And Up-And Coming Businesses</u> </a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174090"><u></u> <u>Set Social Goals For Your Small Business</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174091"><u></u> <u>Define and Own Your Brand’s Voice</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174092"><u></u> <u>Who’s Your Social Audience?</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174093"><u></u> <u>Looking At Competitors’ Past Content—The Proof is in the Pudding</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174094"><u></u> <u>Serve Up Some Value Additive Content</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174095"><u></u> <u>Be a Content Chameleon</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174096"><u></u> <u>Engage, Engage, Engage</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174097"><u></u> <u>It’s All in the Metrics—Review Social Analytics</u> </a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174098"><u></u> <u>Impressions</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174099"><u></u> <u>Engagement</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174100"><u></u> <u>Visits</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174101"><u></u> <u>Mentions</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174102"><u></u> <u>Followers</u> </a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174103"><u></u> <u>Get Platform Specific in Your Approach</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174116"><u></u> <u>Use Social Media As A New Frontier For Customer Service</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174117"><u></u> <u>Look For Trends</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174118"><u></u> <u>Find the Best #hashtags</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174119"><u></u> <u>Double Down on Social Media Optimizations</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc70174120"><u></u> <u>Get Social Media Experts on Board</u> </a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc70174121"><u>Social Media Marketing Plans</u><u>—The Key to Long-Term Success?</u> </a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc70174122"><u>The Ultimate </u><u>Social Media Marketing Strategy For Startups and Small Businesses</u><u>—Wrapping Up</u> </a></p>
<h1><a name="_Toc68802091"></a></h1>
<h1><a name="_Toc69226087"></a><a name="_Toc70174089"></a>Social Media Marketing Strategies That Work! An Essential Guide For Small And Up-And Coming Businesses</h1>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc70174090"></a><b>1. </b><strong><b>Set Social Goals For Your Small Business</b></strong></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3165" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/social-sharing-people.png" alt="graphic of people sharing and consuming social content." width="1378" height="786" /></p>
<p>Here’s a question: can you spell out the impact your social marketing strategy a) has had, and b) aims to have? If you can’t answer in a heartbeat, we have a problem.</p>
<p>What we’re trying to say is, you need to have social media goals for your small business. And every interaction and success you have needs to be measured against these goals.</p>
<p>Walk yourself through the buyer’s journey for your product or service, and at each step, identify what your target is, what kind of social activity you’ll use to achieve that target, what the KPIs are for that activity, and the impact you want it to have. This sets up a nifty feedback loop that allows you to tweak your content to your heart’s content.</p>
<p>Here are a few examples of social media goals to get you started:</p>
<ul>
<li>Increase web traffic</li>
<li>Increase how many people engage with your posts</li>
<li>Make people aware of your brand</li>
<li>Distribute informative content regarding a product/service</li>
<li>Get more sign ups</li>
</ul>
<h2><a name="_Toc70174091"></a><b>2. </b><strong><b>Define and Own Your Brand’s Voice</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3166" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Nordstrom-campaign-facebook.png" alt="Nordstrom’s campaign to do better with sustainable fashion" width="374" height="616" /></p>
<p>Let’s dwell on this campaign from social media titan and clothing behemoth Nordstrom for a bit. Notice how they effortlessly weave in a service they’re offering into a campaign that’s also supposed to help save the planet. Associations like these stay in consumers’ minds, and are very powerful sales tools.</p>
<p>Alongside, the verdict is in—people don’t want to interact with businesses that sound like there’s no one behind them. They want a magical Oz-like character behind the curtains, orchestrating the company; someone who’s a real big personality. They also want this person to be the face of the company, so they’re talking to someone they can trust.</p>
<p>So, what does this mean for your small business’s social media marketing plan? For starters, if you’re the owner and fashion yourself to have even a little bit of charisma, try to put yourself front and center in all the video content you put out. Better yet, get the whole team on board by asking employees if being the public face of the company is something they’re interested in.</p>
<p>You could also go the behind-the-scenes route with your social media presence—this really humanizes your company.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc70174092"></a><b>3. </b><strong><b>Who’s Your Social Audience?</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3167" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/social-marketing-right-person.png" alt="graphic of the right person being targeted with a social media strategy" width="1174" height="726" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It’s marketing 101, but we’ll scream it from the rooftops anyway: <strong><b>you need to know your audience</b></strong>! And when we say know them, we mean really know them.</p>
<p>So, while you may have a general sense of the fact that 20 somethings who identify as women like your beauty products, you also need to know where they are, how engaged they are, and whether there’s additional consumers out there who augment your core audience. Your social media digital marketing strategy needs to account for all possible variables.</p>
<p>The answer, as always, lies in data. And the good news is that social media platforms give you bucketloads of it. Platforms like Twitter and Facebook already come with robust demographics analysis tools, but it doesn’t even stop there; you can complement these tools with some seriously heavy-hitting third party plugins.</p>
<p>All of this comes together to give you a pretty complete picture of who your audience is comprised of, allowing you to take decisions accordingly. Once you have your core demographic, all you have to do is research the kind of content they’re into, and you’re good to go!</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc70174093"></a><b>4. </b><strong><b>Looking At Competitors’ Past Content—The Proof is in the Pudding</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3168" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/GoPro-campaign.png" alt="GoPro’s featured images" width="379" height="593" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>GoPro is the undisputed king of daily featured photos content; and it didn’t have to reinvent the wheel. All it did was take customers using their product in daring situations, and it put a new spin on an old format.</p>
<p>It’s not cheating if you make the content your own! Here’s the thing, there’s no such thing as completely novel content—it’s always a mishmash of what’s been done before, made new with your unique twist on it.</p>
<p>So when we say that the map to your success already exists, we mean it. All you need to do is look at what established competitors have been doing for a really long time—what worked, what didn’t, and what you can take and improve upon.</p>
<p>Remember, industries need to keep up with trends, and you want to be ahead of the curve too, not always catching up. That means you need to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Take competitors’ content and find a way to make it fresh</li>
<li>Alongside, you need to innovate, so customers see you as the popular new kid around the block</li>
<li>You can also mix and match competitors’ content to create new formats altogether</li>
</ul>
<h2><a name="_Toc70174094"></a><b>5. </b><strong><b>Serve Up Some Value Additive Content</b></strong></h2>
<p>Nothing gets your followers to leave en masse like you wasting their time. Here are some social actions that could make your brand a pariah on social media:</p>
<ul>
<li>Spamming your followers with promotional messages</li>
<li>Posting way too much</li>
<li>Not posting at all</li>
<li>Coming up with posts that don’t solve any problems that your audience has</li>
</ul>
<p>The takeaway? That every post you make needs to be worth your audience’s time. We’re not saying you need to be somber and informative either—casual tones work great, but the post still needs to tell potential customers something they want to hear.</p>
<p>Here’s an example of a social media post from social media staple Starbucks:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3169" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/starbucks-post.png" alt="Starbucks’ social media marketing strategy that involved product features" width="397" height="497" /></p>
<p>Notice how the post is beyond chill (pun intended), but it tells you a lot about the product. The featured image is super flattering and you know it’s a mix of salty and sweet that’ll help you beat the heat—it’s a winning combination, and just in a few words (Notice the effective use of the hashtag here too).</p>
<p>Once you strike the balance between the right tone and the right amount of information, every post will be a winner.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc70174095"></a><b>6. </b><strong><b>Be a Content Chameleon</b></strong></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3170" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/mac-cosmetics-instagram.png" alt="Mac Cosmetics’ social media business plan involving many different content strategies" width="650" height="635" /></p>
<p>In the age of digital media consumption, the worst thing you could be is unchanging. The type of content you serve to clients needs to be as varied as possible, taking full advantage of all the media and other features different social platforms give you.</p>
<p>See the image above from Mac Cosmetics’ Instagram page? Notice how at the same time, they have new social media posts, Highlights, and Stories for consumers to peruse. It’s an all-of-the-above approach that really seems to show that the brand is doing well.</p>
<p>Do you only post GIFs on your Buzzfeed-esque pop culture page? How about changing it up by posting compilation videos as well? Have an Instagram feed that your customers already love? Spice up engagement levels by leveraging Stories, IGTV, and Highlights. You get the picture.</p>
<p>Here’s the kicker, even conventional wisdom flies out the door if you’re only posting the same type of content. You know how people say that posts with images do better than just plain text? Well, it turns out, if you keep on posting images, eventually, they get stale, and people want out of your page.</p>
<p>The key is to keep on reinventing yourself for your audience, and to keep them guessing.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc70174096"></a><b>7. </b><strong><b>Engage, Engage, Engage</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3171" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/starbucks-twitter.png" alt="Starbucks’ Twitter marketing plan involves replying to customers’ queries." width="527" height="238" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Starbucks didn’t have to reply to this customer’s question about using personal cups during the pandemic; but it did, because it’s super relevant to a lot of people these days, and makes the brand seem like it cares.</p>
<p>At the end of the day, customers just want to feel like you have their back. There’s nothing more frustrating than getting a product or signing up for a service, only to face a glaring problem with it. Actually, wait, there is—it’s experiencing radio silence when you reach out to the company for help.</p>
<p>Most brands are under the false belief that customers should come to them—but here’s a reality check, when you’re running a small business that still doesn’t have a ton of traction, you’re going to have to bite first.</p>
<p>The good news is, it’s not hard; in fact, we’ve broken it down into a neat list:</p>
<ul>
<li>Kill two birds with one stone by sharing content from someone in your core audience, and tag them for a mutually beneficial relationship (They’re also very likely to give you a shoutout for this!)</li>
<li>When customers comment on your posts, reply to as many comments as you can, especially the ones asking for specific information. There’s nothing like making people feel heard.</li>
<li>Another pro tip is to follow people who are following your competitor, as they’re sure to take notice when a brand takes the time out to give them a follow</li>
</ul>
<h2><a name="_Toc70174097"></a><b>8. </b><strong><b>It’s All in the Metrics—Review Social Analytics</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-3177 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/social-media-metrics.png" alt="different metrics related to different social platforms." width="886" height="626" /></p>
<p>Social media platforms thrive on data; it’s their great money-maker, after all. But data untapped serves no purposes, which is why platforms like Facebook and Instagram give you unprecedented insight into who your followers are, how much engagement they exhibit, and how they find your content.</p>
<p>But metrics can be deceptive; for instance, being bent on the number of likes and followers means nothing if your page isn’t getting the kind of targeted engagement that leads to someone taking a desired business action.</p>
<p>Wait, what does any of that mean? To simplify, if you’re running an up and coming residential repairs business and get a ton of likes on your blog posts, but not one of those leads actually calls you to step in, it’s a major problem.</p>
<p>That’s why it’s super important to identify what metrics are important to you, and then proceed to double down on them.</p>
<p>So, buckle up, because we’re taking a deep dive.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc70174098"></a>a. Impressions</h3>
<p>Impressions is just a metric that tells you how many times a post showed up on people’s social timelines. So while you naturally want impressions to be high, if no one is interacting with your post as they see it, that’s really bad news.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc70174099"></a>b. Engagement</h3>
<p>Engagement is the second piece of the puzzle; your impression to engagement ratio needs to be as close to 1 as possible. This is because engagement tells you how many people actually <em><i>interacted </i></em>with your post. This includes likes, shares, and comments, among a host of other actions, based on the platform.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc70174100"></a>c. Visits</h3>
<p>Visits tells you how many people went from a post to your main profile. It’s a surprisingly important metric because it tells you how much interest your post drummed up for the larger brand.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc70174101"></a>d. Mentions</h3>
<p>Mentions refers to when your brand gets a shoutout, or when someone else refers to your brand—either in passing or in the form of a review or a query. It’s a good indication of whether you’re part of the larger industry conversation.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc70174102"></a>e. Followers</h3>
<p>This one’s pretty simple; it’s the number of people who are following you on your social media page, and indicates how fast your popularity is rising. It’s also a great metric for comparisons against direct competitors.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc70174103"></a><b>9. </b><strong><b>Get Platform Specific in Your Approach</b></strong></h2>
<p>We’re not going to beat around the bush; here’s what you need to do to be successful on some core social media platforms:</p>
<p><img src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/infographic-social-advertising.jpg" alt="Infographic on how to advertise on different social media platforms" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3183" /></p>
<h2><b>10. </b><strong><b>Use Social Media As A New Frontier For Customer Service</b></strong></h2>
<p>We’ve come a long way from the days of snail mail being used to bring up customer complaints. Follow up times were atrocious, and this meant that a lot of people just never reached out</p>
<p>The opposite is true these days. Customers expect near instant replies, and that includes having a responsive Facebook Messenger and Twitter presence.</p>
<p>The best part is that both of these platforms have different levels of automation features in place, so customers don’t have to wait around for the simplest queries to be answered.</p>
<p>But to really get them on board, try to personalize the online customer service experience as much as possible. Hire a team to reply to customers with questions and complaints, and make sure you steer clear of stock answers as you talk to them.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc70174117"></a><b>11. </b><strong><b>Look For Trends </b></strong></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Old Spice ALS Ice Bucket Challenge" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WfO8LR_VosI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>From the #ALSIceBucketChallenge to dabbing, and even the dark places the internet went to with the Tide pod challenge, online pop culture never stays put.</p>
<p>The key here is to take these trends and adopt them in a way that makes sense for your brand. For example, if it’s men’s health week or breast cancer awareness day, it makes sense to highlight employees who have dealt with these issues, and <em><i>then </i></em>talk about how your brand is trying to make a difference.</p>
<p>In a similar vein, if there’s a beauty YouTube trend going around, make your own video using your in-house products if your brand sells cosmetics. Remember, your audience is really honed into content that’s not true to your brand, and any missteps can lead to mistrust.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc70174118"></a><b>12. </b><strong><b>Find the Best #hashtags</b></strong></h2>
<p>Hashtags are more versatile than you’re giving them credit for! They’re equal parts research opportunity and discoverability tool, making them really important in your social media arsenal.</p>
<p>There really are so many ways to use them:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hop aboard trends and ask people to tag your brand in the official hashtag if it’s related to your core business.</li>
<li>Host contests and ask all your followers to use the same hashtags, generating a ton of buzz around the event.</li>
<li>Figure out what hashtags are doing super well for your competitors, and start using them to divert traffic to your website.</li>
</ul>
<p>And that’s just the tip of the iceberg! There are all kinds of tools out there that allow you to find the top ranking hashtag in a certain niche, as well as how hard it is to rank for them. So don’t hesitate, and jump on board the #bandwagon.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc70174119"></a><b>13. </b><strong><b>Double Down on Social Media Optimizations</b></strong></h2>
<p>While this can get a little technical—and is often best left to the social media marketing experts—it’s important to know that even social media content can’t escape our SEO overlords.</p>
<p>But wait, what’s so hard about throwing in a couple of hashtags, right? Well, here are a few questions in rebuttal:</p>
<ul>
<li>How many hashtags for each platform before they’re counted as spam?</li>
<li>What size should the ideal Facebook featured image be?</li>
<li>How do you maximize your returns from your YouTube titles and descriptions?</li>
</ul>
<p>What we’re trying to say is, there’s a ton of platforms out there, and that means the number of variables when it comes to social media optimizations really is staggering.</p>
<p>But if you’re still going solo, here are a few time-honored social media tips:</p>
<ul>
<li>Only use hashtags that are industry specific and medium to high volume.</li>
<li>Stick to three hashtags for Twitter, Facebook, and YouTube, as many as twenty on Instagram.</li>
<li>Where there’s video content, make sure there’s also meta data to make it readable for search engines.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a name="_Toc70174120"></a><b>14. </b><strong><b>Get Social Media Experts on Board</b></strong></h2>
<p>To build upon the previous point, it really is in your best interests to hire social media marketing experts in the long-term. They can help you develop a long-term strategy that takes an omnichannel approach, while also optimizing for each platform keeping best practices in mind.</p>
<p>It’s a win-win scenario, because freeing up resources that would be otherwise spent on social media management will open you up to generating revenues using core business activities.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Social media marketing business plans that work! Need our experts to really take your social media accounts to the next level? Fill out the form below.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h1><a name="_Toc69226106"></a><a name="_Toc70174121"></a><a name="_Toc68784569"></a><a name="_Toc68802111"></a>Social Media Marketing Plans—The Key to Long-Term Success?</h1>
<p>Only a few businesses experience success as a flash in the pan; the rest of us have to put the work in! And when it comes to social media marketing plans, that means taking an all-of-the-above approach to your strategy.</p>
<p>These plans need to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Go in depth when it comes to social media platform specificities, such as when to post, how often to post, and more.</li>
<li>Have an involved understanding of the target market, and whether there are other markets that can be broken into.</li>
<li>Be aware of the resources available to execute said plan.</li>
<li>Populate the social media business planwith all kinds of nuances that come with platforms and certain business niches coming together.</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s a tall order, but with the right mix of expertise and some quick thinking, it’s more than achievable.</p>
<h1><a name="_Toc69226108"></a><a name="_Toc70174122"></a>The Ultimate Social Media Marketing Strategy For Startups and Small Businesses—Wrapping Up</h1>
<p>If your small business is feeling the heat and can’t afford to go undiscovered for a few more years, it’s time to take your social media marketing efforts up a notch!</p>
<p>Knowing how to promote your business on social media will take you a long way, but you really do stand to benefit by aligning yourself with one of the best digital marketing agencies in the U.S. We can completely <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/social-media-management/"><u>manage every aspect of your social media presence</u></a>, so you don’t have to worry about a thing!</p>
<p>For more information about our services, call <a href="tel:8554444777"><u>855-444-4777</u></a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-create-winning-social-media-strategies-for-small-businesses/">How to Create Winning Social Media Strategies for Small Businesses</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-create-winning-social-media-strategies-for-small-businesses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SEO Strategy: How To Get Backlinks With Infographics</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/seo-strategy-how-to-get-backlinks-with-infographics/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/seo-strategy-how-to-get-backlinks-with-infographics/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 16:31:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=3152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Getting Backlinks With Infographics and Guestographics Let’s start with a hard-hitting fact: just the ‘infographic’ hashtag has a weekly reach of over 64,400 people! And whether it’s B2B marketers or people looking for easy instructions for a life hack, infographics are becoming more popular than ever. Whether it’s infographics that are hosted on your website [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/seo-strategy-how-to-get-backlinks-with-infographics/">SEO Strategy: How To Get Backlinks With Infographics</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Getting Backlinks With Infographics and Guestographics</p>
<p>Let’s start with a hard-hitting fact: just the ‘infographic’ hashtag has <a href="https://app.brandmentions.com/h/p/75805/infographic"><u>a weekly reach of over 64,400 people</u></a>! And whether it’s B2B marketers or people looking for easy instructions for a life hack, infographics are becoming more popular than ever.</p>
<p>Whether it’s infographics that are hosted on your website or value additive guestographics that you customize for high DA platforms, they bring the backlinks rolling in.</p>
<p>Are Infographics Good for SEO?</p>
<p>At this point, it probably won’t shock you when we say that infographics—specifically guestographics—are still far and above one of the best ways to generate high-quality backlinks. They’re easily shareable, actually give people content they care about, and are visually appealing—a content marketing trifecta.</p>
<p>All of this leads to more traffic on your website, and proof for search engines that your domain gives a ton of value to visitors.</p>
<p>Having said this, let’s talk about how your SEO strategy needs to use infographics, so you can generate a ton of backlink juice:</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Want to get high-quality infographics made by a team of experts? Fill the form below.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p><strong>Contents</strong></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc71808549"><u>The Perfect </u><u>Infographics SEO Strategy: </u><u>An Essential Guide For Every Business</u> </a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808550"><u></u> <u>Pack Them With Content Value</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808551"><u></u> <u>Tell a Story With Your Infographics</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808552"><u></u> <u>Publish Like a Pro</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808553"><u></u> <u>Generating Backlinks With Guestographics</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808554"><u></u> <u>The More Shareable the Better</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808555"><u></u> <u>Types of Infographic Backlinks and How to Acquire Them</u> </a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808556"><u>Links From Blog Comments</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808557"><u>Links From Topic Specific Forums</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808558"><u>Links From Guestographics</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808559"><u>Links From Google Image Search</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808560"><u>Directory Links</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808561"><u>Editorial Links</u> </a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<ol start="7">
<li><a href="#_Toc71808562"><u></u> <u>It’s All in the Outreach</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808563"><u></u> <u>A Smart Approach to Collecting Data</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808564"><u></u> <u>An Eye For Good Design</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc71808565"><u></u> <u>Get Infographics Experts on Board</u> </a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc71808566"><u>Infographics and SEO</u><u>—A Backlink Match Made in Heaven?</u> </a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc71808567"><u>The Ultimate Guide to </u><u>Getting Backlinks With Infographics and Guestographics</u><u>—Wrapping Up</u> </a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><a name="_Toc68802091"></a></h1>
<h1><a name="_Toc71808549"></a>The Perfect Infographics SEO Strategy: An Essential Guide For Every Business</h1>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc71808550"></a><b>1. </b><strong><b>Pack Them With Content Value</b></strong></h2>
<p>We know we sound like a broken record, but value really is at the heart of creating infographics that people actually care about. Your infographic needs to be bursting at the seams with credible data that’s organized in a really helpful manner.</p>
<p>The best players in the biz conduct their own research, but if you don’t have access to that kind of data or the time to put it together, double down on the research process to put information together that people would otherwise have to spend hours to find on their own.</p>
<p>Remember, there’s no such thing as new information; every piece of media on the internet is a clever remix that people can’t help but go back to.</p>
<p>A few pro tips:</p>
<ul>
<li>Keep the data current, so your infographic can remain in circulation for a long time.</li>
<li>Present credible data, but make sure it doesn’t overwhelm the reader.</li>
<li>All the information should come together to tell a story.</li>
<li>The more unique your content, the more likely third parties are to publish it (a prelude to guestographics). The fresher the content, the more likely it is to be successful.</li>
<li>It always helps to create something that can be the <em><i>ultimate</i></em>guide on a specific topic.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a name="_Toc71808551"></a><b>2. </b><strong><b>Tell a Story With Your Infographics</b></strong></h2>
<p>Yes, we’ve alluded to it above, but you’d be gravely mistaken if you thought that was all there was to it when it comes to the world of <strong><b>data storytelling</b></strong>—there’s even a fancy word for it!</p>
<p>So you have your involved data points and what you want to explain, but how do you prevent the latter from drowning in the former? Data storytelling is like an artform that helps you weave together your primary narrative and your data points together seamlessly, making your infographics so much more useful and easier to follow, all while leaving them jam-packed with value additive content.</p>
<p>From a striking color palette and other visual elements to the content itself, every element interplays to create your story. Remember, humans are visual learners—so <em><i>how </i></em>you present data to them often matters far more than the substance of the data itself—that’s just how the cookie crumbles.</p>
<p>Need some more context? Check out these tips:</p>
<ul>
<li>Make sure the font and color scheme complement each other, and that the infographic sticks to them throughout.</li>
<li>Even the use of charts and boxes needs to conform to the larger aesthetic.</li>
<li>You can have different text in boxes for visual separation, but don’t make it too much of a departure.</li>
<li>Don’t crowd the infographic with too much information or too many visual elements.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here’s a sample that does a really great job at all of the above metrics:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3154" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/POS-infographic.png" alt="An infographic that has a clear narrative." width="461" height="2129" /></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc71808552"></a><b>3. </b><strong><b>Publish Like a Pro</b></strong></h2>
<p>Your work doesn’t end when you’re done crafting the perfect infographic. If you really want it to get you those oh-so-important backlinks with guestographics/infographics, you need to perfect the publishing process, so people can easily link back to you, and so it’s super shareable and discoverable.</p>
<p>For let’s talk about publishing on your own website, and we’ll move to guestographics in the next section. Here’s a breakdown:</p>
<ul>
<li>Make a new page on your website for the infographic, so there’s a direct link to it.</li>
<li>Add a write-up alongside the infographic that serves as both the description, and the SEO optimized text that will help you rank for the appropriate searches on SERPs (If you’re posting it on other websites, change the write-up to match).</li>
<li>Add embed code so publications can add your infographic to their webpage inline, all while guaranteeing that there’s a direct route to your website.</li>
<li>Add social share buttons on the page so your infographic gains more traction.</li>
<li>Don’t forget to add a great call-to-action, telling readers to share your infographic—it guarantees more conversions.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you hit all of these metrics right, you can expect a ton of shares, and for your infographic to show up on Google Search and Image Search!</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc71808553"></a><b>4. </b><strong><b>Generating Backlinks With Guestographics</b></strong></h2>
<p>As big of a deal we make of getting backlinks, here’s something very few people will tell you. The formula for getting them isn’t hard at all. It’s as simple as taking a pinch of great content and adding the right kind of targeting outreach—alongside a great value proposition.</p>
<p>Maybe you’re already emailing hundreds of people on the daily to get more links to your infographic on your website, or even to get it featured on another site or social media feed. But we reckon you’re not getting a lot of link juice if you’re reading this.</p>
<p>If so, it’s time to pay a lot more attention to the words <strong><b>targeted</b></strong> and <strong><b>value proposition</b></strong>. You see, no one will want to feature your content if there’s nothing in it for them; even if the infographic is great, you have to grease some palms before people actually engage with you. Remember, most major platforms are already getting hundreds of people reaching out every day. What makes you different?</p>
<p>Let’s take the example of this infographic on SEO:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3155" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/in-house-infographic.png" alt="searchberg infographic on seo" width="382" height="2131" /></p>
<p>How do you ensure a ton of backlinks for it; we’re glad you asked:</p>
<ul>
<li>Start by finding platforms that post exclusively about SEO—the more they’ve already covered the better.</li>
<li>Send them a <em><i>personalized</i></em>email where you refer to the editor by name, refer to already published content on their website, and then pitch your infographic as something that can augment their already great content (Pro-tip: Don’t be too pushy, ask them if they’d like to see it, don’t always attach it first).</li>
<li>But there’s more! Alongside, offer them even more value by saying you’ll write a mini guest post alongside; this really seals the deal.</li>
</ul>
<p>Here’s the best part, Google doesn’t always like links without surrounding text, but this method subverts that problem by adding a post around it. A win-win (Three times over!).</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc71808554"></a><b>5. </b><strong><b>The More Shareable the Better</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3156" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/social-platforms.png" alt="social media platforms next to a phone with an infographic" width="1121" height="747" /></p>
<p>There’s a ton of ways to make your infographic easily shareable, and all of them involve reducing the friction (or the time it takes) for a reader to take your infographic and get it on either their social feeds or their blogs.</p>
<p>Here’s a neat example; there’s a WordPress plugin called <a href="https://sumo.com/app/image-sharer"><u>Image Sharer by Sumo</u></a> that allows you to add floating social media buttons on all your infographics. It’s a low effort way of guaranteeing that everyone who is inclined to share your post will do so.</p>
<p>And don’t worry, if you’re on a different CMS, there are probably a ton of plugins that you can use to achieve the same thing. And if you have the resources, you can even code your own!</p>
<p>But that’s just the tip of the iceberg; here are some more things you <em><i>need</i></em> to do to make your infographic more shareable:</p>
<ul>
<li>Generate an embed code for your infographic so all it takes for someone to share it is a small HTML tweak.</li>
<li>Submit your infographic to high DA (domain authority) infographic submission sites and reap the benefits of their platforms.</li>
<li>Use platforms like Quora and Reddit to really get buzz around your infographic.</li>
<li>Try to submit it to other platforms using the instructions in the previous section.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a name="_Toc71808555"></a><b>6. </b><strong><b>Types of Infographic Backlinks and How to Acquire Them</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3157" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Infographics-laptop.png" alt="infographics surrounding a laptop with a backlink icon" width="500" height="402" /></p>
<p>This section is going to be information dense, but it’s also a vital one. To know how to get backlinks, you <em><i>need </i></em>to know what types of backlinks you can get. This will help you target platforms more effectively, and optimize your content accordingly too!</p>
<p>There are six primary types of backlinks you can get for infographics; here’s what they are and what you need to know about them:</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc71808556"></a>Links From Blog Comments</h3>
<p>These backlinks come either from you or a reader posting the infographic link in the comments of other blogs that cover a similar topic to what your infographic covers.</p>
<p>They’re a really high traffic driver because people love soliciting other people’s opinions on content pieces they loved, so they’re sure to peruse the comments at least once.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc71808557"></a>Links From Topic Specific Forums</h3>
<p>Yes, this also includes platforms like Reddit and Quora. People who look for specific answers to specific problems, or people who love a certain topic are very likely to click through to links that will help them.</p>
<p>And yes, while most of these will be nofollow links, they will generate more traffic to your website.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc71808558"></a>Links From Guestographics</h3>
<p>We won’t dwell on this because it’s been covered above, but remember that you have an ulterior motive when writing your guest post; try to include an author bio section at the end so people know where the infographic came from.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc71808559"></a>Links From Google Image Search</h3>
<p>You can use Google Image Search to find out who’s using your infographic without linking to it; once you identify these people, send out a mass email asking them nicely to add a link so you don’t miss out on any quality backlinks.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc71808560"></a>Directory Links</h3>
<p>Again, we’ve talked about this once above; it’s a tried and tested way of getting links from sites that probably have a much bigger reach than yours.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc71808561"></a>Editorial Links</h3>
<p>This is your white whale, and just like Melville’s <em><i>Moby Dick</i></em>, it’s going to be a tough one to catch. You might have to invest in first-hand research, and you’ll have to put your best foot forward for industry giants to use your infographics in their content. The payoff is more than worth it, though.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc71808562"></a><b>7. </b><strong><b>It’s All in the Outreach</b></strong></h2>
<p>Outreach isn’t a monolith; it’s every method you use to put your infographic out there. And you need to take an all-of-the-above approach when it comes to marketing.</p>
<p>From leveraging all of your socials to the guestographics method described above, as well as regular email outreach to your existing subscribers, you need to fire on all cylinders. The best of the best have entire outreach times that are dedicated to finding link opportunities, while also optimizing infographics for organic SEO.</p>
<p>And if you don’t have the budget for that, reach out to the professionals!</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Want to ensure that your infographic has a sizable reach and brings in a ton of traffic? Fill the form below.</h3>
<div class="inner">[blog_form1]</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc71808563"></a><b>8. </b><strong><b>A Smart Approach to Collecting Data</b></strong></h2>
<p>Finding the right data is a matter of knowing where to look, and finding data that really jumps out at readers.</p>
<p>To dwell on the latter, let’s look at two examples:</p>
<p><strong><b>22% of marketers use Facebook to increase sales</b></strong></p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p><strong><b>22% of marketers claim that Facebook has increased sales two-fold</b></strong></p>
<p>Is the difference clear to you? It’s night and day for most people. The latter is specific, and mentions a metric that business owners really care about. The first is vague, and holds no special interest for any group of people.</p>
<p>Second, really hone in on official sources that hold a lot of credibility. This means going down the Google Scholar rabbit hole, official sources with .edu or .org in their URL, and even studies commissioned by other players in your industry who aren’t competitors.</p>
<p>The goal is to gather a vast array of data points that all complement each other, allowing you to build on the primary message behind your infographic in succession.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc71808564"></a><b>9. </b><strong><b>An Eye For Good Design</b></strong></h2>
<p>We’re not going to beat around the bush; 50% of marketers primarily use visual marketing in their content, but 24% of them say that design is their biggest challenge. There’s no getting around it, people appreciate visual content more than ever, and they’re hypersensitive to bad aesthetic.</p>
<p>Your infographics thus need to have:</p>
<ul>
<li>A cohesive style when it comes to color palette, text, and spacing.</li>
<li>Complementary visual elements that embody the same style ethos.</li>
<li>A logical flow that’s easy on the eyes and makes the infographic accessible.</li>
<li>Succinct text that doesn’t dwell, and makes the infographic punchy.</li>
</ul>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3158" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/aesthetically-pleasing-infographic.png" alt="infographic with a great design" width="403" height="2129" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc71808565"></a><b>10. </b><strong><b>Get Infographics Experts on Board</b></strong></h2>
<p>It really is in your best interests to hire infographics experts in the long-term. They can help you develop a long-term strategy that takes an omnichannel approach, while also optimizing for each platform keeping best practices in mind.</p>
<p>It’s a win-win scenario, because freeing up resources that would be otherwise spent on infographics will open you up to generating revenues using core business activities.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Need our experts to really take your infographics to the next level? Fill out the form below.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><a name="_Toc71808566"></a><a name="_Toc68784569"></a><a name="_Toc68802111"></a>Infographics and SEO—A Backlink Match Made in Heaven?</h1>
<p>Infographics are an SEO powerhouse, no question about it. Whether they’re hosted on your primary website, or they’re used to generate backlinks from authoritative domains, there’s no better way to get high volume returns on your content investments.</p>
<p>Infographics can also potentially go viral, meaning you could have a major breakthrough on your hands if you play your infographics SEO strategy cards right.</p>
<h1><a name="_Toc71808567"></a>The Ultimate Guide to Getting Backlinks With Infographics and Guestographics—Wrapping Up</h1>
<p>If your small business really needs to get its infographics game going, it’s time to take your infographics SEO strategy up a notch!</p>
<p>Knowing how to promote your infographics will take you a long way, but you really do stand to benefit by aligning yourself with one of the best digital marketing agencies in the U.S. We can completely <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/infographic-design-services/"><u>manage every aspect of your infographics strategy</u></a>—from design to publishing and even SEO optimization, so you don’t have to worry about a thing!</p>
<p>For more information about our services, call <a href="tel:8554444777"><u>855-444-4777</u></a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/seo-strategy-how-to-get-backlinks-with-infographics/">SEO Strategy: How To Get Backlinks With Infographics</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/seo-strategy-how-to-get-backlinks-with-infographics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google vs Facebook What&#8217;s Better For Traffic?</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-vs-facebook-whats-better-for-traffic/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-vs-facebook-whats-better-for-traffic/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 20:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=3143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pay per click advertising services are a dime a dozen these days (and they all charge a pretty penny!). But what’s the best PPC advertising company among the major ones? This infographic breaks down the differences between two of the most popular ones—Google’s and Facebook’s pay per click advertising offerings. How much does each service’s pay per click [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-vs-facebook-whats-better-for-traffic/">Google vs Facebook What&#8217;s Better For Traffic?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3146" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Google-vs-Facebook-whats-better-for-traffic.jpg" alt="Google-vs-Facebook-whats-better-for-traffic" /></p>
<p>Pay per click advertising services are a dime a dozen these days (and they all charge a pretty penny!). But what’s the best PPC advertising company among the major ones? This infographic breaks down the differences between two of the most popular ones—Google’s and Facebook’s pay per click advertising offerings.</p>
<p>How much does each service’s pay per click advertising cost? How do you set up their PPC offerings? We answer all of these questions here.</p>
<p>Among the many metrics we look at, the most important ones are ad targeting options with regard to demographics and location, as well as contextual awareness.</p>
<p>We also help you decide what the most effective platform is based on the amount of traffic you want to generate, breaking down the pros and cons so you can make an informed decision based on a host of different factors. Find out where your audience is, what ad formats each platform has in store for you, and what your returns will look like for each.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3150" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/graph-1.jpg" alt="" width="730" height="398" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-vs-facebook-whats-better-for-traffic/">Google vs Facebook What&#8217;s Better For Traffic?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-vs-facebook-whats-better-for-traffic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Promote Your YouTube Channel: The Only Guide You Need</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-promote-your-youtube-channel-the-only-guide-you-need/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-promote-your-youtube-channel-the-only-guide-you-need/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 19:49:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[YouTube SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=3123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>YouTube’s no longer just the viral video platform that brought us keyboard cat—it can be your whole career. But isn’t YouTube stardom just for a select few; the Logan Pauls and James Charleses of the world? The answer is what you want to hear: a resounding no! As a business owner, if you play your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-promote-your-youtube-channel-the-only-guide-you-need/">How to Promote Your YouTube Channel: The Only Guide You Need</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-3126 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/image-1.jpg" alt="YouTube channel landing view" width="1500" height="990" /></p>
<p>YouTube’s no longer <em><i>just </i></em>the viral video platform that brought us keyboard cat—it can be your whole career. But isn’t YouTube stardom just for a select few; the Logan Pauls and James Charleses of the world? The answer is what you want to hear: a resounding no!</p>
<p>As a business owner, if you play your cards right and tap into the all-powerful algorithm, making it big on YouTube is beyond possible—it’s almost a certainty.</p>
<p>Want to promote your channel for free? Grow your YouTube subscriber count? Get more traffic and conversions than ever on your small business or personal YouTube account? Well, then you’re in the right place!</p>
<p>The best part? You don’t need existing subscribers or deep pockets for these YouTube channel promotion tips (we’ll tell you when one of the steps is paid). Let’s get started:</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Want to hand over YouTube channel management to the pros? Fill out the form below to get in touch with us.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p><strong>Contents</strong></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc69150608"><u>How to Promote Your YouTube Channel</u><u>: 13 Strategies That Work!</u> </a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150609"><u></u> <u>Tap Into the Power of SEO &#8211; Paid</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150610"><u>a)</u> <u>Come Up With a Killer Title</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150611"><u>b)</u> <u>Make Full Use of Video Descriptions</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150612"><u>c)</u> <u>#Hashtags For the Win</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150613"><u>d)</u> <u>Tap Into Tags For Even More Discoverability</u> </a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc69150614"><u>Some Takeaways</u> </a></p>
<ol start="2">
<li><a href="#_Toc69150615"><u></u> <u>Big Collaborations for Big Success</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150616"><u></u> <u>Don’t Forget to Engage With Your Audience</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150617"><u></u> <u>Call(s) to Action</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150618"><u></u> <u>Choose the Right Length For Your Videos</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150619"><u></u> <u>To Invest in </u><u>YouTube PPC Campaigns</u><u>or not to? (Paid)</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150620"><u></u> <u>Jump on the Trending and Evergreen Content Ship</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150621"><u></u> <u>Doubling Down on Successful Content Strategies</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150622"><u></u> <u>To Facebook and Beyond</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150623"><u></u> <u>Comment Ça Va? Find a Worldwide Audience</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150624"><u></u> <u>Branding</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150625"><u></u> <u>Contests and Giveaways</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc69150626"><u></u> <u>Consistency</u> </a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc69150627"><u>How to Grow Your New YouTube Channel?</u> </a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc69150628"><u>What Are the Best Places to </u><u>Promote Your YouTube Channel</u><u>?</u> </a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc69150629"><u>What Do You Hope to Get Out of </u><u>Promoting Your YouTube Channel</u><u>—Wrapping Up</u> </a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1><strong>How to Promote Your YouTube Channel</strong><strong>: 13 Strategies That Work!</strong></h1>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68802092"></a>1. <a name="_Toc69150609"></a>Tap Into the Power of SEO &#8211; Paid</h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3127" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/creator-studio-screenshot.jpg" alt="A screenshot of the ultimate tool for YouTube SEO, Creator Studio" width="554" height="221" /></p>
<p>It’s time to take control of your YouTube destiny; so let’s start with a strategy with a ton of bang for your buck. Whether you want to promote your YouTube channel for free or go all in and benefit from a full suite of SEO services, there’s something here for everyone.</p>
<p>SEO is one of those things everyone knows a little about. Most people know that it involves:</p>
<ul>
<li>keywords</li>
<li>optimization</li>
<li>alt text,</li>
<li>and more</li>
</ul>
<p>But even as these words are tossed around by people around you, very few people can claim expertise in it. <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/youtube-seo-smart-digital-marketing-in-2019-to-expand-your-audience-promote-your-business-and-strengthen-your-brand/"><u>We’ve written about this previously</u></a>, so take a look if you’re interested.</p>
<p>So let’s get specific; here are some steps you can take to ensure that the YouTube algorithm laps up your content:</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc69150610"></a>a) <a name="_Toc68802093"></a>Come Up With a Killer Title</h3>
<p>The thumbnail (more on this later) and title are your first points of contact with potential subscribers; so, you need to invest a lot of time into getting them right.</p>
<p>Your titles need to strike the right balance between compelling and informative (and they can never be spammy). You also need to keep them short; 60 characters is the sweet spot.</p>
<p>Here’s a description that’s toeing the line:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3128" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/sample-title-youtube.jpg" alt="Example of how to use titles to promote a YouTube video to get more views." width="366" height="76" /></p>
<p>The views speak for themselves, but what is it about the title that gets so many views? Well, it’s got volume for one—15 hacks mean a meaty video, and people love bang for their YouTube buck (read: time). On top of that, the word hacks, coupled with genius, elevates the video above others; say, for example, one that said “4 Plumbing Hacks You Need to Know.” Generating excitement is super important in titles.</p>
<p><strong>Pro tip: Try to get all your essential keywords in the beginning of the title; doing so really does maximize views—people on YouTube are usually looking for solutions, so don’t waste their time. </strong></p>
<p>As for the compelling bit, let’s look at an example. Say you’re running a diet and lifestyle channel, and are making an explainer video about the differences between the Keto Diet and the Atkins diet. Let’s take a look at two title options:</p>
<p><strong><b>Our Take on the Timeless Atkins vs. Keto Debate</b></strong></p>
<p>Vs.</p>
<p><strong><b>Comparison of Atkins and Keto</b></strong></p>
<p>Most of us would click on the first one over the second—at least we hope so. It puts your personality front and center (our take), and has both the essential keywords in about 50 characters or so. That’s a win!</p>
<p>So what’s a winning formula for keywords? Here’s a breakdown:</p>
<ul>
<li>Use the YouTube autocomplete suggestions to find keywords that your audience is actually using.</li>
<li>Avoid stuffing keywords into the title—use as many as you can without stylistic compromises.</li>
<li>Pair keywords with titles that spark curiosity.</li>
<li>Modify keywords as needed to—YouTube, like Google, can make out semantic differences.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a name="_Toc69150611"></a>b) <a name="_Toc68802094"></a>Make Full Use of Video Descriptions</h3>
<p>Good descriptions follow many of the same rules that good titles do; it’s just a difference of volume—5,000 as opposed to 60 characters.</p>
<p>Like the titles, keywords should be front and center; but there’s more! You can use descriptions to send view counts soaring across your channel. Do this by:</p>
<ul>
<li>Linking to existing videos that didn’t get the success they deserve, or</li>
<li>by directing views to an entire playlist of similar content.</li>
</ul>
<p>Let’s talk examples now:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3129" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/sample-youtube-description.jpg" alt="Screenshot of video marketing strategy on YouTube by using descriptions to their full potential." width="500" height="354" /></p>
<p>MKBHD isn’t the biggest tech YouTuber out there for nothing—notice how he plugs in his merch page, his Amazon affiliate link, <em><i>and</i></em> a playlist of other videos in one description, while also having all his socials there too.</p>
<p>So, the takeaway is: give the people what they want, and watch the views roll in.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68784573"></a>c) <a name="_Toc68802095"></a><a name="_Toc69150612"></a>#Hashtags For the Win</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3130" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/youtube-hashtags.jpg" alt="A screenshot of YouTube hashtags" width="488" height="55" /></p>
<p>YouTube recently introduced hashtags, and they took the platform by storm not soon after. Much like Twitter, use them to send people down a discoverability rabbit hole. Just make sure you’re using the right ones (tools like Google’s Keyword Planner are your best bet here)</p>
<p>Viewers who click on them and find similar content are much more likely to binge watch it. We like to call it the hashtag hook, line, and sinker.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc69150613"></a>d) Tap Into Tags For Even More Discoverability</h3>
<p>YouTube’s Creator Studio allows you to embed tags—essentially keywords that you want to rank for—in your videos. They’re the least important piece of the YouTube metadata puzzle, but they can get you over the edge when it comes to discovery.</p>
<p>We always suggest adding them because in your quest toward eventual bigtime YouTube fame, you can’t leave any stone unturned.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68784575"></a><a name="_Toc68802097"></a><a name="_Toc69150614"></a>Some Takeaways</h3>
<p>Remember, Google owns YouTube, and it’ll always be a search company first. And search and SEO go hand in hand. This means you need to know the algorithm really well—how it works, what kind of content it prefers, and what it doesn’t.</p>
<p>For example, YouTube transcribes your entire video every time you upload, so even your videos aren’t exempt from keyword optimization!</p>
<p>If this sounds overwhelming, we have some good news: the map to success is already in front of you; all you need to do is see how others are optimizing their videos (especially the most successful creators) and follow suit.</p>
<p>YouTube SEO is involved, we’re not going to lie; if the time investment is too much for you because of the millions of other responsibilities you have, you could always <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-services/"><u>hire us to do it for you</u></a>—we’d be glad to help.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc69150615"></a>2. Big Collaborations for Big Success</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3131" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/beauty-youtubers-collab.jpg" alt="A screenshot of a video of beauty influencers all collaborating, which collectively promotes all their YouTube channels" width="602" height="119" /></p>
<p>The first question that popped up in your head after reading this was probably: “<em><i>But who would want to collaborate with me when I have no views or subscribers?</i></em>”</p>
<p>The answer, surprisingly, is that a lot of bigger creators would. The key is to perfect the two Ps: the pitch and persistence.</p>
<p>A lot of bigger creators are looking for an opportunity to shine a spotlight on up-and-coming talent—and if you’ve been a long-time subscriber, they’re even more likely to take you up on the offer, especially if you’re in the same niche.</p>
<p>Make it beneficial for them—content ideas like fan Q&amp;As are surefire hits; it’s an offer that’s hard to say no to.</p>
<p>But what, why do you want to do this, again? Here are some obvious benefits:</p>
<ul>
<li>The scale of their much bigger platform.</li>
<li>The collab will send viewers torpedoing toward your channel, while also giving you a ton of credibility.</li>
</ul>
<p>Everyone respects clout; so standing in the shadow of a YouTube giant won’t dim your light; it’ll help you shine brighter than ever. In the business, we call it building industry authority.</p>
<p>Not to mention that bigger creators have really diverse audiences; this can open you up to so many new content possibilities as your subscribers diversify.</p>
<p>Remember, YouTube is a personality-first platform; as long as you have an electric personality and are good at what you do, other creators will be on board.</p>
<p>The best part is that there are no consequences with reaching out—it’s free, and the worst you can expect to hear is radio silence.</p>
<p>Another option is to partner with other influencers or even endorse a business’s product; a lot of businesses will pay to promote your content if their product is in it—it’s a you scratch my back world out there—which can be a great equalizer if you don’t have a PPC budget to speak of.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc69150616"></a>3. Don’t Forget to Engage With Your Audience</h2>
<p>Just like Kendrick Lamar, it’s important to stay humble and remember who got you the success you have today. In this case, it’s your existing audience!</p>
<p>As it turns out, the biggest advantage you have is how small your YouTube presence is. Lost us? Let us explain: People love content creators who exude charm and have an electric personality—the problem is one of discoverability, not talent.</p>
<p>So, when you do start attracting a (small) audience, it’s very likely that they’ll start feeling a sense of belonging with you due to the intimate, small nature of your account.</p>
<p>A small audience of, say, 500 people allows you to engage with every single comment. It allows you to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Send push notifications that are customized.</li>
<li>Highlight some subscribers in every video (who doesn’t love a shoutout!).</li>
<li>Have a back-and-forth conversation with them where you address them by name.</li>
</ul>
<p>All of these are super underrated promotional techniques that go a long way.</p>
<p>Your subscribers are very likely to rave about you in their inner circles, which will have a trickle-down effect on your follower count.</p>
<p>Sure, the more success you get the less intimate the channel will be, but it’s important to double down on this while you’re a small creator.</p>
<p>Remember, all this requires is you putting yourself out there and being true to yourself; try not to perform or put on a persona (unless that’s what your account is about) and have honest conversations with your audience. Nothing works better on YouTube than a bit of vulnerability.</p>
<p>Even large channels take out the time to do this:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3132" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/viewer-engagement-youtube.jpg" alt="Comment replies and engagement, and example of a solid YouTube marketing strategy." width="602" height="336" /></p>
<p>Notice how the guys over at Hardware Unboxed have liked the first comment, and have also left one of their trademark Aussie witticisms under another; viewers love being made to feel special—it can set you up for a lifetime of loyalty.</p>
<p>You also want to know them like you know the back of your hand; remember, YouTube doesn’t give you tons of analytics data for kicks—tap into their demographics, locations, preferences, etc. to make content accordingly.</p>
<p>You also want to rely on your subscribers to double down on your success—is someone subscribed but hasn’t clicked the vaunted bell icon? Ask them to in a video!</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68784578"></a>4. <a name="_Toc68802100"></a><a name="_Toc69150617"></a>Call(s) to Action</h2>
<p>YouTube is probably the only platform where you can get away with adding all kinds of calls to action to your content.</p>
<p>We already hinted as much with the title and the thumbnail, but you can double down with multiple CTAs in your video.</p>
<p>You’ve probably seen hundreds of YouTube videos that ask you to “click on the bell icon to get my videos the moment I post them.” Yep, that’s a CTA.</p>
<p>How about this one: “Remember to like and subscribe to my channel if you enjoyed my video.” Also a CTA.</p>
<p>And the thing is, it works; videos with multiple compelling CTAs get viewers to take a desired action. Why? Because YouTube is, you guessed it, a personality-first platform, if people like you enough, they won’t find this spammy.</p>
<p>It <em><i>can </i></em>get spammy if done too much, so try to figure out where the line is, and never cross it. This is the most important thing you need to figure out when trying to promote your YouTube videos.</p>
<p><strong><b>Here’s a small scenario to demonstrate</b></strong>:</p>
<p>A long-time subscriber to your household hacks channel hasn’t been getting your videos in their feed for some reason (it happens a lot!). But then they navigate over to your channel to see what you’ve been up to.</p>
<p>When they do, the first thing they hear in your latest video is that a lot of people haven’t been seeing your videos, and to click on the bell icon to get push notifications. If the person loves your content and persona, it’s more than likely that they’ll follow through.</p>
<p>Plus, YouTube then gets a signal that people want more of your content, and the algorithm will play ball accordingly.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc69150618"></a>5. Choose the Right Length For Your Videos</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3133" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/nyan-cat.jpg" alt="screenshot of a long nyan cat video used as an example of how not to promote YouTube videos" width="602" height="373" /></p>
<p><strong><b>Don’t follow in the footsteps of this </b></strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SkgTxQm9DWM"><strong><u><b>10-hour Nyan Cat video</b></u></strong></a><strong><b>!</b></strong></p>
<p>Depending on what kind of content you make, the length of your videos really does determine whether viewers stick around till the end. If you’re a mukbanger, for example, long-form videos are actually the de facto route, since many people like to eat their meals alongside these videos. And you don’t want to be done before they are!</p>
<p>But if you’re running a channel that gives people tips and life hacks that help them fix things around the home space, viewers will really appreciate shorter videos because all they want is that broken pipe to stop leaking.</p>
<p>The good news is that YouTube gives all kinds of metrics; so, all you need to do is track when people stop watching, how engaged people are in different sections of the video, and what video lengths on your channel are most popular. Once you find the winning formula for your niche, it’ll be smooth sailing.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68784580"></a>6. <a name="_Toc68802102"></a><a name="_Toc69150619"></a>To Invest in YouTube PPC Campaigns or not to? (Paid)</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3134" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/youtube-ads-signup-sheet.jpg" alt="A screenshot of the signup sheet for YouTube ads, one of the best ways to grow a YouTube channel" width="602" height="244" /></p>
<p>So far, we’ve kept the focus squarely on how you can promote your YouTube channel without spending money—it’s in the title! But let’s spend just a little time on whether you should spend money on PPC. Is the payoff worth it? Yes and no!</p>
<p>If you spend a ton of money on PPC and don’t have a lot of content, viewers will arrive at your channel and find the elephant graveyard from <em><i>Lion King</i></em>—that is to say, a ghost town with no content to consume.</p>
<p>They won’t subscribe, and it may even leave a bad taste in their mouths. So, should you only stick to the organic tips in this blog? For now, yes, but after months of producing content and building a solid portfolio—especially if you’ve had no luck getting viewers—it may be time to dip your hand in the PPC cookie jar.</p>
<p>Just remember to limit your spend and to keep prioritizing organic results. And when you’re ready to advertise your YouTube channel, our <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/youtube-advertising/"><u>expertise in YouTube advertising</u></a> will ensure you get every dollar’s worth from your campaign.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68784581"></a>7. <a name="_Toc68802103"></a><a name="_Toc69150620"></a>Jump on the Trending and Evergreen Content Ship</h2>
<p>Plumbing pipes can burst in perpetuity. And while that’s a sad fact, it also means that if you have a video on your channel that helps people fix this problem, they’ll keep coming back to it whenever things go south.</p>
<p>The same goes for channels that feature recipes; if it tickles viewers’ tastebuds, you can bet they’ll come back for a second serving. Encourage viewers to bookmark such content, put it on playlists, and even share it with others. This will multiply the number of viewers you get on every video.</p>
<p>But evergreen content isn’t all there is to it; there’s also the opposite—flashes in the pan like the #ALSIceBucketChallenge. Just remember, when jumping on a bandwagon, paint it in your own colors.</p>
<p>What we mean to say is, you can’t just do what everyone else is doing—think of how you can put a personal spin on these trends because that’s what brought your followers to you in the first place.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68784582"></a>8. <a name="_Toc68802104"></a><a name="_Toc69150621"></a>Doubling Down on Successful Content Strategies</h2>
<p>If you have a video that made a wave in the YouTube space, but the rest of your videos fell flat, it’s probably a safe bet to make a second part to that video.</p>
<p>YouTube is a limited risk game; you take gambit after gambit until you find a strategy that works for you—and then you should stick to it.</p>
<p>We’re not saying you shouldn’t make any big content bets anymore, just that you need to have a stable of ol’ reliable content that you can always bank on during a dry spell.</p>
<p>Here’s a few ideas to ensure great viewership numbers:</p>
<ul>
<li>Put the series of videos you make into playlists.</li>
<li>At the end of every video, remind your viewers to check out all the other videos in the playlist.</li>
</ul>
<p>Also remember that YouTube gives you a lot of tools—use them! From the channel introduction video to featured videos, and recently, YouTube Shorts and Stories (the last two particularly are known for bringing in a swarm of new viewers), if you tap into YouTube’s full potential, you’re looking at a future success story.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68784583"></a>9. <a name="_Toc68802105"></a><a name="_Toc69150622"></a>To Facebook and Beyond</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3136" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/other-social-media-platforms.jpg" alt="An image of social media platforms Instagram, Facebook, and Twitter" width="1000" height="1000" /></p>
<p>You can’t just stay on a YouTube shaped island if you’re going to make it big on the platform. You need to venture out and sail to other social media shores.</p>
<p>Facebook, for example, has hundreds of groups for all kinds of industry niches. These groups are rife with conversion potential, because you already know that the people on them are deeply invested in the type of content you produce. If you want to promote your YouTube videos on Facebook, this is the holy grail.</p>
<p>But don’t just post links to your videos ad nauseam; it’ll be considered spam and might even get you booted! Instead, build relationships on these groups, help people out, and establish trust. Alongside, use your Facebook profile as a landing page of sorts—the people you help will click on your profile, and when they do, they’ll see that you’re also a content creator.</p>
<p>At this point, because of the work you’ve put in, they’re <em><i>very </i></em>likely to click through and subscribe. The spillover effect is that YouTube will get a ton of search signals from this, indicating that your channel is one they want to promote and put forward in recommendations.</p>
<p>For Instagram, don’t make the mistake of using it as a promotional page; no one wants to see a whole feed of “new video up, link in the bio!” It’s repetitive, and just a bad strategy overall. Instead, use your Insta feed like a lifestyle page; it’s an added flair that’ll flesh out your online presence.</p>
<p>Don’t cage yourself in by only looking for keywords that rank in YouTube search. Videos are taking Google SERPs by storm, so you really want to be making content that can rank on the first page of Google for a given keyword.</p>
<p>Ask bloggers and other platform holders—nicely—to embed your content; if you see a blog that’s lacking a video element, for example, and yours fits in like the last piece of the puzzle, drop the platform a pitch.</p>
<p>The last bit, ask yourself; no, this isn’t a spirituality thing; we mean to say that if you already have a website with pages that rake in traffic, embed your videos on those pages to take your success into your own hands!</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68784584"></a>10. <a name="_Toc68802106"></a><a name="_Toc69150623"></a>Comment Ça Va? Find a Worldwide Audience</h2>
<p>Here’s an open YouTube secret that too few creators know about: the more languages you translate your videos into, the more subscribers you’re going to get. And it’s pretty much a given!</p>
<p>But wait, what do closed captions have to do with viewer counts? Remember that little thing called the YouTube algorithm? Well, as it turns out, it wants what’s best for viewers. So the videos it serves to them are always in languages they understand—and this includes captioned videos!</p>
<p>And the good news doesn’t even stop there—YouTube is also a lot less competitive for other languages, so the chances of you swooping in and becoming the content czar in your industry niche are pretty high, we’d say.</p>
<p>This propels you to new heights in terms of reach, and the diversity in your audience will also give you more content possibilities than ever before!</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68784586"></a>11. <a name="_Toc68802108"></a><a name="_Toc69150624"></a>Branding</h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>[EMBED VIDEO FROM SEARCH BERG CHANNEL]</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Fk48tDAVCQ"><u>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Fk48tDAVCQ</u></a></p>
<p>Aesthetic optimizations may seem like they’re a bottom of the barrel optimization, but that approach doesn’t keep in mind how attuned we’ve become to consuming visual content, and how eagle-eyed viewers are when it comes to tacky branding.</p>
<p>For instance, your thumbnails could be even more important than titles when it comes to people clicking through. What can we say, aesthetic is everything these days!</p>
<p>You should really consider—and when we say that, we mean you need to—making custom thumbnails for all your videos; the funnier they are, the more likely they are to attract viewers (but this does depend on the type of content).</p>
<p>Your videos also need to look super professional; you can’t afford to make any compromises here, as even though most people wouldn’t know the first thing about making one, we’re all hyper-attuned to when a video just doesn’t look right—it’s glaringly obvious! And the last thing you want is to fall victim to the YouTube aesthetic police.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Video marketing strategies that work! Need our branding experts to audit your existing YouTube account? Fill out the form below.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc68784587"></a>12. <a name="_Toc68802109"></a><a name="_Toc69150625"></a>Contests and Giveaways</h2>
<p>People love free stuff; it’s an undeniable fact. So when you couple your already small community with the occasional giveaway, your audience will know that their chances of winning are a lot higher than on a channel with millions of viewers.</p>
<p>This is a really solid inceptive that taps into our collective love of free things, without the usual doom and gloom around people saying “I could never win.”</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68802110"></a>13. <a name="_Toc69150626"></a>Consistency</h2>
<p>Let us hammer the point home: consistency really is the most important factor on this entire list—by far. Like all the other strategies, we defer to the actions of the algorithm.</p>
<p>For YouTube, the best creators are those that are always plugging away at content creation, and churning it out on a regular schedule. Why? Because it turns out that more people tuning in to the platform to watch their favorite creators’ daily or weekly videos is great for business!</p>
<p>But more than that, your videos—if your content is up to snuff, can become like traditions for your viewers. How many times have you heard someone say “It’s Wednesday, Tati’s going to drop that new makeup tutorial today?” or something along the same lines? That’s because we thrive on routine—so give viewers what they want.</p>
<p>At least one video a week is generally considered good practice. But two quality concepts is where the fame and fortune are at! You need to treat YouTube like a full-time job if you’re going to make it on the platform.</p>
<p>Oh, and alongside, your posts should be diverse too, because the last thing you want is users getting bored of the same kind of content being posted over and over.</p>
<p>We get it, this sounds like a lot, but if your work takes up most of your time and you can’t devote the time to YouTube, there are always services out there that can do it for you.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Don’t have time to manage your own YouTube channel? That’s what we’re here for! Fill out the form to get started today.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form4" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject4" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name4" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website4" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email4" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number4" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country4" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha4();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h1><a name="_Toc69150627"></a><strong><a name="_Toc68784569"></a><a name="_Toc68802111"></a>How to Grow Your New YouTube Channel?</strong></h1>
<p>The first 1,000 subscribers are the hardest, so we suggest kicking posting activity into high gear until you get to that benchmark.</p>
<p>There’s a snowball effect as you get more subscribers, with shares and word of mouth making the task substantially easier. So remember when we said consistency was your golden ticket? Well, the first few months are when the hustle really is vital.</p>
<p>Get your social circle to share your channel, leverage all the social media strategies in the blog, and fire on all cylinders to ensure you make it big.</p>
<h1><a name="_Toc69150628"></a><strong>What Are the Best Places to </strong><strong>Promote Your YouTube Channel</strong><strong>?</strong></h1>
<p>We’ve touched upon this above, but to really solidify your options, here’s where you should be promoting your YouTube channel:</p>
<ul>
<li>For a channel that does a lot of DIYs, Facebook groups and platforms like Quora are your best bet. Use them to build relationships by helping people, and watch your organic views soar!</li>
<li>For YouTube Shorts and TikTok compilations, as well as other short-format videos, use the Stories feature on all your social media accounts; this is especially successful on Instagram.</li>
<li>If you’re a vlogger, make bite-sized Facebook content that’s shareable, and make your Instagram page a behind-the-scenes style feed.</li>
</ul>
<p>There are way too many categories of content creators to count, so if you want specific feedback regarding your niche, reach out to us, and we’d be glad to make a game plan for you!</p>
<p>We have a pretty <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/social-media-management/"><u>comprehensive set of social media management services</u></a> too, so you really can’t go wrong.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Need the pros to promote your YouTube channel on social media? That’s what we’re here for! Fill out the form to get started today.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form4" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject5" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name5" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website5" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email5" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number5" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country5" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha5();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h1><a name="_Toc69150629"></a><strong>What Do You Hope to Get Out of </strong><strong>Promoting Your YouTube Channel</strong><strong>—Wrapping Up</strong></h1>
<p>Your point of reference matters a whole lot. Your YouTube KPIs fundamentally change based on whether you’re a small creator who makes DIY science videos or a rising commerce startup that’s looking to cover more ground on the web.</p>
<p>Yes, the general rule of thumb is that more followers are better, but <em><i>what kind </i></em>of followers do you want to attract to meet your goals? If making sales is the primary motive for your woodwork business, for example, your best case scenario is a large number of high income Gen Xers.</p>
<p>But if you’re hoping to become the next Mr. Beast, you want to go to the other end of the spectrum and court Gen Zers.</p>
<p>The takeaway? Knowing how to promote your YouTube channel will take you a long way, but you really do stand to benefit by aligning yourself with one of the best digital marketing agencies in the U.S. We can completely manage <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-services/"><u>YouTube SEO</u></a> and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/youtube-advertising/"><u>YouTube advertising campaigns</u></a>!</p>
<p>For more information about our services, call <a href="tel:8554444777"><u>855-444-4777</u></a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-promote-your-youtube-channel-the-only-guide-you-need/">How to Promote Your YouTube Channel: The Only Guide You Need</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-promote-your-youtube-channel-the-only-guide-you-need/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Best CMS for a Successful Website</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Jensen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 09:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Content Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a quest to design a website for your business, it&#8217;s likely that you&#8217;ve come across the term &#8220;CMS&#8221; a few times. A CMS or Content Management System can make setting up and running your website incredibly straight-forward. In this blog, you&#8217;ll discover the top 10 Content Management Systems out there to support your website, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/">10 Best CMS for a Successful Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a quest to design a website for your business, it&#8217;s likely that you&#8217;ve come across the term &#8220;CMS&#8221; a few times. A CMS or Content Management System can make setting up and running your website incredibly straight-forward.</p>
<p><span id="more-2621"></span></p>
<p>In this blog, you&#8217;ll discover the top 10 Content Management Systems out there to support your website, factors to consider when choosing a CMS, and how the best CMS can boost your SEO.</p>
<p>Because of various CMS platforms, you’re left wondering: which CMS should I use?</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s start by defining <strong><em>what a CMS is</em></strong> and how it helps you build your website effectively.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Do you want a killer, professionally designed website that drives sales? Fill out the form below to get in touch with us.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2>Contents</h2>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181237">What is a CMS?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181238">10 Best CMS Software for 2021</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181239"> WordPress</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181241"> Drupal</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181243"> Joomla</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181244"> Magento</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181246"> HubSpot</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181248"> BigCommerce</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181250"> Shopify</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181251"> Squarespace</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181253">Wix</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181254"> Weebly</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181255">What Factors Do You Need to Consider When Choosing a CMS?</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181256"> Pricing Features that are Right for You</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181257"> Stellar Support</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181258"> Which Content Management System Will Support Your SEO Best?</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181259"> Ease of Personalization and Design</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181260"> Website Security</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181261"> Easy Website Migration Capabilities</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181262">The Best Content Management Systems for SEO &amp; Why</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181263"> WordPress</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181264"> Drupal</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181265"> Magento</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181266"> Hubspot</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc68181267"> Shopify</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc68181268">Wrapping Up!</a></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68181237"></a>What is a CMS?</h2>
<p>A CMS, or Content Management System, is a system that allows you to create a website without actually writing any code such as HTML or Java.</p>
<p>Ok, clear so far. Now why do we use CMS?</p>
<p>Without Content Management Systems, those businesses that wanted to create websites would need to rely on experienced coders or learn the languages ourselves. Thankfully, we have Content Management Systems (CMS) at our disposal.</p>
<p>So, a CMS like WordPress makes the process of not only designing, but also <em>managing websites</em> significantly easier and more streamlined.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68181238"></a>10 Best CMS Software for 2021</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181239"></a>1. WordPress: Cost &#8211; $0</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2634" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog2-1.png" alt="wordpress" width="1899" height="804" /><br />
<a href="https://www.searchberg.com/wordpress-seo/">WordPress</a> is the most widely used CMS platform for websites. Using WordPress, you can create any kind of website, including a company website, personal portfolio, online store, etc.</p>
<p>There are many benefits of WordPress. In terms of design freedom, WordPress has thousands of designs available for users to download and use, whether they&#8217;re directly from WordPress or third party WordPress theme websites like <a href="https://themeforest.net/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">ThemeForest</a>.</p>
<p>In addition to being free, WordPress is also great for SEO. It allows you to easily create tags, update URLs and categories, and add separate plug-ins to improve your website&#8217;s SEO.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg" alt="WordPress CMS features from their website's home page." width="730" height="651" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2637" /></p>
<p>The only downside is you&#8217;ll need to purchase your own domain through a domain hosting platform like <a href="https://www.bluehost.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">BlueHost</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181241"></a>2. Drupal: Cost &#8211; $0</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2632" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-9.png" alt="Drupal" width="1891" height="672" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/drupal-seo/">Drupal</a> is super helpful if you have a huge amount of data you want to add on your website. It&#8217;s helpful for this purpose because it can handle extreme customization requirements and data.</p>
<p>It has an in-built user system where you can manage what users can and cannot do. It has a vast array of themes available and you can increase Drupal&#8217;s functions using modules. It has previously installed automation tools for SEO as well.</p>
<p>While you will need a hosting provider, <a href="https://www.drupal.org/hosting" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">here</a> is a list of providers that support Drupal users.</p>
<p>Drupal is also trusted by the following trusted brands.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2631" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-8.png" alt="Six trusted brands known to use Drupal for their websites, promoting it as one of the best CMS software." width="1063" height="477" /></p>
<p>You should know that because the interface is designed to handle complex tasks fit for developers, Drupal is less beginner-friendly relative to WordPress. In addition, its themes can also be pricey.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181243"></a>3. Joomla: Cost &#8211; $0</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2630" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-7.png" alt="The Jooma CMS home page showing three options: to download, use, and learn Joomla." width="1259" height="846" /></p>
<p>As with WordPress and Drupal, you&#8217;re going to need to buy a domain separately. While <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/joomla-seo/">Joomla</a> is also a veteran in the CMS game like WordPress, it&#8217;s equipped to handle large amounts of data and tasks that it can be daunting for beginners. In addition, it features a built-in user access system that allows you to regulate actions of registered users.</p>
<p>If you choose to go with Joomla and have little web development experience, you&#8217;d benefit from hiring a developer to handle building your website.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181244"></a>4. Magento: Cost &#8211; Free, Kind Of.</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2629" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog2.png" alt="Magento" width="1895" height="812" /><br />
Magento is a CMS specifically designed for e-commerce platforms. While there are some standard SEO functions, you&#8217;ll need to download a good extension for more abilities. One example of these extensions is the free Creare SEO 2.0 extension.</p>
<p>While you can certainly access Magento for free using the software Magento OpenSource, you also have the option of paying Magento to manage it on their end. This can start from two grand USD per month.</p>
<p>While Magento is a highly secure, powerful CMS, it&#8217;s not forgiving to beginners and will need you to have technical knowledge or someone on your team who does.</p>
<p>If you own a B2B Ecommerce store and are looking to improve your conversions, check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/11-ways-to-triple-your-b2b-ecommerce-conversions/">11 Ways To Triple Your B2B Ecommerce Conversions.</a></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181246"></a>5. HubSpot: Cost &#8211; $300/mo</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2628" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-6.png" alt="HubSpot" width="1709" height="902" /><br />
Among other benefits, HubSpot provides 24 hour website security and support. The CMS works for users whether you&#8217;re a beginner or a developer because you have the option to write code directly or use the drag-and-drop features.</p>
<p>For that price point, it should be easy to use!</p>
<p>As a bonus, you&#8217;ll also get SEO recommendations and easy A/B testing capabilities in your website.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181248"></a>6. BigCommerce: Cost &#8211; $30/mo</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2627" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-5.png" alt="BigCommerce" width="1894" height="808" /><br />
<a href="https://www.searchberg.com/bigcommerce-seo/">BigCommerce</a> is also specifically for ecommerce stores, as implied by its name. The biggest selling point for BigCommerce is that it allows you to sell products through your own ecommerce website and big ecommerce marketplaces like Amazon and Ebay.</p>
<p>You can either obtain a free domain name from BigCommerce which will have their brand name in the URL or you can purchase a custom domain.</p>
<p>BigCommerce does lack a little in the design department, but you can integrate your BigCommerce site with WordPress to resolve that issue.</p>
<p>The $30 covers a lot for starting companies and sole proprietors, but BigCommerce also has <strong><em>big</em></strong>-ger options with more features for larger organizations.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve ever wondered what CMS big companies use, if it&#8217;s an ecommerce company then it&#8217;s likely BigCommerce.</p>
<p>If you make more than 50,000 USD in sales per year, then you&#8217;ll automatically be bumped up to the more pricey plan which is about $250 per month, so keep that in mind for your expenses.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181250"></a>7. Shopify: Cost &#8211; $29/mo</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2626" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-4.png" alt="The Shopify home page which shows their slogan that anyone, anywhere can start a business online" width="1245" height="614" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/shopify-seo/">Shopify</a> is a simple, drag-and-drop, beginner-friendly CMS for ecommerce. It&#8217;s very straightforward and allows you to accept payments through multiple ways, including Shopify Payments and PayPal.</p>
<p>Additionally, Shopify has apps you can install to your store that make it easy to increase your features. For example, if you&#8217;re dropshipping products, you can import reviews from your third-party supplier&#8217;s website using apps.</p>
<p>While it has a more pricey option of around $300 per month that has more features, unlike BigCommerce, it doesn&#8217;t automatically upgrade your plan.</p>
<p>Shopify&#8217;s main advantage is its simplicity because it handles hosting, security, and site maintenance. These crucial benefits of Shopify leave you free to go out and get customers.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181251"></a>8. Squarespace: cost &#8211; starting at $16/mo</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/squarespace-seo/">Squarespace</a> is great for less technical users who just want to create a basic website. So, personal websites, portfolio websites, and even company websites are easily made using Squarespace.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2625" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-3.png" alt="Squarespace's company message &quot;Simple tools for big ideas&quot; echoing the consensus that it is indeed a simple tool for beginners and non-complex website requirements." width="544" height="383" /></p>
<p>They&#8217;re not the best for ecommerce stores because it&#8217;s so simple that your operation won&#8217;t be heavy-weight, per se.</p>
<p>If you require more robust functionality in your website, though, Squarespace isn&#8217;t your best option.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181252"></a>9. Wix: Cost &#8211; Starts From $14/mo</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2624" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-2.png" alt="wix.com" width="1687" height="890" /></p>
<p style="text-align: right;">&#8211; wix.com</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/wix-seo/">Wix</a> is an incredible platform for beginners who want to make a website. With their subscription, you can pay monthly or annually, and their drag-and-drop features make constructing a website significantly stream-lined.</p>
<p>You should remember, though, that with its simplicity and user-friendliness come some costs. For example, once you choose a designated template for your website, you can&#8217;t change it.</p>
<p>The good thing is that each theme is adaptable to mobiles, tablets, and desktops, so there&#8217;s no bad template options here even if you get pigeon-holed into one template style.</p>
<p>The ecommerce options for Wix will also be limited because it only accepts certain payment pathways like PayPal.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181254"></a>10. Weebly: Cost &#8211; Free and $5 and up.</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2623" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/blog-8.jpg-1.png" alt="Weebly homepage displaying their templates and pricing buttons." width="1240" height="726" /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/weebly-seo/">Weebly</a> is also a solid CMS to use. It allows its users simple drag-and-drop features and is user-friendly. Its mobile-responsive templates have calmed many a business owner regarding their mobile rankings on Google.</p>
<p>Weebly does give the option for SEO, but there are more expansive CMS out there for SEO. If you already have a Weebly CMS for your website, it might help to hire a Weebly-specific SEO specialist to help you maximize your website&#8217;s potential.</p>
<p>Users of Weebly have had issues with exporting their content or migrating from this CMS to other platforms.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Take control and build more a responsive website. With our <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/cms-migration/" style="text-decoration:underline;">website migration services</a>, move to a new CMS platform!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2>What Factors Do You Need to Consider When Choosing a CMS?</h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Our list and each CMS features won&#8217;t mean much if you don&#8217;t know what your needs are, so this section is designed to help you concretize what criteria to look out for in your ideal CMS.</p>
<p>After all, what features should the best CMS include?</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181256"></a>1. Pricing Features that are Right for You</h3>
<p>Some CMS will work with your website using a subscription model where you pay the company a certain amount per month. But there are certainly others that are free of cost.</p>
<p>However, even with the free options, you can still have costs that come out when you need to link it with external applications or software for specific website features you may want to incorporate.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181257"></a>2. Stellar Support</h3>
<p>The best CMS for you needs to have a responsive and supportive customer support team. If you&#8217;re waiting for customer support representatives to get back to you for days or weeks on end regarding an issue with your website, your website and its traffic will.</p>
<p>So make sure the CMS you choose has a high-quality, reliable, and trust-worthy support team that other users can vouch for.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181258"></a>3. Which Content Management System Will Support Your SEO Best?</h3>
<p>Does the CMS feature easy ways for you to manage your website&#8217;s SEO?</p>
<p>Will it allow you to make changes for your SEO using the CMS directly or will you need to go the long route and get a coder?</p>
<p>The best CMS platform will make SEO easier and more efficient for you, not harder.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181259"></a>4. Ease of Personalization and Design</h3>
<p>Since the CMS is what you&#8217;ll use to design your website, your baby, you&#8217;ll naturally want it to look impressive and well-designed.</p>
<p>Some CMS platforms are definitely more outdated than others in terms of design. But a few are extremely good for designing the perfect website for your business or even your personal portfolio. To this end, there should be a wide array of website templates and designs for you to choose the one you want.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181260"></a>5. Website Security</h3>
<p>Some CMS platforms will take care of your website&#8217;s security for you, while when using others you&#8217;ll need to do it yourself.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181261"></a>6. Easy Website Migration Capabilities</h3>
<p>The best kind of CMS platform will not keep you if you want to migrate to a different platform. Instead, it will make the process of exporting your data to another CMS platform streamlined and easy.</p>
<p>After all, what is it they say—<em>if you love something, let it go? </em>So the best CMS software will allow you to move your website wherever you please.</p>
<h2>The Best Content Management Systems for SEO &amp; Why</h2>
<p>So you design a website, but what is the use of this website if it doesn’t make your products and services <em>visible</em>? We’re talking about the SOE value of various CMS platforms.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s evaluate the top contenders based purely on their SEO capabilities and tool kits.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181263"></a>1. WordPress</h3>
<p>WordPress has a massive array of themes and plugins that allow you to optimize your site for SEO. These benefits and unique advantages of WordPress allow it to be one of the most popular CMS used in the world today.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181264"></a>2. Drupal</h3>
<p>Drupal&#8217;s modules work similarly to WordPress&#8217;s plugins in that they support your SEO efforts in addition to in-built tools.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181265"></a>3. Magento</h3>
<p>Magento is a powerful CMS for e-commerce because it has a wide array of functionality. It also includes good resources and features on its website to help its users take full advantage of SEO. It&#8217;s more developer-friendly than beginner-friendly overall, though, so keep that in mind.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181266"></a>4. Hubspot</h3>
<p>Hubspot&#8217;s CMS Hub will give you automatically generated recommendations for SEO. It will even give you keyword recommendations in each part of your web page. It has many robust SEO features which you can have access to for $300/month.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc68181267"></a>5. Shopify</h3>
<p>We recommend <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/shopify-seo/">Shopify</a> in this list in case you&#8217;re a beginner and your domain is ecommerce. If your main target is to make sales through ecommerce, then Shopify is your best bet for SEO.</p>
<p>Shopify&#8217;s benefits are plentiful.</p>
<p>We recommend this CMS because Shopify&#8217;s interface is built for ecommerce SEO, so you&#8217;d have all the tools you need to spruce up your ecommerce store&#8217;s SEO. For its price point of $29/month, Shopify delivers on a lot of fronts in the ecommerce SEO department. Also, once you get some great sales, you can always upgrade to the plan that has even more functionality.</p>
<p>To really nail your SEO for ecommerce, be sure to check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-conversion-rate-optimization-hacks-you-should-know/">10 Conversion Rate Optimization Hacks You Should Know</a>.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Want to transform your website to be responsive and drive sales? Fill out the form below for our expert <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/web-design-and-development/" style="text-decoration:underline;">web design and development services</a>.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form4" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject4" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name4" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website4" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email4" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number4" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country4" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha4();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc68181268"></a>Wrapping Up!</h2>
<p>And that&#8217;s all, folks! We’ve covered the best content management systems, choosing the best CMS for you, and the right CMS that will get you the most juice out of your SEO efforts.</p>
<p>As one of the leading digital marketing agencies in the U.S., we provide high-quality <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/web-design-development-services/">web design services</a> that&#8217;ll transform your website to be responsive and produce sales.</p>
<p>For more information about our services, call <a href="tel:8554444777">855-444-4777</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/">10 Best CMS for a Successful Website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-best-cms-for-a-successful-website/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Guide To Off-Page SEO in 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-guide-to-off-page-seo-in-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-guide-to-off-page-seo-in-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 18:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Link Building]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2595</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In order to get people talking about your products and services, in order to get those calls and clicks, you need to be able to drive traffic on your website—organic traffic. This is basically free traffic that’s generated from search engines. However, how many ‘clicks’ your website gets is completely dependent on how well your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-guide-to-off-page-seo-in-2021/">A Guide To Off-Page SEO in 2021</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In order to get people talking about your products and services, in order to get those calls and clicks, you need to be able to drive traffic on your website—organic traffic. This is basically free traffic that’s generated from search engines. However, how many ‘clicks’ your website gets is completely dependent on how well your website ranks.<span id="more-2595"></span></p>
<p>An effective Search Engine Optimization (SEO) strategy is on-page and off-page SEO.</p>
<p>While On-Page SEO is a foundation, Off-Page SEO is the building itself.</p>
<p>In this blog, we will walk you through all the ins, outs, and Harry-Potter-like secret passage-ways of Off-Page SEO for beginners in 2021. Here, we talk about building that solid, 5-star structure on top of your optimized website to take it to the next level.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s start by defining Off-Page SEO.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Sky-rocket your Off-Page SEO. Fill out the form below for results on your website!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p><strong><b>Table of Contents</b></strong></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc66366897"><u>What is Off-Page SEO?</u> </a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc66366898"><u>Off-Page vs. On-Page SEO: What’s the Difference?</u> </a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc66366899"><u>Benefits of Off-Page SEO &#8211; Why does it matter?</u> </a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366900"><u> It Increases Your Website&#8217;s Rankings In SERPs</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366901"><u> It Can Immediately Boost Traffic In The Form of Referral Traffic</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366902"><u> It Builds Website Authority Through The Nod-Of-Approval Effect</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366903"><u> It Helps You Build And Promote Your Business</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366904"><u> It Helps Increase Your Social Media Presence</u> </a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc66366905"><u>How To Do Off-Page SEO: Step By Step Instructions</u> </a></p>
<ul class="toc-inner">
<li><a href="#_Toc66366906"><u>Understand Off-Page SEO Ranking Factors</u> </a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366907"><u>Link Factors</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366908"><u>Non Link Factors</u> </a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366909"><u>Using State-Of-The-Art Off-Page SEO Techniques</u> </a>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366910"><u> Collaborate with Influencers</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366911"><u> Guest Post Like A Boss</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366912"><u> Find Broken Links</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366913"><u> Market &#8220;Valuable&#8221; Content</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366914"><u> Take Part in Forum Discussions!</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366915"><u> Answer Questions on Q&amp;A Websites</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366916"><u> Use Blog Commenting To Your Advantage</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366917"><u> Create Infographics and other Value-Adding Content to Build Backlinks</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366918"><u> Keep Up with Your Backlinkers and Even Give Back</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366919"><u> Transform Unlinked Mentions into Backlinks</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366920"><u> Use a Newsletter and an Email List</u> </a></li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="#_Toc66366921"><u>Wrapping Up!</u> </a></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc66366897"></a><strong><b>What is Off-Page SEO</b></strong><strong><b>?</b></strong></h2>
<p>Off-Page SEO encompasses all the tasks you do <em>outside of your own website</em> to promote it and build its ranking and traffic. Also known as &#8220;Off-Site SEO,&#8221; Off-Page SEO improves your site&#8217;s relevance, reputation, popularity, trustworthiness, and authority in the eyes of the users and search engines.</p>
<p>A lot of small businesses make the mistake of believing that off-page SEO is all <em>just </em>about building links. Wrong. It involved a <em><u>range of techniques and activities</u></em> (some of which we’ll be discussing ahead) directed to <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/"><u>increase your website’s DA</u></a> and ultimately, its rankings and traffic.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc66366898"></a><strong><b>Off-Page vs. On-Page SEO</b></strong><strong><b>: What’s the Difference?</b></strong></h2>
<p>You may have already gathered this, but On-Page SEO encompasses everything you can do on your site to improve your site&#8217;s rankings.<br />
[table &#8220;2&#8221; not found /]<br />
<br />
We’ll get into a more in-depth discussion regarding Off-Page SEO techniques further within this blog.</p>
<p>Your goal with Off-Page or Off Site SEO is to influence your site&#8217;s <strong>rankings, relevance, popularity,</strong> and <strong>trustworthiness</strong>.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Struggling with low website traffic? Fill out the form below and let’s get started with SEO that makes an impact!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc66366899"></a><strong><b>Benefits of Off-Page SEO</b></strong><strong><b>&#8211; Why does it matter?</b></strong></h2>
<p>You might now be wondering <strong><em>why and how </em></strong>Off-Page SEO can help you influence your site&#8217;s rankings, relevance, popularity, and trustworthiness.</p>
<p>Well, there are some <strong>key strategic advantages and benefits</strong> of implementing Off-Page SEO that you should know in order to keep your efforts streamlined.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366900"></a><strong><b>1. It Increases Your Website&#8217;s Rankings In SERPs</b></strong></h3>
<p>Search engines evaluate content based on relevancy and links. Solid, relevant content is key and links. Link evaluation is what helped Google, as a search engine, to stand out and thrive. It started with <a href="http://infolab.stanford.edu/~backrub/google.html"><u>this paper</u></a> published by the cofounders of Google at Stanford.</p>
<p>Why would a website link to another website if it directs its viewers away from their own site? To provide value to a user via a relevant third-party link.</p>
<p>Therefore, these links are like votes of approval, telling Google: &#8220;This is one of the good ones—let them into the club. &#8220;The symbolic <em>&#8220;club&#8221;</em> in this context is naturally a higher ranking on Google&#8217;s SERP.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366901"></a><strong><b>2. It Can Immediately Boost Traffic In The Form of Referral Traffic</b></strong></h3>
<p>Off-Page SEO increases your rankings on Google but it also directly increases your website&#8217;s traffic. This is because you have built a new source of continuous traffic.</p>
<p>When your Off-Page SEO activity is fresh, such as a newly published guest post linking to your website, your traffic flow may increase exponentially. Eventually, it will level out, but it will <strong><em>continue </em></strong>to bring your site <strong><em>consistent traffic</em></strong> as long as the referring website is functional and up-to-date.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366902"></a><strong><b>3. It Builds Website Authority Through The Nod-Of-Approval Effect</b></strong></h3>
<p>Google evaluates your website&#8217;s Page Rank and Domain Authority factors (to determine your site&#8217;s ranking) using a system. In this ranking system, the sites that get the best quality <strong><em>and </em></strong>quantity of relevant sites linking to them are ranked higher in search engine results.</p>
<p><strong><em>Why </em></strong>does this happen?</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2596" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/awesome-sites.jpg" alt="A guard representing Google's algorithm stands before a gate and only allows high-quality websites with solid Off-Page SEO to pass through the gates." width="296" height="445" /></p>
<p>This happens because of the &#8220;nod of approval&#8221; effect we discussed earlier in the first benefit of Off-Page SEO.</p>
<p>In more technical terms, the site that links to a third-party website (yours) will pass on some of its Page Rank and SEO juice to the site it is linking to.</p>
<h3><strong><b>4. It Helps You Build And Promote Your Business</b></strong></h3>
<p>With Off-Page SEO practices and techniques, you can use certain platforms to showcase your brand personality and message. Helping users understand <em>why</em> you do what you do can help them decide whether their interests align with your business.</p>
<p>Showcasing your brand&#8217;s personality also helps you to attract users and customers that you ideally want to work with.</p>
<h3><strong><b>5. It Helps Increase Your Social Media Presence</b></strong></h3>
<p>Social Media and website traffic feed into each other. Increases in traffic resulting from Off-Page SEO practices result in higher social media following and engagement, which leads to higher website traffic and conversions.</p>
<h2><strong><b>How To Do Off-Page SEO: Step By Step</b></strong><strong><b> Instructions</b></strong></h2>
<h3><strong><b>Understand </b></strong><strong><b>Off-Page SEO Ranking Factors</b></strong></h3>
<p>As a whole, SEO is dependent on 3 key factors: <strong>ART</strong>.</p>
<p>These are <strong><em>A</em></strong>uthority, <strong><em>R</em></strong>elevance, and <strong><em>T</em></strong>rustworthiness. So when you want to consider Off-Page SEO ranking factors, it&#8217;s useful to remember that all the factors we will discuss work because they contribute to the overall <em>ART</em> factors influencing SEO.</p>
<p>Under the larger umbrella of Off-Page SEO, there are two main categories that traffic building practices fall under. These are <strong>Link Factors</strong> and <strong>Non Link factors</strong>.</p>
<h3><strong><b>Link Factors</b></strong></h3>
<p>The key to Off-Page SEO is to <strong>build reputable backlinks</strong>.</p>
<p>The quality of your backlink depends on many factors. These include:</p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>1. The Linking Website&#8217;s Relevance to Your Website and Niche</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>Since Google&#8217;s BERT update, there has been an emphasis on relevance and matching search intent in Google&#8217;s SERP. So if your site is linked on a page that isn&#8217;t relevant to your niche, website, service/product, it likely won&#8217;t give your site the SEO nectar you are seeking.</p>
<p>Without relevance, this SEO nectar might instead be crude oil.</p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>2. The Website&#8217;s Consistent Traffic Flow—Whether it’s High, Medium, or Low</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>A website&#8217;s traffic is good for two reasons. Firstly, it provides your site with plenty of referral traffic. If they approve of and endorse you to their existing audience, their existing audience will be more inclined to follow your business and journey.</p>
<p>A high consistent traffic flow also means the website must have good SEO or internet presence somewhere, which also boosts your site&#8217;s SEO.</p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>3. How Fresh Are The Backlink—is it Still Relevant?</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>For example, if your link was in a blog post that expired or the owner has let their site&#8217;s web rankings go to hell, it might be more beneficial to cut your losses and disavow that link.</p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>4. How Many Additional Links the Web Page Linking to Your Site Includes</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>When you’re building a backlink with a website, it’s important to go through the site&#8217;s content to estimate how many more businesses they provide with backlinks. Check the backlink numbers relative to the word counts.</p>
<p>When one paragraph contains one link, users are more likely to click on it. But if one paragraph contains multiple links, users are significantly less likely to click on them.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2597" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/para.png" alt=" a man is shown at his computer looking frustrated because he stuffed 85+ links in one paragraph but no one clicked on any of them" width="321" height="427" /></p>
<p><em><u>Multiple links</u></em> in a paragraph, therefore, make the link you build <em><u>less clickable.</u></em></p>
<p>Also, if the multiple sites linked are your competitors, then that is yet another red flag.</p>
<p>For further information regarding ideal backlink quantities, check out our blog <a href="#_Toc63698617"><u>Backlink Quality vs. Quantity: What&#8217;s More Important in 2021?</u></a></p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>5. The Linking Website&#8217;s Rank and Domain Authority</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>Put simply, if the site linking to yours has SEO juice, to begin with, it will pass on that juice to your site. SEO juice includes a solid current rank and Domain Authority.</p>
<p>In turn, your own website&#8217;s Domain Authority will also improve, which makes ranking for keywords on new pages from your own site faster.</p>
<p>To learn more about improving your Domain Authority, check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/"><u>What is a Good Domain Authority and How Can You Increase Yours</u></a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366908"></a><strong><b>Non Link Factors</b></strong></h3>
<p>These factors influence the strength of your Off-Page SEO efforts outside of traditional link building.</p>
<p>Non Link Factors include:</p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>1. Unlinked Mentions</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>This would mean hashtags, casual mentions of your brand on social media and in blogs/other web pages. You can find these using Google&#8217;s <a href="https://support.google.com/websearch/answer/2466433?hl=en"><u>Advanced Search options</u></a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2598" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-of-Google-Advanced-search-to-search-a-website-and-find-Off-Page-SEO-opportunities.png" alt="Screenshot of Google Advanced search to search a website and find Off-Page SEO opportunities" width="624" height="377" /></p>
<p>Using these hacks, you can even search through social media using Google.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2599" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Google-advanced-search-screenshot-to-find-social-media-and-other-off-page-SEO-opportunities.png" alt="Google-advanced-search-screenshot-to-find-social-media-and-other-off-page-SEO-opportunities" width="624" height="382" /></p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>2. Social Media Presence</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>A business&#8217;s goal, when using social media, should be to redirect traffic from its social media pages back to its website. So while it&#8217;s not a traditional backlink on a webpage, it still drives traffic and improves SEO.</p>
<p>While some argue that social media does not affect SEO, high Domain Authority (which measures a site&#8217;s ability to rank quickly on Google) is correlated with a good social media presence.</p>
<p>Also, not having social media in the digital age is equivalent to not having a business card. It is an <em>essential platform</em> to engage with your target audience directly.</p>
<p>Your key social media factors are those that affect how likely users are to click on a link you provide them. In a nutshell, this means one thing: user engagement rates.</p>
<p>How receptive are your followers to the new content that you put out? Do they value the posts you already share? Do you have conversation threads starting in your comments section? Do they actively ask you questions and participate in polls/challenges/competitions that you run?</p>
<p>An engaged audience is an excited audience. An audience is excited because they see value being provided to them. Therefore, an engaged audience is more likely to convert into a paying customer.</p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>3. Influencer Marketing</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>When you&#8217;re working with influencers, remember that quality is more important than quantity when it comes to their audiences. While it may be tempting to reach out to simply &#8220;popular&#8221; influencers, it will be more cost-effective and yield higher returns for your business if you focus on targeting influencers within your niche.</p>
<p>Even if they have a relatively average audience size, as long as their followers are interested in what your product/service will be able to offer them, you&#8217;ve got a match.</p>
<p>We’ll discuss the ins and outs of influencer marketing for your Off-Page SEO further in this blog, but for now, know that <strong>relevance matters more than fan following sizes</strong>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong><b>Using State-Of-The-Art </b></strong><strong><b>Off-Page SEO Techniques</b></strong></h2>
<p>Once you understand the ranking factors influencing your Off-Page SEO, your next logical question would be: how do I put this into practice?</p>
<p>To help you practically build your Off-Page SEO, we&#8217;ve compiled the following actionable techniques that have <strong>proven results</strong>.</p>
<h3><strong><b>1. Collaborate with Influencers</b></strong></h3>
<p>You can coordinate with influencers by targeting them based on your content. Say, for example, that you just released a blog post about prepping cookie dough just right before baking.</p>
<p>To find a relevant influencer, it&#8217;s not enough to just find a famous chef with a devoted following, but one who specializes in baked goods. If they specialize in cookies, particularly, then that&#8217;s even better!</p>
<p>Link it to them and ask them for their opinion on the piece. Once they agree and have shared their thoughts on your site, you can highlight that comment on your website as a quote. You can also reach out to them prior to publishing it to get their opinion. In the blog itself, you can highlight their point of view in a relevant quote.</p>
<p>It&#8217;ll be even more enticing for the influencer if you ask them for their expert opinion on a contentious debate topic.</p>
<p>As a completely arbitrary example, say that bakers on the internet often argue about whether the ideal temperature to prepare your cookie dough under is either 72 degrees or 82 degrees.</p>
<p>A useful tiebreaker for your blog would be to consult an expert in the field (i.e., the influencer) to settle the debate for the purposes of your blog by putting their two cents in.</p>
<p>Once you do publish the blog, you can ask the influencer to share the piece with their network. Typically, this would result in a few social media shares from their account, which would link to all of their followers.</p>
<p>Using this tactic, you not only further your site&#8217;s authority by consulting and quoting a well-known expert in the field, but you also get a ton of traffic.</p>
<h3><strong><b>2. Guest Post Like A Boss</b></strong></h3>
<p>Many struggle with finding a guest posting opportunity, but it&#8217;s really not challenging when you know what to look for.</p>
<p>Identify the target keywords that you want to rank for, then look up key terms like &#8220;contribute for us,&#8221; &#8220;write for us, &#8220;and &#8220;guest blogging opportunity.&#8221;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2600" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Google-screenshot-for-searching-guest-posting-opportunities-to-improve-your-off-page-SEO.png" alt="Google-screenshot-for-searching-guest-posting-opportunities-to-improve-your-off-page-SEO" width="624" height="576" /></p>
<p>Instead of using your keyword specifically, you can even just look up guest blogging opportunities within your niche on Google and then pitch whatever content idea you want to write about.</p>
<p>Your content idea should be based on the keywords you want to target. Your topic should be relevant to your expertise, i.e., whatever service or product you are offering on your website to make revenues.</p>
<p>When your guest post topic provides value, and it&#8217;s similar in category to what you deal with and discuss on your own website, it&#8217;s only the natural next step for viewers of your guest post to go to your website.</p>
<p>The means through which these users transport from the guest posting website to yours is a link you will place in your Author Bio at the end of your guest post, along with a helpful blurb about what it is you do and how you help the types of people that would read about your blog topic.</p>
<h3><strong><b>3. Find Broken Links</b></strong></h3>
<p>Broken links on a website are a result of faulty linking, expired links, expired domains, etc.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2601" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/example-error-404-broken-link-page.png" alt="example-error-404-broken-link-page" width="423" height="234" /></p>
<p>The point is the link does not work and provides a poor user experience. It puts a bad taste in a user&#8217;s mouth when they click on a relevant-seeming link, but it&#8217;s not working. It also reflects poorly on the linking site.</p>
<p>But where there are broken links, there is an opportunity.</p>
<p>In sites relevant to your website that have posted links to content similar to yours, see how many of those links work. It will be a trial and error process, or you can invest in some link analyzing software and do it faster.</p>
<p>The idea is: find broken links and reach out to the website owner to tell them about it.</p>
<p>When you tell them that a specific link of theirs is broken, this is your opportunity to suggest your relevant link for the owner to switch their broken link out with.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366913"></a><strong><b>4. Market &#8220;Valuable&#8221; Content</b></strong></h3>
<p>Content Marketing is an insanely powerful marketing tactic. In 2021, it crossed $40 Billion in revenue for companies.</p>
<p>So clearly, it’s important on its own. Marketing valuable content to your audience is key. But did you know that you can enhance your content outside of your website (Off-Page) and use this enhancement to improve your SEO?</p>
<p>Google owns many different properties. So out of all the different websites on the internet, Google naturally has a preference for its own properties and rewards those that use and link multiple Google properties together.</p>
<p>This reward is in the form of higher rankings on Google&#8217;s SERP.</p>
<p>For example, Google owns the video-sharing giant YouTube.</p>
<p>So if you have already posted a blog about, say, the right way to water your hydrangeas, then you can also create a YouTube video on the same subject.</p>
<p>Once you&#8217;ve made the video, link it to your web page and use your web page to link back to your YouTube video (embed it).</p>
<p>So because the two link to each other, in Google&#8217;s eyes, you&#8217;ve linked two of their properties together by using both platforms for your business.</p>
<p>As a result, Google will reward your website.</p>
<p>In regards to the video—even if you&#8217;re just starting out, you can make a video using screen-recording software and a PowerPoint presentation covering the same points in your blog.</p>
<p>This process can take you as little as 15 minutes to record the video and link both your blog and YouTube video to each other.</p>
<p>Of course, <em>the higher your video&#8217;s quality, the more engaged your viewers will be.</em></p>
<p>But for the purposes of Off-Page SEO, you&#8217;ve done your job by linking the two properties.</p>
<p>To help you better understand how you can take full advantage of video marketing, check this out:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4Fk48tDAVCQ" width="730" height="411" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>You can repeat the same link building exercise for your business&#8217;s web pages between Google&#8217;s many other properties such as Google My Business, Google Plus, etc.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366914"></a><strong><b>5. Take Part in Forum Discussions!</b></strong></h3>
<p>In order to effectively use this Off-Page SEO technique, you need to locate and take part in discussions related to your products/services/niche. Connect with the community in your niche, provide them with value, and put your two cents as a professional in the field.</p>
<p>When you&#8217;re creating your profile, it’s important to include a hyperlink in your bio or profile information that leads back to your website. That way, each time that you comment, the link shows up and provides a new valuable backlink to your website.</p>
<p>A hack here is to seek out websites that specifically allow you to use <strong><em>do</em></strong>-follow links as opposed to <em>no</em>-follow ones.</p>
<p>You want the search engine to be notified each time you post a comment in order to improve your Off-Page SEO, so you need to make sure that the link in your profile will be a <strong>do-follow link.</strong></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366915"></a><strong><b>6. Answer Questions on Q&amp;A Websites</b></strong></h3>
<p>On many websites like Quora, Yahoo, etc., there are users in your industry who have questions relevant to your products and/or services. The key is to find these questions, provide them with value-adding answers, and only link to your website when it is relevant.</p>
<p>In your profile, make sure to write about what you do and add a link to your website. This way, you get to meet your target consumers at the grass-roots level and help them by providing impactful answers to their concerns and questions.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366916"></a><strong><b>7. Use Blog Commenting To Your Advantage</b></strong></h3>
<p>Blog commenting is a controversial practice because it can be manipulated as a black-hat SEO Strategy. But major brands use this technique to improve their rankings <strong><em><u>without </u></em></strong>using the infamous <em>keyword stuffing </em>practice.</p>
<p>You can still use Blog commenting to build Off-Page SEO for your website. You just need to do it in a way that provides value and links your website where it is <strong>relevant</strong>.</p>
<p><em>How do you do this?</em></p>
<p>Well, you start by finding relevant blogs and topics and then writing a value-enhancing blog comment. In this comment, you can include a link to a highly relevant blog you may have written on the subject matter or debate at hand.</p>
<p>When uploading comments to a reputable blog, it can help to make your profile as legitimate-looking as possible. Include your full name, a working email address, and perhaps even a picture of yourself in your profile so that the blog owner is more likely to approve your comment.</p>
<p>When you establish yourself as a consistent, high-value commenter, many of the bigger blog owners will even be tempted to check out your website and leave a comment on your blog.</p>
<p>In this way, <strong><em>blog commenting is a gateway to building high-profile relationships </em></strong>in which a larger blogger and yourself can provide each other with mutual benefit.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366917"></a><strong><b>8. Create Infographics and other Value-Adding Content to Build Backlinks</b></strong></h3>
<p>Another way to build Off-Page SEO is to provide value to existing blogs within your niche. This could look like creating an infographic, graphic, bar-chart, or even compiling a helpful statistic that would help enrich a blog whose website you&#8217;re seeking a backlink from.</p>
<p>Ensure that the topic you target is relevant to your business&#8217;s products/services and the niche that the site itself is in.</p>
<p>The last thing a baker needs is to show up on a page about hair gel, for example.</p>
<p>So do your due diligence in this regard. Instead of creating content that just restates what the blogger is already saying, focus your efforts on creating content that improves the quality of the blog.</p>
<p>For example, if the blog discusses a complex topic, to help its readers better understand it, you can create a helpful infographics explaining the concept.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-reasons-why-your-business-needs-a-link-building-strategy-infographic/"><u>Here&#8217;s</u></a> a good example of an infographic we made that you can take inspiration from and mold yours after.</p>
<p>Therefore, because your content helps the blogger&#8217;s target readers, they are more enticed to accept your content and add it to their blog.</p>
<p>If they choose to use your content, you can discuss them linking to your site in your communications with the site owner.</p>
<p>You can also get creative with this approach in terms of how you add value. Your content can even be a video animation, a gifset, a comic strip (depending on the blog&#8217;s niche), etc.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366918"></a><strong><b>9. Keep Up with Your Backlinkers and Even Give Back</b></strong></h3>
<p>You can use free and/or paid backlink tools to track which websites are linking to your website. For your reference, you should create and keep an updated list of websites that are linking to yours because they are helping out your rankings and traffic flow.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s key to keep a list because it&#8217;s possible that websites that may have linked to your site in the past may stop doing so without warning.</p>
<p>In cases like these, because you have your list to refer to, you know which backlinks disappeared and which ones are new.</p>
<p>So in the case that a website stops linking to yours, you can actually reach out and respectfully inquire what happened and why they stopped linking to your website.</p>
<p>Specifically reaching out to them in this way can and has proven to reinstate your backlink on their website, provided you handle it well, and there aren&#8217;t unrelated, third-party reasons that they chose to remove your link.</p>
<p>You can and should also get familiar with backlinks even if they keep your link up. Getting to know about their business and why they linked to your site can play a key role in building a good business relationship with the site owner/s.</p>
<p>When relevant in your blog, you can even provide them with a backlink, thereby continuing that business relationship by also providing them with value.</p>
<p>As time passes, having a good relationship with each of your backlinking partners can help propel you towards even greater online success.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366919"></a><strong>10. Transform Unlinked Mentions into Backlinks</strong></h3>
<p>We mentioned unlinked mentions previously in this blog as a non-linking factor. They are helpful because they build brand awareness and indirectly increase traffic, but they are no comparison to a linked mention.</p>
<p>A linked mention is more valuable for your Off-Page SEO because it&#8217;s a URL that viewers can click to transport to your website. Hence, it builds greater traffic for your site.</p>
<p>Between linked mentions, a do-follow link will provide your site with greater SEO juice than a no-follow link.</p>
<p>But getting back to transforming your unlinked mention: the first step is to find your unlinked blog or website mentions using the techniques listed previously. Secondly, you want to reach out to the website owner/s and request that they link your website where they have mentioned product/services.</p>
<p>Transforming unlinked mentions in this way can be a powerful step to improve your Off-Page SEO, especially in the case that a high domain authority (DA) blog mentions your website.</p>
<p>Take full advantage of the opportunities you currently have with unlinked mentions.</p>
<p>For even further in-depth techniques on building backlinks, check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-advanced-link-building-tips-and-tricks-to-boost-your-seo/"><u>10 Advanced Link Building Tips And Tricks To Boost Your SEO</u></a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366920"></a><strong><b>11. Use a Newsletter and an Email List</b></strong></h3>
<p>Newsletters and email lists are incredibly valuable because you own them.</p>
<p>A problem with social media is that it can be <em>unreliable </em>and even <em>shut down completely</em>.</p>
<p>For example, if you post on social media, your content will go on a dedicated user&#8217;s newsfeed, where out of many posts, they might miss yours entirely.</p>
<p>Instagram and Facebook also notoriously don&#8217;t display all posts put up by users to other users following them, even if the user put it up recently.</p>
<p>In addition to not showing your content to all your followers, social media can also shut down due to reasons outside of your control.</p>
<p>The most salient example of this phenomenon is that of the video-sharing platform <em>Vine</em>, which shut down in October 2016.</p>
<p>Many Vine creators, AKA &#8220;Viners,&#8221; relied on the traffic they got from Vine as a source of income. So when Twitter unexpectedly shut down the Vine application, many business owners were rightfully distraught as they <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2020/02/10/what-is-tiktoks-shelf-life-considering-vine-withered-and-died/?sh=1913d6234a86" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>watched their audience slip away</u></a>.</p>
<p>Unlike social media, email lists are permanent, and you can download your list as an excel file as well as move it to different email marketing platforms with ease.</p>
<p>Firstly, it&#8217;s permanent and reliable to use email marketing to engage with your audience and customers. Secondly, emails are much more likely to be seen in an inbox over posts in a massive, constantly-refreshing newsfeed.</p>
<p>Therefore, open-rates for emails are high and bring greater conversions for business owners relative to social media alone.</p>
<p>To incentivize your email list subscribers, you can even offer exclusive discount codes and resources that they will appreciate if they&#8217;re subscribed to your email list or newsletter.</p>
<p>Now, you can keep your business&#8217;s audience with you regardless of how big corporations decide the fate of various social media platforms.</p>
<h3><strong>12. Piggyback Your Success With Highly Experienced Professionals</strong></h3>
<p>While it may be enticing to learn everything you can about digital marketing and optimizing your off page SEO yourself, it&#8217;s important for you to ask yourself if your time is better spent elsewhere.</p>
<p>This could be creating content, perfecting your services and products to meet your customers&#8217; needs, and more. Digital marketing and SEO professionals, especially companies, have tons of experience and can make the whole process of getting leads, conversions and sales through both SEO and paid advertising incredibly streamlined.</p>
<p>This ultimately frees your time and mental energy to focus on what really matters to you in your business outside off page SEO.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc66366921"></a><strong><b>Wrapping Up!</b></strong></h2>
<p>There you have it! The Off-Page SEO guide every business owner should have. You now understand the benefits of working on this aspect of your website&#8217;s SEO, the most significant link and non-link factors that influence Off-Page SEO, and some killer techniques to boost your ranking and traffic for your targeted keywords.</p>
<p>Off-Page SEO requires time and a diligent trial and error process. Here at <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/"><u>Search Berg</u></a>, our <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service/"><strong><u>Off-Page SEO Specialists</u></strong></a> use state-of-the-art software, years of cutting edge experience, and innovative strategies to help your business thrive in the world of Off-Page SEO and beyond.</p>
<p>Call us at <a href="tel:855-444-4777"><u>855-444-4777</u></a>to improve your Off-Page SEO and boost traffic and conversions on your website now!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-guide-to-off-page-seo-in-2021/">A Guide To Off-Page SEO in 2021</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-guide-to-off-page-seo-in-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is a Good Website Domain Authority and How Can You Increase Yours?</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Harper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 11:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Website SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;re reading this blog, chances are, you&#8217;ve come across the term Domain Authority (DA) a couple of times. But what is Domain Authority? What does it mean for your website’s performance? To help you understand the concept and increase the Domain Authority of your website, we’ve created this comprehensive guide. Want to increase your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/">What is a Good Website Domain Authority and How Can You Increase Yours?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;re reading this blog, chances are, you&#8217;ve come across the term <strong>Domain Authority (DA) </strong>a couple of times. But what <em>is </em>Domain Authority? What does it mean for your website’s performance?</p>
<p><span id="more-2574"></span></p>
<p>To help you understand the concept and increase the Domain Authority of your website, we’ve created this comprehensive guide.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Want to increase your Domain Authority? We know how to get you there! Fill out the form to get great results!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2>Table of Contents</h2>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680080">What is Domain Authority?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680081">So, What Is A Good Domain Authority?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680082">How is Domain Authority Calculated?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680083">How to Increase Domain Authority of Your Website?</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680084"> Accept Only High-Quality, Relevant Backlinks</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680085"> Create a Link Building Strategy</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680086"> Guest Post to boost your Domain Authority</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680087"> Build Domain Authority with Content Syndication</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680088"> Create high-value content that fellow bloggers will want to link to</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680089"> Research your competitor&#8217;s strategies and consider writing power blogs</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680090"> Make sure to work on your on-page SEO</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680091">Update older content</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680092">Optimize images</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680093">Optimize meta tags and descriptions </a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680094">Use keywords naturally</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680095">Use both internal and external links</a></p>
<ol start="8">
<li><a href="#_Toc65680096"> Fix up your Technical SEO</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680097"> Social Signals</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc65680098"> Mobile Friendliness</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc65680099">Wrapping Up!</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc65680080"></a>What is Domain Authority?</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2589" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-14.png" alt="What is Domain Authority?" width="750" height="544" /></p>
<p>Created by Moz, Domain Authority is a ranking metric—an aggregated number—that indicates how <em>authoritative</em> your website is. The higher your website’s domain authority, the more easily it can rank for your target keywords.</p>
<p>Furthermore, Moz states that a website’s DA is calculated by assessing aspects like linking root domains and the number of total links into a DA score.</p>
<p>DA is scored on a scale of 1–100, with 1 being the lowest performing and 100 being the highest. New websites that have very little to no authority typically start out with a DA of 1. The top websites on the internet, including <u><a href="https://www.apple.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Apple</a></u>, <u><a href="https://www.youtube.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">YouTube</a></u>, and <u><a href="https://www.google.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Google</a>,</u> have DAs of 100.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680081"></a>So, What Is A Good Domain Authority?</h3>
<p>DA below 40 is considered poor; 40–50 is considered average; 51–60 is good; anything above 60 is excellent.</p>
<p>So clearly, scoring high when it comes to Domain Authority should definitely be on your business’s bucket list. But instead of focusing on getting the highest possible DA and competing with giants like Apple and Google, look at your competitors. Your goal should be to develop a higher domain authority than them.</p>
<p>Small businesses, for example, have a relatively lower DA overall, making it easier for competitors to scope out the landscape and improve their authority.</p>
<p>The next logical question is, how <em>do</em> you get high domain authority relative to your competitors?</p>
<p>There are many factors, and in this comprehensive blog, we’ll cover them all in depth.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680082"></a>How is Domain Authority Calculated?</h3>
<p>Domain Authority is calculated using the total number of backlinks you receive, including root domains (among a host of other metrics). It defines the ranking capabilities of an entire website for any page it creates, including but not limited to blog posts.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s important to note that <strong>Domain Authority</strong> is different from <strong>Page Authority (PA)</strong>. So what is Page Authority? While PA measures the ranking strength and capabilities of a single web page on a website, DA showcases the strength of the <em>entire website</em>, indicating the likelihood of a web page ranking when you create one. While different, PA largely depends on Domain Authority because they ultimately rely on the same factors.</p>
<p>So without further ado, let&#8217;s get to our comprehensive ways to increase your site&#8217;s Domain Authority.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc65680083"></a>How to Increase Domain Authority of Your Website?</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680084"></a>1. Accept Only High-Quality, Relevant Backlinks</h3>
<p>Your backlinks are arguably the most important factor in improving your Domain Authority score.</p>
<p>Backlinks are created when other websites hyperlink to your website. These links can send traffic to your websites, improve rankings, and increase your Domain Authority.</p>
<p>To better understand backlinks, check out our YouTube video <u><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GwiI6V1eyQg" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">What is Backlinking And Why is it Important for YOUR Business</a></u>.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GwiI6V1eyQg" width="730" height="411" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So your goal with backlinks is to make sure that they’re all high-quality and relevant to your site. Luckily, you can remove irrelevant, spammy backlinks that will harm your domain authority in the long run using the <u><a href="https://search.google.com/search-console/disavow-links?utm_source=wmx&amp;utm_medium=deprecation-pane&amp;utm_content=disavow-links-main" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Disavow tool</a></u>, courtesy of Google.</p>
<p>Way over your head? You can get in touch with a professional SEO company that can run a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/backlink-audit/">backlink audit</a> for you to take care of that.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2588" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-13.png" alt="screenshot of Disavow tool from Google for backlinks which helps improve website Domain Authority by removing irrelevant, low-quality links" width="1075" height="538" /></p>
<p>If only high-quality, relevant websites are able to link to your website, Google’s bots are more likely to trust your website’s domain authority. The industry-standard rule is that do-follow links are better than no-follow links. This is because do-follow links transfer greater &#8220;SEO juice&#8221; from the linking site to yours compared to no-follow links.</p>
<p>No follow links aren&#8217;t bad to have by any means—you just want to try to target more do-follow links because they’ll give you more SEO bang for your buck. Once you audit your current links and regularly remove the “trash” links, so to speak, you can focus on building more high-quality, relevant backlinks.</p>
<p><em><strong>Pro tip </strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>If you’re running a small business, submit your site for local roundups. These include “best XYZ” lists and/or directories that accept submissions. These are easy backlinks for you to grab for your business.</strong></em></p>
<p>Another hack is to collaborate with local businesses that have a similar customer demographic as you. In this way, you can build mutually beneficial links that are relevant to your mutual customers. You can even work with small businesses that you already have a professional relationship with whose customer demographics would be interested in your product or service. There are more ways to build high-quality links, though.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>We’ve helped hundreds of businesses increase their Domain Authority. Become one of them today!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680085"></a>2. Create a Link Building Strategy</h3>
<p>Now that you know you want to maintain only high quality, high authority links and are well aware of how to disavow unwanted links, you need a strategy to build wanted links.</p>
<p>The first most important building block to any great promotion strategy is having something of note or value to say in your industry. The second is to promote this content using every marketing channel at your disposal.</p>
<p>So once you&#8217;ve created in-depth blogs (we will get into details about <strong><em>how </em></strong>to create linkable content in a future point), send it to your email list and promote it on your social media channels. Don&#8217;t underestimate organic reach even if you don&#8217;t have a sizable following yet. Use hashtags that are relevant to your industry and content to get more eyeballs on your content.</p>
<p>The next step once you&#8217;ve squared away what you can do on your own is to reach out to the big boys. Or, at least, the <em>bigger </em>boys in your industry. As long as their website has a similar or greater authority as yours, you should contact them for a backlink. You want to be subtle as opposed to making demands when you contact them. Make sure you do your research regarding their brand beforehand. If the person&#8217;s audience isn&#8217;t relevant to yours, then there&#8217;s no point reaching out.</p>
<p>Express gratitude for the content they publish. Here, it can help to link to a specific blog that resonated with you, one that is similar in topic to the content you are seeking to build a link with. You can then say in your email or message that you also wrote a new blog about *insert similar topic interest* and that you thought they might enjoy it as someone who writes about said topic/s.</p>
<p>You can end your email or message by saying that your blog/guide/article/etc. might make a helpful addition to their page. End the message on a positive note and send it off. If they like your content and think it would help their audience to read it, they will happily link to it. Many will accept, a lot will say no, and some won&#8217;t even respond. That is part of the game of link building.</p>
<p>Another key way to proactively build links is to strategically guest post.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680086"></a>3. Guest Post to boost your Domain Authority</h3>
<p>Guest posting is when you write a piece that is to be published on a third party website instead of your own. A guest post is many times more efficient and effective at boosting your current DA score than only creating content on your native website is.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2587" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-12.png" alt="screenshot of example guest post page for the photography niche" width="1195" height="891" /></p>
<p>With guest posting, you will have many opportunities to link your website in your content or Author Bio yourself. Studies have shown that people are more likely to click on links within a blog while they are still gaining information rather than afterwards, once they have captured said information.</p>
<p>Both ways, however, provide a high quality backlink to your website from a reputable, high DA site that is sure to also boost your own DA. This is important because these links will be on high authority websites that you&#8217;ve found in your niche, showing Google that you are a thought leader in your industry.</p>
<p>In addition, since the new people that will read your post are already interested in your niche, this further improves the chances of them coming to your blog and linking back to <em>your</em> posts.</p>
<p>You can find guest posting websites by searching &#8220;*insert niche* guest posting websites&#8221; on Google.<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2586" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-11.png" alt="Screenshot of Google search to find relevant guest posting sites" width="1042" height="696" /></p>
<p>Yet another way is to locate them using key phrases such as &#8220;write for us&#8221;, &#8220;submit a post&#8221;, &#8220;submit a blog&#8221;, etc.</p>
<p>A final note on guest posts is to make sure that the links being provided to you are &#8220;<strong><em>do follow</em></strong>&#8221; and not &#8220;<em>no follow</em>&#8220;. <u>A do follow link will help your rankings directly</u> by communicating the link to search engines, while a no follow link will not communicate this.</p>
<p><em><strong>Pro Tip</strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>Since guest posting is a time intensive process, don&#8217;t mass produce content to be guest posted everywhere; instead, be more strategic about which websites will give you the biggest bang for your buck.</strong></em></p>
<p>While this information about no follow backlinks can persuade you to avoid no follow links altogether, chances are, you will get them at some point. There&#8217;s no need to remove them as long as they are from a relevant website in your niche.</p>
<p>They still provide referral traffic (which influences your rankings), brand awareness, and greater social media shares and engagement. So while no follow links may not directly impact your rankings and DA, they do indirectly help so there’s no harm to keep relevant no follow links as part of your website&#8217;s backlink portfolio.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680087"></a>4. Build Domain Authority with Content Syndication</h3>
<p>Content syndication is when you publish a singular piece of content on <em>multiple websites</em>. Note that this is separate from guest posting because, instead of creating entirely new content on a website, you are instead reposting it by giving the third party website permission to do so.</p>
<p>You can do this on your own using blog posting websites like <a href="http://www.linkedin.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a> and <a href="http://www.medium.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Medium</a>, and even forum websites such as <a href="https://www.quora.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Quora</a> and <a href="http://www.reddit.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Reddit.</a></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2585" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-10.png" alt="screenshot of LinkedIn blogs site where content can be reposted and linked back to your website to improve your backlinks and hence, Domain Authority" width="1146" height="890" /></p>
<p>You can also reach out to websites that will republish with your permission. To find these, search &#8220;republish with permission&#8221; and add the topic you are covering in your piece or even your niche as a whole so you can explore.</p>
<p>When you do find these web sources where you can republish with permission, you want to reach out to them communicating the value their site will receive through republishing your specific content piece.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680088"></a>5. Create high-value content that fellow bloggers will want to link to</h3>
<p>There’s a reason we keep saying that <em><u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/why-content-driven-seo-is-a-lucrative-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2019-and-beyond/">Content is King</a>. </u></em>That’s because it truly is, fit with a bombastic gold crown and silver scepter.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2584" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-9.png" alt="A content marketer is typing on their laptop writing high-quality content to improve their website’s SEO and Domain AuthorityA content marketer is typing on their laptop writing high-quality content to improve their website’s SEO and Domain Authority" width="962" height="642" /></p>
<p>The truth is, you can follow every single SEO advice and tactic in the proverbial book, but, ultimately, having good SEO clears the path for a site visitor to come to your content. So if your content isn’t helpful, engaging, or even interesting, you’re going to get stuck with a high bounce rate and very minimal to <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2020/03/04/the-secret-to-high-search-engine-rankings-quality-content/?sh=2b42b5b070c5" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">no conversions</a></u>.</p>
<p>People are searching for answers to their pain-points and concerns on the internet. If you’re the one to be able to provide them with answers in a way that makes sense to them, they’ll be grateful and are more likely to remember your site as a future resource.</p>
<p>Good content is helpful to build trust with your prospect. Trust leads to higher site visits, lower bounce rates, greater dwell time, and greater conversions. Yet another awesome benefit of creating high-quality content, though, is that authoritative blogs within your niche will also find it valuable.</p>
<p>Because your blog explains, teaches, or provides some sort of resource to them in an easily digestible manner, they’ll be incentivized to link back to your blog as a citation in one of their pieces. Therefore, your go-to strategy to increase your DA should be to regularly release high-value content for your niche.</p>
<p><em><strong><u>Pro Tip</u></strong></em></p>
<p><em>Provide valuable content that you can use is to create media-rich content such as infographics, graphs, and charts that break down complex topics in your niche into a simple picture.</em></p>
<p>One final tip we will impart here for content is if you&#8217;re wondering what kind of content to create that fills a gap, you might want to check out the content your competitors are creating and figure out what&#8217;s missing. Therein lies your opportunity.</p>
<p>To learn more about writing great content, be sure to check out our blog: <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-to-write-a-blog-that-ranks/">How To Write A Blog That Ranks</a></u>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680089"></a>6. Research your competitor&#8217;s strategies and consider writing power blogs</h3>
<p>If you do your research thoroughly, you&#8217;ll discover the keywords your competitors are targeting. Based on this, you’ll know what’s missing in your content marketing strategy <em>and </em>what you need to beat in order to rank.</p>
<p>Check what kind of sites are already linking to their web page. Are you able to build a Franken-blog that is the MOST comprehensive one out of all these competitors? This kind of blog, also known as a power blog, can be highly sought after by readers because it is a one-stop shop for everything they need to know about a topic. A power blog in this way can help your blog stand out.</p>
<p>If you still need convincing here, be sure to read our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-reasons-why-you-need-power-blog-posts-for-your-website-blog/">5 Reasons Why You Need Power Blog PostsFor Your Website Blog</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680090"></a>7. Make sure to work on your on-page SEO</h3>
<p>In addition to your off-page SEO, which includes setting up backlinks, it’s also important to work on your <em>on-page SEO </em>to increase your domain authority.</p>
<h4><a name="_Toc65680091"></a>Update older content</h4>
<p>The most important factor in your on-page SEO is to make sure your content is up to date and relevant to today’s audiences. If your blog has lost relevance, it will result in an increased bounce rate, which ultimately affects your overall SEO efforts, rankings, and domain authority.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2583" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-8.png" alt="A screenshot of a recent Search Berg blog updated for relevancy in 2021" width="699" height="337" /></p>
<h4><a name="_Toc65680092"></a>Optimize images</h4>
<p>A feature not enough people with websites are aware of is that you can actually add more text at the back-end of every image on your website.</p>
<p>You can do this by updating the image’s file name and the associated Alt Text. The point of these fields is to show the text to the viewer about what’s happening in the image in case it doesn’t load, or your visitor is visually impaired. You can simply describe what your image contains and, where relevant, insert your target keywords in the Alt text.</p>
<h4><a name="_Toc65680093"></a>Optimize meta tags and descriptions</h4>
<p>Each page on your website will have a section in the HTML region to optimize your meta tags and descriptions.<img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2582" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-7.png" alt="Meta tags and descriptions shown in search results, which, when optimized, improve website Domain Authority and SEO" width="952" height="656" /></p>
<p>In a nutshell, these are the titles and descriptions that appear on Google when you search a term.</p>
<p>So if you leave your meta tags and descriptions up to chance, Google will phrase them at random. Since this is the equivalent of your store’s front sign, i.e., the first thing any of your prospects from Google search results will see, it’s worth optimizing for keywords and readability.</p>
<p>To discover more detailed tactics on tackling meta tags and descriptions, you can learn it all in our blog <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-meta-tags-affect-your-websites-seo/">How Meta Tags Affect Your Website’s SEO</a></u>.</p>
<h4><a name="_Toc65680094"></a>Use keywords naturally</h4>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2581" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-6.png" alt="Visual demonstration of web SEO and Domain Authority" width="750" height="544" /></p>
<p>The number one practice that you want to avoid like the plague is keyword stuffing. Keyword stuffing is essentially when a keyword is “stuffed” into a site’s meta data, backlinks, web pages, etc., in an attempt to game the system and unfairly rank higher.</p>
<p>This may have worked very briefly a long, long time ago, but since <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnrampton/2017/01/28/seo-keyword-ratio-guide-how-to-not-kill-your-seo/?sh=5bef0bcd599a" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">the Hummingbird Update</a>, Google and its robots which crawl your website have gotten very smart. Not only do they catch on if your website includes keyword stuffing, but they also penalize your website by rapidly reducing its rankings. So the best policy is to play the game by Google’s rules and win. This means using your target keywords naturally where they are relevant in your blog and web content.</p>
<p>The more you place your keywords based on relevancy, the greater its readability becomes, and therefore, the longer your reader is likely to stay engaged.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680095"></a>Use both internal and external links</h3>
<p>Internal links are important because they create a web of interconnected pages on your website through links. The more coiled and well-connected the <em>web</em> is, the better Google’s <em>Spiders </em>can crawl it.</p>
<p>Who doesn’t love a good spider pun?</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2580" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-5.png" alt="A spider web is shown with a spider crawling it to illustrate that increasing internal links help Google's spiders crawl your website more easily, improving your domain authority." width="962" height="642" /></p>
<p>Internal links build a high-quality network between your web pages the Spiders can index on Google.</p>
<p>Building internal links also helps you &#8220;pass on&#8221; some of the authority you&#8217;ve gained from a reputable page to other specific web pages on your site for which your goal is to rank.</p>
<p>External links help when they are relevant because it shows you are linking to note-worthy blogs and websites related to your topics. The idea is: if you’re commenting about relevant topics within your niche, then your commentary must by proxy also be somewhat relevant.</p>
<p>For further on-page SEO tips to keep your visitor on your website longer, you can check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-to-improve-website-bounce-rate/">10 Proven Tips to Drastically Reduce Website Bounce Rate</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680096"></a>8. Fix up your Technical SEO</h3>
<p>Your technical SEO is the foundation upon which your rankings, domain authority, and everything you&#8217;re doing for your website, stand on. You need to have your website registered on Google Search Console. Once you&#8217;ve registered, submit a file known as the &#8220;xml sitemap&#8221; of your website to Google Search Console.</p>
<p>This is the equivalent of giving Google a &#8220;cheat sheet&#8221; map to send its crawlers through your website. You want these crawlers all over your website because once they are, they can index your web pages.</p>
<p>Indexing your pages means that they become part of the Google Search results. Once you&#8217;ve completed these steps, you can actually test your pages for crawlability.</p>
<p>This can be done using the Fetch tool within Google Search Console. The <a href="https://developers.google.com/search/blog/2011/08/submit-urls-to-google-with-fetch-as" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Fetch as Google bot</a> feature in your Google Search Console dashboard allows you to submit new and updated URLs to Google for sped-up indexing and to check whether your site pages can be crawled by Google&#8217;s bots.</p>
<p>To check the status of existing pages that you&#8217;ve already been in the process of indexing, you can use Google&#8217;s <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/9012289" rel="nofollow">URL Inspection Tool</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2579" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-4.png" alt="A screenshot of a Google tool to help with technical SEO and heighten domain authority" width="962" height="395" /></p>
<p>Crawlability problems, in particular, are frustrating because they mean that even if all the right elements on your website are in place, you are still missing out on some SEO juice that can impact your domain authority score.</p>
<p>Thus, it&#8217;s important to regularly audit your website for crawlability problems including problematic redirects, links that don&#8217;t work, 404 pages, irrelevant or outdated content links, etc.</p>
<p>Another major focus area to improve your DA should be social signals.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680097"></a>9. Social Signals</h3>
<p>Social signals are social media engagements and shares. They’re important because they indicate to Google that your content is creating buzz and is relevant within your niche.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2578" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-3.png" alt="Worldwide social media penetration statistics to demonstrate its importance in the world today and how it can be instrumental in bettering a website's Domain Authority" width="958" height="651" /></p>
<p>While Google has maintained that Social Signals are not an official ranking factor, there’s a huge correlation between pages that rank well and their social media presences. High-ranking pages have great social media presence and engagement metrics.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2577" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-2.png" alt="Screenshot of Searchberg Facebook page" width="1153" height="897" /></p>
<p>This means building your brand and/or small business&#8217;s presence on social media is an integral step to take if you want to secure a high Domain Authority.</p>
<p>Whether you start with <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-to-get-more-followers-on-linkedin/">LinkedIn</a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/top-10-ways-to-grow-a-small-business-through-facebook/">Facebook</a>, or <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/v1/how-to-unleash-the-power-of-instagram-to-promote-your-brand/">Instagram</a>, the key is to build your brand and engage with your customers in a meaningful way. Take the key principles from our content section in this blog and apply them here. You want to provide value, and on social media, this can be as simple as bringing positivity to someone&#8217;s newsfeed.</p>
<p>To learn more in-depth strategies for each social media platform stated previously, be sure to check out the links above. To binge-learn how to create high-quality social media content for your business and improve your engagement, here’s a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/category/social-media-management/">list</a> of our social media marketing blogs for businesses to help you out.</p>
<p>Specifically to improve your SEO and therefore, DA, we suggest reading our blog Social Media and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-and-seo-how-to-use-social-media-to-improve-seo-rankings/">SEO: How to Use Social Media to Improve SEO Rankings</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc65680098"></a>10. Mobile Friendliness</h3>
<p>Making sure your website is mobile friendly is important for three key reasons:</p>
<ol>
<li>Mobile friendly sites are easier to use, providing a more high quality user experience</li>
<li>They are looked upon more favorably by Google&#8217;s ranking system</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Thus, they are more likely to secure backlinks, so it&#8217;s a key way to improve your site&#8217;s Domain Authority.</li>
</ul>
<p>Since <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/groupthink/2015/05/15/can-your-business-survive-googles-mobile-geddon/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Mobilegeddon</a> in 2015, Google has cracked down on websites which are not friendly to use on a mobile device or smartphone and rewards those sites that are.</p>
<p>So if a website is easy to use on a smartphone or a tablet, then Google notices and ranks that site higher in the search results for the site&#8217;s target keywords.</p>
<p>If it&#8217;s not, however, then the algorithm punishes the site by reducing its rankings and pushing its web pages lower in search results.</p>
<p>You can easily measure your website&#8217;s mobile friendliness capabilities using the Google <a href="https://search.google.com/test/mobile-friendly" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Mobile Friendly Test Tool.</a><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2576" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/blog2-1.png" alt="screen shot of mobile friendly test tool through Google to help improve mobile friendliness and increase Domain Authority" width="1188" height="875" /></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc65680099"></a>Wrapping Up!</h2>
<p>In this blog, we dove into the deep end to learn all about website DA and how to increase domain authority.</p>
<p>While many of these tips can easily be performed by an everyday Joe who is just learning about domain authority and discovering the world of SEO, it will definitely speed things up and prevent errors if you consult with professionals who have been in the game for a long time.</p>
<p>We, at <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/">Search Berg</a>, can help you <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/high-domain-authority/">increase your website&#8217;s domain authority today</a>. Call us at <a href="tel:855-444-4777">855-444-4777</a> to kick-start your domain authority score and SEO rankings or fill out the form below!</li>
</ol>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/">What is a Good Website Domain Authority and How Can You Increase Yours?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Algorithm Updates That Changed SEO</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-algorithm-updates-that-changed-seo/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-algorithm-updates-that-changed-seo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 09:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Google&#8217;s Ranking System includes the use of multiple advanced algorithms that sort through billions of web pages per second to deliver the most relevant information to users.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-algorithm-updates-that-changed-seo/">Google Algorithm Updates That Changed SEO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google&#8217;s Ranking System includes the use of multiple advanced algorithms that sort through billions of web pages per second to deliver the most relevant information to users.<span id="more-2562"></span></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/searchberg_revised-01-1-min1.jpg"  alt="Google's Ranking System includes the use of multiple advanced algorithms that sort through billions of web pages per second to deliver the most relevant information to users."  width="730" height="5008" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2569" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-algorithm-updates-that-changed-seo/">Google Algorithm Updates That Changed SEO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/google-algorithm-updates-that-changed-seo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
