<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Link Building &#8211; Search Berg</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/category/link-building/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 18:00:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>A Guide To Off-Page SEO in 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-guide-to-off-page-seo-in-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-guide-to-off-page-seo-in-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 18:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Link Building]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2595</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In order to get people talking about your products and services, in order to get those calls and clicks, you need to be able to drive traffic on your website—organic traffic. This is basically free traffic that’s generated from search engines. However, how many ‘clicks’ your website gets is completely dependent on how well your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-guide-to-off-page-seo-in-2021/">A Guide To Off-Page SEO in 2021</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In order to get people talking about your products and services, in order to get those calls and clicks, you need to be able to drive traffic on your website—organic traffic. This is basically free traffic that’s generated from search engines. However, how many ‘clicks’ your website gets is completely dependent on how well your website ranks.<span id="more-2595"></span></p>
<p>An effective Search Engine Optimization (SEO) strategy is on-page and off-page SEO.</p>
<p>While On-Page SEO is a foundation, Off-Page SEO is the building itself.</p>
<p>In this blog, we will walk you through all the ins, outs, and Harry-Potter-like secret passage-ways of Off-Page SEO for beginners in 2021. Here, we talk about building that solid, 5-star structure on top of your optimized website to take it to the next level.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s start by defining Off-Page SEO.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Sky-rocket your Off-Page SEO. Fill out the form below for results on your website!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p><strong><b>Table of Contents</b></strong></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc66366897"><u>What is Off-Page SEO?</u> </a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc66366898"><u>Off-Page vs. On-Page SEO: What’s the Difference?</u> </a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc66366899"><u>Benefits of Off-Page SEO &#8211; Why does it matter?</u> </a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366900"><u> It Increases Your Website&#8217;s Rankings In SERPs</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366901"><u> It Can Immediately Boost Traffic In The Form of Referral Traffic</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366902"><u> It Builds Website Authority Through The Nod-Of-Approval Effect</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366903"><u> It Helps You Build And Promote Your Business</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366904"><u> It Helps Increase Your Social Media Presence</u> </a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc66366905"><u>How To Do Off-Page SEO: Step By Step Instructions</u> </a></p>
<ul class="toc-inner">
<li><a href="#_Toc66366906"><u>Understand Off-Page SEO Ranking Factors</u> </a>
<ul>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366907"><u>Link Factors</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366908"><u>Non Link Factors</u> </a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366909"><u>Using State-Of-The-Art Off-Page SEO Techniques</u> </a>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366910"><u> Collaborate with Influencers</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366911"><u> Guest Post Like A Boss</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366912"><u> Find Broken Links</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366913"><u> Market &#8220;Valuable&#8221; Content</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366914"><u> Take Part in Forum Discussions!</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366915"><u> Answer Questions on Q&amp;A Websites</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366916"><u> Use Blog Commenting To Your Advantage</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366917"><u> Create Infographics and other Value-Adding Content to Build Backlinks</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366918"><u> Keep Up with Your Backlinkers and Even Give Back</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366919"><u> Transform Unlinked Mentions into Backlinks</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc66366920"><u> Use a Newsletter and an Email List</u> </a></li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="#_Toc66366921"><u>Wrapping Up!</u> </a></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc66366897"></a><strong><b>What is Off-Page SEO</b></strong><strong><b>?</b></strong></h2>
<p>Off-Page SEO encompasses all the tasks you do <em>outside of your own website</em> to promote it and build its ranking and traffic. Also known as &#8220;Off-Site SEO,&#8221; Off-Page SEO improves your site&#8217;s relevance, reputation, popularity, trustworthiness, and authority in the eyes of the users and search engines.</p>
<p>A lot of small businesses make the mistake of believing that off-page SEO is all <em>just </em>about building links. Wrong. It involved a <em><u>range of techniques and activities</u></em> (some of which we’ll be discussing ahead) directed to <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/"><u>increase your website’s DA</u></a> and ultimately, its rankings and traffic.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc66366898"></a><strong><b>Off-Page vs. On-Page SEO</b></strong><strong><b>: What’s the Difference?</b></strong></h2>
<p>You may have already gathered this, but On-Page SEO encompasses everything you can do on your site to improve your site&#8217;s rankings.<br />
[table &#8220;2&#8221; not found /]<br />
<br />
We’ll get into a more in-depth discussion regarding Off-Page SEO techniques further within this blog.</p>
<p>Your goal with Off-Page or Off Site SEO is to influence your site&#8217;s <strong>rankings, relevance, popularity,</strong> and <strong>trustworthiness</strong>.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Struggling with low website traffic? Fill out the form below and let’s get started with SEO that makes an impact!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc66366899"></a><strong><b>Benefits of Off-Page SEO</b></strong><strong><b>&#8211; Why does it matter?</b></strong></h2>
<p>You might now be wondering <strong><em>why and how </em></strong>Off-Page SEO can help you influence your site&#8217;s rankings, relevance, popularity, and trustworthiness.</p>
<p>Well, there are some <strong>key strategic advantages and benefits</strong> of implementing Off-Page SEO that you should know in order to keep your efforts streamlined.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366900"></a><strong><b>1. It Increases Your Website&#8217;s Rankings In SERPs</b></strong></h3>
<p>Search engines evaluate content based on relevancy and links. Solid, relevant content is key and links. Link evaluation is what helped Google, as a search engine, to stand out and thrive. It started with <a href="http://infolab.stanford.edu/~backrub/google.html"><u>this paper</u></a> published by the cofounders of Google at Stanford.</p>
<p>Why would a website link to another website if it directs its viewers away from their own site? To provide value to a user via a relevant third-party link.</p>
<p>Therefore, these links are like votes of approval, telling Google: &#8220;This is one of the good ones—let them into the club. &#8220;The symbolic <em>&#8220;club&#8221;</em> in this context is naturally a higher ranking on Google&#8217;s SERP.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366901"></a><strong><b>2. It Can Immediately Boost Traffic In The Form of Referral Traffic</b></strong></h3>
<p>Off-Page SEO increases your rankings on Google but it also directly increases your website&#8217;s traffic. This is because you have built a new source of continuous traffic.</p>
<p>When your Off-Page SEO activity is fresh, such as a newly published guest post linking to your website, your traffic flow may increase exponentially. Eventually, it will level out, but it will <strong><em>continue </em></strong>to bring your site <strong><em>consistent traffic</em></strong> as long as the referring website is functional and up-to-date.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366902"></a><strong><b>3. It Builds Website Authority Through The Nod-Of-Approval Effect</b></strong></h3>
<p>Google evaluates your website&#8217;s Page Rank and Domain Authority factors (to determine your site&#8217;s ranking) using a system. In this ranking system, the sites that get the best quality <strong><em>and </em></strong>quantity of relevant sites linking to them are ranked higher in search engine results.</p>
<p><strong><em>Why </em></strong>does this happen?</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2596" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/awesome-sites.jpg" alt="A guard representing Google's algorithm stands before a gate and only allows high-quality websites with solid Off-Page SEO to pass through the gates." width="296" height="445" /></p>
<p>This happens because of the &#8220;nod of approval&#8221; effect we discussed earlier in the first benefit of Off-Page SEO.</p>
<p>In more technical terms, the site that links to a third-party website (yours) will pass on some of its Page Rank and SEO juice to the site it is linking to.</p>
<h3><strong><b>4. It Helps You Build And Promote Your Business</b></strong></h3>
<p>With Off-Page SEO practices and techniques, you can use certain platforms to showcase your brand personality and message. Helping users understand <em>why</em> you do what you do can help them decide whether their interests align with your business.</p>
<p>Showcasing your brand&#8217;s personality also helps you to attract users and customers that you ideally want to work with.</p>
<h3><strong><b>5. It Helps Increase Your Social Media Presence</b></strong></h3>
<p>Social Media and website traffic feed into each other. Increases in traffic resulting from Off-Page SEO practices result in higher social media following and engagement, which leads to higher website traffic and conversions.</p>
<h2><strong><b>How To Do Off-Page SEO: Step By Step</b></strong><strong><b> Instructions</b></strong></h2>
<h3><strong><b>Understand </b></strong><strong><b>Off-Page SEO Ranking Factors</b></strong></h3>
<p>As a whole, SEO is dependent on 3 key factors: <strong>ART</strong>.</p>
<p>These are <strong><em>A</em></strong>uthority, <strong><em>R</em></strong>elevance, and <strong><em>T</em></strong>rustworthiness. So when you want to consider Off-Page SEO ranking factors, it&#8217;s useful to remember that all the factors we will discuss work because they contribute to the overall <em>ART</em> factors influencing SEO.</p>
<p>Under the larger umbrella of Off-Page SEO, there are two main categories that traffic building practices fall under. These are <strong>Link Factors</strong> and <strong>Non Link factors</strong>.</p>
<h3><strong><b>Link Factors</b></strong></h3>
<p>The key to Off-Page SEO is to <strong>build reputable backlinks</strong>.</p>
<p>The quality of your backlink depends on many factors. These include:</p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>1. The Linking Website&#8217;s Relevance to Your Website and Niche</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>Since Google&#8217;s BERT update, there has been an emphasis on relevance and matching search intent in Google&#8217;s SERP. So if your site is linked on a page that isn&#8217;t relevant to your niche, website, service/product, it likely won&#8217;t give your site the SEO nectar you are seeking.</p>
<p>Without relevance, this SEO nectar might instead be crude oil.</p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>2. The Website&#8217;s Consistent Traffic Flow—Whether it’s High, Medium, or Low</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>A website&#8217;s traffic is good for two reasons. Firstly, it provides your site with plenty of referral traffic. If they approve of and endorse you to their existing audience, their existing audience will be more inclined to follow your business and journey.</p>
<p>A high consistent traffic flow also means the website must have good SEO or internet presence somewhere, which also boosts your site&#8217;s SEO.</p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>3. How Fresh Are The Backlink—is it Still Relevant?</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>For example, if your link was in a blog post that expired or the owner has let their site&#8217;s web rankings go to hell, it might be more beneficial to cut your losses and disavow that link.</p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>4. How Many Additional Links the Web Page Linking to Your Site Includes</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>When you’re building a backlink with a website, it’s important to go through the site&#8217;s content to estimate how many more businesses they provide with backlinks. Check the backlink numbers relative to the word counts.</p>
<p>When one paragraph contains one link, users are more likely to click on it. But if one paragraph contains multiple links, users are significantly less likely to click on them.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2597" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/para.png" alt=" a man is shown at his computer looking frustrated because he stuffed 85+ links in one paragraph but no one clicked on any of them" width="321" height="427" /></p>
<p><em><u>Multiple links</u></em> in a paragraph, therefore, make the link you build <em><u>less clickable.</u></em></p>
<p>Also, if the multiple sites linked are your competitors, then that is yet another red flag.</p>
<p>For further information regarding ideal backlink quantities, check out our blog <a href="#_Toc63698617"><u>Backlink Quality vs. Quantity: What&#8217;s More Important in 2021?</u></a></p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>5. The Linking Website&#8217;s Rank and Domain Authority</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>Put simply, if the site linking to yours has SEO juice, to begin with, it will pass on that juice to your site. SEO juice includes a solid current rank and Domain Authority.</p>
<p>In turn, your own website&#8217;s Domain Authority will also improve, which makes ranking for keywords on new pages from your own site faster.</p>
<p>To learn more about improving your Domain Authority, check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-a-good-website-domain-authority-and-how-can-you-increase-yours/"><u>What is a Good Domain Authority and How Can You Increase Yours</u></a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366908"></a><strong><b>Non Link Factors</b></strong></h3>
<p>These factors influence the strength of your Off-Page SEO efforts outside of traditional link building.</p>
<p>Non Link Factors include:</p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>1. Unlinked Mentions</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>This would mean hashtags, casual mentions of your brand on social media and in blogs/other web pages. You can find these using Google&#8217;s <a href="https://support.google.com/websearch/answer/2466433?hl=en"><u>Advanced Search options</u></a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2598" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-of-Google-Advanced-search-to-search-a-website-and-find-Off-Page-SEO-opportunities.png" alt="Screenshot of Google Advanced search to search a website and find Off-Page SEO opportunities" width="624" height="377" /></p>
<p>Using these hacks, you can even search through social media using Google.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2599" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Google-advanced-search-screenshot-to-find-social-media-and-other-off-page-SEO-opportunities.png" alt="Google-advanced-search-screenshot-to-find-social-media-and-other-off-page-SEO-opportunities" width="624" height="382" /></p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>2. Social Media Presence</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>A business&#8217;s goal, when using social media, should be to redirect traffic from its social media pages back to its website. So while it&#8217;s not a traditional backlink on a webpage, it still drives traffic and improves SEO.</p>
<p>While some argue that social media does not affect SEO, high Domain Authority (which measures a site&#8217;s ability to rank quickly on Google) is correlated with a good social media presence.</p>
<p>Also, not having social media in the digital age is equivalent to not having a business card. It is an <em>essential platform</em> to engage with your target audience directly.</p>
<p>Your key social media factors are those that affect how likely users are to click on a link you provide them. In a nutshell, this means one thing: user engagement rates.</p>
<p>How receptive are your followers to the new content that you put out? Do they value the posts you already share? Do you have conversation threads starting in your comments section? Do they actively ask you questions and participate in polls/challenges/competitions that you run?</p>
<p>An engaged audience is an excited audience. An audience is excited because they see value being provided to them. Therefore, an engaged audience is more likely to convert into a paying customer.</p>
<h4><strong><em><b><i>3. Influencer Marketing</i></b></em></strong></h4>
<p>When you&#8217;re working with influencers, remember that quality is more important than quantity when it comes to their audiences. While it may be tempting to reach out to simply &#8220;popular&#8221; influencers, it will be more cost-effective and yield higher returns for your business if you focus on targeting influencers within your niche.</p>
<p>Even if they have a relatively average audience size, as long as their followers are interested in what your product/service will be able to offer them, you&#8217;ve got a match.</p>
<p>We’ll discuss the ins and outs of influencer marketing for your Off-Page SEO further in this blog, but for now, know that <strong>relevance matters more than fan following sizes</strong>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><strong><b>Using State-Of-The-Art </b></strong><strong><b>Off-Page SEO Techniques</b></strong></h2>
<p>Once you understand the ranking factors influencing your Off-Page SEO, your next logical question would be: how do I put this into practice?</p>
<p>To help you practically build your Off-Page SEO, we&#8217;ve compiled the following actionable techniques that have <strong>proven results</strong>.</p>
<h3><strong><b>1. Collaborate with Influencers</b></strong></h3>
<p>You can coordinate with influencers by targeting them based on your content. Say, for example, that you just released a blog post about prepping cookie dough just right before baking.</p>
<p>To find a relevant influencer, it&#8217;s not enough to just find a famous chef with a devoted following, but one who specializes in baked goods. If they specialize in cookies, particularly, then that&#8217;s even better!</p>
<p>Link it to them and ask them for their opinion on the piece. Once they agree and have shared their thoughts on your site, you can highlight that comment on your website as a quote. You can also reach out to them prior to publishing it to get their opinion. In the blog itself, you can highlight their point of view in a relevant quote.</p>
<p>It&#8217;ll be even more enticing for the influencer if you ask them for their expert opinion on a contentious debate topic.</p>
<p>As a completely arbitrary example, say that bakers on the internet often argue about whether the ideal temperature to prepare your cookie dough under is either 72 degrees or 82 degrees.</p>
<p>A useful tiebreaker for your blog would be to consult an expert in the field (i.e., the influencer) to settle the debate for the purposes of your blog by putting their two cents in.</p>
<p>Once you do publish the blog, you can ask the influencer to share the piece with their network. Typically, this would result in a few social media shares from their account, which would link to all of their followers.</p>
<p>Using this tactic, you not only further your site&#8217;s authority by consulting and quoting a well-known expert in the field, but you also get a ton of traffic.</p>
<h3><strong><b>2. Guest Post Like A Boss</b></strong></h3>
<p>Many struggle with finding a guest posting opportunity, but it&#8217;s really not challenging when you know what to look for.</p>
<p>Identify the target keywords that you want to rank for, then look up key terms like &#8220;contribute for us,&#8221; &#8220;write for us, &#8220;and &#8220;guest blogging opportunity.&#8221;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2600" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Google-screenshot-for-searching-guest-posting-opportunities-to-improve-your-off-page-SEO.png" alt="Google-screenshot-for-searching-guest-posting-opportunities-to-improve-your-off-page-SEO" width="624" height="576" /></p>
<p>Instead of using your keyword specifically, you can even just look up guest blogging opportunities within your niche on Google and then pitch whatever content idea you want to write about.</p>
<p>Your content idea should be based on the keywords you want to target. Your topic should be relevant to your expertise, i.e., whatever service or product you are offering on your website to make revenues.</p>
<p>When your guest post topic provides value, and it&#8217;s similar in category to what you deal with and discuss on your own website, it&#8217;s only the natural next step for viewers of your guest post to go to your website.</p>
<p>The means through which these users transport from the guest posting website to yours is a link you will place in your Author Bio at the end of your guest post, along with a helpful blurb about what it is you do and how you help the types of people that would read about your blog topic.</p>
<h3><strong><b>3. Find Broken Links</b></strong></h3>
<p>Broken links on a website are a result of faulty linking, expired links, expired domains, etc.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2601" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/example-error-404-broken-link-page.png" alt="example-error-404-broken-link-page" width="423" height="234" /></p>
<p>The point is the link does not work and provides a poor user experience. It puts a bad taste in a user&#8217;s mouth when they click on a relevant-seeming link, but it&#8217;s not working. It also reflects poorly on the linking site.</p>
<p>But where there are broken links, there is an opportunity.</p>
<p>In sites relevant to your website that have posted links to content similar to yours, see how many of those links work. It will be a trial and error process, or you can invest in some link analyzing software and do it faster.</p>
<p>The idea is: find broken links and reach out to the website owner to tell them about it.</p>
<p>When you tell them that a specific link of theirs is broken, this is your opportunity to suggest your relevant link for the owner to switch their broken link out with.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366913"></a><strong><b>4. Market &#8220;Valuable&#8221; Content</b></strong></h3>
<p>Content Marketing is an insanely powerful marketing tactic. In 2021, it crossed $40 Billion in revenue for companies.</p>
<p>So clearly, it’s important on its own. Marketing valuable content to your audience is key. But did you know that you can enhance your content outside of your website (Off-Page) and use this enhancement to improve your SEO?</p>
<p>Google owns many different properties. So out of all the different websites on the internet, Google naturally has a preference for its own properties and rewards those that use and link multiple Google properties together.</p>
<p>This reward is in the form of higher rankings on Google&#8217;s SERP.</p>
<p>For example, Google owns the video-sharing giant YouTube.</p>
<p>So if you have already posted a blog about, say, the right way to water your hydrangeas, then you can also create a YouTube video on the same subject.</p>
<p>Once you&#8217;ve made the video, link it to your web page and use your web page to link back to your YouTube video (embed it).</p>
<p>So because the two link to each other, in Google&#8217;s eyes, you&#8217;ve linked two of their properties together by using both platforms for your business.</p>
<p>As a result, Google will reward your website.</p>
<p>In regards to the video—even if you&#8217;re just starting out, you can make a video using screen-recording software and a PowerPoint presentation covering the same points in your blog.</p>
<p>This process can take you as little as 15 minutes to record the video and link both your blog and YouTube video to each other.</p>
<p>Of course, <em>the higher your video&#8217;s quality, the more engaged your viewers will be.</em></p>
<p>But for the purposes of Off-Page SEO, you&#8217;ve done your job by linking the two properties.</p>
<p>To help you better understand how you can take full advantage of video marketing, check this out:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4Fk48tDAVCQ" width="730" height="411" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>You can repeat the same link building exercise for your business&#8217;s web pages between Google&#8217;s many other properties such as Google My Business, Google Plus, etc.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366914"></a><strong><b>5. Take Part in Forum Discussions!</b></strong></h3>
<p>In order to effectively use this Off-Page SEO technique, you need to locate and take part in discussions related to your products/services/niche. Connect with the community in your niche, provide them with value, and put your two cents as a professional in the field.</p>
<p>When you&#8217;re creating your profile, it’s important to include a hyperlink in your bio or profile information that leads back to your website. That way, each time that you comment, the link shows up and provides a new valuable backlink to your website.</p>
<p>A hack here is to seek out websites that specifically allow you to use <strong><em>do</em></strong>-follow links as opposed to <em>no</em>-follow ones.</p>
<p>You want the search engine to be notified each time you post a comment in order to improve your Off-Page SEO, so you need to make sure that the link in your profile will be a <strong>do-follow link.</strong></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366915"></a><strong><b>6. Answer Questions on Q&amp;A Websites</b></strong></h3>
<p>On many websites like Quora, Yahoo, etc., there are users in your industry who have questions relevant to your products and/or services. The key is to find these questions, provide them with value-adding answers, and only link to your website when it is relevant.</p>
<p>In your profile, make sure to write about what you do and add a link to your website. This way, you get to meet your target consumers at the grass-roots level and help them by providing impactful answers to their concerns and questions.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366916"></a><strong><b>7. Use Blog Commenting To Your Advantage</b></strong></h3>
<p>Blog commenting is a controversial practice because it can be manipulated as a black-hat SEO Strategy. But major brands use this technique to improve their rankings <strong><em><u>without </u></em></strong>using the infamous <em>keyword stuffing </em>practice.</p>
<p>You can still use Blog commenting to build Off-Page SEO for your website. You just need to do it in a way that provides value and links your website where it is <strong>relevant</strong>.</p>
<p><em>How do you do this?</em></p>
<p>Well, you start by finding relevant blogs and topics and then writing a value-enhancing blog comment. In this comment, you can include a link to a highly relevant blog you may have written on the subject matter or debate at hand.</p>
<p>When uploading comments to a reputable blog, it can help to make your profile as legitimate-looking as possible. Include your full name, a working email address, and perhaps even a picture of yourself in your profile so that the blog owner is more likely to approve your comment.</p>
<p>When you establish yourself as a consistent, high-value commenter, many of the bigger blog owners will even be tempted to check out your website and leave a comment on your blog.</p>
<p>In this way, <strong><em>blog commenting is a gateway to building high-profile relationships </em></strong>in which a larger blogger and yourself can provide each other with mutual benefit.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366917"></a><strong><b>8. Create Infographics and other Value-Adding Content to Build Backlinks</b></strong></h3>
<p>Another way to build Off-Page SEO is to provide value to existing blogs within your niche. This could look like creating an infographic, graphic, bar-chart, or even compiling a helpful statistic that would help enrich a blog whose website you&#8217;re seeking a backlink from.</p>
<p>Ensure that the topic you target is relevant to your business&#8217;s products/services and the niche that the site itself is in.</p>
<p>The last thing a baker needs is to show up on a page about hair gel, for example.</p>
<p>So do your due diligence in this regard. Instead of creating content that just restates what the blogger is already saying, focus your efforts on creating content that improves the quality of the blog.</p>
<p>For example, if the blog discusses a complex topic, to help its readers better understand it, you can create a helpful infographics explaining the concept.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-reasons-why-your-business-needs-a-link-building-strategy-infographic/"><u>Here&#8217;s</u></a> a good example of an infographic we made that you can take inspiration from and mold yours after.</p>
<p>Therefore, because your content helps the blogger&#8217;s target readers, they are more enticed to accept your content and add it to their blog.</p>
<p>If they choose to use your content, you can discuss them linking to your site in your communications with the site owner.</p>
<p>You can also get creative with this approach in terms of how you add value. Your content can even be a video animation, a gifset, a comic strip (depending on the blog&#8217;s niche), etc.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366918"></a><strong><b>9. Keep Up with Your Backlinkers and Even Give Back</b></strong></h3>
<p>You can use free and/or paid backlink tools to track which websites are linking to your website. For your reference, you should create and keep an updated list of websites that are linking to yours because they are helping out your rankings and traffic flow.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s key to keep a list because it&#8217;s possible that websites that may have linked to your site in the past may stop doing so without warning.</p>
<p>In cases like these, because you have your list to refer to, you know which backlinks disappeared and which ones are new.</p>
<p>So in the case that a website stops linking to yours, you can actually reach out and respectfully inquire what happened and why they stopped linking to your website.</p>
<p>Specifically reaching out to them in this way can and has proven to reinstate your backlink on their website, provided you handle it well, and there aren&#8217;t unrelated, third-party reasons that they chose to remove your link.</p>
<p>You can and should also get familiar with backlinks even if they keep your link up. Getting to know about their business and why they linked to your site can play a key role in building a good business relationship with the site owner/s.</p>
<p>When relevant in your blog, you can even provide them with a backlink, thereby continuing that business relationship by also providing them with value.</p>
<p>As time passes, having a good relationship with each of your backlinking partners can help propel you towards even greater online success.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366919"></a><strong>10. Transform Unlinked Mentions into Backlinks</strong></h3>
<p>We mentioned unlinked mentions previously in this blog as a non-linking factor. They are helpful because they build brand awareness and indirectly increase traffic, but they are no comparison to a linked mention.</p>
<p>A linked mention is more valuable for your Off-Page SEO because it&#8217;s a URL that viewers can click to transport to your website. Hence, it builds greater traffic for your site.</p>
<p>Between linked mentions, a do-follow link will provide your site with greater SEO juice than a no-follow link.</p>
<p>But getting back to transforming your unlinked mention: the first step is to find your unlinked blog or website mentions using the techniques listed previously. Secondly, you want to reach out to the website owner/s and request that they link your website where they have mentioned product/services.</p>
<p>Transforming unlinked mentions in this way can be a powerful step to improve your Off-Page SEO, especially in the case that a high domain authority (DA) blog mentions your website.</p>
<p>Take full advantage of the opportunities you currently have with unlinked mentions.</p>
<p>For even further in-depth techniques on building backlinks, check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-advanced-link-building-tips-and-tricks-to-boost-your-seo/"><u>10 Advanced Link Building Tips And Tricks To Boost Your SEO</u></a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc66366920"></a><strong><b>11. Use a Newsletter and an Email List</b></strong></h3>
<p>Newsletters and email lists are incredibly valuable because you own them.</p>
<p>A problem with social media is that it can be <em>unreliable </em>and even <em>shut down completely</em>.</p>
<p>For example, if you post on social media, your content will go on a dedicated user&#8217;s newsfeed, where out of many posts, they might miss yours entirely.</p>
<p>Instagram and Facebook also notoriously don&#8217;t display all posts put up by users to other users following them, even if the user put it up recently.</p>
<p>In addition to not showing your content to all your followers, social media can also shut down due to reasons outside of your control.</p>
<p>The most salient example of this phenomenon is that of the video-sharing platform <em>Vine</em>, which shut down in October 2016.</p>
<p>Many Vine creators, AKA &#8220;Viners,&#8221; relied on the traffic they got from Vine as a source of income. So when Twitter unexpectedly shut down the Vine application, many business owners were rightfully distraught as they <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2020/02/10/what-is-tiktoks-shelf-life-considering-vine-withered-and-died/?sh=1913d6234a86" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>watched their audience slip away</u></a>.</p>
<p>Unlike social media, email lists are permanent, and you can download your list as an excel file as well as move it to different email marketing platforms with ease.</p>
<p>Firstly, it&#8217;s permanent and reliable to use email marketing to engage with your audience and customers. Secondly, emails are much more likely to be seen in an inbox over posts in a massive, constantly-refreshing newsfeed.</p>
<p>Therefore, open-rates for emails are high and bring greater conversions for business owners relative to social media alone.</p>
<p>To incentivize your email list subscribers, you can even offer exclusive discount codes and resources that they will appreciate if they&#8217;re subscribed to your email list or newsletter.</p>
<p>Now, you can keep your business&#8217;s audience with you regardless of how big corporations decide the fate of various social media platforms.</p>
<h3><strong>12. Piggyback Your Success With Highly Experienced Professionals</strong></h3>
<p>While it may be enticing to learn everything you can about digital marketing and optimizing your off page SEO yourself, it&#8217;s important for you to ask yourself if your time is better spent elsewhere.</p>
<p>This could be creating content, perfecting your services and products to meet your customers&#8217; needs, and more. Digital marketing and SEO professionals, especially companies, have tons of experience and can make the whole process of getting leads, conversions and sales through both SEO and paid advertising incredibly streamlined.</p>
<p>This ultimately frees your time and mental energy to focus on what really matters to you in your business outside off page SEO.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc66366921"></a><strong><b>Wrapping Up!</b></strong></h2>
<p>There you have it! The Off-Page SEO guide every business owner should have. You now understand the benefits of working on this aspect of your website&#8217;s SEO, the most significant link and non-link factors that influence Off-Page SEO, and some killer techniques to boost your ranking and traffic for your targeted keywords.</p>
<p>Off-Page SEO requires time and a diligent trial and error process. Here at <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/"><u>Search Berg</u></a>, our <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service/"><strong><u>Off-Page SEO Specialists</u></strong></a> use state-of-the-art software, years of cutting edge experience, and innovative strategies to help your business thrive in the world of Off-Page SEO and beyond.</p>
<p>Call us at <a href="tel:855-444-4777"><u>855-444-4777</u></a>to improve your Off-Page SEO and boost traffic and conversions on your website now!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-guide-to-off-page-seo-in-2021/">A Guide To Off-Page SEO in 2021</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-guide-to-off-page-seo-in-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Backlink Quality vs. Quantity: What’s More Important in 2021?</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/backlink-quality-vs-quantity-whats-more-important-in-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/backlink-quality-vs-quantity-whats-more-important-in-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 05:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Link Building]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2542</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Think “effective SEO strategies” and link building instantly springs to mind. It’s a quick, actionable, and power-packed resuscitator for your rankings. By generating high-quality backlinks, you can redirect a ton of convertible traffic your way. More leads, massive sales, and consistent business growth. Sounds like the perfect mix for your company, right? When it comes to creating [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/backlink-quality-vs-quantity-whats-more-important-in-2021/">Backlink Quality vs. Quantity: What’s More Important in 2021?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Think “effective SEO strategies” and link building <em>instantly</em> springs to mind.</p>
<p>It’s a quick, actionable, and power-packed resuscitator for your rankings.</p>
<p>By generating high-quality backlinks, you can redirect <em><u>a ton of</u></em> convertible traffic your way.<span id="more-2542"></span></p>
<p>More leads, massive sales, and consistent business growth. Sounds like the perfect mix for your company, right?</p>
<p>When it comes to <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service/"><u>creating a winning link building strategy</u></a>, you should have a razor-sharp focus on two aspects: backlink quality and quantity.</p>
<p>In this blog, we’ll dive deeper into why these aspects matter so much. We’ll also take a closer look at what’s more important: backlink quality or quantity?</p>
<p>Let’s get started!</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Struggling to build lots of high-quality backlinks? Fill out the form to let our link building experts do the trick!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>Contents</p>
<p><a href="#_Toc63698612"><u>What Are Backlinks and How Do I Get Them?</u> </a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc63698613"><u>Link Building Quality vs. Quantity: What Should I Focus On?</u> </a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc63698614"><u>Backlink Quality</u> </a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc63698615"><u> Backlink Placement</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc63698616"><u> Backlink Relevance</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc63698617"><u> Backlink Count</u> </a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc63698618"><u>Backlink Quantity</u> </a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc63698619"><u> Referring Domains</u> </a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc63698620"><u> Spam Avoidance and Elimination</u> </a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc63698621"><u>Wrapping Up!</u> </a></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc63698612"></a><strong><b>What Are Backlinks and How Do I Get Them?</b></strong></h2>
<p>Before we deconstruct backlink quality and quantity, let’s start with the basics so you can get up to speed.</p>
<p>Simply put, a backlink is <strong><u>a hyperlink that redirects web users to your web content</u></strong>, i.e., product/service pages, blogs, etc.</p>
<p>Here’s a video that illustrates this:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GwiI6V1eyQg" width="730" height="410" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"><span style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" data-mce-type="bookmark" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></p>
<p>Let’s consider an example to make things a tad clearer.</p>
<p>Let’s say you’ve written <em>a stellar blog</em> that covers a new topic in your industry.</p>
<p>The blog is packed with rich insights, value-added tips, high-quality images, and research-backed statistics.</p>
<p>Shortly after you publish your blog, Forbes decides to cover a similar topic owing to its popularity and demand in your niche.</p>
<p>They haven’t come across your content yet, but as they’re working on their piece, they stumble upon your blog during their research process.</p>
<p>They’re impressed with the insights, and choose to reference your piece in their own work.</p>
<p>As they quote your blog, they offer you a backlink by using <a href="https://moz.com/learn/seo/anchor-text" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>anchor text</u></a>.</p>
<p>Here’s what this looks like:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2543" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/a-screenshot-of-Forbes’-blog-featuring-a-backlink.png" alt="a screenshot of Forbes’ blog featuring a backlink" width="463" height="170" /></p>
<p>When web users click on the anchor text, they’ll be redirected to your site.</p>
<p>And you don’t <em>have</em> to include statistics in your content to earn backlinks; simply writing engaging content can do the trick!</p>
<p>In fact, if your SEO efforts have been top-tier, a high-DA <a href="https://moz.com/learn/seo/domain-authority" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>(domain authority)</u></a> company like Forbes will notice you and send some link juice your way without being prompted to do so via a blog or any other form of content.</p>
<p>Here’s a glimpse of what this may look like:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2544" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/a-screenshot-of-Forbes’-blog-featuring-a-backlink-to-Beautyque-NYC.png" alt="a screenshot of Forbes’ blog featuring a backlink to Beautyque NYC" width="440" height="160" /></p>
<p>These are all examples of high-quality backlinks.</p>
<p><em>Why are they high-quality?</em></p>
<p>Because they’re coming from a reputable company like Forbes that has an impressive DR (domain rating) of 93.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2545" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Forbes’-domain-rating.png" alt="Forbes’ domain rating" width="621" height="348" /></p>
<p>Forbes is a tour de force. The company attracts <em>millions of web users</em> on a regular basis.</p>
<p>If they offer you a backlink, you’ll notice <strong>a massive upsurge in your traffic and rankings.</strong></p>
<p>This is why building high-quality backlinks should be one of your top priorities.</p>
<p>But what else constitutes a high-quality backlink? And where does backlink quantity fit into the equation?</p>
<p>Let’s find out.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>New to link building? Fill out the form to let our experts take the reins! We’ll help you rank higher and bag more clients with high-quality backlinks.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2><strong><b>Link Building Quality vs. Quantity</b></strong><strong><b>: What Should I Focus On?</b></strong></h2>
<h3><strong><b>Backlink Quality</b></strong></h3>
<p>Building high-quality backlinks is your golden ticket to getting a power-packed SEO boost.</p>
<p>If you earn a backlink from an industry giant like Forbes, Medium, Business Insider, or Entrepreneur, you’ll notice <em>a generous rise in conversions</em>.</p>
<p>In addition, your company’s reputability and authoritativeness will increase by leaps and bounds.</p>
<p>As stated earlier, backlink quality is largely determined by a company’s DA.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2556" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/a-scale-featuring-companies-and-their-DA-1.png" alt="a scale featuring companies and their DA" width="1195" height="283" /></p>
<p>The higher, <em>the better</em>.</p>
<p>We recommend checking your company’s DA prior to launching your link building strategy.</p>
<p>If you’re just starting off, aim to build backlinks from companies with a DA score that’s roughly 20 points more than yours.</p>
<p>This will help you start off on the right (and steady) foot as opposed to shooting for the stars and returning with your hands empty.</p>
<p>While checking a company’s DA can help you determine whether it offers high-quality or low-quality backlinks, <em><u>you shouldn’t stop there</u></em>.</p>
<p>There are several other factors that come into play here.</p>
<p>No matter how reputable a company may be, a poorly placed or tangential nod to your site won’t do you any favors.</p>
<p>If you’re looking to bag high-quality backlinks, make sure you <u>take more than just the DA into consideration</u>.</p>
<p>Here are some key factors you should focus on:</p>
<h4><strong><b>1. Backlink Placement</b></strong></h4>
<p>A high-quality backlink appears <strong><u>organically</u></strong> in text. It’s not awkwardly forced into a paragraph; instead, it fits in smoothly and seamlessly.</p>
<p><em>Here’s why this matters: </em></p>
<p>Web users are smart. They know when a company is trying to be promotional, and they’re likely to opt out if there’s excessive and unshrouded promotion involved.</p>
<p>If you receive a backlink that’s awkwardly placed and looks promotional, you won’t get much out of it—no matter how credible the backlink lending company may be.</p>
<p>A stellar backlink is placed in the body or CTA (call-to-action) of a blog, article, or any other form of content.</p>
<p>If you receive a backlink from a high-DA site but notice that it’s not well-placed, feel free to <u>reach out to your link building partner via email</u>.</p>
<h4><strong><b>2. Backlink Relevance</b></strong></h4>
<p><strong><u>Let’s say you run a furniture store in New York. </u></strong></p>
<p>While touching upon how technology is influencing interior design, TechRadar (DA = 90) ends up offering you a backlink.</p>
<p><em>Great, right?</em></p>
<p>Well, in the same vein, Architectural Digest (DA = 87) includes a link to your content in their own long-form blog on the hottest furniture trends in New York this year.</p>
<p>Sure, TechRadar has a higher DA than Architectural Digest.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2547" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/techradar.png" alt="TechRadar’s domain rating" width="607" height="226" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2548" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/Architectural-Digest’s-domain-rating.png" alt="Architectural Digest’s domain rating " width="608" height="226" /></p>
<p>But which backlink is <strong><u>more relevant</u></strong> to your products, audience, industry, content, topics, and location?</p>
<p><em>The latter.</em></p>
<p>Backlink relevance is a make-it or break-it factor here.</p>
<p>It’s important to note that TechRadar’s audience is largely interested in tech news and reviews.</p>
<p>If they offer you a backlink, you’ll manage to target a small subset of people who enjoy both tech and interior design.</p>
<p>This may be 10%, 15%, or 20% of their audience, at best.</p>
<p>However, earning a backlink from Architectural Digest will help you engage <em>interior design aficionados.</em></p>
<p>As a furniture store owner, <strong><u>that’s your target audience.</u></strong></p>
<p>And as you engage your ideal demographic, you’ll maximize conversions.</p>
<p>Keep backlink relevance in mind each time you receive a backlink.</p>
<p>This isn’t to say that receiving backlinks from companies that deviate from your industry is useless.</p>
<p><em><u>It’s not.</u></em></p>
<p>However, it’s not as significant as receiving backlinks from industry-specific businesses.</p>
<p>In addition, look for <strong><u>topical relevance</u></strong>. And if the backlink is <strong><u>locally relevant</u></strong>, you’ve hit the jackpot.</p>
<p>Keeping these factors in mind will go a long way in helping you double down on high-quality backlinks that can benefit your business the most.</p>
<h3><strong><b>3. Backlink Count</b></strong></h3>
<p>Each time you earn a backlink, scan the lending company’s content to gauge how many other businesses they’ve provided backlinks to.</p>
<p>If the number’s pretty high in relation to the word count, <em><u>you’re in trouble</u></em>.</p>
<p>You’ve probably connected the dots by now.</p>
<p>If a paragraph features a single backlink, web users are <strong><u>more likely to click on it.</u></strong></p>
<p>However, if the same paragraph is filled with multiple hyperlinks, your backlink instantly becomes less clickable; there’s a smaller chance of web users clicking on it.</p>
<p>And if the other companies that have been linked are your competitors, your backlink further goes down in value.</p>
<p>If you’re looking to get valued backlinks to your website, make sure you keep an eye out for backlink count.</p>
<h2><strong><b>Backlink Quantity</b></strong></h2>
<p>By now, we’re sure you have a strong grasp on the importance of backlink quality.</p>
<p>If you fail to check off the right boxes, you’ll struggle to reap the benefits of link building.</p>
<p>And while building high-quality backlinks is important, ensuring you receive <em>sizeable backlinks</em> is just as imperative.</p>
<p>In essence, <strong><u>both backlink quality and quantity are equally important.</u></strong></p>
<p>However, people often prioritize backlink quality over quantity.</p>
<p>Here’s why you should avoid doing this if you’re looking to tap into long-term SEO success.</p>
<p>Let’s say you receive a couple of high-quality backlinks (DA = 90) every other month. Over time, the number of backlinks remains consistent but fails to increase.</p>
<p>In comparison, one of your key competitors earns <em>a lot of backlinks</em> from companies with an average DA of 75.</p>
<p>Ultimately, you’re both garnering a similar amount of traffic and ranking identically on Google SERPs.</p>
<p>While you’ve prioritized quality, you’ve sidelined quantity. And while your competitor has doubled down on quantity, they’ve let go of quality.</p>
<p>If you give one aspect more importance over the other, you’ll struggle to unlock your link building potential and improve your online presence.</p>
<p>Here are some key aspects of backlink quantity that should be kept in mind when creating a link building strategy:</p>
<h3><strong><b>1. Referring Domains</b></strong></h3>
<p>A referring domain is a site that “refers” to your business without providing a hyperlink, i.e., they mention your company without including clickable anchor text.</p>
<p>If you’re hyperfocused on backlink quality, you’ll disregard the importance of referring domains.</p>
<p>After all, how can you possibly benefit from mere mentions that don’t redirect web users to your site?</p>
<p>Well, <em>you can,</em> and more than you may think.</p>
<p>According to research, the number of referring domains determines how well you rank on Google SERPs.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2549" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/a-graph-illustrating-the-correlation-between-the-number-of-referring-domains-and-Google-position.png" alt="a graph illustrating the correlation between the number of referring domains and Google position" width="624" height="420" /></p>
<p>Of course, converting unlinked mentions into strong backlinks is a great way to <em>rank even higher </em>on SERPs.</p>
<p>But dismissing the quantity of referring domains altogether will cost you in the long run.</p>
<p>While they may not be clickable, unlinked mentions cause visible ripples.</p>
<p>Web users may have to do a little extra work by manually looking up your business, but they <em><u>will</u></em> take the initiative if the mention is compelling enough!</p>
<p>By focusing on the quantity of backlinks, you’ll manage to increase your referring domains and gradually work towards converting them into backlinks.</p>
<h3><strong><b>2. Spam Avoidance and Elimination</b></strong></h3>
<p>Backlink quantity has gotten a bad rap over the years. And it’s hard to point fingers because the criticism is partly justified.</p>
<p>If you’re creating a link building strategy with backlink quantity in mind, you can easily go wrong.</p>
<p>This is because using tactics to generate more (as opposed to quality) backlinks can result in generating unreliable links from spammy websites.</p>
<p>If you fall into this trap, you could end up getting penalized by Google.</p>
<p>To avoid resorting to black hat SEO techniques—albeit inadvertently—make sure you only focus on increasing backlink quantity <strong><u>after you’ve covered all the bases of backlink quality</u></strong><strong>.</strong></p>
<p>This way, you’ll eliminate the risk of getting spammy mentions and backlinks.</p>
<p>In other words, make sure you fall in the middle and avoid the extremes.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2550" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/backlink-quality-vs.-quantity-scale.png" alt="backlink-quality-vs.-quantity-scale" width="624" height="357" /></p>
<p>By creating a strategy without falling on the opposite ends of the spectrum, you’ll get a steady start.</p>
<p>As you master the middle strategy, start focusing on building a high amount of high-converting traffic.</p>
<h1><a name="_Toc63698621"></a><strong><b>Wrapping Up!</b></strong></h1>
<p>In this blog, we walked you through the key aspects of backlink quality and quantity.</p>
<p>If your search history is filled with queries like <em>“</em><em>how to get dofollow backlinks</em><em>,” “</em><em>how to do link building in SEO</em><em>,”</em> and <em>“</em><em>how to get quality backlinks</em><em>,”</em> we can give you a head start.</p>
<p>Browse through our blog, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-advanced-link-building-tips-and-tricks-to-boost-your-seo/"><u>10 Advanced Link Building Tips and Tricks to Boost Your SEO</u></a>, to revamp your link building strategy.</p>
<p>And if you’re still unsure about how link building can benefit your business, check out our blog, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-marketers-guide-to-the-powerful-benefits-of-consistent-link-building/"><u>A Marketer’s Guide to the Powerful Benefits of Consistent Link Building</u></a>.</p>
<p>Once you’re ready to get started, give us a call at <a href="tel:8554444777"><u>855-444-4777</u></a> and our <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service/">link building pros</a> will create a customized link building strategy for your business!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/backlink-quality-vs-quantity-whats-more-important-in-2021/">Backlink Quality vs. Quantity: What’s More Important in 2021?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/backlink-quality-vs-quantity-whats-more-important-in-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Reasons Why Your Business Needs A Link Building Strategy [Infographic]</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-reasons-why-your-business-needs-a-link-building-strategy-infographic/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-reasons-why-your-business-needs-a-link-building-strategy-infographic/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 14:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Link Building]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As one of the most effective and whip-smart digital marketing strategies, consistent link building is designed to help companies attract high-quality traffic and increase revenue.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-reasons-why-your-business-needs-a-link-building-strategy-infographic/">5 Reasons Why Your Business Needs A Link Building Strategy [Infographic]</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<p></p>



<p>As link building becomes one of the fastest-growing SEO strategies, marketers are jumping on the bandwagon stat.</p>



<p>And there’s a good reason why.</p>



<p>But, what is link building? High-quality backlinks are among the top three Google ranking factors for 2020. As you build authoritative backlinks from websites with high domain authority, you make it much, <em>much</em>&nbsp;easier for Google to crawl, index, and rank your site page(s).</p>



<p>Google’s algorithm also perceives your site as a reputable source in the industry when you work toward this goal, owing to the <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-marketers-guide-to-the-powerful-benefits-of-consistent-link-building/"><u>quantity and quality of backlinks</u></a>&nbsp;pointing in your direction.</p>



<p>While you may have leveraged web design and development and mastered the art of content creation, sidelining link building for SEO&nbsp;could end up doing more harm than good.</p>



<p>In this infographic, our experts walk you through five reasons why your business needs the best link building strategy.</p>



<p>We dive into some compelling statistics and offer numerous tips to help you make the most of our <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service/"><u>backlink building service</u></a>&nbsp;and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/get-ranked-high-in-2020-6-proven-seo-strategies-for-small-businesses-and-startups/"><u>climb search engine result pages (SERPs)</u></a>.</p>



<span id="more-1905"></span>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service/"><img src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/SB-Copy.png" alt="As link building becomes one of the fastest-growing SEO strategies, marketers are jumping on the bandwagon stat. 
And there’s a good reason why. 
But, what is link building? High-quality backlinks are among the top three Google ranking factors for 2020. As you build authoritative backlinks from websites with high domain authority, you make it much, much easier for Google to crawl, index, and rank your site page(s). 
Google’s algorithm also perceives your site as a reputable source in the industry when you work toward this goal, owing to the quantity and quality of backlinks pointing in your direction. 
While you may have leveraged web design and development and mastered the art of content creation, sidelining link building for SEO could end up doing more harm than good. 
In this infographic, our expertswalk you through five reasons why your business needsthe bestlink building strategy. 
We dive into some compelling statistics and offer numerous tips to help you make the most of our backlink building service and climb search engine result pages (SERPs)." class="wp-image-1930"/></a></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-reasons-why-your-business-needs-a-link-building-strategy-infographic/">5 Reasons Why Your Business Needs A Link Building Strategy [Infographic]</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-reasons-why-your-business-needs-a-link-building-strategy-infographic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Advanced Link Building Tips and Tricks to Boost Your SEO</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-advanced-link-building-tips-and-tricks-to-boost-your-seo/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-advanced-link-building-tips-and-tricks-to-boost-your-seo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Harper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 07:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Link Building]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; You’ve developed a visually engaging and seamless website. Your social media presence has been off the charts lately. And you recently leveraged Google My Business to increase visibility and revenue. However, the numbers still seem to be stuck in limbo. If you’re struggling to figure out why your business is failing to meet KPI targets and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-advanced-link-building-tips-and-tricks-to-boost-your-seo/">10 Advanced Link Building Tips and Tricks to Boost Your SEO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>You’ve developed a visually engaging and seamless website. Your social media presence has been off the charts lately. And you recently leveraged <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-optimize-google-my-business-listing-and-leverage-it-for-more-sales/"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Google My Business</span> to increase visibility</a> and revenue.<span id="more-1593"></span></p>
<p>However, the numbers <em><i>still</i></em> seem to be stuck in limbo.</p>
<p>If you’re struggling to figure out why your business is failing to meet KPI targets and reach new milestones, it may be time to look inwards.</p>
<p><em>Have you invested in <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service/">quality link building services</a> by a reputable link building SEO company?</em></p>
<p>According to a recent study, receiving plentiful high-quality backlinks has the highest correlation to Google rankings.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1595" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/a-graphic-design-with-the-term-‘link-building’-written-in-the-center.png" alt="a graphic design with the term ‘link building’ written in the center" width="624" height="368" /></p>
<p>While you may have leveraged SEO to boost traffic, leaving link building out of the mix can easily cause your numbers to plummet. And while you may already have a link building strategy in place, doing the bare minimum simply isn’t enough in today’s competitive digital marketing space.</p>
<p>Opting for generic and ineffective link building strategies is one of the most common reasons why businesses get stuck in a rut that seems impossible to get out of.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/292366" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>Entrepreneur</u></a>, having a weak link building strategy has a detrimental impact on rankings, brand presence, and customer acquisition. On the other hand, a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-link-building-and-why-does-my-business-need-it/"><u>strong link building strategy</u></a> is a surefire way to increase traffic, improve search rankings, convert visitors into leads, and reduce customer attrition and bounce rates.</p>
<p>That’s why we’ve rounded up ten advanced link building tips and tricks to help <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-services.html"><u>boost SEO</u></a> and increase revenue.</p>
<h2><strong><b>1. Maintain a Strong Online Presence to Build Quality Relationships</b></strong></h2>
<p>Link building is quite simply the process of acquiring one-way hyperlinks (commonly known as “backlinks”) from other websites to your own. Instead of waiting for established companies to naturally link to your page, you need to take charge and facilitate the process.</p>
<p>Most brands either forgo link building strategies entirely or go overboard by overtly requesting links through excessive emails, social media messages, and calls.</p>
<p>Opting for a strategy that falls on either end of the spectrum is a recipe for disaster.</p>
<p>Instead, we recommend carefully navigating the link building landscape and creating a strong and balanced strategy. Building quality relationships in your industry through active—albeit non-intrusive—online networking is a great way to acquire quality links for your products/services and web content.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1596" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/a-computer-screen-displaying-Facebook-messages-and-indicating-strong-business-networking.png" alt="a computer screen displaying Facebook messages and indicating strong business networking" width="624" height="428" /></p>
<p>Start by focusing on niche-related communities on social media and professional networking platforms like Facebook, Twitter, and LinkedIn.</p>
<p>Moreover, join local link building groups like <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/283822378314765/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer">Link Building Experts on Facebook</a>. As you interact with business leaders in your community, you’ll establish strong connections over time. This will organically increase your chances of receiving backlinks.</p>
<p>We recommend actively participating in group activities by posting relevant comments, responding to questions, adding contextual value to conversations, and sharing insightful updates. These strategies will collectively place you on the virtual business networking map, thereby bolstering your chances of receiving backlinks.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1597" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/backlinks.png" alt="backlinks" width="624" height="130" /></p>
<h2><strong><b>2. Master the Art of Producing Engaging and Value-Added Content</b></strong></h2>
<p>According to a recent study, companies with consistent and high-quality blogs received <a href="https://neilpatel.com/blog/11-ways-to-get-authority-links-for-your-new-blog/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>97%</u></a> more quality backlinks. Moreover, long-form content receives <a href="https://backlinko.com/content-study" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>up to 77.2%</u></a> more backlinks than short-form content.</p>
<p>Creating <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2020/02/20/four-content-marketing-trends-to-keep-an-eye-on-in-2020/#641e61603b56" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>engaging and value-added content</u></a> is one of the most effective ways to increase your chances of receiving reputable links to your website.</p>
<p>Instead of resorting to rehashed, unoriginal, and unappealing content, focus on improving quality. This simple yet transformative switch will help you generate more traffic and acquire links from established companies with high domain authority.</p>
<p>Ouai’s frequent, informative, witty, and value-added blogs are a <em><i>great</i></em> example of striking the perfect balance between quantity and quality:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1598" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/value-added-blogs.png" alt="value-added blogs" width="335" height="709" /></p>
<p>Their high-quality content and images, creativity, keyword usage, and posting frequency have helped them establish an impressive domain rating of 63, and they have secured approximately 18,000 backlinks.</p>
<p>Here’s a breakdown of the data acquired through the <a href="https://ahrefs.com/backlink-checker" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>Ahrefs Backlink Checker</u></a>:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1599" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Ahrefs-Backlink-Checker.png" alt="Ahrefs Backlink Checker" width="520" height="105" /></p>
<p>It’s vital to actively research relevant keywords and optimize anchor text accordingly to ensure your content climbs SERPs.</p>
<p>We also suggest posting at least 2–5 long-form blogs or articles per month to increase your chances of receiving backlinks. Long-form content generally has a 2,000+ word count.</p>
<p>You should ideally focus on creating different types of content, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Articles</li>
<li>Blogs</li>
<li>Press Releases</li>
<li>Case Studies</li>
<li>Infographics</li>
<li>Instructographics</li>
<li>Videos</li>
</ul>
<p>Check out <a href="https://www.apple.com/newsroom/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>Apple’s informative and newsworthy press releases</u></a> to incorporate similar content production tactics into your digital marketing strategy!</p>
<h2><strong><b>3. Strike the Perfect Balance between Using Internal </b></strong><strong><em><b><i>and</i></b></em></strong><strong><b> External Links</b></strong></h2>
<p>While using relevant and well-placed internal links is a powerful link building strategy, incorporating external links into the mix is <em><i>equally</i></em> important.</p>
<p>Simply put, internal links are hyperlinks that direct readers to your products/services or web pages. Alternatively, external links are hyperlinks that direct readers to external websites.</p>
<p>While using external links may sound counter intuitive, it’s a great way to encourage reputable websites to link back to your own content. Most companies receive notifications from Google Alerts or BuzzSumo each time a brand mentions or links to their products/services or content. If you have similar domain authority, it’s very likely that you’ll receive a backlink or social share from the website.</p>
<p>In addition, using reputable and informative external links helps your audience have an engaging and curated reading experience. This is a great way to boost SEO rankings by increasing audience engagement and retention.</p>
<p>Over time, you’ll notice an increase in monthly website traffic and a reduced bounce rate.</p>
<p>Strike the perfect balance between using internal and external links to increase the overall quality of your content. A central deciding factor for whether a company will give you a backlink, quality will ultimately help you ride the waves of link building with ease and adroitness.</p>
<h2><strong><b>4. Use Guest Blogging to Build Quality Links</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1600" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/a-computer-screen-displaying-a-guest-blog.png" alt="a computer screen displaying a guest blog" width="624" height="416" /></p>
<p>Writing <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/guest-blogging-services/"><u>high-quality guest blogs</u></a> for established companies within the same industry is one of the best link building tricks in the game. The tried-and-tested tactic works seamlessly by helping you tap into a new and wide audience base that would otherwise remain untargeted and unengaged.</p>
<p>The process involves writing content for another company’s website.</p>
<p><em>Sounds ridiculous, doesn’t it?</em></p>
<p>Here’s the trick.</p>
<p>While guest blogs are generally non-promotional in nature, they may include a few internal links to redirect readers to the host’s website. This increases traffic and enables the host to attract a new demographic.</p>
<p>Guest blogs also include a concluding section entitled “About the Author” or “Guest Article Written By.” This includes anchor text that redirects readers to the hosting company.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1601" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/About-the-Author.png" alt="About the Author" width="576" height="176" /></p>
<p>High-quality guest blogs are more likely to compel readers to visit the host’s website. If they like the content, they’ll feel the need to keep up with that style, format, and type of content in the future.</p>
<p>If you’re new to digital marketing, we strongly recommend browsing through our blog on the <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/"><u>benefits of guest blogging for small business owners</u></a> for more insights.</p>
<h2><strong><b>5. Keep Up With Backlinking Partners</b></strong></h2>
<p>Most link building tools enable companies to monitor websites that give them backlinks. Leveraging these tools is essential to keep up with your backlinking partners.</p>
<p>We recommend creating a list to track the brands that link to your products/services or webpages. This is especially important because certain companies that were a source of reputable backlinks in the past may stop linking to your pages.</p>
<p>In such cases, it’s imperative that you reach out to them with a polite email to determine why your site was dropped. This interaction can play a big role in reactivating backlinks and helping further business relationships.</p>
<p>Moreover, familiarizing yourself with your company’s backlinking partners is a great way to connect with them and return the favor, thereby concretizing the backlinking cycle.</p>
<p>Over time, establishing a large number of active backlinking partners will help your business maintain a strong online presence, target quality traffic, build trust and credibility, and break into new markets.</p>
<h2><strong><b>6. Become a Pro at Broken Link Building</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1602" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/a-graphic-design-displaying-a-computer-screen-and-a-webpage-with-multiple-links.png" alt="a graphic design displaying a computer screen and a webpage with multiple links" width="624" height="416" /></p>
<p>The broken link building strategy is undeniably one of the most powerful ways to <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-art-of-linkbuilding-by-earning-links-through-content-in-2018-and-beyond/"><u>leverage link building</u></a> and boost SEO. The process prevents readers from visiting broken webpages.</p>
<p>Start off by reviewing your backlinking history.</p>
<p>Compile a list of the times your website was referenced through anchor text but led to a dead link. Once you’re done, reach out to the respective companies and request them to replace the broken link with an active link to similar content on your website.</p>
<p>You may also create new content accordingly!</p>
<p>This is a great way to reactivate dead links and boost website rankings. While it may sound like a lot of work, SEO experts can help you out by identifying each broken backlink and sharing accompanying metrics.</p>
<p>This will help you determine which broken backlinks should be replaced on a priority basis. As the process is streamlined, you’ll manage to optimize your backlinks and direct a wide audience to your content that would otherwise receive a 404 page and remain out of the loop.</p>
<h2><strong><b>7. Convert Unlinked Mentions into Backlinks</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1603" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Convert-Unlinked-Mentions-into-Backlinks.png" alt="Convert Unlinked Mentions into Backlinks" width="624" height="130" /></p>
<p>In many cases, companies may mention your page without including a link. Not only is this a wasted opportunity, but it restricts a wide potential audience from interacting with your content.</p>
<p>People are more likely to click on anchor text that directly takes them to the respective website. A mere mention, unfortunately, induces little to no action.</p>
<p>We strongly recommend taking this step if a company with <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/high-domain-authority/">high domain authority</a> and SEO ranking mentions your brand.</p>
<h2><strong><b>8. Submit Testimonials</b></strong></h2>
<p>Testimonial link building is a great way for one company to build trust and credibility while the other receives a backlink.</p>
<p>It’s a win-win scenario any way you look at it!</p>
<p>If you’ve used products/services from a company in your industry, offer to submit testimonials in return for a backlink. This process also has a high approval rate compared to other link building strategies that may leave you in limbo as you await a response.</p>
<p>The trick is drafting a professional, persuasive, and concise email that poses the request without sounding overbearing. If done right, you’re more likely to receive a timely response and have your request processed.</p>
<p>We recommend offering to send testimonials to reputable and established websites with high domain authority and organic search rankings. However, reserve this strategy for when you have the time to try the respective product/service.</p>
<p>Refrain from writing inaccurate and misleading testimonials.</p>
<p>Done organically, you’ll manage to submit numerous authentic testimonials and receive strong backlinks that you feel good about!</p>
<h2><strong><b>9. Create High-Quality Infographics and Instructographics </b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1604" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/a-woman-using-a-drawing-tablet-and-a-pen-to-create-graphic-designs.png" alt="a woman using a drawing tablet and a pen to create graphic designs" width="624" height="417" /></p>
<p>According to recent research:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://blog.polleverywhere.com/visual-content/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>91% </u></a>of people prefer visual content over written content</li>
<li>Infographics have enjoyed <a href="https://contentmarketinginstitute.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/2018-b2b-research-final.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>the highest increase in popularity</u></a> among B2B marketers in the last five years</li>
<li><a href="https://www.office.xerox.com/latest/COLFS-02UA.PDF" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>Over 65%</u></a>of brands incorporate infographics in their marketing strategy</li>
<li>Content with infographics earns <a href="https://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/33393/The-Marketer-s-Ultimate-Guide-to-Link-Bait.aspx#sm.0001h5vdmybjoedew9c2oonp879wc" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow noreferrer"><u>178%</u></a> more links than standard content</li>
</ul>
<p>Infographics and instructographics are <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/earning-backlinks-with-infographics-in-2018/"><u>powerful link building tools</u></a> that are seldom done justice. As one of the lesser known link building strategies, these resources are a great way to earn quality backlinks and boost revenue.</p>
<p>We recommend creating high-quality, visually compelling, and easy-to-navigate infographics and instructographics that inform your audience without boring them.</p>
<p>Like any content, optimizing infographics and instructographics is the key to ranking success. Start with keyword research to identify primary and secondary keyword phrases. Use the right file name, alt text, H1 tag, and meta description to help Google determine the content category.</p>
<p>Lastly, your infographic or instructographic should have a short loading time to reduce the bounce rate on the page. Use PageSpeed Insights by Google to test the loading speed. PNGs, JPEGs, GIFs, and BMPs have the fastest loading times, so pick the right file format accordingly.</p>
<p>Once you’re done, share your infographic or instructographic on social media to increase visibility and the chance of acquiring high-quality backlinks.</p>
<h2><strong><b>10. Turn to </b></strong><strong><b>Quality Link Building Services</b></strong><strong><b> for Help</b></strong></h2>
<p>While you may have familiarized yourself with expert link building strategies, leveraging them without consulting an expert <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service/">link building SEO company</a> may pose to be a challenge.</p>
<p>Our backlink specialists utilize state-of-the-art SEO software tools, years of experience, and winning strategies to help businesses make the most of effective link building. As a leading digital marketing company in <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-new-york/">New York</a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-orlando/">Orlando</a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-seattle/">Seattle</a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-san-diego/">San Diego</a>, and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-washington-dc/">Washington</a>, we can help you get started!</p>
<p>Our cutting-edge link building strategies, resources, and tools are designed to help businesses receive high-quality backlinks, increase conversion rates, improve overall marketing ROI, generate more referral traffic, and decrease cost per acquisition.</p>
<p>Our white-hat approach to link building also eliminates the chances of incurring Google penalties, so you can increase organic traffic without worrying about any drawbacks.</p>
<p>Our quality link building services come with a 30-day money back guarantee.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/free-proposal.html"><u>Request a proposal and free SEO audit report</u></a> to get started! If you have any questions, feel free to call us at <a href="tel:8554444777"><u>855-444-4777</u></a> and we’ll take it from there.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-advanced-link-building-tips-and-tricks-to-boost-your-seo/">10 Advanced Link Building Tips and Tricks to Boost Your SEO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-advanced-link-building-tips-and-tricks-to-boost-your-seo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Marketer’s Guide to the Powerful Benefits of Consistent Link Building</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-marketers-guide-to-the-powerful-benefits-of-consistent-link-building/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-marketers-guide-to-the-powerful-benefits-of-consistent-link-building/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 18:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Link Building]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1559</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; If you’ve been in the SEO game for a while now, we’re sure you’ve picked up on the indispensable nature of consistent link building. Imagine walking into an upscale restaurant in Beverly Hills and being ushered to your table by an impeccably dressed server. You can’t help but feast your eyes on the compelling interior [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-marketers-guide-to-the-powerful-benefits-of-consistent-link-building/">A Marketer’s Guide to the Powerful Benefits of Consistent Link Building</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If you’ve been in the SEO game for a while now, we’re sure you’ve picked up on the indispensable nature of consistent link building.<span id="more-1559"></span></p>
<p>Imagine walking into an upscale restaurant in Beverly Hills and being ushered to your table by an impeccably dressed server. You can’t help but feast your eyes on the compelling interior design that fuses modern décor with eclectic colors and textures.</p>
<p>You’re handed a gorgeous manila menu that carries a soft whiff of fresh lavender and boysenberry.</p>
<p>As you browse through the delectable offerings, you notice perfectly-placed recommendations for pre-dining and post-dining festivities. While the thought of diving into flavorful filet mignon sounds like a dream, following the gourmet meal with a local outdoor concert sounds <em><i>just as good</i></em>.</p>
<p>In fact, you’re already browsing through the pre-dining activities so you can plan ahead and have an even <em><i>better</i></em> experience next time around!</p>
<p>While you leave with a great impression of the restaurant’s engaging and interactive approach, the restaurant owner and their collaborators leave with <strong><b>great business.</b></strong></p>
<p>Replicate the same strategy for your online business, and you have link building at its finest.</p>
<p>Simply put, an experienced <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service/"><strong><u><b>link building service</b></u></strong></a> helps businesses acquire backlinks from websites with a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/high-domain-authority/"><u>high page and domain authority</u></a> (i.e. the restaurant in this case). As one of the most effective and whip-smart digital marketing strategies, consistent link building is designed to help companies attract high-quality traffic and increase revenue.</p>
<p>If you’re new to the world of link building, we suggest checking out <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-link-building-and-why-does-my-business-need-it/"><u>our previous blog on link building tips and tricks</u></a> where we cover all the basics.</p>
<p>In this blog, we’ll walk you through the powerful benefits of link building so you can get a glimpse into <em><i>how</i></em> your business can benefit from partnering with a white hat link building service.</p>
<p>Curious?</p>
<p><em>Let’s dive in!</em></p>
<h2><strong><b>1. Get a Much-Needed Boost in Quality Website Traffic</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1561" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/graphic-design-displaying-four-adults-browsing-the-internet.png" alt="graphic design displaying four adults browsing the internet" width="624" height="390" /></p>
<p>According to <a href="http://ww2.conductor.com/rs/conductor2/images/SEO%20Enterprise%20Benchmark%20Study_Conductor.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u><b>41%</b></u></strong></a> of established companies, link building is the <em><i>single most difficult</i></em> SEO tactic to engage in.</p>
<p>While its efficacy makes the process worthwhile, many brands tend to abandon their link building strategies halfway through.</p>
<p><em>The outcome?</em></p>
<p>They fail to reap the benefits of consistent link building.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1562 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/earning-backlinks.png" alt="earning backlinks" width="624" height="130" /></a></p>
<p>If you tried your hand at <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/earning-backlinks-with-infographics-in-2018/"><u>earning backlinks</u></a> but couldn’t keep up with the project in the long run, you may not have witnessed the results you were hoping for.</p>
<p>As one of the most effective ways to build a hyper-specific audience, consistent link building helps attract targeted and localized quality traffic.</p>
<p>As established companies within the same industry link to your products/services, you’ll attract <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/stephanieburns/2020/01/29/4-tips-for-building-a-devoted-and-engaged-audience-online/#1d7923f3d796" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u><b>the </b></u></strong><strong><em><u><b><i>right</i></b></u></em></strong><strong><u><b> kind of audience</b></u></strong></a>.</p>
<p><em>Let’s look at it this way.</em></p>
<p>If you run a hair salon business in Manhattan, targeting men who are passionate about video games in Iowa is probably not the best way to go about things. And unless you have a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-art-of-linkbuilding-by-earning-links-through-content-in-2018-and-beyond/"><u>streamlined link building strategy</u></a> in place, it’s very likely that you’ll attract haphazard traffic.</p>
<p>While the numbers may indicate you’re on the right track, your efforts will ultimately go in vain.</p>
<p>Instead, link building strategies increase your chances of receiving <a href="https://neilpatel.com/blog/build-high-quality-backlinks/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>quality backlinks</u></a> from industry-relevant companies. This helps boost systematic traffic, thereby increasing the <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/theyec/2020/03/09/four-tactics-to-improve-your-conversions-in-2020/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>visitor-to-lead conversion rate</u></a>.</p>
<p>We suggest using <a href="https://ahrefs.com/backlink-checker" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Ahrefs’ free backlink checker</u></a> to determine the number of backlinks your website is currently receiving.</p>
<p>Here’s what the results should look like:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1563" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/free-backlink-checker.png" alt="free backlink checker" width="624" height="122" /></p>
<p>Consult link building specialists to help break down the information and demarcate <em><i>high-quality backlinks</i></em> from <em><i>low-qua</i></em><em><i>lity backlinks</i></em>.</p>
<p>As you receive a customized white hat link building plan for your website, you’ll manage to increase and sustain <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-website-seo-can-bring-your-new-website-high-rankings-increased-traffic-new-customers-and-more-leads/"><strong><u><b>quality website traffic</b></u></strong></a> in the long run.</p>
<p>Here are some key link building strategies you should focus on to attract quality traffic:</p>
<ul>
<li>Write engaging, optimized, and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-benefits-of-guest-blogging-for-small-businesses-owners/"><u>value-added guest blogs</u></a></li>
<li>Use high-quality external and internal links</li>
<li>Leverage a broken link building strategy</li>
<li>Convert unlinked mentions into backlinks</li>
<li>Maintain an <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-social-media-strategies-can-boost-my-seo/"><u>active social media presence</u></a></li>
<li>Create eye-catching, optimized, and easy-to-navigate <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/infographics/"><u>infographics</u></a></li>
</ul>
<h2><strong><b>2. Improve Search Rankings for Better Visibility and Exposure</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1564" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/graphic-design-displaying-a-phone-with-search-results.png" alt="graphic design displaying a phone with search results" width="624" height="624" /></p>
<p>According to research, a whopping <a href="https://www.link-assistant.com/news/link-building-survey-2017.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u><b>72%</b></u></strong></a> of SEO experts admit that quality backlinks are one of the leading factors that boost Google rankings.</p>
<p><em>Still not convinced?</em></p>
<p>A recent survey confirmed this postulation by revealing that the number of domains linking to a page has the <a href="https://backlinko.com/search-engine-ranking"><u>highest correlation</u></a> to Google rankings.</p>
<p>If your search rankings have been suffering lately, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-importance-of-link-building-in-seo/"><u>leveraging link building</u></a> is a great way to get your website to climb SERPs.</p>
<p>Web pages with a high number of quality backlinks are more likely to be perceived as reputable sources by Google’s algorithm. Not only will this help your website show up on the first page of Google, but it’ll also <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-build-a-good-reputation-for-your-business-that-will-entice-viewers-and-create-a-positive-brand-image/"><u>strengthen brand identity</u></a> in the long run.</p>
<p>The top search result on Google has an average of <a href="https://backlinko.com/search-engine-ranking" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u><b>3.8 times</b></u></strong></a> more backlinks than positions 2–10. So while your content may be great, it’s less likely to show up on the first page if there are little to no backlinks supporting it.</p>
<p>Leverage white hat link building strategies to increase your chances of receiving high-quality backlinks.</p>
<p>Forbes’ powerful piece titled <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jrose/2019/01/22/work-from-home-jobs-from-remote/#ef1785328f4d" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u><b>“The 10 Best Jobs Working From Home,”</b></u></strong></a> is exemplary of an engaging, optimized, and well-timed blog.</p>
<p>Not only has the impressive piece amassed over 1,700 backlinks, but it has also established a spectacular URL rating of 42.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1565" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/1700-backlinks.png" alt="1,700 backlinks" width="624" height="122" /></p>
<p><em>The best part?</em></p>
<p>You probably guessed it. It shows up on the <a href="https://neilpatel.com/blog/first-page-google/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>first page of Google search results</u></a> when you so much as type “work from home.”</p>
<p>That’s all it takes!</p>
<p>If you sift through the piece, you’ll notice <em><i>stellar</i></em> optimization and impactful content that flows <em><i>seamlessly</i></em>. The right use of keywords, title tag, meta description, alt text, and internal and external links goes a long way in attracting quality backlinks.</p>
<p>The clever shout-outs to established companies is another one of the many aspects of a strong link building strategy that the piece swiftly checks off.</p>
<p>Using the right link building strategies will ultimately help you earn high rankings and <a href="https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/160262" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>boost visibility and exposure</u></a>.</p>
<h2><strong><b>3. Increase Domain and Page Authority</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1567" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/graphic-design-displaying-web-analytics-on-a-web-page-1.png" alt="graphic design displaying web analytics on a web page" width="624" height="416" /></p>
<p><a href="https://moz.com/learn/seo/domain-authority" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u><b>Domain authority (DA)</b></u></strong></a><strong><b> </b></strong>and <a href="https://moz.com/learn/seo/page-authority" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u><b>page authority (PA)</b></u></strong></a> are search engine ranking scores that predict how well a website or specific page will rank on SERPs, respectively.</p>
<p>If you have a low domain and page authority, it’s <em><i>less likely</i></em> that your content will rank high on SERPs.</p>
<p>Despite the strong correlation, the large majority of businesses spend little to no time on improving their domain and page authority.</p>
<p>Consistent link building is one of the most effective ways to improve each score. As you receive quality backlinks from websites with a high domain authority, Google will perceive your content as more reputable. This, in turn, will help you climb SERPs and attract even more backlinks.</p>
<p>As the cycle continues, your website and individual pages will be deemed as established and trustworthy sources.</p>
<p>Google uses this information to determine the domain and page authority of each business with an online presence. And while there are other tricks to improving each score, receiving quality backlinks is the most effective.</p>
<p>Increase your chances of earning quality backlinks by researching businesses with high domain authority in your niche.</p>
<p>Focus on both local and international brands.</p>
<p>For instance, if you run an online interior design business, your research should include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Key players in the industry (<a href="https://www.architecturaldigest.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Architectural Digest</u></a>, <a href="https://www.elledecor.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Elle Décor</u></a>, <a href="https://www.dwell.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Dwell</u></a>, etc.)</li>
<li>Local businesses that are non-competitors (door designers, lighting companies, interior rug suppliers, bedding experts, etc.)</li>
</ul>
<p>Of course, take special care to keep direct competitors (other interior designers) off the list.</p>
<p>Once you’ve finalized the list, circulate it among your writing team so they can incorporate relevant external links in the <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog-writing-services/"><u>blogs</u></a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/article-writing/"><u>articles</u></a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/guest-blogging/"><u>guest posts</u></a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/infographics/"><u>infographics</u></a>, and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/press-release-writing/"><u>press releases</u></a>.</p>
<p>As you give virtual shout-outs to established companies within your industry, you’ll increase your chances of receiving a backlink in return.</p>
<p>Just make sure your content is <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2020/02/27/15-best-practices-for-producing-quality-engaging-content/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>witty, engaging, and informative</u></a> so they feel comfortable returning the favor! When paired with other <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service/"><u>white hat link building</u></a> strategies, this tactic will go a long way in helping you polish your domain and page authority.</p>
<h2><strong><b>4. Build Long-Term Relationships With Established Businesses</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1568" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/graphic-design-displaying-a-strong-digital-business-partnership.png" alt="graphic design displaying a strong digital business partnership" width="624" height="356" /></p>
<p>If you haven’t heard about <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2019/03/20/stop-looking-inward-for-success-what-to-know-about-co-branding/#4803cfe61264" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u><b>co-branding</b></u></strong></a> yet, it’s time to jump on the bandwagon and stay put!</p>
<p>In a nutshell, co-branding is a marketing partnership between two or more brands.</p>
<p>Over the years, high-profile brand partnerships have proven to be immensely successful. And we’re not just talking incredible exposure here, we’re talking <em><i>big</i></em> sales and profits!</p>
<p>From the popular collaboration between <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/nomiprins/2015/05/19/the-spotify-starbucks-partnership-is-digital-co-branding-genius/#6dec6c274a7a" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Starbucks and Spotify</u></a> to the powerful partnership between <a href="https://www.today.com/money/taco-bells-cool-ranch-tacos-co-branding-genius-1B7920357" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Taco Bell and Doritos</u></a>, the large majority of co-branding examples have struck gold. And while high-profile brand collaborations have stood out over the years, low-profile partnerships between small businesses have been equally successful—albeit at a smaller scale.</p>
<p>Link building opens up avenues for profitable co-branding opportunities by establishing long-term relationships between businesses.</p>
<p>In most cases, businesses track their backlinks using <a href="https://analytics.google.com/analytics/web/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Google Analytics</u></a>. As they receive quality backlinks, they’re more likely to engage with the company through an email or phone call to ensure backlink continuity over the years.</p>
<p>This interaction plays a big role in initiating and facilitating communication between companies, thereby increasing the likelihood of a potential partnership.</p>
<p>We strongly suggest monitoring your backlinks and keeping in touch with backlink partners.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/guest-blogging/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1569 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/backlink-partners.png" alt="backlink partners" width="624" height="130" /></a></p>
<h2><strong><b>5. Improve Brand Credibility and Reputation</b></strong></h2>
<p>Each quality backlink is a virtual endorsement for your business.</p>
<p>As your audience engages with backlinks to your products/services and content on reputable websites, they’re more likely to form a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/8-reasons-to-protect-your-brands-online-reputation-during-the-covid-19-pandemic/"><u>positive perception</u></a> about your brand. In fact, new audiences will also feel more inclined to visit your website as they come across anchor text linking to your page(s).</p>
<p>Additionally, local and international businesses in your niche are more likely to offer your website a backlink in their content.</p>
<p>As Google’s go-to ranking signal, a high number of quality backlinks will ultimately help you climb SERPs and establish <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/business-reputation-management/"><u>even greater credibility</u></a>.</p>
<p>As your brand identity improves, you’ll reap the benefits of increased audience engagement and retention!</p>
<h2><strong><b>6. Reduce Customer Churn Rate and Bounce Rate</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1570" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/graphic-design-displaying-multiple-adults-satisfied-with-a-brand’s-product.png" alt="graphic design displaying multiple adults satisfied with a brand’s products/services" width="624" height="377" /></p>
<p>As two of the most crucial KPIs, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbescommunicationscouncil/2020/02/05/five-churn-reduction-and-customer-retention-strategies/#1c1677416d7f" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u><b>customer churn rate</b></u></strong></a><strong><b> </b></strong>and <a href="https://neilpatel.com/blog/13-ways-to-reduce-bounce-rate-and-increase-your-conversions/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong><u><b>bounce rate</b></u></strong></a> can make or break a business.</p>
<p>If things get out of hand, a brand can suffer <em><i>massive</i></em> revenue loss and cost per acquisition rates can surge.</p>
<p>Consistent link building practices reduce customer churn rate and bounce rate by improving brand perception and lending much-needed credibility to a business. As a brand continues to attract high-quality backlinks, customers are less likely to branch out into a competitor’s products/services.</p>
<p>Receiving plentiful quality backlinks is also indicative of creating impactful and informative content.</p>
<p>As customers continue to engage with high-quality content, they enjoy a greater level of satisfaction and don’t feel the need to look for alternative products/services.</p>
<p>It’s no surprise that over 63% of customers admit that they think more positively about brands that offer value-added, engaging, and relevant content. And if they were redirected to your content from a website with high domain authority, you <em><i>already</i></em> have a head start!</p>
<h2><strong><b>7. Increase Your Social Media Following</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1571" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/graphic-design-displaying-a-tablet-screen-with-multiple-social-media-analytics.png" alt="graphic design displaying a tablet screen with multiple social media analytics" width="624" height="416" /></p>
<p><em>Struggling to boost your <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/social-media-management/"><u>social media following</u></a>?</em></p>
<p>While it’s less likely that you’ll receive a backlink to your social media pages, it’s something you can do yourself!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service/"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1572" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/link-building.png" alt="link building" width="624" height="130" /></a></p>
<p>We suggest using <a href="https://neilpatel.com/blog/anchor-text/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>anchor text</u></a> in your content to redirect users to your social media pages. While you may feel compelled to spread numerous links across the length of your content, we strongly suggest limiting them to the call-to-action (CTA). This will keep your content focused while allowing readers to follow up on the relevant links.</p>
<h2><strong><b>8. Long-Term Growth</b></strong></h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1573" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/graphic-design-demonstrating-business-growth.png" alt="graphic design demonstrating business growth" width="624" height="624" /></p>
<p>Consistent link building isn’t an easy feat to accomplish.</p>
<p>If you manage to keep up with your link building strategies, you’re simultaneously increasing the chances of ensuring <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/allbusiness/2020/03/30/business-experts-share-strategies-for-maximum-growth/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>long-term growth</u></a> for your business.</p>
<p>As your business expands and evolves over the years, you’ll reap the benefits of a stellar online presence, widening audience base, high traffic and rankings, and impressive profits.</p>
<p>As one of the leading link building companies in New York, Seattle, Orlando, San Diego, and Washington DC, we can help you get started. Our link building specialists have decades of experience and unique insights into the intricacies of link building.</p>
<p>We offer <strong><b>award-winning </b></strong><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service/"><strong><u><b>white hat link building services</b></u></strong></a> to help businesses:</p>
<ul>
<li>Build impressive domain and page authority</li>
<li>Increase quality traffic and visibility</li>
<li>Boost search rankings</li>
<li>Establish long-term backlink relationships</li>
</ul>
<p>Over the years, our link building specialists have helped countless businesses in the automotive, construction, education, travel, health, shipping, technology, and real estate industries.</p>
<p>We’ve successfully completed <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-successfully-completes-30000-projects/"><strong><u><b>over 30,000 projects</b></u></strong></a> and don’t plan on stopping any time soon!</p>
<p>Find out more about our white hat link building services to help your brand establish and maintain a competitive edge in the realm of digital marketing.</p>
<p>We also offer expert <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/"><u>SEO and lead generation</u></a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/ppc-marketing/"><u>paid marketing</u></a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/content-marketing/"><u>content marketing</u></a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/web-design-development-services/"><u>website design and development</u></a>, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/social-media-management/"><u>social media management</u></a>, and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/reputation-management/"><u>reputation management services</u></a> across the U.S.</p>
<p>Call <a href="tel:8554444777"><u>855-444-4777</u></a> to get started. Check out our <a href="https://www.facebook.com/searchberg"><u>Facebook page</u></a> for more information.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-marketers-guide-to-the-powerful-benefits-of-consistent-link-building/">A Marketer’s Guide to the Powerful Benefits of Consistent Link Building</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-marketers-guide-to-the-powerful-benefits-of-consistent-link-building/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Link Building Services and Strategies for Websites and Small Businesses</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-link-building-services-and-strategies-for-websites-and-small-businesses/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-link-building-services-and-strategies-for-websites-and-small-businesses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matt Jensen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 15:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Link Building]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Small Business SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to running a small business, entrepreneurs often feel the pressure to market their brand without going over the budget. Finding convenient and affordable promotion options can be a difficult task, but that’s where SEO marketing comes in. SEO marketing is a highly effective way to promote your business and not just for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-link-building-services-and-strategies-for-websites-and-small-businesses/">10 Link Building Services and Strategies for Websites and Small Businesses</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to running a small business, entrepreneurs often feel the pressure to market their brand without going over the budget. Finding convenient and affordable promotion options can be a difficult task, but that’s where <a href="https://www.shopify.com/blog/seo-marketing">SEO marketing</a> comes in.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1302" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/1.jpg" alt="Link Building Services and Strategies for Websites and Small Businesses" width="750" height="483" /></p>
<p>SEO marketing is a highly effective way to promote your business and not just for the short term. With the right services, you can ensure your top spot at Google’s search engine rankings consistently.</p>
<p>However, there are some things you’d want to heed caution over. One major problem with promoting your business online is that if you’re not well-versed with SEO, you might end up using keyword-stuffed pages on low-quality links. Not only does this affect your search engine rankings, but it also signs you up for <a href="https://www.searchenginejournal.com/the-complete-list-of-google-penalties-and-how-to-recover/201510/">SEO penalties</a>.</p>
<p>But with the help of an established <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/">digital SEO marketing agency</a> like Search Berg, you can get white hat SEO strategies to boost the visibility of your local business. We believe in the power of link building to help steer small businesses to the top of Google’s search results page. In today’s blog, we’ll show you how you can build links that will benefit the growth of your online business!</p>
<h2>1. Initiate Partnerships with Other Local Businesses</h2>
<p>The essence of link building lies in networking. You need businesses to link back to your website so your business grows in credibility, yields more traffic and climbs up the SEO ranks. However, local businesses will only want to feature you on their website if they feel like they have some connection to your work—without feeling like you’re an outright competitor.</p>
<p>For example, if you sell cat food then you should get in touch with vets, cat grooming salons and pet shelter businesses.</p>
<p>Now, as an entrepreneur, you’d know the importance of providing incentives to get work done. Likewise, when you’re building links, try to offer rewards like discounts to some of your customers who link or refer to your business on their website. The more relationships you build, the more attention your business will get.</p>
<h2>2. Contribute to Local Organizations or Events</h2>
<p>While you keep forging new networks within your local industry, it’ll help to offer sponsorships to local not-for-profit organizations. A sponsorship can easily put you on the map and if you’re aligned with your partner organization’s values, then you can also tap into a broader market segment.</p>
<p>Keep an eye out for arts and music festivals, conferences and other events that could potentially bring in more customers for you. As a promotion for the event begins, your business’s name will be on pretty much every online poster and newsletter published by that organization. This will improve your chance to build authentic links within the local community.</p>
<h2>3. Become a Member of a Professional Organization that has Access to Directories</h2>
<p>When it comes to the local industry, different cities have different chambers that are built to cater to a specific business demographic. For example, a <a href="https://www.creditdonkey.com/chamber-people.html">chamber of commerce</a> can be dedicated to uplifting minority groups within your community.</p>
<p>Many such professional organizations have links to these industry chambers and winning a link with them could work brilliantly for you. Keep an eye out for organizations that are relevant to you and the ones that offer membership with directory access.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1306" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/b1.jpg" alt="" width="750" height="156" /></p>
<h2>4. Host a Fundraiser or Charity Drive</h2>
<p>Becoming part of community events is a great strategy to build legitimate links. Not only do you get to support a good cause, but people are more likely to share links and spread the word regarding such events.</p>
<p>Once non-profits begin promoting your support on their website, local bloggers and journalists are going to be interested in featuring you on their story. It’s a good way to win your business some press coverage.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1303" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/2.jpg" alt="Host a Fundraiser or Charity Drive" width="750" height="483" /></p>
<h2> 5. Get into Content Marketing</h2>
<p>Fresh and relevant content is a huge aspect of link building. When you post something new, other websites have a reason to link back to you. Make sure you have a blog portal on your website that you regularly update.</p>
<p>Now, content marketing can get extremely competitive since there are lots of businesses that are using this method to build links. However, your focus shouldn’t be to compete with all these businesses; just focus on the local industry that serves your target market.</p>
<p>When it comes to reaching out to your clients via content marketing, you need to write about something that’s useful to them and is presented in a locally relevant context. Try to produce work on topics that work for you and your community members.</p>
<p>For example, if you own a shop that sells ATVs and scooters, you can write a blog about the best spots in town to ride your one-person vehicle.</p>
<h2>6. Get in Touch with Local Bloggers</h2>
<p>Bloggers come with an established reader fan base and can help you market content that’s new and relevant to locals. Make the first move and get in touch with bloggers who’d be interested in partnering with you. Ask them to cover something related to your website or put in a positive review for your business.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1307" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/b2.jpg" alt="" width="750" height="156" /></p>
<h2>7. Keep an Eye Out for Local Round-up Pages</h2>
<p>You’ve probably seen online content with some kind of countdown or a list of the best businesses in a particular industry; these are round-up pages.</p>
<p>Round up pages are location-specific and are usually ranked highly on search engine results. This means these pages are going to get plenty of clicks and visitor traffic. Figure out what categories or tags your business could fit into and try to get in touch with the writer for a promotion link. Even if they’re not ready to feature you in the upcoming list, they can shortlist your business for future references.</p>
<h2>8. Write Guest Posts</h2>
<p>If you’re looking for a reliable white hat linking strategy, then guest posts are going to be your best bet. Guest posting promotes both ways; you and the website business you’re writing for.</p>
<p>Small businesses, in particular, can benefit from guest posting because they don’t have to pay or make any offers to anyone for promotion. You’re essentially putting your business out there by writing for someone else’s audience.</p>
<p>Do some research on local blogs that are useful for your business and are willing to partner with you on guest posts.</p>
<p><strong>Pro-tip:</strong> Pitch your proposal for guest posting with a relevant topic that works for both, you and your partner. That way, you can insert links back to your website in a natural way, without it ever seeming forced.</p>
<h2>9. Build Broken Links</h2>
<p>Broken links are a bane for many online businesses, but the solution to it is fairly simple. Keep your eyes peeled for local industry websites that have broken page links. Alert the website owners about the problem and offer them your website link as a replacement.</p>
<p>It might seem too good to be true, but this strategy works precisely because fixing broken links helps that website’s SEO ranks and your website serves as a quick and convenient fix for their problem.</p>
<p>Try to get in touch with businesses that deal with similar products or services because that way it becomes easier for you to convince them that you’re a good replacement for their site.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1304" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/3.jpg" alt="Build Broken Links" width="750" height="483" /></p>
<h2> 10. Practice Awards and Giveaways</h2>
<p>Winning an award is a matter of pride and everyone wants to share their achievement with the world. If your business begins handing out awards, honorable mentions and credits to local businesses and their owners there’s a high likelihood you’ll be the talk of the town for the upcoming week.</p>
<p>People would love to post about their honors, especially on their social media pages. If you’re able to present the winning names on your website, you can easily manage plenty of link shares to your website.</p>
<p>Giveaways are also a great way to reach out to local customers and introduce traffic to your website. Fun competitions that involve people sharing links to your website can get you many links in a short amount of time. It can also connect you to other businesses who’d want to partner with you and hold a bigger event in the near future.</p>
<h2>And There You Have It!</h2>
<p>These were some of our trusty tactics to help you build links in an authentic and reliable manner. The great thing about our strategies is that they don’t just win your business better visibility, but they also make you more appreciated and valued in your community.</p>
<h2>Looking for Professional Link Building Services?</h2>
<p>Building links is not an overnight task. It can take weeks and months of patient work. You can skip the labor and let Search Berg help you find your way to the top! One of the most prominent <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-services.html">SEO marketing</a> and <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service.html">link development agencies</a> in the United States, we’re offering all our clients <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/content-marketing.html">content marketing services, starting at $199</a> only!</p>
<p>Get in touch with our team <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/contact-us.html">here</a> or call now at 855-444-4777 to earn more links for your growing online business!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-link-building-services-and-strategies-for-websites-and-small-businesses/">10 Link Building Services and Strategies for Websites and Small Businesses</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-link-building-services-and-strategies-for-websites-and-small-businesses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Is Link Building And Why Does My Business Need It?</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-link-building-and-why-does-my-business-need-it/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-link-building-and-why-does-my-business-need-it/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 10:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Link Building]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=962</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What Is Link Building? The SEO landscape is ever-evolving. Therefore, strategies pertaining to SEO must change accordingly. This includes link building as well. The importance of high-value links is undeniable today. In order to thrive online and get a competitive advantage, businesses must implement effective link building campaigns. In its most basic form, link building [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-link-building-and-why-does-my-business-need-it/">What Is Link Building And Why Does My Business Need It?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>What Is Link Building?</h2>
<p>The SEO landscape is ever-evolving. Therefore, strategies pertaining to SEO must change accordingly. This includes link building as well. The importance of high-value links is undeniable today. In order to thrive online and get a competitive advantage, businesses must implement effective link building campaigns.</p>
<p>In its most basic form, link building is simply the process of gathering links from high-traffic websites that are relevant to your business to your own. Mastering the techniques involved in building high-value links will be the best way to improve your SEO efforts.</p>
<p>The more high-quality links you get to your website, the better you will rank on Google and the more traffic your site will receive.</p>
<h2>Why Should Businesses Use Link Building?</h2>
<p>Links are important for search engines to determine a website’s credibility and determine its ranking. The more high quality links direct toward your website, the higher it will rank in search engine results.</p>
<p>Here are the top three benefits of link building for businesses.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h3>Building Relationships</h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Building links require you to interact with top ranking blogs and websites within your industry. When you reach out to such websites to promote your content, you get a chance to build meaningful relationships with influencers who are important in your industry. Promotions from such individuals or platforms lend your business an air of credibility and trust.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h3>Referral Traffic</h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Simply put, links increase referral traffic. If your link is featured on a high-ranking website that attracts a lot of readers then relevant traffic will be directed to your site which may increase sales in the long-run.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<h3>Brand Building</h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p>When link building is done right, it can result in your company becoming an authority in your industry which establishes your brand identity. Content creation, as part of the link building strategy, is a great way to convey your company’s expertise and services to a local audience.</p>
<p>For example, when a website publishes a well-research content piece based on industry data, you have an opportunity to make a name for yourself in your niche. While reaching out to industry giants to get links, you are actively promoting your content and establishing yourself as a business to be reckoned with.</p>
<p>For affordable <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service.html">link building services</a>, contact Search Berg. Our SEO experts offer effective link building strategies that drive traffic, increase search engine rankings and boost online revenue. <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/contact-us.html">Contact us</a> today to find out how we can help your business scale new heights.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-link-building-and-why-does-my-business-need-it/">What Is Link Building And Why Does My Business Need It?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-link-building-and-why-does-my-business-need-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Art of Linkbuilding by “Earning” Links Through Content in 2018 and Beyond</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-art-of-linkbuilding-by-earning-links-through-content-in-2018-and-beyond/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-art-of-linkbuilding-by-earning-links-through-content-in-2018-and-beyond/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 13:52:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Link Building]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=976</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Google has undeniable dominance in the world of search engines. It’s unparalleled. It’s undisputed and its unmatched because no other search engine even comes close to offering the level of information and accuracy that Google does. But what makes Google so powerful, so accurate and so reliable? Its user-focused algorithms! Google algorithms simply leave no [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-art-of-linkbuilding-by-earning-links-through-content-in-2018-and-beyond/">The Art of Linkbuilding by “Earning” Links Through Content in 2018 and Beyond</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Google has undeniable dominance in the world of search engines. It’s unparalleled. It’s undisputed and its unmatched because no other search engine even comes close to offering the level of information and accuracy that Google does.</p>
<p>But what makes Google so powerful, so accurate and so reliable?</p>
<p>Its <em>user-focused</em> algorithms!</p>
<p>Google algorithms simply leave no page unturned (*pun intended*) when it comes to providing internet users (like us) with a matchless search experience. If a page is ranked high on Google, it’s because the algorithms have found it authoritative, important, reliable and most importantly, relevant to the user’s search query and most likely to lead to a positive search experience.</p>
<p>To gauge websites across all these parameters, Google assess them on multiple ranking factors. One such ranking factor is links or the number of “backlinks” indexed to the page to be more specific.</p>
<p>Think of backlinks as references in the offline world.</p>
<p>In the offline world, companies and individuals endorse and promote various products and services. The more different types and number of recommendations, the more popular that brand becomes.</p>
<p>Same is the case here.</p>
<p>Backlinks are a recommendations or citation for a webpage. The websites and social media profiles backlinking to the webpage are the media, companies and the people.</p>
<p>When a webpage has more backlinks coming from quality sources, Google considers that page of high value. Consequently, Google ranks that page higher in the SERPs.</p>
<p>The process of acquiring backlinks for a webpage is known as <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service.html">link building</a>; a very popular and in-demand digital marketing service today.</p>
<p>Some common ways to build backlinks to a webpage (or website) include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Link requests</strong>, where the website administrator simply asks other admins of other websites to link back to their webpage. They may agree as is, or they may ask for a reciprocating backlink in favor.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraging online directories</strong>, where web admins create free listings and build backlinks to their webpages. It’s similar to link buying, but it’s not considered a “bad link buying” practice as per Google’s guidelines.</li>
<li><strong>Guest blogging</strong>, where you submit a blog or article to another website and create backlinks via the submitted content piece.</li>
<li><strong>Creating high-value content</strong>, where you create content that is truly unique, acting as an authority (and reference-worthy) content piece on the subject of discussion.</li>
</ul>
<p>Through link building, SEO expect generate web traffic, brand awareness, search engine rankings and higher web page visibility and higher domain or page authority.</p>
<p>However not all links are created equal and over the years, focus has shifted from building links to earning links. SEO’s today have a much better understanding of how search engines work and what entails a good link building process.</p>
<p>As a result, web admins and SEO experts have started focusing more on <em>earning</em> backlinks than <em>building</em> them.</p>
<p>Anna Crowe <a href="https://www.searchenginejournal.com/link-building-guide/guide-link-building-link-earning/">writes</a> for Search Engine Journal:</p>
<p>To build a high-quality, credible backlink profile, you need to stop working on building links and start working on earning links.</p>
<h2><strong>What’s the difference between Link Building and Link Earning</strong></h2>
<p>The concept is same, to get more backlinks to your website or webpage. However, link earning specifically focuses on establishing generic associations as opposed to establishing reciprocated or paid associations.</p>
<p>Link earning is like a subset of link building.</p>
<p>Since you’re seeking generic associations in link earning, the only link building technique which then remains relevant in the context is creating high value content. If you create high value, authority content, website administrators are likely to cite your content on their webpage or website. This way you get to generically generate backlinks for your webpage. Readers who end up on your page also acknowledge the content as worthy of earning backlinks, and it enables them to see it through their skepticism and appreciate the information.</p>
<h2><strong>Creating High Value Linkable Content </strong></h2>
<p>So how to create high value linkable content?</p>
<p>It all starts with a strategy.</p>
<p>Ask yourself: What theme would you like to have for your content? Does the theme align with your business goals? Is the theme relevant to your target audience? How strongly it resonates with their problems?</p>
<p>These questions will help you create a strategy for your content.</p>
<p>Once you have a strategy in place, the next step is to research the facts and information. Study everything there is to be studied about the topic.</p>
<p>Using the gathered information from your research, create a compelling content for your audience. Use visuals where possible. Bake in the resources. Maintain clarity. Discuss your point comprehensively. Spoon feed them. One thing to note is that quality viral content doesn’t have to come in the shape of a blog. There are many avenues you can pursue. Make a short video about a product you are selling. Create a visually stunning infographic on the benefits of a particular service that your business is offering. Make your content standout. It doesn’t have to be a blog post</p>
<p>In addition, you can promote your content through influencers and industry leaders. Of course, they won’t just facilitate your request (as they’ve a reputation to maintain), so you’ll have to work towards building a partnership with them first. You’ll have to earn their trust to convince them to promote your content. This will further help you generate more backlinks to your web page.</p>
<h2><strong>Hire Search Berg for Link Building Services</strong></h2>
<p>In this age of content skeptics and critics, link building is all about link earning links through quality content!</p>
<p>Do you run a business that needs <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/small-business-seo.html">online presence</a>?</p>
<p>Looking to monetize your site through quality link building and link earning techniques?</p>
<p>Do you want your product or service pages to rank on the first in Google?</p>
<p>Search Berg is at your service!</p>
<p>We’re one of the leading digital marketing service providers in the United States. We are an award winning agency. In 2017 we won the <strong>Site Jabber Customer Choice </strong>award. In mid-2018, we were ranked in the top <strong>10 web agencies in New York</strong>. We completed our 15,000<sup>th</sup> SEO project and cemented our place as a leading SEO services provider in the US. Employing an experienced and knowledgeable SEO team that is always up to date with industry developments and standards, we can transform your website, making it more effective at helping you achieve your business goals.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/contact-us.html">Get in touch</a> with us today to discuss your link building project.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-art-of-linkbuilding-by-earning-links-through-content-in-2018-and-beyond/">The Art of Linkbuilding by “Earning” Links Through Content in 2018 and Beyond</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-art-of-linkbuilding-by-earning-links-through-content-in-2018-and-beyond/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of Link Building and Why It Continues to Dominate SEO In 2018 After Panda and Penguin Updates</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-importance-of-link-building-in-seo/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-importance-of-link-building-in-seo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 07:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Link Building]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=873</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Is link building still important? Short answer, Yes. Content, for good reason will always remain king but the importance of backlinks in SEO and that of link building in general cannot be denied or ignored. In fact content and links go hand in hand. Any content that gets published essentially comes a URL to which [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-importance-of-link-building-in-seo/">The Importance of Link Building and Why It Continues to Dominate SEO In 2018 After Panda and Penguin Updates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is link building still important? Short answer, Yes. Content, for good reason will always remain king but the importance of backlinks in SEO and that of link building in general cannot be denied or ignored. In fact content and links go hand in hand. Any content that gets published essentially comes a URL to which a link could point to.</p>
<p>The SEO landscape has evolved dramatically over the past two decades. From using optimized keywords to mobile-friendly websites, marketers rely on different techniques to improve search engine rankings of businesses. Another crucial ranking factor is backlinks.</p>
<p>‘Link building’ is a term often thrown around by SEO experts. Incorporating links to web content is an effective way to get traffic to your website traffic and increase the likelihood of conversion.</p>
<h2>Link Building 101</h2>
<p>Link building simply means to link other websites to your website. In other words, you add a hyperlink from another website to your own.</p>
<p>Link building is a crucial part of search engine optimization. If done right, it can increase your website’s visibility in search results.</p>
<h2>Importance Of Link Building</h2>
<p>A successful link building strategy can work well for any business. Here is why link building should be part of your SEO campaign:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Improves Google ranking</strong>: Although the battle to the top of the search ranking table is based on many <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/googles-most-important-ranking-factors-according-to-seo-industry-practices/">factors</a> such as using quality content, meta description and more, links affect how <a href="https://searchengineland.com/new-google-link-study-shows-links-important-ever-ranking-well-search-282488">Google ranks web pages</a>. To put it simply, if you want your website to earn meaningful, organic ranking in search engine, you need quality. Once people start clicking the links, your web traffic will increase.</li>
<li><strong>Boosts brand awareness</strong>:For new or small businesses striving to spread the word about their products and services, link building can help them achieve this goal. Incorporating links from established brands adds values to your website, thereby improving its visibility in the search engines.</li>
</ul>
<p>Increased visibility results in greater business recognition in the long term. If properly planned and executed, a link building campaign can take your web traffic and returns to the next level.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Builds brand trust and authority</strong>: In addition to enhancing brand visibility, high quality links help establish a brand’s credibility and authority.</li>
</ul>
<p>When people see links from credible, popular resources (relevant to your business) on your website, they are likely to take your brand more seriously. As more and more online users become interested in your website, you will see a massive improvement in your web traffic and conversion rates.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Keep an eye on competition</strong>: As links are available online, you can check out what links your competitors are using on their websites. You can even target the same links. Effective link building can put you ahead of your competitors.</li>
<li><strong>Lasts forever</strong>: Links are a worthwhile investment because they last forever. As long as a link is active, customers can access it. Unlike ads with limited or temporary visibility, links offer a permanent solution for improving your website’s visibility, traffic and your conversion rates.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Link Building: The Beginner’s Guide to Getting Started</h2>
<p>If you’re adding links to your website, it’s important to separate the good from the bad. Google may penalize you for low quality links. What makes a good quality backlink?</p>
<p>Generally speaking, a quality link comes from a source that is:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Trustworthy</strong>: Has the website been penalized? Is it a reliable source? A penalized site can adversely affect your SEO. Perform an audit of the website before using it for link building.</li>
<li><strong>Prominent</strong>: Do people use the site a lot? It is a household name in your industry? Does the website cite its sources? The more respected your source website is, the better. Check out the website traffic to assess its authority.</li>
<li><strong>Relevant</strong>: Is the website content relevant to your business and industry? If it’s not, to your industry or your target audience, Google could penalize your site.</li>
<li><strong>Content Quality</strong>: Does the website offer fresh, original, insightful, engaging, thorough, well-researched and visually appealing content? The <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jaysondemers/2014/08/25/the-12-essential-elements-of-high-quality-content/#5518bebf533c">basic rules of content</a> apply to backlinks. After all, links should add value to your website.</li>
<li><strong>Diversified Sources</strong>: Instead of acquiring links from just one website, it’s better to use various links from a variety of domains to increase your rankings.</li>
</ul>
<p>Apart from the strategies mentioned above, combining internal links and external links can help you achieve amazing search results. If you would like to know more about this, get in touch with us.</p>
<p>At <a href="http://searchberg.com">Search Berg</a>, you can count on our link building solutions to achieve optimal results! Our <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service.html">customized link building</a> and SEO solutions are developed to meet your website needs and improve its search ranking. Above all, our SEO solutions come with a <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/money-back-guarantee.html">100% money-back guarantee</a> and require no contractual obligations whatsoever.</p>
<p>We offer comprehensive <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service.html">link building services</a> to clients from diverse industries, such as education, health, real estate, finance, technology, travel and more. Last year, we completed our <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/searchberg-completes-10000-projects/">10,000th SEO project</a>, making us as one of the most dependable SEO companies in the country.</p>
<p>Call now at 855-444-4777 to learn more about our services.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-importance-of-link-building-in-seo/">The Importance of Link Building and Why It Continues to Dominate SEO In 2018 After Panda and Penguin Updates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-importance-of-link-building-in-seo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
