<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Social Media Management &#8211; Search Berg</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/category/social-media-management/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 06:33:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to Get More Followers on LinkedIn</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-followers-on-linkedin/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-followers-on-linkedin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 06:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2439</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>With an astounding 675 million monthly users, LinkedIn is a gold mine for businesses in 2021. The mega networking platform isn’t just your regular go-to for employment purposes; it’s also a game-changing marketing tool. If you’ve already dipped your toes in the LinkedIn marketing water, you’re on the right track. But simply creating a business [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-followers-on-linkedin/">How to Get More Followers on LinkedIn</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With an astounding <strong><u>675 million monthly users</u></strong>, LinkedIn is a gold mine for businesses in 2021. The mega networking platform isn’t just your regular go-to for employment purposes; it’s also a <em>game-changing</em> marketing tool.</p>
<p>If you’ve already dipped your toes in the LinkedIn marketing water, you’re on the right track. But simply creating a business profile isn’t enough. You <em>have</em> to go the extra mile and leverage LinkedIn marketing tips to grow your <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/setup/new/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">company page</a>.</p>
<p>In this blog, we want to walk you through top-tier strategies to get more followers on LinkedIn. We’ll cover the basics, dive into the deep end, and get into the nitty-gritty.</p>
<p>By the end of this blog, you’ll have a firm grasp on how to engage followers on LinkedIn like a seasoned pro. Let’s jump right into it!</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Struggling to revive your LinkedIn follower count? We’ve been in the game long enough to know what works and what doesn’t. Fill out the form to get great results!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2>Contents</h2>
<ul class="toc_list">
<li><a href="#_Toc61021480">Ways to Get More Followers on LinkedIn</a>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021481"> Create a Winning Company Page from the Get-Go</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021482"> Use the <em>Right</em> Hashtags the <em>Right</em> Way!</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021483"> Include High-Quality Images in Your Posts</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021484"> Don’t Sideline the Importance of Engaging Videos</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021485"> Share Value-Added, Insightful, and Compelling Content</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021486"> Make the Most of Polls</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021487"> Highlight Your Company’s Accomplishments</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021488"> Create Special Posts for Major Events, Holidays, and Trends</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021489"> Encourage Your Employees to Join the Action</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021490"> Actively Participate in LinkedIn Groups</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021491"> Use LinkedIn Sponsored Ads</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021492"> Promote Your LinkedIn Page on Social Media and Your Website</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><a href="#_Toc61021493">Wrapping Up! </a></li>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc61021480"></a>Ways to Get More Followers on LinkedIn</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021481"></a>1. Create a Winning Company Page from the Get-Go</h3>
<p>When getting started with LinkedIn marketing, many companies have a razor-sharp focus on optimization. As they should!</p>
<p>However, jumping straight into optimization without taking care of the basics is <em><u>not</u></em> the right way to go. If your company page isn’t up-to-date, optimization simply won’t do the trick.</p>
<p>Start by creating a strong foundation and working your way upwards. Let’s take a quick look at how you can do that with an example.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2441" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-1.png" alt="DELL’s LinkedIn Page as example of a Winning Company Page " width="1119" height="367" /></a></p>
<p>Dell’s LinkedIn company page checks off all the fundamental boxes.</p>
<p>High-quality profile picture and cover image? Check.</p>
<p>Accurate industry and location? Check.</p>
<p>Concise and catchy subheading? Check.</p>
<p>Once you take a closer look, you begin to realize that <em>they haven’t stopped there</em>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-2.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2442" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-2.png" alt="DELL’s LinkedIn Page as example of a Winning Company Page " width="542" height="527" /></a></p>
<p>The “overview” section is replete with to-the-point information.</p>
<p><em>“What does this have to do with getting more followers?”</em> you may ask.</p>
<p>As a professional platform, LinkedIn has set a high standard for its users. They don’t expect subpar, incomplete nuggets of information. Instead, they’re looking to <em>connect</em> with companies that are <strong><u>on top of their game</u></strong>.</p>
<p>If your company page is incomplete, your lack of interest in comprehensiveness will reflect poorly on your business as a whole. Ultimately, it may cost you your follower count. As a rule of thumb, make sure your company page is updated with <strong><u>accurate information</u></strong>. Avoid going overboard; the descriptions should be concise and the images professional. Anything too flashy or verbose will do more harm than good.</p>
<p>We also recommend adding the <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/1593/affiliated-linkedin-pages?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">“affiliated pages” section</a> to your profile.</p>
<p>Here’s how this section appears on Dell’s company page:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-3.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2443" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-3.png" alt="DELL’s LinkedIn Page as example of a Winning Company Page " width="299" height="444" /></a></p>
<p>As a parent page, you can link child pages, i.e., companies that are closely associated with your business and owned by you. If you’re a small business or a startup, you can choose to forgo this option.</p>
<p>Ultimately, covering <em><u>as many bases as possible</u></em> will help you make a great first impression on professionals who are looking to interact with your brand. A professional, clean, and comprehensive company page will go a long way in adding a touch of legitimacy to your business.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021482"></a>2. Use the <em>Right</em> Hashtags the <em>Right</em> Way!</h3>
<p>Is your company page up and running? Great.</p>
<p>It’s time to turn your attention to <strong><u>optimization</u></strong>. Optimization is your golden ticket to engaging a wide audience on LinkedIn. And while there are many ways to optimize your profile (we’ll cover all of them shortly), using hashtags is still one of the most effective strategies in 2021.</p>
<p>If you’ve been navigating the digital marketing industry for a while now, you’re probably familiar with the importance of using the right keywords in your content.</p>
<p>Hashtags are like <em>keywords</em> for your LinkedIn company page. Yes, this means you should have a stellar “hashtag research” (akin to “keyword research”) strategy in place.</p>
<p>If you’re new to LinkedIn, you can use the platform’s in-built hashtag recommendations.</p>
<p>Let’s say you’re sharing an engaging article that covers the benefits of link building.</p>
<p>Once you start typing a relevant hashtag, you’ll get recommendations accordingly.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-4.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2444" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-4.png" alt="how to use hashtags on LinkedIn posts " width="525" height="372" /></a></p>
<p>If you’re completely unsure of which hashtags to use, LinkedIn will do the job for you. The platform will pick up on keywords used in the post, and display a set of relevant hashtags accordingly.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-6.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2446" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-6.png" alt="how to use hashtags on LinkedIn posts " width="522" height="365" /></a></p>
<p>If you’re just starting off, you can rely on LinkedIn’s impressive hashtag prowess. However, for more advanced hashtag research, we recommend consulting LinkedIn marketing pros. They’ll create a customized hashtag strategy for each post, resulting in optimal reach.</p>
<p>Go for <strong><u>3–5 hashtags</u></strong> in each post. Too little and you won’t reach your target audience; too much and the LinkedIn algorithm will work to your detriment.</p>
<p>Now, when it comes to standing out from the massive competition on LinkedIn, you <em><u>need</u></em> to think outside the box. In addition to having a strong hashtag strategy in place, we also suggest letting your creative juices flow.</p>
<p>Sounds vague?</p>
<p>Here’s what we’re talking about. Head over to Puma’s LinkedIn company page and you’ll notice that they’ve sprinkled a specific hashtag across every other post: #PumaFam.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-7.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2447" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-7.png" alt="how to customize hashtags on LinkedIn posts " width="541" height="442" /></a></p>
<p>Here’s another glimpse of the catchy hashtag in action:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-8.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2448" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-8.png" alt="how to customize hashtags on LinkedIn posts " width="540" height="462" /></a></p>
<p>Creating a whip-smart, memorable, and standout hashtag for your company is a great way to set yourself apart from the hundreds of companies in your industry and city/state.</p>
<p>Whether you create a hashtag for your audience, your products/services, or your brand, you’ll manage to get an edge in your competitive industry.</p>
<p>Over time, <strong><u>the hashtag will catch on</u></strong>.</p>
<p>As your followers use it, it’ll build momentum and <a href="https://medium.com/@steve_fabrik/forget-boring-branding-the-elements-of-brand-recall-strategy-e08c2105269b" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">increase brand recall</a>.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Want to grow your LinkedIn business page and get more followers? Let’s make it happen.</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021483"></a>3. Include High-Quality Images in Your Posts</h3>
<p>A whopping <strong><u>87.5% of marketers</u></strong> state that they use visual elements in online content.</p>
<p>Over the years, the human attention span has dropped to a measly <em><a href="https://time.com/3858309/attention-spans-goldfish/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">eight seconds</a></em>. In comparison, a goldfish has an attention span of <em>nine seconds</em>—one second more than ours!</p>
<p>Here’s where we’re going with this: we don’t like paying attention to things that don’t excite us.</p>
<p>Five pages of continuous text? Boring.</p>
<p>A dull concept illustration? Next.</p>
<p>A set of statistics with no visual elements? Pass.</p>
<p>What <em>does</em> excite us, however, is <strong><a href="https://neilpatel.com/blog/visual-content-you-need-to-use-in-your-marketing-campaign/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">engaging visual content</a></strong>.</p>
<p>Content with high-quality images and videos does much better than content that entirely lacks visual elements. In essence, if your LinkedIn posts feature chunky bites of text without images or videos, you can wave your followers goodbye.</p>
<p>How can you undo the damage? Befriend gripping visuals and don’t let that friendship turn sour.</p>
<p>Let’s take a quick look at brands who walk the visual talk on LinkedIn.</p>
<p>iRobot’s LinkedIn posts feature stunning images that not only instantly catch your eye, but also compel you to engage with the content. The content itself features the perfect mix of high-quality images—enough to make you want to stay put till the very end.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-9.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2449" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-9.png" alt="LinkedIn posts with stunning images" width="541" height="516" /></a></p>
<p>A closer look and you’ll notice that they’ve also used a hashtag that fits perfectly. While we have to deduct a few points for the low hashtag usage (remember: use 3–5 as a general rule of thumb), the engaging image <em>more than makes up for it</em>.</p>
<p>While using the right images in each post is important, we also recommend ensuring that your company page is replete with pictures that pack a powerful punch.</p>
<p>Here’s what we mean by this. Each company page features a section entitled “company photos.” Some businesses make the mistake of uploading little to no images in this section. So when a LinkedIn user clicks on your profile and browses through the “company information” section, all they’ll see is a bunch of text. If there are no visual elements supplementing the text, you can imagine what’ll happen next: the user will “bounce”.</p>
<p><strong><u>What do you do to set things right? </u></strong></p>
<p>Here’s what McDonalds did:<a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-10.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2450 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-10.png" alt="LinkedIn posts with stunning images" width="540" height="249" /></a></p>
<p>And Apple:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-11.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2451" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-11.png" alt="LinkedIn posts with stunning images" width="542" height="249" /></a></p>
<p>And Dell:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-12.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2452" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-12.png" alt="LinkedIn posts with stunning images" width="540" height="249" /></a></p>
<p>Just to reiterate, make sure you upload a set of relevant, engaging, and high-quality images that satiate your audience’s visual thirst.</p>
<p>This is a great way to increase engagement on your LinkedIn company page and, of course, get more followers.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021484"></a>4. Don’t Sideline the Importance of Engaging Videos</h3>
<p>As another form of visual content, <strong><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2020/06/01/three-reasons-video-marketing-is-important-on-social-media-in-2020/?sh=58a80a456e55" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">videos are imperative</a></strong>. Maybe more so than images since they stimulate an additional sense: hearing. LinkedIn pages that feature high-quality videos do much better than pages that don’t. But this is where things get a little tricky—especially for startups and small businesses that don’t have a lot of (<em>or any</em>) video content ready to go.</p>
<p>If you’re unprepared, consider getting help from a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/video-design-services/">professional video design team</a>.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4Fk48tDAVCQ" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Once you’re equipped with a set of high-quality videos, start featuring them on your LinkedIn company page. Each profile incudes a “recently posted videos” section that shows up right after the “about” section.</p>
<p>Here’s a glimpse:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-13.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2453" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-13.png" alt="LinkedIn posts with engaging videos" width="541" height="233" /></a></p>
<p>By default, this section displays the most recently posted video, and features a “+ more videos” tab for LinkedIn users who wish to engage with additional video content.</p>
<p>Once you click on this tab, the rest of the videos uploaded on your page show up.</p>
<p>This is what Walmart’s video panel looks like:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-14.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2454" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-14.png" alt="LinkedIn posts with engaging videos" width="877" height="533" /></a></p>
<p>Quite a visual treat, right?</p>
<p>If you take a closer look, you’ll notice that the engagement on each video is <em>pretty impressive</em>. Lots of views, and a plethora of “like,” “celebrate,” “love,” and “support” reactions.</p>
<p><strong><u>That’s the power of video content, in a nutshell</u></strong>.</p>
<p>A power-packed mix of explainer videos, testimonial videos, company culture videos, product demonstration videos, and behind-the-scenes videos will breathe life into your LinkedIn profile. The outcome? A steady increase in LinkedIn company page followers.</p>
<p>Over time, this LinkedIn marketing tip will help you grow your company page and actively engage your target audience.</p>
<p>If you’ve already uploaded high-quality videos on YouTube (or any other video sharing platform), and engaged an impressive audience there, you don’t have to re-upload them on LinkedIn. Simply embed the video so you can steadily increase views, likes, and comments on YouTube. This is a great way to grow your YouTube page and increase ad revenue via AdSense.</p>
<p>Here’s an example from LARQ’s LinkedIn company page:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-15.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2455" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-15.png" alt="LinkedIn posts with engaging videos" width="541" height="533" /></a></p>
<p>As stated earlier, make sure you use 2–5 hashtags in <em>every</em> post, whether it links to a blog, video, or infographic. We’re continually doubling down on this because it’s absolutely imperative. Hashtags are just as important on LinkedIn as they are on Twitter, so take special care to incorporate them into every post.</p>
<p>By combining the power of strong visuals (images and videos) and the right hashtags, you’ll manage to reach, engage, and convert a wide audience.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021485"></a>5. Share Value-Added, Insightful, and Compelling Content</h3>
<p>Content has always been at the forefront of any social media or networking platform. If you want your company page to strike a chord with your audience, you <em>have</em> to share <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-the-ultimate-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2020/">engaging content</a> that achieves its purpose.</p>
<p>Remember, people won’t hit the “follow” button if your posts doesn’t resonate with them. Your page should <strong><u>inform, inspire, and excite your audience</u></strong>.</p>
<p>Start by creating a customized content marketing plan for your LinkedIn page. Incorporate different types of content into the mix—blogs, articles, guest posts, press releases, infographics, and instructographics.</p>
<p>Once you have a set of value-added and optimized content ready to go, write an equally compelling LinkedIn post to supplement your content.</p>
<p>Patricia Hartmann, a writer in Ojai, California, creates the perfect segue into one of her blogs:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-16.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2456" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-16.png" alt="Sharing Value-Added, Insightful, Compelling Content on LinkedIn to gain followers" width="545" height="578" /></a></p>
<p>Keeping the current context in mind, she focuses on inspiring her audience by helping them break away from the ongoing uncertainty, chaos, and stress triggered by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>
<p><strong>Recommended Read: </strong><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/8-ways-to-adjust-your-seo-strategy-amid-the-ongoing-covid-19-pandemic/">8 Ways to Adjust Your SEO Strategy Amid the Ongoing COVID-19 Pandemic</a></p>
<p>Starbucks used a similar approach on New Year’s Eve:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-17.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2457" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-17.png" alt="Sharing Value-Added, Insightful, Compelling Content on LinkedIn to gain followers" width="541" height="497" /></a></p>
<p>Ultimately, your content should <em><u>make an impact</u></em>. Avoid cookie-cutter content strategy. The more creative you can get, the better. And, of course, keep optimization in mind at all times.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021486"></a>6. Make the Most of Polls</h3>
<p>Over the past few years, polls have taken LinkedIn by storm, and it’s easy to see why. They’re quick. They’re engaging. They’re exciting. The best part? You can leverage polls for <em><u>a wide range of purposes</u></em>.</p>
<p>Whether you’re trying to get feedback on a newly-launched product or curious about where your audience stands with respect to something like remote working, creating a quick poll is a great way to double down on engagement.</p>
<p>Netflix’s smart poll earned a whopping 13,633 votes because of the compelling question and equally impressive options.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-18.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2458" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-18.png" alt="Using polls to increase followers on LinkedIn" width="541" height="399" /></a></p>
<p>Let’s be real; if we could, we’d immediately hit one of those four options depending on our Netflix viewing history.</p>
<p>There’s something about polls that <em>compels people to participate</em>, which is exactly why they’re so popular on LinkedIn.</p>
<p>We strongly recommend posting <strong><u>1–2 polls every other week</u></strong>.</p>
<p>However, make sure you’re not posting polls <em>just for the sake of it</em>. If you don’t have a great idea in mind, it’s better to skip your weekly poll than to post one that’s too dull to engage people.</p>
<p>Here’s another great example to help you get inspired:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-19.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2459" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-19.png" alt="Using polls to increase followers on LinkedIn" width="537" height="444" /></a></p>
<p>What makes this specific poll even better is the unique way it brilliantly prompts further engagement in the comments. This is how you check off <em><u>all the boxes</u></em>! Not only did this post receive a plethora of votes, but it also earned a decent amount of comments.</p>
<p>Follow suit and you’ll be taken aback by how rapidly you manage to increase your LinkedIn followers.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021487"></a>7. Highlight Your Company’s Accomplishments</h3>
<p>Whether you run a small business or recently launched a startup, we’re sure you’ve accomplished certain milestones along the way—both big and small. Many businesses manage to check off 1–2 accomplishments within the first few month of inception!</p>
<p>If you have something to show off, <em><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2020/06/02/14-tips-for-showing-off-awards-and-accolades-without-bragging/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">show it off</a></em>.</p>
<p>Be proud of your company’s performance and growth, and don’t shy away from announcing it on LinkedIn. You’ll manage to present your business in a flattering light, and engage more people.</p>
<p>Tesla frequently posts its accomplishments, and this strategy always works in their favor.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-20.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2460" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-20.png" alt="tesla" width="541" height="291" /></a></p>
<p>18,385 reactions and 402 comments. Now, <em>that’s</em> engagement. Showcase your company’s achievements accordingly and you’ll manage to climb the rungs of LinkedIn. You don’t have to highlight awards. You can also announce the number of projects you closed, especially if your company exceeded its goals. If a certain product did exceptionally well, highlight that. If you earned a noteworthy mention by an industry giant, highlight that. If your customer satisfaction (CSAT) score improved by leaps and bounds, highlight that.</p>
<p>In essence, drawing attention to your company’s successes will help you build a great reputation and get more followers on LinkedIn.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021488"></a>8. Create Special Posts for Major Events, Holidays, and Trends</h3>
<p>Struggling to increase engagement on your LinkedIn company page? Take a quick look at your recent posts. Did you create a custom post for New Year’s? Christmas? Black Friday? Cyber Monday? If you didn’t, make sure you double down on major events, holidays, and trends in 2021. Covering important occasions will help you connect with your audience and watch your follower count go up.</p>
<p>Here are some <em><u>great</u></em> examples to help you get inspired:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-21.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2461" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-21.png" alt="1" width="546" height="533" /></a> <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog3.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2462" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog3.png" alt="2" width="541" height="593" /></a></p>
<p>Plan ahead to ensure you don’t miss out on an important event or holiday. Since you can’t plan trends in advance, make sure you have a team ready to create content for trends that develop within a matter of hours. This will help you stay on top of things!</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021489"></a>9. Encourage Your Employees to Join the Action</h3>
<p>When it comes to growing your business via LinkedIn, your company page isn’t the only page that should be spruced up and optimized at all times.</p>
<p>We touched upon Puma’s custom hashtag (#PUMAFam) earlier. If you browse through the hashtag on LinkedIn, you’ll come across <em>a plethora of posts</em>, and not all of them come from their company page!</p>
<p>In fact, their managers and employees have also joined the action to keep the momentum going.</p>
<p>Here’s a glimpse:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-22.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2463" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-22.png" alt="puma" width="539" height="853" /></a></p>
<p><em><u>This</u></em> is team effort at a glance. And when it comes to succeeding on LinkedIn, you can’t run a tight ship on your own. You <em><u>have</u></em> to recruit the rest of your team to help grow your company page and crystallize your online presence on the mega platform.</p>
<p>Encourage your team to share frequent posts that reflect your company in a positive light. They can share behind-the-scenes images, repost your company’s posts, and help custom hashtags do even better. You can also request them to engage with your posts to improve their reach. Collectively, these strategies will go a long way in helping your company page grow.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021490"></a>10. Actively Participate in LinkedIn Groups</h3>
<p>Looking to connect with likeminded individuals in your industry? And we don’t mean your competitors, we mean thought leaders and industry insiders who are passionate about the same products/services/ideas/strategies. If you’re nodding your head in the affirmative, make sure you join relevant LinkedIn groups.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-23.png"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2464" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-23.png" alt="groups" width="771" height="485" /></a></p>
<p>As you engage in niche-specific conversations, you’ll manage to reflect your company’s expertise and <a href="https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/310427" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">create awareness for your brand</a>.</p>
<p>You can also start your own group and share your content (blogs, articles, etc.). It’s a little more work, but <em><u>it’s worth it</u></em>. As the group gains momentum, you’ll marvel at how much traffic it generates for your company page.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021491"></a>11. Use LinkedIn Sponsored Ads</h3>
<p>If you’re still frowning upon your LinkedIn follower count, it’s time to let the professionals take care of things for you. Over the years, LinkedIn sponsored ads have become a go-to for thousands of companies across the platform. You can choose from a wide range of ads depending on the specific goal you want to reach. Whether you want to prompt more visits to your page, increase reach, or boost conversions, you can select the right ads accordingly.</p>
<p>Take your time to acclimatize to the purpose of each ad. Once you have a good grasp on the ins and outs of LinkedIn advertising, you’ll manage to make an informed decision that pays off in the long run!</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc61021492"></a>12. Promote Your LinkedIn Page on Social Media and Your Website</h3>
<p>While you can take several measures to promote your LinkedIn profile on the platform itself, you also need to branch out into other platforms.</p>
<p>Sharing your LinkedIn profile on social media is a great way to target a different audience that wouldn’t normally discover your company page on LinkedIn. In addition, we recommend linking your LinkedIn page on the “home” and “contact” pages of your website.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc61021493"></a>Wrapping Up!</h2>
<p>In this blog, we delved deep into the top LinkedIn marketing tips that can help you increase followers in 2021. Some are straightforward, some require a little assistance, and some can only be implemented by professionals (e.g., LinkedIn advertising).</p>
<p>Depending on where you stand, get a good grasp on your requirements and head in the right direction accordingly.</p>
<p>When it comes to LinkedIn marketing, <strong><u>consistency is the name of the game</u></strong>. Post high-quality, engaging, and optimized content <em>on a regular basis</em> and you’ll manage to steadily increase your LinkedIn followers.</p>
<p>If you’re ready to get started, we can help. Give us a call at <a href="tel:8554444777">855-444-4777</a> to kick-start your <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/linkedin-marketing/">LinkedIn marketing strategy</a>!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-followers-on-linkedin/">How to Get More Followers on LinkedIn</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-followers-on-linkedin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Social Media and SEO: How to Use Social Media to Improve SEO Rankings</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-and-seo-how-to-use-social-media-to-improve-seo-rankings/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-and-seo-how-to-use-social-media-to-improve-seo-rankings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Harper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 08:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contents How Does Social Media Affect SEO Rankings? 5 Tips To Use Social Media To Boost SEO Move Away From Creating and Sharing Mediocre Content Master the Art of Social Media Optimization Make Your Content Shareable Connect With Your Audience Leverage Social Media to Craft a Pristine Brand Identity What Are The Best Social Media [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-and-seo-how-to-use-social-media-to-improve-seo-rankings/">Social Media and SEO: How to Use Social Media to Improve SEO Rankings</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Contents</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203060">How Does Social Media Affect SEO Rankings?</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203061">5 Tips To Use Social Media To Boost SEO</a>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203062"> Move Away From Creating and Sharing Mediocre Content</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203063"> Master the Art of Social Media Optimization</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203064"> Make Your Content Shareable</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203065"> <em>Connect</em> With Your Audience</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203066"> Leverage Social Media to Craft a Pristine Brand Identity</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203067">What Are The Best Social Media Sites For SEO?</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc57203068">Wrapping Up!</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Is on-page SEO the only way to boost Google rankings?</p>
<p>Is there a link between social media marketing and SEO?</p>
<p>In this blog, we want to talk about how social media optimization can help you become more visible on the web.</p>
<div class="blog-cta" style="padding: 0;background: none;height: auto;min-height: inherit;">
<div class="inner">
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/social-media-management/">View Our Social Media Management Services</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc57203060"></a>How Does Social Media Affect SEO Rankings?</h2>
<p>Over <strong><u>4.57 billion people</u></strong> use social media around the world.</p>
<p><strong>Now, let’s get to the question that’s on everyone’s mind: Is social media marketing one of Google’s ranking factors?</strong></p>
<p>So, for most of this blog, we’re going to talk about how you can leverage your presence on social sites to boost your online presence. But it’s important to note that social media marketing <em>isn’t a direct element of SEO; </em>in fact, it <em>supports</em> elements that impact SEO.</p>
<p>For example: sharing engaging posts on Facebook, Twitter, etc., can make your content shareable, which increases your content’s visibility, which <em>in turn boosts Google rankings.</em></p>
<p>So if a blog was shared over 10,000 times and generated over 1 million likes and 30,000 comments, it may bag the first spot on Google for several of its keywords.</p>
<p>There’s absolutely no denying that social media and SEO have a meaningful and powerful link. Now let’s jump right into how you can leverage that!</p>
<div class="blog-cta style2">
<div class="inner">
<h3>Consult Our Experts For A Social Media SEO Plan.</h3>
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/contact-us/">Get a Free Proposal!</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc57203061"></a>5 Tips To Use Social Media To Boost SEO</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc57203062"></a>1. Move Away From Creating and Sharing Mediocre Content</h3>
<p>Curious about how many U.S. businesses have a social media marketing strategy in place?</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/203513/usage-trands-of-social-media-platforms-in-marketing/#:~:text=In%202017%20it%20was%20calculated,to%2091%20percent%20in%202019.&amp;text=Everyone%20knows%20that%20social%20media,to%20a%20powerful%20marketing%20tool." target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">90%</a></strong><strong>.</strong> And it’s easy to see why.</p>
<p>While taking things into your own hands may sound compelling, it’s very likely that you’ll fall short of the high standard set by the leading brands today.</p>
<p>Most top-tier businesses have a winning social media SEO strategy that helps them speedily climb ranks.</p>
<p>Take a quick look at Longines’ simple yet unmistakably engaging Facebook post:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe loading="lazy" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FLongines%2Fposts%2F10158707841863399&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=773&amp;appId" width="552" height="773" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>From using their signature hashtag to reach the intended audience to painting a vivid picture of the client’s admiration for Longines watches, this post makes <u>a lasting impression</u> on the audience.</p>
<p>And the more it resonates with people, the greater the likes, shares, page views, and sales.</p>
<p>These factors collectively play a fundamental role in increasing your search visibility and improving your rankings.</p>
<p>Nordstrom’s social media posts expertly follow the same recipe of creativity, uniqueness, and storytelling at its best:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe loading="lazy" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FNordstrom%2Fposts%2F10159194091224837&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=754&amp;appId" width="552" height="754" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>When it comes to using social media for SEO success, you have to stand out from the crowd by creating and sharing content that’s <em>a cut above the rest</em>.</p>
<p>An experienced social media marketing team will help you post gripping, moving, and impactful content that compels casual social media users to get immersed in your brand’s story and visit your website.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc57203063"></a>2. Master the Art of Social Media Optimization</h3>
<p>You’ve heard about content optimization.</p>
<p>You’re also familiar with webpage optimization.</p>
<p><em>But what on earth is social media optimization?</em></p>
<p>This is where social media and SEO cross paths. In essence, social media optimization is the process of “optimizing” your social media activity to build a wide audience and become more visible on SERPs.</p>
<p>How do you go about this?</p>
<p>Here’s a roundup of the top strategies:</p>
<ul>
<li>Use high-ranking hashtags for your industry and location</li>
<li>Set up your profile on the leading social media platforms (Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, YouTube, and Pinterest)</li>
<li>Integrate your social media links in your site architecture</li>
<li>Post high-quality content on a regular or semi-regular basis</li>
<li>Post media-rich content (e.g., blogs with engaging images or concept illustrations, infographics, videos, etc.)</li>
<li>Determine the optimal posting times for your business based on your demographic</li>
<li>Optimize your social media profile by posting a professional cover photo and profile photo, writing an engaging bio, and using an uncomplicated username</li>
<li>Monitor your campaign and make changes accordingly</li>
</ul>
<p>As you optimize your pages, you’ll engage more social media users and increase your chances of <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-marketers-guide-to-the-powerful-benefits-of-consistent-link-building/">establishing link building partners</a>.</p>
<p><u>This is one of the most impressive boons of social media optimization</u>!</p>
<p>As more non-competitor businesses come across your profile and engage with your content, they’ll become familiar with your presence in the industry.</p>
<p><em>The outcome?</em></p>
<p>Better chances of earning a lucrative backlink from high-DA businesses.</p>
<p>And it should come as no surprise that high-quality backlinks are <strong><u>power-packed juice shots</u></strong> for fatigued rankings! If you’re stuck at the back end of SERPs, you’ll manage to climb your way to the middle and eventually the top.</p>
<p>But leveraging social media sites for SEO isn’t enough. Make sure you turn to on-page SEO strategies as well.</p>
<p><strong>Recommended Read: </strong><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-likes-on-facebook-in-2020/">How to Get More Likes on Facebook in 2020</a></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc57203064"></a>3. Make Your Content Shareable</h3>
<p>Sure, you’ve created a winning social media campaign. You’ve also written the perfect social media post to get your content out in the open with a bang!</p>
<p>But did you make the post <em>shareable</em>?</p>
<p>While every social media post features a “share” button, it’s very likely that your audience won’t use it unless they’re prompted to. And losing potential shares will ultimately cause your SEO efforts to self-destruct.</p>
<p>Go for damage control ASAP.</p>
<p>Here’s an example:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">We now have plenty of Feather Edge Panel in stock for immediate collection or delivery!!!!</p>
<p>Call us now on 01553760000 or email us sales@timberservices.com</p>
<p>Please share!! <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/featheredgepanel?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">#featheredgepanel</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/kingslynn?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">#kingslynn</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/timber?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">#timber</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/instock?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">#instock</a> <a href="https://t.co/vvnjXUcfu2" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">pic.twitter.com/vvnjXUcfu2</a></p>
<p>— Timber Services Ltd (@ServicesTimber) <a href="https://twitter.com/ServicesTimber/status/1326128127349829635?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">November 10, 2020</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>Requesting your audience to “share” your posts is a great way to prompt action and <strong><u>get the most out of your social media content</u></strong>.</p>
<p>You can also experiment with different CTAs like “visit our website for more,” “feel free to give us a call,” “check out our services/products,” and “sign up for our newsletter,” among others.</p>
<p>Make sure you prioritize creativity; the more <u>unique</u> and <u>compelling</u> your posts, the better the outcome!</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc57203065"></a>4. <em>Connect</em> With Your Audience</h3>
<p>Social media isn’t a lecture hall; it’s a seminar room that involves active discussion.</p>
<p>If you plan on posting content and exiting until it’s time for a new post, you may want to rethink your strategy.</p>
<p>To improve your rankings and get people talking about your products/services, <strong><u>actively converse</u></strong> with your audience and initiate mini conversations between them.</p>
<p>Let’s take a look at how Starbucks puts this strategy into play:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><iframe loading="lazy" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FStarbucks%2Fposts%2F10158957429378057&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=609&amp;appId" width="552" height="609" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>If you scroll down, you’ll notice that they’ve engaged with the large majority of people who have left a comment. And the responses aren’t lackluster and generic; they’re <strong>witty, creative, and a breath of fresh air!</strong></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2346 aligncenter" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/blog2-13.png" alt="comments" width="463" height="201" /></p>
<p>And if you so much as enter “pumpkin cream” on Google, Starbucks shows up as the second most relevant search result.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2345 aligncenter" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/blog2-12.png" alt="how to use social media for SEO" width="713" height="364" /></p>
<p>This, in a nutshell, is a masterclass in how to use social media for SEO. It shows you how social signals help your SEO strategy succeed.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc57203066"></a>5. Leverage Social Media to Craft a Pristine Brand Identity</h3>
<p>Branding is at the core of successful SEO.</p>
<p>If your business has a weak brand identity, it’s very likely that your audience will gradually begin to lose interest and turn to your competitors.</p>
<p>Mediocre branding also reduces brand recall, resulting in dwindling audience engagement and retention.</p>
<p><em>So how do you turn things around?</em></p>
<p>You create an <strong><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/sarabliss/2019/02/13/how-to-build-a-brand-through-social-media/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">immaculate brand identity</a></strong> through social media.</p>
<p>Portray your business as an empathetic, attentive, and accommodating brand that actually cares about its audience.</p>
<p>Posting meaningful content, engaging with customers on a frequent basis, responding to queries with care and concern, and going the extra mile to ensure a seamless user experience are a few of the many ways to make a mark in your industry.</p>
<p>When executed with consistency and quality in mind, these strategies will help you become more visible on the web and <strong><u>rank your way to the top SERPs</u></strong>!</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc57203067"></a>What Are The Best Social Media Sites For SEO?</h2>
<p>Believe it or not, there are several dozen social sites you can choose from, but we want to focus on a few popular (read: powerful) ones in this blog:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="size-full wp-image-2344 aligncenter" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/blog2-11.png" alt="Social Media Sites For SEO" width="1079" height="1079" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Source</strong>: <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/272014/global-social-networks-ranked-by-number-of-users/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Statista</a></p>
<ol>
<li><strong><a href="https://twitter.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a></strong>: Most brands really overlook this powerhouse social media site. Twitter is huge. It has a great audience (over 330 million monthly active users) that you can tap into.</li>
<p></br></p>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">YouTube</a></strong><strong>: </strong>If video marketing isn’t part of your SEO strategy, it’s time to rethink that plan. 22% of the social media traffic in the U.S. is on this platform.</li>
<p></br></p>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a></strong>: Definitely the most popular, Facebook allows you to direct your advertising to your target audience and attract major traffic straight to your website. In addition to attracting traffic organically, there are paid options like Facebook sponsored content.</li>
<p></br></p>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Instagram</a></strong>: Over a billion people use Instagram on a monthly basis; it’s more than just posting images; think stories, video sharing, etc.</li>
<p></br></p>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a></strong><strong>: </strong>If you’re operating under the B2B model, you need to be on this professional platform. This is where you connect with potential clients, engage with existing customers, and build your brand. 53% of B2B companies that look up clients here have 50% chances of making a purchase from them.</li>
<p></br></p>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.pinterest.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Pinterest</a></strong>: The future is imagery. There are over 50 billion pins on the site, with over 175 million users.</li>
<p></br>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc57203068"></a>Wrapping Up!</h2>
<p>And so, with that, you’ve understood more or less about SEO and its relationship with social media. But there’s so much more to it! And we’d love to talk to you about it!</p>
<p>If you want to get your business’s social media marketing off the ground, let’s talk! Call <strong><a href="tel:855-444-4777">855-444-4777</a></strong> now to speak with a strategist or fill out the form below!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-and-seo-how-to-use-social-media-to-improve-seo-rankings/">Social Media and SEO: How to Use Social Media to Improve SEO Rankings</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-and-seo-how-to-use-social-media-to-improve-seo-rankings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Get More Likes on Facebook in 2020</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-likes-on-facebook-in-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-likes-on-facebook-in-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 09:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Facebook Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contents Why Do Facebook Likes Matter? 13 Ways to Get More Facebook Likes Make Your Facebook Page Super Easy to Find! Share Engaging, Data-Driven Content Make Sure Your Facebook Profile Stands Out Shift Your Focus to Shareability Get to Know the Best Posting Times Leverage the 80/20 Rule Get Creative With Your Calls-to-Action (CTAs) Giveaways [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-likes-on-facebook-in-2020/">How to Get More Likes on Facebook in 2020</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Contents</h2>
<p><a href="#_Toc52223224">Why Do Facebook Likes Matter?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc52223225">13 Ways to Get More Facebook Likes</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223226"> Make Your Facebook Page Super Easy to Find!</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223227"> Share Engaging, Data-Driven Content</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223228"> Make Sure Your Facebook Profile Stands Out</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223229"> Shift Your Focus to Shareability</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223230"> Get to Know the Best Posting Times</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223231"> Leverage the 80/20 Rule</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223232"> Get Creative With Your Calls-to-Action (CTAs)</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223233"> Giveaways and Contests Are a Big Yes!</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223234"> Facebook Ads: Get 1000+ likes on Facebook</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223235"> Add Social Media Links to Your Website and Blog</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223236"> Engage, Engage, Engage!</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223237"> Create a Customer Lookalike Audience</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223238"> Create More Image and Video Content </a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc52223239">Final Thoughts on How to Get More Likes and Followers on Facebook Posts! </a></p>
<p>Want to increase likes on Facebook?</p>
<p>Since its inception in 2004, Facebook has continued to grow exponentially and dominate the digital marketing landscape. With <strong><u>over 2.7 billion monthly users</u></strong>, the powerful platform is the world’s third-most visited website.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/264810/number-of-monthly-active-facebook-users-worldwide/" rel="nofollow"><img class="aligncenter" style="width: 100%; height: auto !important; max-width: 1000px; -ms-interpolation-mode: bicubic;" src="https://www.statista.com/graphic/1/264810/number-of-monthly-active-facebook-users-worldwide.jpg" alt="Statistic: Number of monthly active Facebook users worldwide as of 2nd quarter 2020 (in millions) | Statista" /></a><br />
Find more statistics at <a href="https://www.statista.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Statista</a></p>
<p>In fact, a whopping <strong><u>74% of Americans</u></strong> use the social networking site regularly. And <strong><u>over 90 million small businesses</u></strong> use Facebook to increase their reach, get their phones ringing, and bag impressive sales.</p>
<p>While there’s a lot that goes into using Facebook to your advantage, there’s one key feature that stands out: Facebook likes.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc52223224"></a>Why Do Facebook Likes Matter?</h2>
<p>We won’t beat around the bush: Facebook’s organic reach has been on the decline for a few years now.</p>
<p>It’s a bitter pill to swallow. And while we’d love nothing more than to create a Facebook page and watch the dough roll in, that’s not quite how things work anymore. As the competition becomes more cut-throat, resting on your laurels isn’t an option.</p>
<p>If you’re looking to maximize reach and conversions, you need to set yourself apart from the crowd.</p>
<p>This is where Facebook steps in. As you get more likes on your Facebook page, posts, comments, and activity, you catch the eye of the sole entity that matters most here: <strong><u>the Facebook algorithm</u></strong>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2189 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog1-1.jpg" alt="Facebook Algorithmn" width="700" height="480" /></p>
<p>Since the popularity of your posts is a key <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-8-google-ranking-factors-for-2020/">ranking signal</a>, you’ll manage to break into your target audience’s feed and earn more conversions.</p>
<p>In short, as you get more likes on Facebook, your business will become more visible on the mega platform. The outcome? Impressive sales and sustained business growth in the long run.</p>
<p>In this post, we wanted to address top strategies and tips on how to increase likes on Facebook in 2020.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a name="_Toc52223225"></a>13 Ways to Get More Facebook Likes</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223226"></a>1. Make Your Facebook Page Super Easy to Find!</h3>
<p>We’re going to start off with the easy stuff: people cannot find you if you’re not easy to find! And we cannot emphasize this enough!</p>
<ul>
<li>Choose a simple Facebook page name. Don’t add unnecessary keywords.</li>
<li>How to get more likes on your page using your blog? Add Facebook follow and Like buttons to your website or blog. This can direct traffic to your Facebook page.</li>
<li>Embed a FB post on your website</li>
<li>Promote your page on other channels like LinkedIn, YouTube, Twitter, and vice-versa.</li>
<li>Create a promotional video promoting your Facebook page</li>
</ul>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223227"></a>2. Share Engaging, Data-Driven Content</h3>
<p>Take a quick guess at how many images are uploaded on Facebook every day.</p>
<p>100 million? Far off.</p>
<p>200 million? Nope.</p>
<p>300 million? You’re in the right ballpark.</p>
<p><strong><u>350 million</u></strong>, to be precise.</p>
<p>And this figure only covers image-based posts. You can only imagine how many text-based posts are shared on the mega platform each day!</p>
<p>In short, there is an abundance of content on Facebook. If your posts are unengaging and lack value, they’ll get a couple of likes at best.</p>
<p><em>“How do I get more likes on my Facebook posts?” Or “how to get more likes on my Facebook business page?”</em></p>
<p>You think outside the box. Sharing <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-the-ultimate-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2020/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">value-added, data-driven, and proven content</a> is a great way to compel your target audience to engage with your posts.</p>
<p>Instead of adopting a generic Facebook content marketing approach, <strong><u>pull out all the stops</u></strong>.</p>
<p>Actively share value-added blogs, engaging infographics, conversion-focused videos, and other types of high-quality content to prompt action. You don’t necessarily have to include media in your posts each time; you can also share text-based posts so long as they’re brimming with value.</p>
<p>Once you put your strategy to the test, keep a close eye on which posts are performing better than the others. This is a great way to replicate strategies that generate great results.</p>
<p>For instance, you’ll notice that Starbucks periodically shares inspiring stories from their customers.</p>
<p>Here’s a glimpse:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FStarbucks%2Fposts%2F10158353973898057&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=735&amp;appId" width="552" height="735" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FStarbucks%2Fposts%2F10158385056388057&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=716&amp;appId" width="552" height="716" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></p>
<p>If you take a closer look at post engagement, you’ll notice that each post has garnered 10K and 6.5K likes respectively. In fact, the posts have also earned a substantial number of comments and shares.</p>
<p>This is a masterclass in reusing the same strategy because of impressive results.</p>
<p>If certain posts outperform others, don’t consider it an accomplishment and call it a day. Instead, consider it an accomplishment and actively work towards incorporating similar themes into upcoming posts to maintain high levels of engagement.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223228"></a>3. Make Sure Your Facebook Profile Stands Out</h3>
<p>While your Facebook posts may be engaging, if you’ve let your Facebook page collect dust over the years, you may want to step back and re-strategize.</p>
<p>An off-putting or outdated Facebook page is a recipe for disaster. As potential customers visit your page to engage with more posts, they’re very likely to bounce if your cover photo doesn’t look the part or your profile photo is pixelated.</p>
<p>Over time, you may lose likes and notice a drop in conversions.</p>
<p>Here’s how you can revamp your Facebook page.</p>
<p>Start by focusing on the images. Engage customers by striking the perfect aesthetic balance between your profile photo and cover photo. We suggest keeping the profile photo simple, clean, and classic while leaving ample room for experimentation with your cover photo.</p>
<p>HP’s Facebook page is the embodiment of this delicate ratio:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2190 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog.png" alt="HP" width="931" height="479" /></p>
<p>If you keep up with their page, you’ll notice that they periodically change their cover photo to ensure relevance. This is a great way to add a unique touch of novelty to your page to prompt more likes.</p>
<p>Use high-quality, creative, and aesthetically pleasing images to do the trick.</p>
<p>Once you’ve taken care of the images, shift your focus to the “About” section. Keep it concise and engaging. Moreover, fill out each section to ensure comprehensiveness.</p>
<p>Wayfair’s succinct and feel-good “About” section checks off all the boxes:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2191" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-1.png" alt="about" width="349" height="496" /></p>
<p>As you get more likes on your Facebook page, your posts will reach a wide demographic. Not only will you notice a boost in revenue, but your brand identity will also crystallize over time.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style1">
<div class="inner">
<h3>Is your Facebook page lacking the wow factor?<br />
Our Facebook marketing experts can help!</h3>
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/facebook-advertising/" rel="nofollow">Click here to revamp and optimize your page!</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223229"></a>4. Shift Your Focus to Shareability</h3>
<p><em>“How can I increase my Facebook likes automatically?”</em></p>
<p>If you’ve found yourself pondering this question, you’re one of the millions of business owners and marketers who are looking to get the ball rolling without going to great lengths.</p>
<p>Well, there <em>is</em> a way to go about this.</p>
<p>It’s called <strong>shareability</strong></p>
<div class="pro-tip">
<div class="left">
<h3>When it comes to maximizing Facebook likes,</h3>
<p>creating shareable content is your best bet. If your post resonates with your followers, they’re more likely to share it on their timeline or send it to their friends/family.</p>
</div>
<div class="right"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2217" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/cta-icon1.png" alt="" width="143" height="137" /></div>
</div>
<p>This is equivalent to winning the lottery in the world of digital marketing. In short, your post has a fair shot at going viral.</p>
<p><a href="https://buzzsumo.com/blog/facebook-engagement-guide/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">According to Buzzsumo</a>, the most viral Facebook posts of 2017 were:</p>
<ul>
<li>Practical tips and hacks</li>
<li>Inspiring content</li>
<li>Food and recipes posts</li>
<li>Cute animals</li>
<li>Music videos</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As the shares and likes continue to snowball, your follower count and sales will go up.</p>
<p>Let’s get back to the crux of the argument: <em>how do you create shareable content</em>?</p>
<p>It’s simple. <strong><u>You focus on trends</u></strong>.</p>
<p>One of the most common themes among all viral Facebook posts is relevance. They’re carefully formulated with the ongoing landscape in mind.</p>
<p>From using the right pop culture references to incorporating trending holidays, viral posts rely on relevance to prompt clicks and shares.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Ftarget%2Fposts%2F10158914913043120&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=590&amp;appId" width="552" height="590" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" align="center"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></p>
<p>Target’s recent Fall-friendly Facebook posts pack the power of relevance in abundance: they’re creative, unique, and a visual treat.</p>
<p>If you take a quick look at the comments, you’ll notice that people have actively interacted with the post and shared their own variations of fall-friendly décor.</p>
<p>With over 15K likes and 4.6K shares, the post checks off all the boxes of high-quality, shareable, and out-of-the-box content.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223230"></a>5. Get to Know the Best Posting Times</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2194 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog1-2.jpg" alt="The best time to post on Facebook" width="701" height="451" /></p>
<p>You’ve probably heard about the importance of posting at the right time numerous times.</p>
<p>You’ve <em>also</em> probably rolled your eyes and never given it another thought because of how preposterous it sounds.</p>
<p>We’ll be the first ones to admit that it doesn’t sound like something that can substantially impact the number of Facebook likes your posts get. However, once you scratch the surface, you quickly realize that it’s a game changer. In fact, that would be an understatement.</p>
<p>Depending on your business, your target audience is most likely active on Facebook during certain hours of the day. Delve deep into your demographics to determine peak activity hours.</p>
<p>While optimal posting times largely vary, posting between <strong><u>12 to 3 pm on weekdays</u></strong> and <strong><u>12 to 1 pm on weekends</u></strong> will yield great results if you’re new to this.</p>
<p>Of course, calibrate and recalibrate posting times until you find the perfect mix that yields optimal likes.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223231"></a>6. Leverage the 80/20 Rule</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2195 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-4.png" alt="The type of content to post on Facebook" width="700" height="480" /></p>
<p>Sure, posting content that largely revolves around your brand may sound tempting. In fact, it may also sound like the only option you have.</p>
<p>However, excessive branding doesn’t go down too well with most audiences.</p>
<p>If your posts are solely centered on your products/services, sales, special offers, and the like, your customers may get bored. Instead, use the 80/20 rule to maintain a balance and prompt more likes.</p>
<p>80% of your posts should comprise brand-related content whereas the remaining 20% should feature your customers, relevant industry updates, etc.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223232"></a>7. Get Creative With Your Calls-to-Action (CTAs)</h3>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fwatch%2F%3Fv%3D552249608923213&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=734&amp;height=502&amp;appId" width="734" height="502" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></p>
<p>Using the same ol’ CTAs is a surefire way to watch your Facebook likes take a dip. Not only will they fail to prompt action, but the lack of creativity will also keep you from maximizing audience engagement.</p>
<p>Master the art of creating <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbescoachescouncil/2018/12/26/why-your-call-to-action-needs-to-be-clear-and-compelling/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">compelling, action-oriented, and concise CTAs</a> that carry a hint of urgency.</p>
<p>Instead of opting for a generic “Call us for more info,” think outside the box.</p>
<p>“Ready to get piping hot pizza delivered to your home? Our speedy delivery services are a call away!” is <em>twice</em> as engaging and actionable.</p>
<p>Let your creative juices run wild!</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223233"></a>8. Giveaways and Contests Are a Big Yes!</h3>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FHelloFreshus%2Fphotos%2Fa.499635223397667%2F2361316220562882%2F&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=659&amp;appId" width="552" height="659" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>Who doesn’t love a good giveaway/contest? While there may be a couple naysayers, surprises are <em>a big hit</em> on Facebook.</p>
<p>Engage and convert your audience by posting exciting giveaways and contests.</p>
<p>You can offer your products/services, special discounts, or customized packages.</p>
<div class="pro-tip">
<div class="left">
<h3>As part of the rules,</h3>
<p>ask your audience to follow your page, like that particular post, like the last five posts on your page, and tag 3–5 friends.</p>
</div>
<div class="right"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2218" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/cta-icon2.png" alt="" width="168" height="113" /></div>
</div>
<p>Of course, you can get creative with the rules and add/remove as you’d like. However, don’t sideline the importance of requesting likes.</p>
<p>We also suggest getting creative with the countless features on Facebook. From posting polls to engaging your audience with Facebook Live, experiment with different elements to drive more likes and get your page seen by more people.</p>
<p>If you’re willing to go the extra mile, share links to scheduled Facebook Live sessions or exclusive Facebook giveaways on other social media pages, including Twitter, Instagram, Pinterest, Snapchat, etc. This is a great way to generate more buzz around your products/services, major brand events, or anything else that you’d like to showcase!</p>
<p>Ultimately, these strategies will help you get more likes on your Facebook page and increase followers.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223234"></a>9. Facebook Ads: Get 1000+ likes on Facebook</h3>
<p>An average Facebook user clicks on an astounding <strong><u>11 ads per month</u></strong>. When it comes to maximizing Facebook likes, leveraging Facebook ads is your best bet.</p>
<p>As Facebook ads continue to grow in popularity, more brands are jumping on the bandwagon to maximize reach and engagement, get 1000+ likes on Facebook, and establish a winning brand identity.</p>
<p>Here’s how you can kick things off. Consult <strong><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/facebook-advertising/">Facebook marketing experts</a></strong> to determine the right ads for your business. Depending on your business model, demographic, and project scope, they’ll help you choose between video ads, photo ads, slideshow ads, canvas ads, carousel ads, and dynamic product/service ads.</p>
<p>They’ll also optimize your ad schedule and ad placement to ensure maximum engagement and yield impressive results.</p>
<p>Facebook marketing specialists are adept at A/B testing your ideas to determine what works best and maximize conversion. From monitoring and analyzing Facebook Insights to overseeing each aspect of your business page, they’ll make sure you get more likes on Facebook and consistently engage a wide audience.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style1">
<div class="inner">
<h3>Want more likes on your Facebook page and posts? We can make it happen!</h3>
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/facebook-advertising/">Click here to sign up</a></p>
<p>for our Facebook advertising services starting from $199!</p>
</div>
</div>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223235"></a>10. Add Social Media Links to Your Website and Blog</h3>
<p>Have a great website? Great! A Facebook page? Even better! But are you linking the two?</p>
<p>Most business owners forget to add their social media links on their website. These links could be in your header, footer or in the sidebar, depending on your website’s theme.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2198" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-7-1024x541.png" alt="Adding Social Media Links to Your Website" width="1024" height="541" /></p>
<p>Another great recommendation is to add your social sharing icons—like Facebook follow and Like buttons—on your blog posts. This increases the shareability of your content.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2199" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-8-1024x544.png" alt="Adding Social Media Links to Your Blog Posts" width="1024" height="544" /></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223236"></a>11. Engage, Engage, Engage!</h3>
<p>Some of the biggest brands on Facebook don’t engage with their followers. With thousands of tags, mentions, posts, it’s hard to keep up. However, smaller businesses can really engage with the community.</p>
<p>It’s not just about replying about delivery times and work hours; CONNECT! Build relationships. It humanizes your brand. It makes the interaction memorable. And it engages.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2200" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-9-1024x605.png" alt="Engaging with followers on Facebook" width="1024" height="605" /></p>
<p>Don’t stop here; invest in community participation by joining relevant Facebook groups and commenting on topics that are in line with your products and services or business values.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223237"></a>12. Create a Customer Lookalike Audience</h3>
<p>According to Facebook for Businesses,</p>
<p>A Lookalike Audience is a way to reach new people who are likely to be interested in your business because they&#8217;re similar to your best existing customers.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2201" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-10.png" alt="Create a Customer Lookalike Audience" width="778" height="344" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Source: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/learn/lessons/using-ads-manager-to-create-custom-lookalike-audiences?ref=ahc_lwe" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Facebook Business</a></strong></p>
<p>Using the list of people who already follow you, Facebook will analyze data and identify similarities in interests, demographics, etc., and then list an audience that shares these characteristics for targeted Facebook advertising.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223238"></a>13. Create More Image and Video Content</h3>
<p>One study found that images received <a href="http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/33800/Photos-on-Facebook-Generate-53-More-Likes-Than-the-Average-Post-NEW-DATA.aspx" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">far more engagement</a>—53% more Likes, 104% more comments, and 84% more click-throughs—than an average post.</p>
<p>But here’s something better: video posts receive <strong>135% better organic reach</strong> than image posts.</p>
<p>Mic drop.</p>
<p>So, how do you leverage this?</p>
<ul>
<li>Identify the kind of images and videos your target audience would engage with.</li>
<li>With your videos, make an impact in the first 5 seconds.</li>
<li>Create immersive stories</li>
<li>Don’t forget to include a call to action!</li>
</ul>
<p>One last thing: another research indicates that Facebook native videos perform up to 4 times better than other video formats.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc52223239"></a>Final Thoughts on How to Get More Likes and Followers on Facebook Posts</h2>
<p>Getting more likes, followers and shares on Facebook is proven to be a great way to get more traffic for your business, regardless of the industry you operate in.</p>
<p>We’ve highlighted 13 tactics on how to get Facebook likes, pretty much for free<em> and </em>FAST! Should you start with all these? Absolutely; if you can maintain that. If you can’t, that’s where we come in.</p>
<p>We help manage your Facebook page to get you more likes and followers! That includes creating a Facebook profile if you don’t already have one, scheduling posts, sharing content, analyzing metrics and engaging with your followers!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Call <a href="tel:855-444-4777">855-444-4777</a> now and fill out the form below and let’s get started on your <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/facebook-advertising/">Facebook marketing campaign</a>! </strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-likes-on-facebook-in-2020/">How to Get More Likes on Facebook in 2020</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-likes-on-facebook-in-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 10 Ways to Grow a Small Business Through Facebook</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-ways-to-grow-a-small-business-through-facebook/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-ways-to-grow-a-small-business-through-facebook/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jay Melendez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 13:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Facebook Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1482</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The ongoing COVID-19 pandemic has inevitably transformed how business is done across the globe. A recent Goldman Sachs report revealed that over 96% of small business owners reported being impacted by the crisis. In addition, over 51% admitted that they would be forced to close their business within 0–3 months. As the ongoing lockdown demands a shift toward digitalization, many [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-ways-to-grow-a-small-business-through-facebook/">Top 10 Ways to Grow a Small Business Through Facebook</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The ongoing COVID-19 pandemic has inevitably transformed how business is done <strong>across the globe</strong>.</p>
<p><span id="more-1482"></span></p>
<p>A recent Goldman Sachs report revealed that over <u><a href="https://www.goldmansachs.com/citizenship/10000-small-businesses/US/no-time-to-waste/index.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">96%</a></u> of small business owners reported being impacted by the crisis. In addition, over <u><a href="https://www.goldmansachs.com/citizenship/10000-small-businesses/US/no-time-to-waste/index.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">51%</a></u> admitted that they would be <strong>forced to close</strong> their business within <strong>0–3 months</strong>.</p>
<p>As the ongoing lockdown demands a <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/2020/03/20/why-companies-turn-to-digital-marketing-to-survive-covid-19/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">shift toward digitalization</a></u>, many local offline businesses are struggling to undertake this massive transformation. However, it may be their only way to maintain (and boost) metrics, audience engagement, and audience retention.</p>
<p>According to Forbes, the <strong>COVID-19 pandemic has increased internet use</strong> by <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/markbeech/2020/03/25/covid-19-pushes-up-internet-use-70-streaming-more-than-12-first-figures-reveal/#3cbc21903104" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">70%</a></u>.</p>
<p>Brands that have successfully leveraged the power of digital marketing have managed to keep their business afloat and increase revenue sales.</p>
<p>While digital marketing comprises an eclectic blend of <strong>PPC marketing, reputation management, web design</strong> and <strong>development</strong>, and <strong>content production</strong>, there’s one key player that stands out for its unparalleled performance.</p>
<p>Research indicates that coronavirus has pushed Facebook usage through the roof. People are spending <u><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21193094/facebook-coronavirus-covid-19-messaging-service-reliable-strain-outages" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">50%</a></u> more time on the popular social media application, thereby interacting with more digital marketing content and fueling conversion rates for online businesses.</p>
<p>A recent survey conducted in March revealed that over <u><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1106338/facebook-usage-increase-due-to-coronavirus-home-usa/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">63%</a></u> of Americans stated that they were <strong>expecting to use Facebook more during the pandemic</strong> to stay informed about recent developments. Not only has that estimate increased across the globe, but it has also helped a lot of small businesses gain greater visibility and boost their business.</p>
<p>If your business has been struggling to weather the COVID-19 storm, we’ve rounded up <strong><em><u>ten powerful ways to leverage Facebook</u> </em></strong>for greater audience reach, revenue sales, and brand identity during the ongoing crisis.</p>
<h2>1. Create a Separate Business Page</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1484" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/1-1.png" alt="" width="628" height="420" /></p>
<p>Facebook helps businesses grow.</p>
<p>Research indicates that there are currently <u><a href="https://expandedramblings.com/index.php/by-the-numbers-17-amazing-facebook-stats/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">over 65 million</a></u> active small business pages on Facebook. With the number expected to increase as the COVID-19 pandemic continues, <strong><u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/2010/08/17/internet-marketing-twitter-technology-facebook.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">creating a separate Facebook business page</a></u></strong> is a surefire way to <strong>boost audience engagement</strong> and <strong>retention</strong>.</p>
<p>The powerful tool helps small businesses centralize their audience, thereby strengthening brand identity and allowing you to reach a vast expanse of potential customers successfully. Instead of using conventional marketing strategies, marketing your target audience through a strong Facebook page will lower your marketing expenses. This is extremely beneficial for up-and-coming startups and small businesses that are actively on the lookout for cost-effective marketing strategies.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1488" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/5-1.png" alt="" width="629" height="471" /></p>
<p>Creating and running a <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/thesba/2014/05/05/5-content-tips-for-your-facebook-business-page/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Facebook business page</a></u> is free, so you don’t have to worry about investing in unpredictable marketing sources that may not deliver the expected results.</p>
<p>A Facebook business page is also extremely effective in <strong>boosting SEO</strong>, <strong>increasing website traffic</strong>, and <strong>increasing customer retention</strong>.</p>
<p>Target your <u>intended audience</u> based on <em>key demographics, interests</em>, and <em>location </em>to enhance localized engagement further.</p>
<p>These strategies will collectively help you establish a targeted social media presence and solid reputation.</p>
<p>As you continue to use the platform, you’ll also establish a strong sense of <strong>competitor strategies</strong>. As you analyze their <strong><u>performance, marketing tactics, content quality, and reputation management practices</u>,</strong> you’ll be able to <strong><u>tweak and polish your branding strategy accordingly.</u></strong></p>
<p>We recommend examining the <strong>Facebook business presence </strong>of small businesses and established corporations that fall within the same industry.</p>
<p>This will help you incorporate a unique and effective mesh of “glocal” (global and local) strategies that resonate with the intended audience.</p>
<h2>2. Post Empathetic and Crisis-Friendly Content That Resonates With Your Audience</h2>
<p>While the ongoing lockdown has necessitated the creation of a strong Facebook business page, many small businesses are struggling to use the platform in an <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/tracybrower/2020/03/16/the-coronavirus-makes-communication-more-important-than-ever-9-tips-for-communication-that-reassures-and-reengages-people/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">empathetic and crisis-friendly manner</a></u>.</p>
<p>While you may feel compelled to leverage the application by solely marketing your products/services, you may want to reevaluate your strategy.</p>
<p>The sensitive crisis demands a gradual departure from unadulterated branding. Instead, <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jefffromm/2020/03/20/usefulness--speed-with-a-heavy-dose-of-empathy-will-build-brand-preference-during-covid-19/#f0199fd7831d" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">prioritize support and care</a></u> to make your audience feel comforted during a time of chaos and uncertainty.</p>
<p>Moving toward a humanized marketing approach—in contradistinction to an automatized marketing approach—will strengthen your brand identity.</p>
<p>Slack’s genuine, heartfelt, and altruistic check-ins are a great example of prioritizing audience health (physical, mental, and emotional) and wellness before promoting products/services:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1485" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/2-1.png" alt="" width="567" height="190" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1486" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/3-1.png" alt="" width="595" height="198" /></p>
<p>We also love Foreo’s empathetic marketing approach that prioritizes care and follows it up with timely and appropriate product recommendations:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1487" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/4-1.png" alt="" width="499" height="554" /></p>
<p>Building an understanding and comforting Facebook presence will ultimately help you establish a strong brand identity and generate more sales.</p>
<p>We also recommend posting thoughtful and crisis-sensitive blogs, articles, press releases, guest posts, infographics, and videos to crystallize brand visibility and attract new audiences.</p>
<p>For more strategies on empathetic, crisis-friendly marketing practices, be sure to check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/6-digital-marketing-tips-for-small-businesses-struggling-to-navigate-covid-19/">8 Digital Marketing Tips For Small Businesses Struggling To Navigate COVID-19</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>3. Closely Monitor Insights to Improve Your Strategy Accordingly</h2>
<p>One of the most beneficial features of Facebook marketing is the ability it gives you to monitor insights closely.</p>
<p>As Facebook use continues to increase, small businesses are increasingly leveraging <u><a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/learn/facebook-audience-insights" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Audience Insights</a></u> to determine areas of improvement and connect with potential customers who may have been overlooked through conventional marketing strategies.</p>
<p>Access page summary data and scrutinize metrics to develop an understanding of what works and what doesn’t. As you browse through the posts with the highest organic reach and determine the most popular content style on your page, you’ll be able to realign your strategy without breaking a sweat successfully.</p>
<p>This tactic is essential for small business owners with a limited understanding of digital metrics and KPIs. The easy-to-use dashboard allows quick, accurate, and digestible statistics that’ll help you steer your business to success.</p>
<p>We also recommend benefiting from <strong><u><a href="https://developers.facebook.com/docs/analytics" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Facebook Analytics</a></u></strong><strong> </strong>to visualize and optimize the customer experience.</p>
<h2>4. Leverage Facebook Videos for Improved Audience Engagement and Retention</h2>
<p>While the lockdown has given people more free time than before, the average human attention span has remained constant. According to Time, humans have an average attention span of <u><a href="https://time.com/3858309/attention-spans-goldfish/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">8 seconds</a></u>—1 second less than that of a goldfish!</p>
<p>While image and text-based marketing content is effective, video content is <em>twice</em> as powerful. Research indicates that videos generate <u><a href="https://medium.com/@slicevideo/this-is-why-video-is-the-most-engaging-type-of-content-e5ca46d5cef1" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">1,200% more shares</a></u> than images and text combined. Moreover, Facebook videos enjoy <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/miketempleman/2017/09/06/17-stats-about-video-marketing/#17dcaa35567f" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">over 8 million</a></u> views per day!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1489" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/7-1.png" alt="" width="618" height="419" /></p>
<p>The way to use videos to engage an audience is by creating videos that:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Serve to inspire your viewers.</strong> This can be in the form of telling a story, sharing an inspirational quote related to your business and consumers. Having inspirational music in the background of such videos is a big plus because it helps audiences connect emotionally with your message.</li>
<li><strong>Educate them in some way. </strong>This can look like providing your audience with a hack that can help them do something better or teaching them something useful.</li>
<li><strong>Provide entertainment value.</strong> During the pandemic, stuck in their homes, the fact is that people are really, really bored.</li>
</ol>
<p>So <strong>free entertainment</strong> is a welcome and <strong>highly rewarded release</strong>.</p>
<p>This doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean you should whip out the <em>prank videos</em> and try to go viral just <em>for the sake of going viral. </em></p>
<p>Instead, you can create content with a <strong>business purpose</strong> in an entertaining way.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><strong>Are organized and systematic.</strong> You can do so by placing videos following a similar theme into a <strong>Facebook video playlist. </strong></li>
</ol>
<p>For example, say your company sells baking products, and you create videos like &#8220;Baking The Perfect Croissant&#8221;, and &#8220;Baking The Perfect Chocolate Cake&#8221;, you can combine these into a relevant playlist on Facebook entitled, let&#8217;s say, &#8220;Baking The Perfect Good.&#8221;</p>
<p>As the most viewed and shared form of content on Facebook, videos facilitate the buyer decision-making process by increasing reach, engagement, and retention.</p>
<p>Share effective, empathetic, and engaging <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-you-need-video-content-for-your-website-if-you-want-to-gain-new-customers-and-strengthen-your-brand-online/">video content</a></u> to promote your products/services.</p>
<h2>5. Don’t Abandon Your Facebook Page</h2>
<p>The initial boost in metrics and sales revenue can easily <em>induce complacency</em>, thereby preventing businesses from maintaining a <strong>consistent effort.</strong></p>
<p>While you may be tempted to relax after building some momentum and reduce Facebook interactivity to a lower frequency, it’s essential that you continue to post regularly. This will help you maintain the <strong>growth and visibility</strong> established for your business on the Facebook page in the initial months.</p>
<p>Instead, abandoning your page can wreak havoc on previous accomplishments and can gradually make your business disappear among the active competition.</p>
<p>Post <strong><u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2018/05/07/four-ways-to-engage-your-facebook-audience-in-2018/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">meaningful and compelling content</a></u></strong> that keeps audiences engaged. <strong>Celebrating powerful events</strong> is a great way to <strong>contribute to a good cause </strong>while concurrently <strong>maintaining your brand presence</strong>.</p>
<p>TOMS’ frequent posts commonly include heartfelt messages that commemorate annual days that carry <strong>social, economic, political</strong>, and <strong>cultural significance.</strong></p>
<p>For instance:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1490" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/8-1.png" alt="" width="495" height="475" /></p>
<p>Sharing <strong>strong messages</strong> on annual holidays and celebratory days will <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2018/04/03/want-to-keep-reaching-your-facebook-audience-11-tips-for-adjusting-your-strategy/#2693dca12845" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">help your brand stand out</a></u> while fighting the good fight. If you run out of ideas, share general posts with a slice of wit to keep engagement levels high!</p>
<p>Little Owl—an up-and-coming small eatery in New York—has established a strong reputation and presence owing to its frequent posts—many of which include re-shares when inspiration runs low!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1491" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/9-1.png" alt="" width="495" height="305" /></p>
<p>The <strong>consistency</strong> and <strong>continual empathy </strong>have helped them earn incredible ratings and attract cosmopolitan audiences across New York. Keeping yourself on the map by actively sharing and re-sharing content will also increase your brand’s overall SEO.</p>
<h2>6. Give Facebook Ads a Shot</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1492" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/10-1.png" alt="" width="628" height="420" /></p>
<p>As one of the most effective tools for small businesses, <strong><u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnhall/2018/07/29/3-strategies-that-will-make-your-facebook-ads-more-successful/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Facebook Ads</a></u></strong> are a powerful way to increase revenue and brand awareness. With Facebook use at an all-time high, small businesses can <u><a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/boost/grants" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">effectively market their products/services</a></u> without worrying about engagement.</p>
<p>As the fastest and most cost-effective advertising strategy, Facebook Ads increase website traffic and dramatically lower cost per acquisition. According to research, over <u><a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/news/3-million-advertisers" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">3 million</a></u> businesses actively advertise on Facebook!</p>
<p><strong>Facebook’s Ad Manager</strong> facilitates campaign management, thereby making the process easier than alternative advertising strategies. With a few clicks, you can successfully run your ads across multiple platforms and receive extensive and robust analytics.</p>
<p>Facebook’s <strong>excellent targeting capabilities</strong> are extremely effective in helping small businesses micro-target their audience.</p>
<p>They do so by allowing you to tag not only specific demographics of users but also their exact interests. For example, if someone has liked a page related to your niche, you can literally ride off the coattails of this page&#8217;s audience to target them for your business.</p>
<p>For a Facebook ad to be successful, it needs to have three key components:</p>
<ol>
<li>Specific and <strong>accurate targeting</strong>. Picture hitting a bull&#8217;s eye in a sea of people with varied interests.</li>
<li><strong>Compelling words</strong> or <strong>copy</strong>.</li>
<li>A <strong>solid image or video</strong> to make your point and reel the <strong>casual scroller into being a customer</strong>.</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Not only does this <u><a href="https://medium.com/marketing-and-entrepreneurship/these-are-9-reasons-why-you-should-use-facebook-ads-right-now-3fefbeef7ae5" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">increase conversions</a></u>, but it also reduces customer attrition (loss) as users that deviate from the target audience are gradually eliminated.</p>
<p>The platform’s rich payoff helps businesses <strong><u><a href="https://www.inc.com/larry-kim/9-important-reasons-you-need-to-use-facebook-ads-right-now-first-90-days.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">remarket to audiences</a></u></strong> and build a <strong><u>sustainable brand identity</u></strong>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>7. Collaborate With Similar Businesses to Increase Your Following</h2>
<p>Struggling to boost your following? Collaborating with businesses in the same industry is a great way to double or triple your following.</p>
<p>Ideal for small businesses, partnerships increase visibility within the same niche, thereby attracting potential customers with a strong intent to purchase.</p>
<p>For instance, if you own a small salon, we recommend partnering with local businesses that sell hair products or skin rejuvenation tools. Approach them with a cross-promotional offer to increase following and sales for your business. Similarly, they’ll also benefit from the collaboration, as your customers will visit their website and purchase their products/services.</p>
<p>While the clientele will be similar, the contrasting products/services will ensure that one business’s traffic isn’t transferred to the other. Instead, the mutual benefits will help each business enjoy greater audience reach and sales.</p>
<h2>8. Boost Post Views by Using Hashtags</h2>
<p>Using <strong>Facebook hashtags the right way</strong> is <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2018/12/26/how-to-optimize-hashtags-on-social-media/#47d556547a17" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">extremely effective</a></u> in organically boosting page views. A recent study revealed that Facebook posts with hashtags receive <u><a href="https://later.com/blog/ultimate-guide-to-using-instagram-hashtags/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">12.6%</a></u> more engagement than those without.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1493" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/11-1.png" alt="" width="626" height="132" /></p>
<p>Facebook brought in Hashtags <strong><u>to bring conversations regarding people, public events, and topics to the forefront. </u></strong>Meaning, the purpose of a hashtag is to get eyeballs on the conversation.</p>
<p>Each hashtag has its <strong>own unique URL</strong> and can be found using the Facebook search bar. You can research it by looking through the hashtag on Facebook. You can also click on a hashtag that is generated on another site such as LinkedIn or Instagram. Chances are, there will be a continuation of that hashtag on Facebook as well.</p>
<p>Once you find the trending topics in your niche/industry, <strong>participate</strong>!</p>
<p>Join the conversation, take a stance, and/or provide deeper insight/value into the topic.</p>
<p>This will help you stand out.</p>
<h2>9. Create a Private Group to Establish a Close Connection with Your Loyal Audience</h2>
<p>While this powerful strategy seems counterintuitive to many, it’s a great way to establish a strong connection with loyal customers. A private Facebook group increases personal engagement and helps frequent customers feel included in the brand’s decision-making process.</p>
<p>Whether you’re working on a new product or are considering releasing an in-demand service, a <strong>quick heads up to your customers</strong> can go a long way in increasing audience retention.</p>
<p>We recommend posting <strong>polls</strong>, <strong>updates</strong>, and <strong>behind-the-scenes images</strong> and <strong>videos</strong> to keep your audience engaged and entertained. In addition, ask for their <strong>feedback </strong>and announce <strong>special discounts</strong> to establish a connection that goes beyond a superficial buyer-seller relationship.</p>
<p>CJ’s Coffee Cafe’s lighthearted, fun, and rewarding poll is a great example of engaging with group members and incorporating a little giveaway at the end:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1494" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/12.png" alt="" width="495" height="437" /></p>
<p>Whether you follow a similar strategy or create a unique <strong>group atmosphere</strong> for your customers, <u>conscientiousness and dedication</u> will help create a <u>community</u>.</p>
<p>As the group members feel appreciated and involved, they’re also more likely to <strong>unknowingly market your products/services</strong> to friends and family, thereby boosting reach and engagement.</p>
<h2>10. Ask Professionals for Help!</h2>
<p>Now you know all the basics, you need to build a strong foundation to understand how to build your small business&#8217; Facebook page growth.</p>
<p>You understand the importance of creating a <strong>separate Facebook business page</strong>, having an <strong>empathetic</strong> and <strong>crisis-friendly</strong> tone in your <strong>brand messaging</strong>, <strong>monitoring insights</strong> to improve, using engaging <strong>Facebook videos</strong>, <strong>Facebook Ads</strong>, staying <strong>consistent</strong> in your <strong>content release frequency</strong>, <strong>Hashtags</strong>, <strong>collaborating</strong> with other small businesses, and the power of <strong>private groups/communities</strong>.</p>
<p>While this is critical information and certainly will put you on your path to success, it is by no means the end of your research phase entirely.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1495" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/13.png" alt="" width="628" height="134" /></p>
<p>You may come across many hiccups along the way that can easily be eliminated as a result of vast previous experience in this field of Digital Marketing.</p>
<p>As one of the leading digital marketing service providers in the U.S., we offer <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/social-media-management.html">expert Facebook management services</a></u> across the globe. Our experience has helped us complete <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-completes-20000-projects/">over 20,000 SEO projects</a></u> for a wide range of clients in varying industries.</p>
<p>We also offer award-winning <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/ppc-marketing.html">PPC marketing</a></u>, reputation management, <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/content-marketing.html">content marketing</a></u>, and web design and development services to help small businesses boost revenue and use Facebook to expand their business during the ongoing crisis. Our <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/money-back-guarantee.html">100% back money guarantee</a></u> ensures there are no contractual obligations that make small business owners feel hesitant.</p>
<p>Browse through our <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/how-it-works.html">3 phase SEO process</a></u> to get started!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-ways-to-grow-a-small-business-through-facebook/">Top 10 Ways to Grow a Small Business Through Facebook</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-ways-to-grow-a-small-business-through-facebook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bye-Bye Google Plus!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/bye-bye-google-plus/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/bye-bye-google-plus/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 07:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social Media Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=997</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While for some it came as a shock, others saw it coming and knew it was imminent—Google announced its plans to shut down the consumer version of its social network, Google+. According to Google’s VP of Engineering, Ben Smith, 90% of user sessions on Google+ lasted for less than two seconds. A big problem no [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/bye-bye-google-plus/">Bye-Bye Google Plus!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While for some it came as a shock, others saw it coming and knew it was imminent—<a href="https://www.blog.google/technology/safety-security/project-strobe/">Google announced its plans</a> to shut down the consumer version of its social network, Google+.</p>
<p><a href="http://digg.com/2018/google-plus-shutting-down">According to Google’s VP of Engineering, Ben Smith</a>, 90% of user sessions on Google+ lasted for less than two seconds. A big problem no doubt, but what ultimately led to the platform’s demise was a much bigger issue that recently surfaced.</p>
<p>An unexpected bug in the Google+ code lead to a private data breach of profiles of up to <a href="https://www.blog.google/technology/safety-security/project-strobe/">500,000</a> individuals. While there’s no evidence of the data being misused or the developers abusing the API, the platform will be shut down for consumers over the next 10 months.</p>
<h2>What Caused The Breach?</h2>
<p>In a detailed blog post published by Google, the reason behind this phenomenon was explained. A software bug in the Application Programming Interface (API) of Google+ gave third-party developers free reign over consumer data.</p>
<p>The breach was discovered back in March 2018 but since there was <strong>no evidence of misuse</strong>, it was exposed to the public only recently.</p>
<h2>The Devil’s In the Details</h2>
<p>Google+ users can choose who they allow access to their profiles. However, the bug granted unauthorized access to over 438 applications without the user’s knowledge and without these apps being marked as public.</p>
<p>The data that was breached includes names, age, gender, occupations, email addresses, and more. Note that no other data posted on or connected to Google+ was exposed. This includes Google account data, Google+ posts, G Suite content, phone numbers, messages etc.</p>
<p>Since the API log of Google+ was only kept for a couple of weeks, it cannot be confirmed who the victims of this breach were. Users were reassured that there was no deliberate misuse of the data.</p>
<p>Users can check their Google+ data by downloading it from Google’s Takeout. More information will be given on how to download and migrate existing Google+ data.</p>
<h2>We Lost Google Plus, But Was It A Loss?</h2>
<p>Although Google should be commended for launching an ambitious plan to introduce its own social network, the fact remains that the platform never really clicked with the target audience. This begs the question, ‘<em>How Impactful Was Google+ To ROI?’</em></p>
<p>Google’s blog post admitted an uncomfortable truth about Google+ and consumer engagement. The post highlighted the fact that nearly 90% of the user sessions on Google Plus ended in 5 seconds or less—<em>yikes</em>!</p>
<p>This meant that a major reason that users were accessing Google+ was likely…by mistake. Once there, they didn’t find many satisfactory reasons to stay.</p>
<p><strong>Not All Is Doom &amp; Gloom—Not for enterprise customers, that is.</strong></p>
<p>Enterprises found great value in using the network for their products. This was especially true in companies where co-workers engaged in internal discussions regarding a secure corporate social network.</p>
<p>From setting access rules to using central controls, there are many ways enterprise customers benefitted from using Google+. It seems like Google+ might have shut down for consumers but not for enterprise users.</p>
<h2>So, What Does This Mean?</h2>
<p>Created with the vision to eliminate the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiple_audience_dilemma">multiple audience dilemma</a>, Google+ was meant to be a ray of hope for anxious network members concerned that their content reached the wrong audience.</p>
<p>Some believe that these supposedly good intentions were to blame for the early demise of Google+. It’s not such a bad thing after all, to see a post on social media which wasn’t mean for a particular consumer.</p>
<p>There was a time when Google tried to push the adoption of Google+ as a means to personalize search results. All this to say that although, its departure likely won’t be sorely missed, it’s worth noting that Google+ will be shut down for good.</p>
<p>Let’s discuss the impact this will have on:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Digital Marketers</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>If there’s one thing digital marketers know, it’s to not keep all their eggs in one basket. The digital media space is incredibly dynamic. The latest data breach from a tech giant is a lesson for marketers that whether it’s Facebook, YouTube, or Instagram, when it comes to developing a marketing strategy, we can’t predict what the future holds.</p>
<p>Issues like these cause consumers to lose trust in tech companies which is why marketers should never rely solely on any one marketing platform. Marketers would do well to remember that a strong social media marketing campaigns consists of a healthy variety of social networks.</p>
<p>As more and more of such breach scandals come to the limelight, maintaining consumer trust will become that much harder.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Social Media and SEO</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>It’s no secret that social media and SEO go hand in hand.  Social media platforms proved to be useful ranking tools to boost SEO efforts. Google+ was used to combine both these features to help companies increase their conversion rates.</p>
<p>Google+ contributed to building a site’s online authority, despite not being an official ranking indicator. Even though it was Google’s own network, when the loss in audience engagement started, it didn’t significantly impact SEO.</p>
<p>Social media might not be the most crucial factor to constructing a solid SEO strategy. However, the position of your SERPs <em>can</em> be affected by YouTube and the popularity of your social media channels.</p>
<p>Still, the loss of Google+ might not be such a loss, after all.</p>
<h2>Get Social With Search Berg Social</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/">Search Berg</a> offers proactive lead generation on a number of popular social media platforms. Our comprehensive <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/social-media-marketing.html">social media marketing</a> packages start from $199 only. Our social media marketing strategies are designed to boost active client engagement, organic website traffic, and revenue.</p>
<p>We aim to help our clients establish their business in the social arena. We offer engaging, content-driven social media marketing services to create buzz about their brand and offerings. From daily progress reports to relevant community engagement services, our packages cover them all.</p>
<p>The ingredients in our expert social media optimization packages include identifying audience search, gauging customized social media presence, reporting in-depth analysis, and managing reputation building as well as community development.</p>
<p>Call us at 855-444-4777 to start building your social media presence!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/bye-bye-google-plus/">Bye-Bye Google Plus!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/bye-bye-google-plus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Use Instagram to Promote Your Brand and Drive Sales</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-unleash-the-power-of-instagram-to-promote-your-brand/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-unleash-the-power-of-instagram-to-promote-your-brand/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 07:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social Media Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=927</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contents Marketing Tips to Help Grow Your Brand on Instagram Prioritize Aesthetics Leverage the Digitization of Interactions Use Relevant Hashtags to Sell on Instagram Incorporate Photo Tags Conversations With Followers Matter Share Insightful Stories to Humanize Your Brand Final Thoughts If you’re new to Instagram or have been struggling to increase user engagement on your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-unleash-the-power-of-instagram-to-promote-your-brand/">How to Use Instagram to Promote Your Brand and Drive Sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Contents</h2>
<p><a href="#_Toc46483164">Marketing Tips to Help Grow Your Brand on Instagram</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc46483165">Prioritize Aesthetics</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc46483166">Leverage the Digitization of Interactions</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc46483167">Use Relevant Hashtags to Sell on Instagram</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc46483168">Incorporate Photo Tags</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc46483169">Conversations With Followers Matter</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc46483170">Share Insightful Stories to Humanize Your Brand</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc46483172">Final Thoughts</a></p>
<p>If you’re new to Instagram or have been struggling to increase user engagement on your IG account lately, you’re probably wondering how to turn things around. If you don’t have the right tools, insights, and resources, <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/instagram-marketing/">using Instagram for business</a> can seem like an uphill battle.</p>
<p><span id="more-927"></span></p>
<p>When it comes to Instagram marketing, joining the platform is a great step in itself. The social media site ranks 3<sup>rd</sup> on the most-used (per daily basis) social media platforms, according to the statistics reported in <a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2018/03/01/social-media-use-in-2018/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">Pew Research Center’s 2018 Social Media Use Survey</a>.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc46483164"></a>Marketing Tips to Help Grow Your Brand on Instagram</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc46483165"></a>Prioritize Aesthetics</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1827 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/blog-2.jpg" alt="engaging and attractive Instagram design templates" width="626" height="417" /></p>
<p>The people featured on Instagram accounts are attractive, the sceneries pretty, and the packaging pristine. Plus, there’s consistency; the pictures on many popular IG accounts follow a similar theme, so that when displayed in a grid format on the profile, the photos look cohesive.</p>
<p>Whether you’re a photographer or not, you will find yourself appreciating the nature of these pictures, their beautiful subjects, their use of focal points and negative space, and the inclusion of complementary, often pastel hues. Makeup brands are particularly competent in establishing a perfect flow of colors in pictures on IG.</p>
<p>So how do you do what they do? Yes, they have professional photographers and graphic designers, but you don’t need to master either to have an attractive Instagram profile.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1817" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/blog.jpg" alt="insta" width="1200" height="250" /></p>
<p>You’ll find a ton of photo editing tools and filters, perfect for non-designers who find working with light and colors challenging. In fact, nearly <strong>60% of top brands’ Instagram accounts</strong> use a consistent filter for all content.</p>
<p>Plus, as most beauty brands do, you can also reuse a picture in a different shade if you are selling one product in multiple colors. Recolor and repeat—it works well for those with scarce content.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc46483166"></a>Leverage the Digitization of Interactions</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1818 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/blog1.jpg" alt="phone screen displaying a user’s Instagram feed" width="755" height="500" /></p>
<p>To understand Instagram users, we need to understand human behavior today.</p>
<p>We’re social creatures and crave interaction; the growth of social media—with its many features for sharing information in a creative manner—allows humans to take their usual conversations online.</p>
<p>This includes asking for advice to finalize purchase decisions. So if a person loves a particular product and talks about it on IG, you can bet that their friends and family will be curious and develop interest in it.</p>
<p>In short, to sell in 2020, you need to implement a <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-social-media-strategies-can-boost-my-seo/">strong social media strategy</a>.</p>
<p>Instagram has witnessed substantial user growth in the past few years, from 28% of U.S. adults using IG in 2016 to <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/fact-sheet/social-media/" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">37% of U.S. adults</a> using Instagram today. The underlying contributor? Brands with visually engaging and informative Instagram pages.</p>
<p>To use IG the <em>right</em> way, follow their lead. Here are a few reasons why these brands’ IG accounts look amazing and receive a great response.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc46483167"></a>Use Relevant Hashtags to Sell on Instagram</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1819 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/blog2.jpg" alt="template of an Instagram post illustrating the importance of using hashtags to sell on Instagram" width="626" height="626" /></p>
<p>Beauty brands are not popular for their powerful aesthetic alone. They’re also popular for their words. In particular, their use of hashtags and phototags. IG is visual, so graphics are everything—if they reach the right people.</p>
<p>Like Twitter and Facebook hashtags, Instagram hashtags are an organic way of boosting content visibility. Instagram posts that include at least one hashtag receive <strong>over 12% more engagement</strong> than posts that exclude hashtags entirely.</p>
<p>And just like Twitter, the right hashtags matter on Instagram, which allows up to 30 hashtags per post. But this can look too spammy and overdone. However, if you’re using Instagram like a beauty brand does, you’ll use hashtags the way they do: separate from the main caption, with periods-for-line-breaks. You can also add your hashtags to the first comment, posted separately.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/heatherleighton/2019/08/31/where-instagram-hashtags-should-go-caption-first-comment/#6e88cacd384c" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">Hunting the right hashtags</a> requires thought and some additional help. You can use online analytics tools to find hashtags on IG. You can also search for hashtags directly on IG’s “Discover” section, where you can view the number of times a particular hashtag has been used.</p>
<p>Or you can hand over this task over to <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/social-media-marketing.html">social media marketing experts</a> who are adept at sifting through and finding the best keywords for your brand. Not only will they help make your content more visible, but they’ll also ensure you’re able to effectively sell on Instagram.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc46483168"></a>Incorporate Photo Tags</h3>
<p>Beauty brands make use of photo tagging on their posts. Photo tagging on IG is similar to tagging people in your photos on Facebook; only you can tag anyone outside your followers list (provided they allow tagging). Beauty brands tag celebrities—whose fans can then discover that post.</p>
<p>In addition to tagging other people, you can also tag your products (which you have been allowed to sell through IG) in your photos. Users can access the product pages directly though these. It’s that simple.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc46483169"></a>Conversations With Followers Matter</h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1820 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/blog1-1.jpg" alt="concept illustration of a brand representative and customer communicating via Instagram direct messages" width="626" height="626" /></p>
<p>Whether you’re a commercial contractor or a turnkey white label gaming software provider, you have much to gain from engaging and responding to customers on any social media account, including Instagram.</p>
<p>Here are some ways to enhance engagement:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ask followers questions about their favorite products, content preferences, and recommendations</li>
<li>Host product giveaways or offer free services provided that your followers tag their friends in the comments and request them to follow your account</li>
<li>Collaborate with an influencer to expand your audience (more on <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/influencer-marketing/">influencer marketing</a> here)</li>
<li>Answer queries in the comments and reply to any compliments/concerns</li>
</ul>
<h3><a name="_Toc46483170"></a>Share Insightful Stories to Humanize Your Brand</h3>
<p>Give your followers unique insight into the product creation/service delivery process with the <a href="https://help.instagram.com/1660923094227526" target="_blank" rel="noopener ”nofollow” noreferrer">Stories feature</a>. Make sure they’re engaging! However, don’t share important updates that should be announced through a regular post. Remember, Instagram stories only last for 24 hours. Use stories with polls to gather more insights from your followers.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1822 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/blog1-2.jpg" alt="pin certain stories" width="1200" height="250" /></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc46483172"></a>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>Test out every feature Instagram has to offer to increase account visibility and engage the community. At <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/">Search Berg</a>, we offer expert <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/social-media-management/">social media services</a> to help your business rank higher and dominate the online landscape!</p>
<p>If you’re still unsure about how social media marketing and management can benefit your company, we suggest referring to our earlier blog on <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-here-is-why-your-business-need-it/">the benefits of social media for businesses</a>.</p>
<p>Our social media marketing experts are dedicated to consistent research to apply the latest strategies to your social accounts. If you’ve been struggling to use Instagram to promote your brand and drive sales, we can help you kick things off.</p>
<p>Our <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/instagram-marketing/">Instagram marketing and management services</a> start at as little as $199 and focus on how to sell on Instagram.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-unleash-the-power-of-instagram-to-promote-your-brand/">How to Use Instagram to Promote Your Brand and Drive Sales</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-unleash-the-power-of-instagram-to-promote-your-brand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Social Media Strategies Can Boost my SEO?</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-social-media-strategies-can-boost-my-seo/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-social-media-strategies-can-boost-my-seo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 07:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social Media Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=698</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>For businesses to succeed in the digital world, they need a foolproof social media strategy, backed with a sure-fire SEO plan! The world we live in is not what our ancestors had predicted.Although we take it for granted, the technology around us has had a massive influence on how we live our lives. Today our [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-social-media-strategies-can-boost-my-seo/">What Social Media Strategies Can Boost my SEO?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For businesses to succeed in the digital world, they need a foolproof social media strategy, backed with a sure-fire SEO plan!</p>
<p>The world we live in is not what our ancestors had predicted.Although we take it for granted, the technology around us has had a massive influence on how we live our lives.</p>
<p>Today our life is a massive web of global inter connectedness.</p>
<p>One of the major breakthroughs of this era is the rise of social media websites. These platforms have become so powerful that a page on Facebook can bring about a revolution, changing the course of a <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/kathleenchaykowski/2017/09/27/zuckerberg-defends-facebooks-role-in-election-but-regrets-dismissing-impact-of-fake-news/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">country’s future in drastic ways</a>.</p>
<p>With the rapid integration of digital platforms and strategies, businesses are now constantly on the lookout for innovative marketing techniques. According to majority of marketers, modern marketing campaign are incomplete, and some even useless without an engaging online presence.</p>
<p>In 2017, social media users reached a whopping <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/278414/number-of-worldwide-social-network-users/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2.46 billion</a>. This number is expected to rise in the coming years. It’s as simple as this—as a business owner you cannot afford to ignore any of the relevant social media platforms.</p>
<h2>Social Media Management and Search Engine Optimization</h2>
<p>Social media management and search engine optimization are the two crucial pillars of any digital marketing campaign. For success, the two must work in conjunction with each other. Both are organic strategies that aim to bring visitors to your website.</p>
<h2>Incredible Social Media Practices to Enhance Your SEO</h2>
<p>As a business, you might be uncertain about how social media affects SEO. We at <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SearchBerg</a> have outlined some great social media practices to help you achieve success in the SEO landscape. Read on:</p>
<h2>Increase Your Number of Followers</h2>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jaysondemers/2015/01/27/6-social-media-practices-that-boost-seo/#334f02e83d17" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Forbes</a>, the number of followers on your social media page can impact SEO rankings. A company with just 100 Twitter followers will surely not be as impactful for Google as a company with a million followers. But the number of followers is not all that Google analyzes.</p>
<p>Google can detect the quality of these connections and followers. This means that it will penalize social media pages with fake likes or followers.</p>
<p>What’s more, social media marketing is a major purchasing factor. According to <a href="http://www.socialmediatoday.com/marketing/masroor/2015-05-28/social-media-biggest-influencer-buying-decisions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Social Media Today</a>, 4 in 10 social media users have bought a product after sharing it or marking it as favorite on platforms like Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest.</p>
<p>Growing your network of followers is a process and takes time. From creating unique blogs on aspects that people care about, to producing how-to videos, there are many ways to create value for your visitors and potential customers. Engaging with your customers is the only way to build followers.</p>
<h2>Encourage External Links</h2>
<p>In its early days, Google used to rate external links very highly (it still does so, though other factors have taken precedence).</p>
<p>Even though to a certain extent, Google still considers external links to identify that the website is worthy enough to be linked.</p>
<p>Social media is a platform that can help you garner these important external links from reliable sources. Again, for this, you will need to have high-quality and relevant content posted on your social media website.</p>
<p>Use hashtags to create relevance and visibility. Also, have your social media team put your content out there on platforms like online threads and discussion boards.This will help you portray yourself as a reliable expert in the field.</p>
<h2>Optimize Your Posts according to Google’s Preference</h2>
<p>When looking for websites around the web,Google uses relevant keywords to rank pages. You can take advantage of this by optimizing content accordingly.</p>
<p>For instance, if you have created a video, you can add a short, catchy description to go with it. This description will help Google better understand your shared content and rank it. You can also add seasonal keywords, such as ‘Christmas’, and guarantee your chances of showing up when users search with that particular keyword.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify; text-justify: inter-ideograph;">Encourage Social Sharing</h2>
<p>Social sharing can impact SEO rankings in the same way as external links. When your content is shared by a third-party, neutral source, Google gets its cue that your content must be valuable. The more people you get to share your content, the better it will be for your SEO results.</p>
<p>You can reward people for sharing your content. For instance, you could offer deals or discounts to people who re-tweet your videos. You can also carry out an interactive survey campaign. For example, you could take a (non-controversial) stance and ask your followers if they agree with it.</p>
<h2>Optimize Posts for Local Search</h2>
<p>With <a href="http://www.internetlivestats.com/google-search-statistics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">40,000 search queries every second</a>, Google is a busy platform. However, the search engine has devised algorithms to provide users with what they want <em>within milliseconds</em>. To get ahead in the search engine, you have to make it easy for it to recognize you in the vast world of web.</p>
<p>In recent times, Google has focused more on local. This is to ensure a good user-experience. For instance, it is very likely that a person typing the keyword ‘restaurants to eat’ is looking for restaurants in his/her area.</p>
<p>This is the reason your focus should be local. One way to do this would be to optimize your posts with location specific keywords (for example with the name of the city or town).</p>
<p>Another good approach would be to participate in local events, like festivals or trade shows. You could go live or post pictures of the event.</p>
<p>By stamping your local presence, you can make an impact on both social media platforms and search engines.</p>
<h2>Never Miss a Chance to Spread Your Brand’s Awareness</h2>
<p>For starters, why would you? You should aim towards creating an impeccable social media reputation that translates into highly effective brand visibility.</p>
<p>Any negative comments should be handled with care. You cannot afford to have people go against you in the online landscape where reviews spread like wildfire.</p>
<p>Whether it is through creating relevant infographics or a killer mobile app for users, you need to ensure that users have wonderful experience every time they interact with you.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: justify; text-justify: inter-ideograph;">Some Social Media Tools to Make SEO More Impactful</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-702" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/pexels-photo.jpg" alt="" width="1920" height="1280" /></p>
<p>With businesses going digital at a faster pace than ever before, we now have a variety of online tools and resources at our disposal. Using them intelligently can prove to be the difference between an ordinary digital marketing campaign and an extraordinary one.</p>
<p>Let us take a look at some effective social media tools to take your SEO campaigns to the next level:</p>
<h2>BuzzSumo</h2>
<p>BuzzSumo, with its incredible categorization features, helps you find the most popular and relevant content across the web regarding your industry. From interviews to guest posts, it allows you to share a diverse array of content.</p>
<p>Through BuzzSumo, you can also discover hot trends on social media platforms like Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn.</p>
<p>What’s more, you can track what type of content resonates with what audiences. This is a great way to figure out an approach that works.</p>
<h2>Oktopost</h2>
<p>This is a B2B tool that helps generate leads for businesses in the online landscape. Through this platform, you can easily schedule and share posts on your social media profiles. What’s more, you can detect which posts led to conversions and which posts did not. It has a comprehensive reporting tool that helps track progress.</p>
<h2>SE Rank</h2>
<p>SE Rank contains a variety of SEO tools combined in a single package. What makes it unique is its incredible social media management offering.</p>
<p>From scheduled publishing to ranking content, it can make your social media campaigns more targeted.</p>
<p>Finally, it helps you assess SEO metrics – that is, how exactly are your social media marketing efforts affecting your SEO. This, according to some, can be a digital marketer’s dream come true.</p>
<h2>Cyfe</h2>
<p>Having a 360-degree view of all your social marketing efforts can be the key to success in the digital media landscape. This is where Cyfe differentiates itself as a social media management tool.</p>
<p>With a comprehensive dashboard, it allows you to get all your analytics in one place. This can help you track per-post performance, which allows you to create better strategies for the long-run.</p>
<p>Finally, with its amazing pre-built widgets, you can keep track of what’s happening on all your digital advertising channels, such as websites, emails, digital displays, etc.</p>
<h2>Inkybee</h2>
<p>The goal of this social media platform is to help you share social content, monitor activities and build great relationships with your audience.</p>
<p>Employing this tool in the right manner can help you single out influencers. By entering the relevant keywords, you can get data insights, such as social media connections, number of times they post content and other SEO-related metrics.</p>
<p>We at SearchBerg are a reliable SEO company for small businesses. With years of experience in the field and a team of web SEO experts, we help businesses form the right digital marketing strategy. From <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/content-marketing.html">content marketing</a> to <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/social-media-management.html">reputation management</a>, we offer all the digital solutions you could ask for!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-social-media-strategies-can-boost-my-seo/">What Social Media Strategies Can Boost my SEO?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-social-media-strategies-can-boost-my-seo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Social Media, Here is Why your Business Need It!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-here-is-why-your-business-need-it/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-here-is-why-your-business-need-it/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 07:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social Media Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=704</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-here-is-why-your-business-need-it/">Social Media, Here is Why your Business Need It!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-500 size-full" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/social-media.png" alt="searchberg" width="1400" height="4450" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-here-is-why-your-business-need-it/">Social Media, Here is Why your Business Need It!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/social-media-here-is-why-your-business-need-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
