<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Video Content &#8211; Search Berg</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/category/video-content/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 17:00:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>What is Google My Business and How Does It Help Small Businesses?</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-google-my-business-and-how-does-it-help-small-businesses/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-google-my-business-and-how-does-it-help-small-businesses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 17:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Video Content]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=3187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There are currently over 400 million small businesses located across the globe. In fact, the accurate figure is expected to be much, much greater. With so many local businesses struggling to engage their target audience, it’s impossible to ignore the thick layer of competition they’re engulfed in. As a small business, you’re competing with thousands of local businesses [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-google-my-business-and-how-does-it-help-small-businesses/">What is Google My Business and How Does It Help Small Businesses?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="What is Google My Business and How Does It Help Small Businesses?" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w4LUqYzm9AI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe><br />
There are currently <strong><u>over 400 million</u></strong> small businesses located across the globe. In fact, the accurate figure is expected to be <em>much, much</em> greater.</p>
<p>With so many local businesses struggling to engage their target audience, it’s impossible to ignore the thick layer of <strong>competition</strong> they’re engulfed in.</p>
<p>As a small business, you’re competing with thousands of local businesses in your industry.</p>
<p>Sure, you’ve launched a website. And great, your marketing team is putting out word on social media.</p>
<p>But <em>that’s not enough</em>.</p>
<p>As the competition thickens every day, you have to stand out to your local audience. <strong>Google My Business helps you do just that</strong>.</p>
<p>What is Google My Business? It’s a versatile tool that enables small businesses to <u>engage and convert</u> their local target audience.</p>
<p>Let’s say a web user looks up “the best pizza places near me.” If they’re located in Brooklyn, New York, the top-rated pizzerias in their surrounding area will show up.</p>
<p>If you run a pizza parlor in Brooklyn, you can leverage Google My Business to help <em><u>your</u></em> business show up among the first few search results.</p>
<p>The outcome? More clicks, leads, conversions, and sales.</p>
<p>It’s that simple and quick.</p>
<p>In this video, we break down the basics of Google My Business and walk you through its benefits for small businesses.</p>
<p>Get your business seen today. Call us at <a href="tel:855-444-4777"><strong><u><b>855-444-4777</b></u></strong></a> to speak with our Google My Business experts and start achieving local visibility.</p>
<p>Subscribe now: <a href="https://bit.ly/3kL0Ka4"><u>https://bit.ly/3kL0Ka4</u></a></p>
<p>Check out: <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/gmb-optimization/"><u>https://www.searchberg.com/gmb-optimization/</u></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Stay tuned for more!</p>
<p>Facebook: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/searchberg/"><u>https://www.facebook.com/searchberg/</u></a></p>
<p>Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/searchberg"><u>https://twitter.com/searchberg</u></a></p>
<p>LinkedIn:<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/searchberg"><u>https://www.linkedin.com/company/searchberg</u></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-google-my-business-and-how-does-it-help-small-businesses/">What is Google My Business and How Does It Help Small Businesses?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/what-is-google-my-business-and-how-does-it-help-small-businesses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Digital Marketing for Small Businesses &#124; Small Businesses SEO Services &#8211; Video</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/digital-marketing-for-small-businesses-small-businesses-seo-services-search-berg/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/digital-marketing-for-small-businesses-small-businesses-seo-services-search-berg/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 15:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Video Content]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1129</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Search Berg have worked with many small businesses to strengthen their online presence in today’s fierce competitive market. Our proven digital marketing strategies have worked tremendously well for many of our small business clients. We can help your brand get the recognition it deserves! Hire Search Berg for small business SEO today! Call 855 444 [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/digital-marketing-for-small-businesses-small-businesses-seo-services-search-berg/">Digital Marketing for Small Businesses | Small Businesses SEO Services &#8211; Video</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Small Businesses SEO Services | Digital Marketing for Small Businesses - Search Berg" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Djs7yJKCCLI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Search Berg have worked with many small businesses to strengthen their online presence in today’s fierce competitive market. Our proven digital marketing strategies have worked tremendously well for many of our small business clients. We can help your brand get the recognition it deserves!</p>
<p>Hire Search Berg for small business SEO today!</p>
<p>Call 855 444 4777 for customized quote.</p>
<p>Visit us at: <a class="yt-simple-endpoint style-scope yt-formatted-string" spellcheck="false" href="https://www.youtube.com/redirect?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.searchberg.com&amp;v=Djs7yJKCCLI&amp;redir_token=crMt_EmBCkiieOzhA1AwJrRdPJV8MTU0NjYxNDIwMkAxNTQ2NTI3ODAy&amp;event=video_description" rel="nofollow">https://www.searchberg.com</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/digital-marketing-for-small-businesses-small-businesses-seo-services-search-berg/">Digital Marketing for Small Businesses | Small Businesses SEO Services &#8211; Video</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/digital-marketing-for-small-businesses-small-businesses-seo-services-search-berg/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why You Need Video Content for Your Website If You Want to Gain New Customers And Strengthen Your Brand Online</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-you-need-video-content-for-your-website-if-you-want-to-gain-new-customers-and-strengthen-your-brand-online/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-you-need-video-content-for-your-website-if-you-want-to-gain-new-customers-and-strengthen-your-brand-online/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 12:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Video Content]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1013</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Content marketing is ever evolving in the sense that new and better forms of content have emerged and in some cases replaced older approaches. Take print media and digital media for example. Before people used to get their news from the local newspaper. Now they get it online, from their tablet. Nothing against print media [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-you-need-video-content-for-your-website-if-you-want-to-gain-new-customers-and-strengthen-your-brand-online/">Why You Need Video Content for Your Website If You Want to Gain New Customers And Strengthen Your Brand Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/content-marketing.html">Content marketing</a> is ever evolving in the sense that new and better forms of content have emerged and in some cases replaced older approaches. Take print media and digital media for example. Before people used to get their news from the local newspaper. Now they get it online, from their tablet. Nothing against print media which is still there in some form. But with this shift, we basically witnessed an example of content evolving to serve the vast interest of the public.</p>
<p>Today, we are seeing another similar paradigm shift where digital media is being replaced by Video media.</p>
<p>Video content has been here for some time, and it has been gradually shaping up into a VERY strong trend. It’s turning into a super content marketing craze.</p>
<p>And for some very impressive reasons.</p>
<h2><strong>No Medium Attracts Traffic Faster and Larger than Video</strong></h2>
<p>The results are in. Study after study has shown people response more to Video which is why Video content has big admirers across the globe.</p>
<p>Case in point—YouTube— the giant boasts a viewership of <a href="https://www.smartinsights.com/social-media-marketing/social-media-strategy/new-global-social-media-research/">1.5 billion monthly active users</a>.</p>
<p>Our current worldwide population is <a href="http://www.worldometers.info/world-population/">nearly 7.6 billion</a>.</p>
<p>That means, one out of every five people in the world has a YouTube account and since you don’t actually need an account to view YouTube, imagine how many people actually use it in their daily lives — now that would be a massive number!</p>
<p>And of course, with huge audience, comes huge traffic.</p>
<p>According to the <a href="http://www.aberdeen.com/about/">Aberdeen Group</a>, a leading market intelligence firm, companies using videos on their websites generate 41% more web traffic from search engines than those that don’t.</p>
<p><strong>The takeaway:</strong> If you want more traffic on your website, start creating videos of your products or services.</p>
<h2><strong>Videos Leads To Sales!</strong></h2>
<p>Okay, traffic without conversions isn’t really impressive.</p>
<p>But who says videos don’t convert?</p>
<p>Latest data <a href="http://awesome.vidyard.com/rs/273-EQL-130/images/Vidyard_Aberdeen_Impact_of_Video_Marketing.pdf">reveals</a>, video users enjoy 27% higher click-through rates and 34% higher web conversion rates, compared to non-users.</p>
<p>Another <a href="https://instapage.com/blog/video-landing-page-examples">study</a> reveals adding video to a landing page boosts conversions by as much as 80%.</p>
<p>One case study that makes for a strong case is that of Dropbox.</p>
<p>When Dropbox was first launched, the concept was foreign to most.</p>
<p>Users could not understand what it was about and how it operated.</p>
<p>As a result, the company struggled with conversions.</p>
<p>Later, they decided to add an introductory video to their landing page.</p>
<p>And guess what?</p>
<p>Their conversions instantly increased!</p>
<p><strong>The takeaway: </strong>If you want more conversions on your website, start investing in videos</p>
<h2><strong>Videos Sell Products and Services</strong></h2>
<p>Arguably the strongest point of videos is that they sell a product or service effectively.</p>
<p>It has been found that companies that use video boost revenue <a href="http://awesome.vidyard.com/rs/273-EQL-130/images/Vidyard_Aberdeen_Impact_of_Video_Marketing.pdf">49% faster year-over-year</a> than companies that don’t.</p>
<p>This can be attributed to four factors:</p>
<ul>
<li>Videos communicate marketing messages and product concepts in a <a href="https://www.forrester.com/report/How+Video+Will+Take+Over+The+World/-/E-RES44199?isTurnHighlighting=false&amp;highlightTerm=1.8%2520million%2520words">clear manner</a>.</li>
<li>Consumers <a href="https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/consumer-insights/youtube-stars-influence/">trust</a> video content more in comparison to other content pieces</li>
<li>It’s <a href="http://www.brainrules.net/vision">easy to retain information</a> about a product when communicated through video, thereby increasing the likelihood of conversions.</li>
<li>Consumers consume video content <a href="https://medium.com/@CarolForden/how-video-can-raise-customer-engagement-and-revenue-744493902a6f">more thoroughly</a> than blogs, articles, whitepapers and e-books.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The takeaway:</strong> If you want to increase business revenue, start investing in videos.</p>
<h2><strong>This is THE TIME to take advantage of the opportunity</strong></h2>
<p>Businesses around the world have already started creating marketing strategies around video content. And they’re very aggressive in their plans.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/53/assets/hubspot.com/research/reports/State%20of%20Inbound%202018%20Global%20Results.pdf?t=1540466138190&amp;__hstc=20629287.2955a610c217d83a92b53681ece29d53.1540466163549.1540466163549.1540466163549.1&amp;__hssc=20629287.1.1540466163548&amp;__hsfp=364299786">State of Inbound 2018</a>, 45% of marketers are planning to prioritize video next year. More will definitely join them in the future when they see video attracting traffic, boosting conversions and increasing business revenue.</p>
<p>Interested in creating videos for your business website?</p>
<p>Search Berg can help you!</p>
<p>We’re one of the leading content marketing service providers in the United States, specializing in video content creation and video voiceovers. <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/contact-us.html">Get in touch</a> with us today to discuss your video marketing needs.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-you-need-video-content-for-your-website-if-you-want-to-gain-new-customers-and-strengthen-your-brand-online/">Why You Need Video Content for Your Website If You Want to Gain New Customers And Strengthen Your Brand Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-you-need-video-content-for-your-website-if-you-want-to-gain-new-customers-and-strengthen-your-brand-online/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
