<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Pay Per Click &#8211; Search Berg</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/category/pay-per-click/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 09:30:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>A Simple Guide to Getting Started with PPC</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-simple-guide-to-getting-started-with-ppc/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-simple-guide-to-getting-started-with-ppc/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jonathan Mears]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 09:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pay Per Click]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2504</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>These days, being a business owner or marketer is akin to entering a Baskin Robbins franchise and facing decision paralysis because of the sheer volume of flavors and choices available. In marketing, there are many avenues you can explore. Some certainly take time to implement and have an incubation period to garner results such as [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-simple-guide-to-getting-started-with-ppc/">A Simple Guide to Getting Started with PPC</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>These days, being a business owner or marketer is akin to entering a <em>Baskin Robbins </em>franchise and facing decision paralysis because of the sheer <em>volume </em>of flavors and choices available.</p>
<p><span id="more-2504"></span></p>
<p>In marketing, there are many avenues you can explore. Some certainly take time to implement and have an incubation period to garner results such as SEO and Content Marketing.</p>
<p>The<strong> fastest </strong>way to market all around, though, resoundingly, is <strong><u>PPC&#8211;AKA Pay Per Click Advertising</u>.</strong></p>
<p>While you may be somewhat familiar with paid advertising and how to become a Google Ads specialist, you may not know what PPC is specifically. Basically, it’s a <strong>paid advertising model for use in Search Engines</strong>. In this model, you <strong>only pay every time someone clicks on your ad</strong>.</p>
<p>As a bonus, if someone saw your ad and became<strong> aware </strong>of your brand but doesn’t click it,<strong> you don’t have to pay for that impression</strong>. Since people who saw your ad are now aware of your brand, they’re automatically<em> more likely to click on it </em>the next time that they see your ad.</p>
<p><em>Pretty cool, right?</em></p>
<p>Learning how to set up PPC ad campaigns in Google can be very lucrative because <em>most online consumers </em><em><u>do</u></em> click on Google Ads when they’re shopping online. And unlike unpaid marketing methods such as SEO, which can take months to yield impressions, clicks, and conversions, <strong><em>PPC yields immediate results</em></strong>.</p>
<p>But because you don’t want to blow your ad budget on a not-so-great ad that doesn’t actually give you the conversions and click-throughs you desire, it’s crucial to <u>create a solid plan for your PPC campaign</u>.</p>
<p>Having a good, thought-through plan also helps you <u>reduce your ad spend</u>. This is because the <strong>more relevant </strong>your ad is to your target audience’s search keywords, the more a search engine like Google will<strong> reward you with a lower ad cost.</strong></p>
<p>Google wants to connect the right ad with an audience that would appreciate it, so they reward the advertisers and businesses that play the game well and according to their rules.</p>
<p>Use our simple guide to make sure you both have a<strong><u> successful campaign</u></strong>, and search engines reward it so you can <strong><u>lower your costs.</u></strong></p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Setting up your PPC campaign can skyrocket your marketing efforts! We’ve been in the game long enough to know what works. Fill out the form to get great results!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form2" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject2" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name2" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website2" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email2" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number2" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country2" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha2();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Catalog</h2>
<p><a href="#_Toc15858">Phase 1: The Research Phase</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc19244">Phase 2: The Organization Phase</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc21899">Phase 3: Check Out Your Competition</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc11837">Pro Tip: Look into Negative Keywords</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc21223">Phase 4: Create PPC Ads</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc22039"> The headline</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc16558"> The description</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc3432"> The Display URL</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc1771">Description &amp; Headline: PPC Ad Copy That Converts</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc11198">Final URL: Have A Solid Landing Page For When Your Prospect Clicks Your Ad</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc14305">Top PPC Platforms</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc22420">Google Ads</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc20569">Bing Ads</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc12766">Facebook Advertising</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc28544">Wrapping Up!</a></p>
<h2>Phase 1: The Research Phase</h2>
<p>So the result of your research phase will be your <em>keyword list</em>. To have a successful campaign, you can’t use just any random keywords. You need to look into<em> who </em>your customer is, <em>what </em>they want,and most importantly,<em> how </em>they’re searching for those wants in search engines.</p>
<p>There’s actually a built-in <strong>keyword searching tool within Google Adwords</strong> that you can utilize for this purpose. The tool will ask you for<em> “seed words or phrases.”</em> These will be terms you think your ideal customer will search for.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2508" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-46.png" alt="Google Ads Keyword Searching Tool For pay per click guide" width="828" height="390" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>How are you supposed to know what they are searching for?</p>
<p>One way is to make detailed <em>customer personas </em>using the data you have available. Your first list will be everything that you <em>think</em> your <strong>ideal customer</strong> is looking for. Then, later on, when you’re running campaigns, you can refine this list using the polishing strategy that’s <strong>A/B testing</strong>.</p>
<p>A/B testing is essentially <u>testing different versions of your ad</u> (version A, B, C, etc.) to see which version gets a greater, more efficient response from your target audience. When you know what’s working in your tests, you do more of that for better results.</p>
<p>When you input your<strong> “seed phrases”</strong> into Google Adwords, it will spit out a bunch of related keywords that people are searching for alongside their average monthly search volumes and cost per click, among other values. You definitely don’t need to consider them all. The main ones are the <strong>monthly search volume, how competitive each keyword is, and their estimated cost per click. </strong></p>
<p>This handy dandy tool also spits out <em>“related” keywords </em>that you may not have even thought of but might want to consider looking into using for your campaign.</p>
<p>Another <strong><u>fun fact</u></strong>: you can specifically target your keywords and <strong><u>get the data for a specific location</u></strong> that you want to advertise in. For example, if you only want to advertise in specific regions in New York, you can narrow the data you get for search volumes in those places to see what the people in those places’ <em>search patterns </em>are like.</p>
<p>Now that you have a whole bunch of juicy, raw data, you can take it and <strong>organize it </strong>into specific categories for your ads.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style3">
<h3>Struggling to understand how setting up a PPC campaign can skyrocket your marketing efforts? We’ve been in the game long enough to know what works and what doesn’t. Fill out the form to get great results!</h3>
<div class="inner"><form id="form3" name="form1">
  <input id="Subject3" name="Subject" type="hidden" value="Request a Quote (Blog Post Form)">
  <div class="row">
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Name" type="text" id="Name3" class="cforminput-ind" placeholder="Your Full Name">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
  	<input name="Website" type="text" id="Website3" class="cforminput-ind4" placeholder="Website">
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Email" type="email" id="Email3" class="cforminput-ind3" placeholder="Email Address">    
  </div>
  <div class="col">
    <input name="Number" type="tel" id="Number3" class="cforminput-ind2" placeholder="Phone Number">
  </div>
  </div>
  <input id="Source1" name="Source" type="hidden" value="19">
    <input id="country3" name="Country" type="hidden" value="Location of 122.2.98.13: City of Taguig, Philippines
">
  <div class="submit-button"><a href="javascript:void(0)" onclick="return validateCaptcha3();" id="home-submit-button"> Submit Request</a></div>
  <div class="clear_fix"></div>
</form>
</div>
</div>
<h2><a name="_Toc19244"></a>Phase 2: The Organization Phase</h2>
<p>In this phase, you’ll <strong>put together keywords that are similar</strong> to each other or follow a certain pattern that aligns with each other. When you put them in groups like this that are similar, these groups are called <strong>Ad Groups.</strong></p>
<p>The more specific your Ad Groups become, the easier it will become for you to <em><u>create an ad tying all of those keywords together</u></em> because they already fit together naturally.</p>
<p>When you’re organizing your keywords, you want to keep in mind that users may have varying <strong>intentions </strong>when they’re looking for products or services online. Some may search with the intention to<strong> gather information,</strong> while others may search for a term with the intention to purchase. The good thing is that you can look at keywords and discern what the searcher’s likely intention is.</p>
<p>You can do this by reading the word and analyzing what might be going through someone’s mind when searching that word or phrase into Google. <u>Shorter,</u> one or two-word keywords are generally <u>information seeking</u> in nature.</p>
<p>For example: <strong><em>“glue gun”</em></strong></p>
<p>Compare this with the search term<strong><em> “glue gun cost near me” </em></strong></p>
<p>Looking at the second keyword, you can tell that the second searcher is far more likely to purchase a glue gun rather than simply gather information about a glue gun, what it is, how it works, etc.</p>
<p>You can still use either or both keywords, depending on<strong> what your campaign goal </strong>is. If your goal is to get<strong> more sales</strong>, it would make sense to put greater emphasis on “glue gun cost near me” as opposed to just “glue gun.”</p>
<p>But if your goal is<strong> brand recognition</strong> or just getting your business’s name out there, you might be able to use both keywords because they both fit that purpose.</p>
<p>If you’re looking for further information regarding how to use the internet to build your personal and business brand, be sure to check out two of our blogs on brand building:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/10-ways-to-build-a-strong-personal-reputation-for-individuals-and-entrepreneurs/"><strong>10 Ways to Build a Strong Personal Reputation For Individuals and Entrepreneurs</strong></a> and</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-build-a-good-reputation-for-your-business-that-will-entice-viewers-and-create-a-positive-brand-image/"><strong>How to Build A Good Reputation for Your Business That Will Entice Viewers and Create A Positive Brand Image</strong></a></p>
<h2><a name="_Toc21899"></a>Phase 3: Check Out Your Competition</h2>
<p>Now that you have many assorted keywords organized by Ad Groups, you want to <em>test them out </em>and <em>see what kind of ads come up</em> when you search them. This will lead you to see ads from your competitors and will be instrumental in your approach because you can spy on what kind of ads they’re running.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2507" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog3.jpg" alt="Guide to PPC Competition Keyword Research" width="977" height="385" /></p>
<p>This also helps you gauge whether the keyword is good. Suppose you see<strong> many businesses competing</strong> over that keyword, <strong>but they’re not within your niche</strong>. In this case, that keyword might not be right for you, and there’s no sense in spending good money from your Ad Budget on it.</p>
<p><em>So scrap it.</em></p>
<p>On the flip side, if relevant competitors are fighting over a keyword, you know it’s a good keyword that you want to also get in on.</p>
<p>You can also use free tools to watch your competition’s performance, such as <a href="https://www.spyfu.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Spyfu</a>.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc11837"></a>Pro Tip: Look into Negative Keywords</h3>
<p><strong>Negative Keywords are keywords that you don’t want to show up in search results for</strong>, even if they’re related to your niche. An example of this would be a keyword that’s related to your niche but doesn’t relate to your product. This could look like the use of the word<em> “free”</em> in a keyword when you’re trying to make sales.</p>
<p>Using the goal of making sales, it would not be a great match to connect with a customer who’s looking for free items rather than to pay. Therefore, you can put the word “free” as a negative keyword. That way, if someone searches for this keyword in addition to a word or phrase in your keyword list, <strong>Google knows not to show your ad to this person</strong>.</p>
<p>This is great because it ultimately<strong> saves you money</strong> on pointless impressions and clicks that aren’t a match for both parties to begin with.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc21223"></a>Phase 4: Create PPC Ads</h2>
<p>There are three main components for how to set up your PPC campaign:</p>
<ol>
<li>The headline</li>
<li>The description</li>
<li>The Display URL</li>
</ol>
<p>You have limited character space for your <em>headline and description,</em> so make sure to <strong>take full advantage </strong>of the real-estate space the search engine provides you with for the headline and description.</p>
<p>The <em>display URL</em> is basically for aesthetic purposes. The ad would go to your landing page that you put into the ad as the “<u>final URL,</u>” but the display URL appears on the search engine in the ad itself when your prospect is looking at it.</p>
<p>Aside from Text Ads (also known as <strong>Search Ads</strong>), you have the option of choosing:</p>
<ol>
<li>Display Ads, which consists of text, image, <strong>video</strong>, audio, and motion <strong>ads</strong></li>
<li>Remarketing Ads</li>
<li>Google Shopping</li>
<li>Gmail Sponsored Ads</li>
<li>Social Ads</li>
<li>Local Service Ads &amp;</li>
<li>Instream Ads</li>
</ol>
<p>For further information regarding video ads, in particular, be sure to check out our video on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Fk48tDAVCQ" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Using Video Marketing to Maximize Traffic</a>.</p>
<p>Whichever Ad type you use, you will have to <strong>write words to entice your audience </strong>to click on them and become part of your <strong>sales funnel</strong>. These words make up your ad copy.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc1771"></a>Description &amp; Headline: PPC Ad Copy That Converts</h3>
<p>What people love to click on is<strong> content that’s personalized </strong>for them. If you address their <strong>specific pain points and concerns</strong>, your prospect will feel seen and validated and therefore is more likely to engage with your ad over others.</p>
<p>Your <strong>keyword research and customer profile</strong> will help you understand why your customer would be searching for the terms that you are targeting. What’s the<strong> underlying concern</strong> they want to resolve or need that they are trying to meet?</p>
<p>In your <em>Ad Copy</em>, you want to emphasize <strong><u>how your product/company/business meets the need that this user is searching for</u></strong>. This is your <strong><u>unique selling proposition or USP</u></strong>. So you want to <strong><u>include your USP clearly where you can in your Ad</u></strong> to put it where your prospects can see.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc11198"></a>Final URL: Have a Solid Landing Page for When Your Prospect Clicks Your Ad</h3>
<p>A <strong>solid landing page</strong> is a <strong>relevant landing page</strong>. Basically, whatever you promise the prospect in your PPC ad itself, you want the landing page that they click on to be relevant to what the ad said. The landing page should<strong> bridge a gap and help solve the same problem</strong> with your USP that the ad had summarized for them earlier in the search engine.</p>
<p>An aesthetically appealing landing page is nothing without relevance. That being said,<strong> a good design</strong> doesn’t hurt once you have the relevance down.</p>
<p>By creating really specific landing pages tailored for your ads, you essentially <strong>eliminate any extra work a lead may have to do</strong> in navigating your site. Less work means less tedious scrolling to navigate your site, which means more time spent digesting <strong><em>why your product and your unique selling point solves their problem</em></strong><em>. </em></p>
<p>This efficient allotment of time spent, in turn, increases your<strong> conversion rate in the PPC campaign you have run</strong>.</p>
<p>Now that you have a good idea about running a campaign, let’s look at the best platforms that you can use to run these awesome campaigns on.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc14305"></a>Top PPC Platforms</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2506" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/blog2-45.png" alt="concept illustration top PPC platforms" width="970" height="783" /></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc22420"></a>Google Ads</h3>
<p>Google is a giant and by far the largest search engine on the planet. Even the creator of Amazon, Jeff Bezos, <a href="https://medium.com/the-innovation/here-is-why-jeff-bezos-said-treat-google-like-a-mountain-60b5243e5747" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">recently said</a> to treat Google like a Mountain: you can climb the mountain, but you can’t move it.</p>
<p>Google isn’t going anywhere, and most of the world is using this platform to search for answers to their problems and queries. So use it to find your target audience because if it’s not on a platform as universal and all-encompassing as Google, it’s likely not anywhere else on the internet.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc20569"></a>Bing Ads</h3>
<p>Bing is also a good platform that you can run PPC campaigns on. The benefit here is that Bing is cheaper to run ads on in terms of cost per click (CPC), but it’s no Google. The audience and reach is definitely smaller for Bing.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc12766"></a>Facebook Advertising</h3>
<p>Facebook Ads is super great for narrowing down to a very specific audience demographic because you can pick out pages, ideas, and topics that have proven interesting in the past. Therefore, you can use your customer profile to the max on this platform and create extremely targeted ads that have the potential for sky-high click-through-rates.</p>
<p>Also, you can utilize the giant that is Instagram Advertising through the Facebook platform as well. For further information on Facebook advertising, including how to get 1000+ likes on Facebook, check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-likes-on-facebook-in-2020/">How to Get More Likes on Facebook In 2020</a>.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc28544"></a>Wrapping Up!</h2>
<p>Remember that once you use this newfound knowledge to get your ads up and running, your work is far from over. This is because now you need to <strong><u>watch your campaign to see how it performs</u></strong>. No one can predict this for you. You need to periodically check it, see what’s working, stop campaigns that are simply <strong><em>not performing</em></strong>, and continue to innovate ads to incorporate what <strong><em>is </em></strong>working in your campaign.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Follow this simple guide to PPC advertising to maximize your chances of success.</p>
<p><em>Happy advertising!</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-simple-guide-to-getting-started-with-ppc/">A Simple Guide to Getting Started with PPC</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/a-simple-guide-to-getting-started-with-ppc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Difference Between Organic and Paid Search</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-difference-between-organic-and-paid-search/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-difference-between-organic-and-paid-search/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 08:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pay Per Click]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Do you sell products/services online? If so, you should have a strong grasp on the difference between organic and paid search. As an online business, your primary goal is to reach a wide audience and maximize conversions. Both organic and paid search help you do just that! They boost your online visibility, improve your SERP [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-difference-between-organic-and-paid-search/">The Difference Between Organic and Paid Search</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do you sell products/services online? If so, you should have a strong grasp on the difference between organic and paid search. <span id="more-2473"></span><br />
As an online business, your primary goal is to reach a wide audience and maximize conversions. Both organic and paid search help you do just that! They boost your online visibility, improve your SERP rankings, and help you generate more traffic. Sounds like the perfect mix?<br />
In this infographic, we dive deeper and walk you through the differences between organic and paid search. We cover their position, cost, ranking, and speed. We also discuss some genius tips to improve both organic and paid search campaigns. Let’s get right into it!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2474" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/SearchBerg_revised-01-min.jpg" alt="Difference between organic and paid search" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-difference-between-organic-and-paid-search/">The Difference Between Organic and Paid Search</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-difference-between-organic-and-paid-search/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pay Per Click Advertisement Stats &#038; Facts</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/pay-per-click-advertisement-stats-facts/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/pay-per-click-advertisement-stats-facts/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 14:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pay Per Click]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/pay-per-click-advertisement-stats-facts/">Pay Per Click Advertisement Stats &#038; Facts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-694" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/searchberg-revised-ppc-infograph.jpg" alt="" width="690" height="1438" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/pay-per-click-advertisement-stats-facts/">Pay Per Click Advertisement Stats &#038; Facts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/pay-per-click-advertisement-stats-facts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Undeniable Benefits of PPC for Your Business</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/7-reasons-you-want-ppc-for-your-website/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/7-reasons-you-want-ppc-for-your-website/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 13:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pay Per Click]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>For businesses that are desperately looking for reliable, proven ways to increase sales and increase clientele, we discuss some very important reasons in this post explaining why a small investment in PPC Marketing can yield a sizable return on your investment and increase your online revenue within months! PPC Marketing has revolutionized how companies harness [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/7-reasons-you-want-ppc-for-your-website/">7 Undeniable Benefits of PPC for Your Business</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For businesses that are desperately looking for reliable, proven ways to increase sales and increase clientele, we discuss some very important reasons in this post explaining why a small investment in PPC Marketing can yield a sizable return on your investment and increase your online revenue within months!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/pay-per-click-advertisement-stats-facts/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">PPC Marketing has revolutionized</a> how companies harness the power of the internet to maintain their market share in their target niches and ensure that steady revenue continues to flow through the information highway with each passing month.</p>
<p>Despite an across the board ringing endorsement for PPC Advertising to by millions around the world, many businesses remain skeptical; not on the concept of PPC and what it brings to the table but rather, how can they utilize it to benefit their online business. The simple truth is that PPC can benefit any business of any kind at any time to enable them in generating new leads and increase sales provided that they are carefully planned and executed. Our today’s post will focus on why pay per click is advantageous for small and medium size businesses and why they should seriously consider PPC.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" src="http://streaming.yayimages.com/images/photographer/onephoto/f8c4f4e7552b1be36dd147ee25fdebaf/pay-per-click.jpg" alt="pay-per-click " width="600" height="350" /></p>
<h2>Reasons &amp; Benefits of PPC</h2>
<p>Many business owners consider that PPC is too expensive as compared to the advantages of pay per click for their business, but today you will have changed views regarding the immense advantages of PPC having read this post.</p>
<h3>1 – Verifiable, Actionable Results</h3>
<p>One of the best benefits of pay per click is that is provides actionable results; results that companies can actually <strong><i>see</i></strong>. A properly configured PPC campaign keeps a detailed record of all important activity happening on Google as well as on the website. Every time an ad is clicked, it is marked. Every time a newsletter is signed up for, it is marked. Everyone a sale is made on a website it is marked. Every time a phone call is initiated through an Ad, it is marked. Companies can see the progress of their campaign and determine whether it is actually contributing to the business success.</p>
<h3>2 – You Only Pay When Someone Clicks On Your Ad</h3>
<p>So many of Search Berg clients like PPC just for this feature. A great advantage of PPC marketing is that you only pay when you Ads are being clicked on in Google and that’s good for 2 reasons. First, it eliminates the scenarios of having recurring fixed budget amount every month even if that amount is not fully used. You only fund the campaign when your budget is completely exhausted. Secondly, it’s fail-safe. If your monthly budget is not being utilized fully and a big portion of it goes unattended, that either your monthly budget is too high and that you should bring it down or something is very, very wrong. Are people even seeing your ads in Google? Is the campaign properly optimized for your target keywords? What ARE your target keywords? Was Keyword Research done effectively? A Google AdWords certified PPC analyst will be able to tell you all that.</p>
<h3>3 – A Marketing Campaign That Never Goes Over Budget</h3>
<p>Some businesses are not targeting online sales as their primary objective, yet they still want to a sizable presence on Google and hence allocate a specific budget for the entire fiscal year. PPC can accommodate that provided the initial Keyword Research and analysis pertaining to the industry, target audience, target keywords and their CPC cost is correctly determined.</p>
<p>You can never go over budget with PPC. Your ads disappear once you have used up your daily spend. Businesses have the flexibility to adjust their daily spend at any time. However the point here is that everything is under your control. You can actually <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/boost-your-organic-marketing-efforts-with-pay-per-click-advertising/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">put a cap on your daily PPC spending and still have the flexibility</a> to change it at any time.</p>
<h3>4 – Reach Out to Your Target Market Immediately</h3>
<p>What if you wanted to target a member from your audience while they are at a specific location at a specific time of the day? You might need to dive into the depths of geo-tagging and location based search with organic ranking strategies. PPC makes it easy.</p>
<p>Pay-Per-Click advertising agency like us, make use of various delivery tools and location targeting options along with <a href="https://support.google.com/adwords/answer/2393039?hl=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">platform-specific preferences</a> to deliver your message to your target audience at a time you decide, when they are at a geographical location you prefer.</p>
<p>This obviously opens up doors to a number of exciting online promotional strategies that companies are benefitting from, even as you read this!</p>
<h3>5 – Works Best When Joined with SEO Strategies</h3>
<p>PPC is PAID search marketing. SEO is natural search that is free. Combined them both and you have are well on your way to making some serious money from your website through Google’s natural results and paid ads.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" src="http://streaming.yayimages.com/images/photographer/wavebreakmedia/a2bb667b9e7009d3112eea4b0e494e1b/composite-image-of-seo-doodle.jpg" alt="SEO services" width="600" height="350" /></p>
<p>The core of our <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/impact-of-seo-services-on-small-businesses/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">business</a> is SEO yet we routinely pitch PPC to our existing clients because we have seen the results first hand. So many of our clients have dual projects with us, SEO and PPC and the results are there to see. Both complement each other and strengthen a website’s position in Google rankings. Imagine rankings for your target keywords in the natural SERP listings and seeing your paid ad on the top and bottom of the results as well. This directly leads to more Sales because you are occupying more slots on a given SERP result page.</p>
<h3>6 – PPC is Pivotal to Branding!</h3>
<p>When companies talk about <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/reputation-branding.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">branding</a>, they are referring to the degree of exposure their online strategies can help them gain. Factors like the ultimate goals in terms of leads or sales and even email list building come under this branding umbrella.</p>
<p>PPC already exposes your brand name and primary message to fresh prospects. The takeaway? It doesn’t brand your offerings to everyone, but only to qualified prospects.</p>
<p>While this is not pure branding, it is still a branch of branding for small businesses that don’t typically have whopping budgets.</p>
<p>Even though branding isn’t something as easily measurable as direct sales, PPC metrics like the ones mentioned below can help quickly identify where your company stands:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>The number of impressions<strong> equals the degree of exposure.</strong></strong></li>
<li><strong>Click-through-rates</strong> can be used to indicate the effectiveness of prospect targeting and the level of prospect interest towards a particular ad.</li>
<li><strong>Conversion rates</strong> also indicate the number of new prospects coming in every day.</li>
</ul>
<h3>7 – Always Return on Your Investment</h3>
<p>Arguably, the one thing that can be said about PPC without pause is that if is done right, it will bring about a nice return on your investment. That’s why Search Berg has Google Certified PPC experts working for us; people who have practical experience working with high-volume campaigns. PPC advertising is the perfect fit for almost every business. You can use it to promote your products and services, boost brand awareness, and secure new leads through search engines and social media platforms.</p>
<p>I hope I have answered ‘why do PPC’ will be advantageous for your business.</p>
<p>Ready to join hands with a leading <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/ppc-advertisement.html"><strong>PPC advertising agency</strong></a> to dominate search engine results and uncover new opportunities? Start with a <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/free-proposal.html"><strong>free PPC audit report</strong></a> and streamline the path towards online success, today!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/7-reasons-you-want-ppc-for-your-website/">7 Undeniable Benefits of PPC for Your Business</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/7-reasons-you-want-ppc-for-your-website/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boost Your Organic Marketing Efforts With Pay Per Click Advertising</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/boost-your-organic-marketing-efforts-with-pay-per-click-advertising/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/boost-your-organic-marketing-efforts-with-pay-per-click-advertising/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 14:58:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Pay Per Click]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know? the top 3 paid advertising spots get 46% of overall clicks. Why Make PPC a part of your online marketing strategy? &#160;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/boost-your-organic-marketing-efforts-with-pay-per-click-advertising/">Boost Your Organic Marketing Efforts With Pay Per Click Advertising</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you know? the top 3 paid advertising spots get 46% of overall clicks. Why Make PPC a part of your online marketing strategy?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Boost-Your-Organic-Marketing.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-598" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Boost-Your-Organic-Marketing.png" alt="Boost Your Organic Marketing" width="1200" height="6662" /></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/boost-your-organic-marketing-efforts-with-pay-per-click-advertising/">Boost Your Organic Marketing Efforts With Pay Per Click Advertising</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/boost-your-organic-marketing-efforts-with-pay-per-click-advertising/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
