<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>E-Commerce SEO &#8211; Search Berg</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/category/e-commerce-seo/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 09:41:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>11 Ways to Triple Your B2B Ecommerce Conversions</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/11-ways-to-triple-your-b2b-ecommerce-conversions/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/11-ways-to-triple-your-b2b-ecommerce-conversions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ryan Fernandez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 09:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Conversions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[E-Commerce SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1365</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The B2B market is growing exponentially! Forrester reports that B2B ecommerce sites in the US are estimated to reach $1.8 trillion by 2023. But let’s face it: a lot goes into launching and building an ecommerce business. Once set up, you can increase your B2B conversion rates by helping your buyers find what they’re looking for in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/11-ways-to-triple-your-b2b-ecommerce-conversions/">11 Ways to Triple Your B2B Ecommerce Conversions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The B2B market is growing exponentially! <a href="https://www.forrester.com/report/US+B2B+eCommerce+Will+Hit+12+Trillion+By+2021/-/E-RES136173" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Forrester</a> reports that B2B ecommerce sites in the US are estimated to reach $1.8 trillion by 2023.</p>
<p>But let’s face it: a lot goes into launching and building an ecommerce business.</p>
<p>Once set up, you can increase your B2B conversion rates by helping your buyers find what they’re looking for in a seamless manner.</p>
<p>However, this is easier said than done; there are some hidden factors that contribute to your conversion goals:</p>
<ol>
<li>Email signups</li>
<li>Social media shares</li>
<li>A profitable online sale</li>
<li>Visitors adding products to their carts</li>
<li>Visitors adding products to their wish list</li>
<li>KPIs that are valuable for your company</li>
<li>Let Customers review the products you sell them</li>
</ol>
<h2>Understanding ecommerce conversion rates</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1375" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Understanding-ecommerce-conversion-rates.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="250" /></p>
<p>The ecommerce conversion rate is the percentage of users that visit your website and complete a desired action.</p>
<p>So, what’s a good conversion rate?</p>
<p>The <a href="http://monetate.com/research/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Monetate Ecommerce Quarterly</a> regularly updates the benchmarks on ecommerce conversions for large brands. From this data, we can deduce that the average ecommerce conversion rate is somewhere between 2 and 4%.</p>
<p>Let’s look at 10 ways you can increase your ecommerce conversions:</p>
<h2>1. Improve your analytics</h2>
<p>Analytics that are in tune with your business goals give you real insight into your customers’ buying behavior and point out the improvements that you need to make in your Conversion Rate Optimization (CRO) strategy.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1369" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/analysis-1841158_960_720.jpg" alt="Improve your analytics" width="960" height="640" /></p>
<p>High-tier brands know what their top selling commodities are, and when it’s high-time to remarket them.</p>
<p>Your B2B firm is no different.</p>
<p>When you fix your analytics to properly track your goals, you’ll be able to map out the journey of top customers and learn how likely are customers to go through your products.</p>
<p>For instance, find out what people are looking for when they visit your site, including specific categories, product pages and information pages.</p>
<p>Constructing customer journey is an essential and integral part of <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/ecommerce-seo.html">B2B ecommerce SEO Services and marketing</a></u>, which in turn translates into higher conversions.</p>
<p>Without having access to the trigger events, scenarios and unified data source that synchronizes offline sales with the online activity, your B2B business will not be able to reach its potential.</p>
<p>Your digital plan should primarily include the concept of storing customer data and acting upon it in real-time.</p>
<p>You can even tweak your analytics by segmenting the traffic to track repeat purchasers and for insights into the events leading to a purchase.</p>
<h2>2. Mobile Optimization</h2>
<p><u><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/330695/number-of-smartphone-users-worldwide/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Studies</a></u> show that the number of smartphone users worldwide surpasses the three million mark, and this figure is forecasted to further increase by several hundred million in the upcoming years. This gives way to the increasing trend of mobile shopping.</p>
<p>Mobile conversion rates can take a massive hit if ecommerce businesses don’t follow the best practices of mobile landing pages. In fact, a <u><a href="https://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/data/cpg-shoppers-smartphone-purchase/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">study</a></u> has shown that 67% of smartphone users are likely to purchase from businesses with content customized according to their location.</p>
<p>To optimize for mobile devices, it is very important to keep your text concise, to the point, and also impactful.</p>
<p>You need to hit the customer&#8217;s pain points and benefits right on the bull&#8217;s eye. This will significantly improve and increase your b2b conversions rate via your mobile website.</p>
<p>You can do this by writing essentials-only product descriptions and copy. On a mobile phone, a person is scrolling and therefore has a more limited screen size and attention span.</p>
<p>No one likes to read pointless fluff, especially mobile users.</p>
<p>Another important note to optimize your ecommerce site for mobile users is speed. To figure out whether your website is currently optimized for speed on mobile devices, you can use Google&#8217;s Pagespeed Insights <a href="https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">tool</a>.</p>
<p>The tool will then spit out firstly what speed your users are experiencing when using your site and secondly what you should change in order to improve their experience.</p>
<p>Making sure your speed is fast in this way optimizes your customer experience, which in turn, massively improves your b2b website conversion rate.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1370" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/device-digital-ecommerce-35550.jpg" alt="Mobile Optimization" width="1280" height="853" /></p>
<p>As illustrated, mobile site’s performance plays a major role in the success of any online venture.</p>
<p>By providing your customers with a fast and seamless mobile experience, enhanced merchandizing and auto complete features, you’ll quickly see the web conversions and revenue increase significantly.</p>
<p><u><a href="https://www.nngroup.com/articles/how-long-do-users-stay-on-web-pages/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Research</a></u> shows that 47% of the visitors expect the website to load in less than 2 seconds. Conversely, 40% visitors are likely to leave the site if the load time is more than 3 seconds.</p>
<p>So remember to plug your URL into <u><a href="https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Google’s PageSpeed Insights</a></u> to make sure your site’s load time is within these parameters and if it&#8217;s not, make the recommended changes to boost your b2b conversion rate.</p>
<h2>3. Give clear and detailed product descriptions</h2>
<p>Once you’ve captured your visitor’s attention, it’s time to keep them engaged. That’s where product page optimization comes in. You can drive high levels of B2B online sales by adding unique content to your site that speaks to the challenges of your customers. Always add as much information as you can about the product; visitors bounce from pages that aren’t able to answer their questions. This includes the products’ features, benefits, how it works, and what it can and cannot do.</p>
<p><u><a href="https://www.salesforce.com/blog/2016/06/selling-to-the-modern-b2b-buyer.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Salesforce reports</a></u> that nearly 59% of all B2B buyers conduct online research on the products that they require, instead of contacting a customer service.</p>
<p>You should also try to include a product reviews section into your site to enhance your B2B ecommerce experience. Doing so creates the “Amazon Effect”, which reinforces positive feelings in your buyers.</p>
<p>Be sure to integrate the cross sell and upsell functionalities in the website’s initial presentation as well as the order confirmation stage—the website should speak to the visitors in a way that complements the products that they’re about to purchase.</p>
<h2>4. Consider adding a product video/demonstration</h2>
<p>Images are great, but videos are better. Adding a product video will go hand-in-hand with the product description. Since your site isn’t a brick and mortar store where visitors can talk directly to representatives and ask them questions, your aim should be to provide a digital experience that’s as close to the real deal as possible.</p>
<p>Provide a clear walk through of how to set up the product and its use through a demo video. Customers prefer to assess the ease of using the product.</p>
<h2>5. Product filtering and site search</h2>
<p>Setting your site with powerful characterization and filtering will help your customers find exactly what they’re looking for. For instance, give visitors the ability to filter products by price, size, color or style. Going through a long list of products without categories would be chaotic!</p>
<p>Moreover, in case you offer services instead of products, make sure your services are clearly listed in a structured product menu. You can even add a ‘Suggested Products’ functionality that will increase your cross-selling and upselling opportunities.</p>
<h2><strong>6. Provide free shipping</strong></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1371" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/free-shipping-with-aeroplane.jpg" alt="Provide free shipping" width="816" height="816" /></p>
<p>Statistics show that nearly <u><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/05/17/almost-half-of-all-online-orders-now-include-free-shipping/https:/nrf.com/media-center/press-releases/nrf-study-says-more-online-shoppers-want-free-shipping" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">75% of consumers</a></u> expect free shipping—even if their orders are under $50. Amazon’s Prime membership is based entirely on consumers’ obsession with free shipping. This is a pretty smart strategy. <u><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/04/free-shipping-isnt-hurting-amazon/559052/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Analysts</a></u> believe that Amazon is trying to get the customers hooked on the convenience of free shipping; once customers get their Prime ID, they start buying everything without really paying attention to the prices.</p>
<p>What’s more is that an <u><a href="https://conversionxl.com/blog/shopping-cart-abandonment-how-to-recover-baskets-of-money/#." target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">average of 67.75%</a></u> shopping carts are abandoned due to unexpected costs like shipping and taxes.</p>
<p>A psychology hack for this that you could implement is to make it look like you&#8217;re offering free shipping when your shipping cost is actually included in your overall cost, which technically allows you to say free shipping in your product pricing section.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s an example of this.</p>
<p>Say you have one product, which is $30 + $5 shipping.</p>
<p>A customer will not like the idea of paying $5 extra for shipping. Instead, if you simply wrote:</p>
<p>$35 + free shipping</p>
<p>The same customer is much more likely to make invest in your product.</p>
<p>It can be funny to see because you are getting the same amount of money, either way, you phrase it, but it&#8217;s a common practice among marketers and business people to take advantage of this interesting quirk in the human psyche and buyer mentality.</p>
<p>Ultimately this simple psychology hack can help you boost your b2b conversions by changing almost nothing on your site but how your pricing is phrased.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>7. User Personalization</h2>
<p>According to <u><a href="https://www.smartinsights.com/ecommerce/web-personalisation/types-ecommerce-personalisation/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Smart Insights</a></u>, adding suggestive personalization in your website—for instance, “visitors who viewed this, also viewed”—can generate up to 68% of your ecommerce revenue.</p>
<p>Amazon.com is a clear example of user personalization in ecommerce marketing sites. Nearly every element on their page is personalized; from the personal hello to the “Wish List” and suggested items based on the visitor’s previous searches—nothing is recommended to the user outside their realm of interests.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1372" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Untitled-1.jpg" alt="personalization in ecommerce marketing" width="624" height="416" /></p>
<p>Additionally, you can increase B2B conversion rates by giving your customers star treatment through a personalized dashboard that displays relevant products, their recent orders and timely promotions. It can even offer additional rewards like early product availability, custom pricing, enhanced customer service and invoicing options.</p>
<h2>8. Use chatbots or live chat</h2>
<p>Using chatbots will help you avoid the overhead of staffing someone for live chat, but in reality you’ll get a better response from visitors if you use live chat. This is because buyers are always looking for a personalized customer experience, just as they would expect from a brick and mortar store. Plus, it builds a direct communication line between you and your potential customer.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1373" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/chatbot-3589528_1280.jpg" alt="Using chatbots" width="1280" height="1106" /></p>
<p>B2B stores can gain the customers’ trust and prove that a real expert is on the other end by displaying an actual photo, name, contact number, ratings and the number of customers that have been served.</p>
<p>In case you do opt for the chatbot route, be upfront with your customers about it. A prime example is Facebook’s chatbot ‘<a href="https://www.chatbots.org/chatbot/bitcoin_buddy/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Bitcoin Buddy</a>.’</p>
<h2>9. Obtain customer emails</h2>
<p>Try to access your customer’s email addresses through a coupon code or a pop-up, and market your best selling products to the customer while they’re still in their decision phase.</p>
<p>One such example is <a href="https://www.zappos.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Zappo’s</a> rewards program that offers free shipping and exclusive 24/7 customer service access upon sign up.</p>
<p>Email marketing is a practice that every B2B ecommerce business should adopt because people—business executives in particular—constantly check their email. In fact, studies show that email marketing generates <u><a href="https://www.campaignmonitor.com/resources/guides/email-marketing-new-rules/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">40 times more ROI</a></u> compared to other marketing tactics.</p>
<p>An email campaign should focus on addressing the pains of the customers and informing them of what the brand’s services are, how they work, and what challenges they aim to solve.</p>
<h2>10. Offer coupons</h2>
<p>Coupons can be a great way to gain your visitor’s interest and encourage them to try your services and products out. However, make sure to use coupons sparingly, because offering low prices all the time can end up hurting your business.</p>
<p>For instance, offering 50% discount on too many services can cut your revenue in half. Although it may attract new customers but that still doesn’t guarantee repeat business. How many times did you end up buying a product only because it was discounted?</p>
<p>Instead, focus on offering a unique brand experience and an outstanding service.</p>
<p>Here are some ingenious ways of using coupons to boost revenue:</p>
<h2>Sell “stale” inventory</h2>
<p>Introduce coupons when you notice low sales volumes. Either offer a percentage discount on individual items in the inventory or offer a free item once the buyer hits a certain spending threshold.</p>
<h2>Appreciating customers</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1374" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Appreciating-customers.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="250" /></p>
<p>That’s all the more reason to show your loyal customers some love! Email your customers coupon codes to thank them for their continued support.</p>
<p>Reward new customers with discounts.</p>
<p>When a new customer purchases from your business for the first time, you can automatically apply discounts on their order. Although try not to sell this upfront; little bonuses like discounts that apply at checkouts may be a great tactic to making lifetime customers.</p>
<h2>11. Let your customers leave reviews for the products they buy from you.</h2>
<p>Reviews are incredibly important, not just for you as a business owner and seller to know that you are, in fact, selling good products that actually do help people, but also for your future customers.</p>
<p>This is people&#8217;s hard-earned money, so naturally, they will want to check out your page to see what other users of the product had to say about it upon receiving it.</p>
<p>Good product reviews mean a more confident buyer, which translates into skyrocketing your conversion rate for your b2b ecommerce website.</p>
<p>So let your customers leave reviews within your product page itself and, in fact, encourage them to leave reviews.</p>
<p>A best practice related to reviews is to display your top reviews to potential customers who are scrolling through the product page. Yet another best practice to boost your conversion and customer retention rate is to actually take the time to as a seller respond to each of your customers&#8217; reviews, whether they are good or bad.</p>
<p>If they are good, be sure to express your gratitude, thank them, and mention that you look forward to helping them find success with their pain points in the future.</p>
<p>The more personalized rather than generic the response, the better.</p>
<p>The same principle applies to negative reviews. Be gracious and accept feedback where it makes sense.</p>
<p>One thing you want to highlight in your top reviews is how your company works and what your unique selling point is to fellow businesses that you are selling to.</p>
<p>The way you can do this is by approaching previous clients and asking them specifically how your business has made a solid and helpful impact on their business to even help them improve their workflow/conversion rate, depending on the nature of their business.</p>
<p>Another hack that is arguably even a step up from top reviews is to take advantage of the power of a testimonial.</p>
<p>Testimonials are particularly powerful because they tend to be more detailed than a regular review would be because the person essentially swears by your product enough to give you a testimonial.</p>
<p>In this way, video testimonials are particularly powerful and impactful to consumers because video just acts as more solid social proof to a fellow customer than writing a review would.</p>
<p>A person can see that another person has needs similar to theirs&#8217;, which were met by your product on your b2b website.</p>
<p>Therefore, seeing this testimonial would increase their confidence in their purchasing decision and subsequently increase your b2b web conversion rate as a whole.</p>
<h2>In conclusion</h2>
<p>There isn’t a “one size fits all” strategy when it comes to how to best boost your B2B ecommerce conversions. The goal should be to implement these tactics intelligently. Showcase your brand’s distinctive features, use Artificial intelligence, a dynamic pricing business model and offer unique packages to new and repeat customers.</p>
<p>If you’re able to get happy customers to sign up to your referral program and leave positive reviews, you’ll be amazed at the impact it has on your ROI.</p>
<p><strong>Bio: </strong>The author is a digital marketing and SEO expert at Search Berg, an <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/">award-winning digital marketing firm</a></u>. He specializes in on-page SEO, <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/link-building-service.html">link building</a></u> and SEO ecommerce services and marketing solutions.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/11-ways-to-triple-your-b2b-ecommerce-conversions/">11 Ways to Triple Your B2B Ecommerce Conversions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/11-ways-to-triple-your-b2b-ecommerce-conversions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 2021 E-Commerce SEO Checklist for Small Business Owners and Entrepreneurs</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-2019-e-commerce-seo-checklist-for-small-business-owners-and-entrepreneurs/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-2019-e-commerce-seo-checklist-for-small-business-owners-and-entrepreneurs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jay Melendez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 08:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[E-Commerce SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Small Business SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1330</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In today’s digitized world, entrepreneurs and small business owners can’t get away with not knowing SEO strategies. In fact, e-commerce and SEO tools have become fundamental aspects of online marketing. Research suggests that people prefer mobile browsing over laptop or desktop searches. This growing trend has created the need for online business owners to ensure that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-2019-e-commerce-seo-checklist-for-small-business-owners-and-entrepreneurs/">The 2021 E-Commerce SEO Checklist for Small Business Owners and Entrepreneurs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1333" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/1-3.jpg" alt="E-Commerce SEO Checklist for Small Business Owners and Entrepreneurs" width="750" height="483" /></p>
<p>In today’s digitized world, entrepreneurs and small business owners can’t get away with not knowing SEO strategies. In fact, e-commerce and SEO tools have become fundamental aspects of online marketing.</p>
<p><u><a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2018/07/17/use-of-mobile-devices-for-news-continues-to-grow-outpacing-desktops-and-laptops/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Research suggests</a></u> that people prefer mobile browsing over laptop or desktop searches. This growing trend has created the need for online business owners to ensure that their website is optimized for mobile device viewing and has a user-friendly interface.</p>
<p>As simple as this may sound, many entrepreneurs struggle to implement SEO strategies effectively. The result is poor search engine rankings and foregone opportunities to make profits.</p>
<h2>How to Optimize Your E-Commerce SEO?</h2>
<p>You must strike when the iron is hot. Global events like Halloween, Christmas and Black Friday are prime days for e-commerce businesses to make profits and improve the visibility of their brand. However, you can’t yield the benefits of these events if you don’t even have an SEO strategy set up in the first place.</p>
<p>Everything from the content you post online to how your website is designed can play a crucial role in how well your business capitalizes on opportunities and converts them into a loyal customer base.</p>
<p><u><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/most-online-shoppers-are-using-search-engines-before-they-buy-2016-4" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Nearly 35 percent</a></u> of customers come from organic search engine results. This means that there’s a broad market you can tap into if you occupy any of the top search result ranks. So how do you rank better on Google?</p>
<p>At Search Berg, we’ve mastered the art of SEO marketing. We’ve been offering our award-winning digital <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/seo-services.html">SEO services</a></u> to clients all over the world and can provide you with optimized tools to help your business thrive!</p>
<p>Here are some of our best tips on a mandatory SEO checklist for small business owners and entrepreneurs aiming to go big this year!</p>
<h2>Part A: Website Architecture and Design</h2>
<p>The architecture and design of your website refer to the overall structure of your site, including the hosting server and the plug-ins and applications installed in it. Your website’s structure makes a huge difference in terms of how big your e-commerce store is.</p>
<p>A six-page website will likely load and operate faster compared to a thousand-page one. Using a Content Management System, however, can take the burden off of you to take care of your website since the design and operations are already programmed.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1337" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/b1-3.jpg" alt="" width="750" height="156" /></p>
<p>Here are some things you can do to improve your website design.</p>
<h3>1. Simplify your Website’s Structure</h3>
<p>A complicated homepage structure can chase away even the most enthusiastic customers. Your website should always be UX and UI friendly. This means that your site visitors should be able to navigate their way to the product page under 3 clicks. Also, keep in mind that a <u><a href="https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2011/01/guidelines-for-responsive-web-design/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">responsive website design</a></u> that’s adaptable to mobile device viewing will improve your chances of getting visitors to stay on your site. This is known as dwell time and it works wonderfully to improve your business’s SEO rankings.</p>
<h3>2. Incorporate Breadcrumbs on Your Site</h3>
<p>Breadcrumbs are a navigational aid that tells the visitor what part of the website they’re on.</p>
<p>This feature should also be beneficial for your business since the right breadcrumb tags can make you more searchable.</p>
<p>When you first read about breadcrumb navigation for your site, it can sound rather confusing and abstract so let&#8217;s break it down.</p>
<p>Basically, the term comes from the tale Hansel and Gretel, in which Hansel leaves bread crumbs behind him so that they can navigate the path that they have walked to get to where they are.</p>
<p>Subsequently, breadcrumb navigation on your website is specifically designed to help your website visitor understand what path they have followed on your website&#8217;s pages to wind up on the page that they currently are at.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s akin to having left a trail of breadcrumbs behind them to navigate their path.</p>
<p>Traditionally the breadcrumb navigation feature is placed at the top of the web page so that the user can easily see it.</p>
<p>It will look something like: Home &gt; Blogs &gt; Breadcrumb blog piece &gt; Contact Us Page.</p>
<p>In this above case, the page that the user ended up on was the Contact Us page, and the breadcrumb tells them the story of how they navigated through the site to get there.</p>
<p>This ultimately helps the user understand your site structure and therefore navigate your site more easily to the pages that they want to access.</p>
<p>The key &#8220;secret sauce&#8221; which makes the breadcrumb navigation system work is that each &#8220;crumb&#8221; is linked so that the user can immediately skip back and forth to pages that they want to go to.</p>
<p>You may be wondering: how can this practice improve an Ecommerce site&#8217;s SEO for entrepreneurs and small business owners?</p>
<p>The answer is that Google actually uses breadcrumb navigation to crawl your website and place it into categories.</p>
<p>Therefore, if your site already has an effective breadcrumb navigation system in place, Google is much more likely to rank it on the first page.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>3. Optimize Links to your Site</h3>
<p>When it comes to organic searches, site links can help your visitors easily navigate the most important pages. These are usually the most frequently visited pages on your website.</p>
<p>It helps to add internal links to related products on your ecommerce site or even products that your other customers bought with the product in question.</p>
<p>This helps you up-scale your revenue and sales through up-selling your customers more products.</p>
<p>A smart way to include internal links is to use your keywords as the &#8220;call to action&#8221; rather than a generic phrase like &#8220;click over here.&#8221;</p>
<p>A key way to increase your authority as well as get some good internal links in is to create an About Us page.</p>
<p>This helps your target customer understand your company better, and if your mission is something they resonate with, they&#8217;re much more likely to regularly support you as a brand.</p>
<p>If you have specific product types that you specialize in, you can definitely link those pages in your About Us section.</p>
<p>Therefore, an About Us page is definitely something to add to your Ecommerce SEO checklist.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1334" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/2-3.jpg" alt="Optimize Links to your Site" width="750" height="483" /></p>
<h2>Part B: On-Page SEO Tactics</h2>
<p><u><a href="https://backlinko.com/on-page-seo" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">On-page SEO</a></u> refers to the process of optimizing each page on your site, including the codes and content, to make them readable as search engine result pages. Small businesses that wish to boost their SEO rankings can and should definitely work on SEO page tactics.</p>
<p>Here’s what to focus on:</p>
<h3>1. Keywords</h3>
<p>Prepare a list of keywords you’d like to get ranked for.</p>
<p>Remember to own the keyword you choose; don’t spread your content so thinly that you don’t get ranked for anything.</p>
<p>Website crawlers are always on the lookout for content that features the right percentage of keyword-to-text ratio.</p>
<p>A keyword strategy that you should definitely take advantage of is to target long-tail keywords as much as possible.</p>
<p>This is because long-tail keywords are not only lower competition overall but also have a higher chance of bringing you conversions because of the sheer specificity with which a user is searching for something.</p>
<p>Find keywords that are relevant to your e-commerce store but don’t stuff them in meaningless prose. Search engines are a lot smarter than you think.</p>
<h3>2. Increase Your Page Speed</h3>
<p>We’ve talked about improving the loading speed of your website; now it’s time to talk about the operational speed of each page on your site.</p>
<p>Loading and buffering speeds are key indicators to Google’s algorithms on how to rank your page.</p>
<p>You can get in touch with Search Berg’s website development department to help you with this feature.</p>
<p>Having slow loading speeds definitely does not do favors for your Ecommerce SEO as an entrepreneur.</p>
<h3>3. Create Localized Landing Pages</h3>
<p>E-commerce stores can benefit from creating specific pages that target a particular kind of promotion.</p>
<p>The holiday season is specifically useful for this endeavor, since there are more searches guaranteed for particular keywords around those dates.</p>
<p>Aside from holiday events, it can also be beneficial to your site to create category pages with specific keywords.</p>
<p>An example of this could be &#8220;Women&#8217;s Soccer Shoes&#8221; or &#8220;Men&#8217;s Date Night Shoes,&#8221; depending on your keyword research.</p>
<p>The biggest keywords should definitely have a category of their own under which you can place smaller keywords that fit into the larger category.</p>
<p>If your landing page features something exciting like a giveaway or a competition, your visitors are likely to share your page on social media—earning your authentic links that will boost your SEO rank.</p>
<p>You can optimize your localized landing pages by immediately showing your visitors your most popular and most bought items within that genre.</p>
<p>This can immediately get the proverbial sales ball rolling.</p>
<p>Sales start flowing in using this technique because it gets people interested fast.</p>
<h3>4. Add Descriptions for Product Pages</h3>
<p>Promote your products by adding small description texts to entice potential buyers. Feel free to write descriptions however you want them. Here are some tips to keep in mind while writing them:</p>
<p>– Keep your description in the 300 to 700 word range.</p>
<p>– Pepper your text with internal links to other pages on your site.</p>
<p>– Add a customer review section to your product pages. Anytime someone types ‘reviews’ in the search bar can get linked to your product description pages.</p>
<p>– Communicate any and all special offers or discounts on your products.</p>
<p>When you&#8217;re writing your product descriptions and titles, make sure to create a sense of urgency.</p>
<p>This applies even to crafting your meta descriptions for your organic search results on Google and other search engines.</p>
<p>A useful <strong>pro-tip</strong> for your Ecommerce SEO checklist for 2021 to create that sense of urgency is to use a countdown clock for specific deals and prices.</p>
<p>A bonus pro-tip that a lot of ad-copy writers use is to take full advantage of powerful words in your product descriptions and titles.</p>
<p>These specific words are timeless and have been tested to psychologically prime your visitors to invest in products.</p>
<p>While there are many power words out there for you to research, <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/richardkestenbaum/2018/04/15/words-that-will-help-you-sell-and-words-that-will-hurt-you/?sh=460f1cdb2ecf" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">this</a> should help you get started.</p>
<h2>Part C: Off-Page SEO Strategies</h2>
<p>No Ecommerce SEO checklist for entrepreneurs and small business owners is complete without off-page SEO Tactics.</p>
<p>A lot of the work that goes into improving your e-commerce business’s search engine ranking happens offline. Off-page SEO is slightly different from writing a blog or optimizing your web page.</p>
<p>Here, we deal with topics like offering sponsorships for certain events, partnering with local businesses within your industry and improving your outreach with white hat link building techniques. Let’s discuss each one of them in a little more detail.</p>
<h3>1. Link Building Strategies</h3>
<p>The simplest way to build authentic links is to promote a product, service or event.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1338" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/b2-3.jpg" alt="" width="750" height="156" /></p>
<p>Insert them into all of your content, but in ways that make them look like a natural fit and not a forced block of promotional text.</p>
<p>You can also embed links into the images you upload onto your website. <u><a href="https://searchengineland.com/library/google/google-algorithm-updates" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Google’s algorithms</a></u> will take that into consideration when they’re building your SEO rank.</p>
<p>One key strategy to find places that can link to your site is to see which sites are linking to your competitors.</p>
<p>You can easily build links on forums and directories that your competitors have built links on already.</p>
<p>A key place to also find an easy backlink is to get in touch with your manufacturer and ask them to link to you as a merchant for their product on their website.</p>
<p>If they aren&#8217;t forums or submission-based directories, you can also reach out to the websites linking to your competitors and ask for a link to your site.</p>
<p>If you ship your product internationally, it can also help you to check international competitors in the countries you can ship to.</p>
<p>Then repeat the same practice for the websites that are linking to your international competitors&#8217; ecommerce websites.</p>
<h3>2. Develop Industry Partnerships</h3>
<p>This is perhaps the most important element of off-page SEO marketing. Get in touch with local industry e-commerce website owners and build a reciprocal promotional deal. Ask them to link your business on their content and offer them something in return.</p>
<p>You can even hire some already high-ranking online businesses to serve as licensed distributors for your products. From white hat link building to the chance to reach out to a larger consumer base, there are many benefits to expanding your industry partnerships.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1335" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/3-3.jpg" alt="Develop Industry Partnerships" width="750" height="483" /></p>
<h3>3. Embrace the Sponsorship Culture</h3>
<p>Getting your products sponsored by a third party website is actually easier than you think. There are many blogs that would happily promote your products. You can also opt to sponsor an event and request your partners to promote you on their website and on-ground activities. This should help put your e-commerce brand’s name on the SEO map.</p>
<h3>4. Reach Out to Bloggers</h3>
<p><u><a href="https://creativeresources.threadless.com/how-to-get-influencers-to-promote-you/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Bloggers</a></u> bring in loads of traffic and a loyal fan base with them. Get your small business’s name out there by having bloggers feature you on their blogs. You don’t even need to get anything major done for a promotion—simply ask them to link back to your home or product page and you’re surely going to have a lot of their traffic directed to your pages. Many bloggers would be willing to promote you for free; however, some will ask you for some compensation. The choice is yours.</p>
<h3>5. Start Guest Posting</h3>
<p>Backlinks are crucial for improving your SEO rank. You can use those and harness the power of online influencers to create a solid SEO marketing strategy for your small business to bloom. Ask popular blog owners or local industry groups to let you publish a guest post for them. You’ll be able to convince them better if you already have a few topics in mind. Try to work on something that benefits both of you. In most cases, your partner will agree to guest posting since the backlinks benefit their SEO rank as well.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1336" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/4-1.jpg" alt="Start Guest Posting" width="750" height="483" /></p>
<h2>Final Word</h2>
<p>Memorize these <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/ecommerce-seo.html">e-commerce SEO marketing</a> tips and strategies and maximize your gains during any major shopping season!</p>
<p>A simple, user-friendly and responsive website can help increase your visitor dwell time, while the right kinds of links and promotional pages can help boost activity on and off your page throughout the year.</p>
<p>While SEO tips for Ecommerce stores, startups, and entrepreneurs can be challenging to understand, you are already ahead of the game by taking the time to understand this blog&#8217;s points.</p>
<p>A good business person also knows when to delegate work so that they can focus on what matters most in their ecommerce business.</p>
<p>If you’re looking for <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/web-design-development-services.html">professional website design</a></u>, SEO marketing or <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/content-marketing.html">content development</a></u> strategies, feel free to <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/contact-us.html">get in touch with us</a></u> today!</p>
<p>Search Berg is one of the leading white hat SEO marketing agencies in the United States and offers some of the most affordable rates to get you started on your way to the top of search engine result pages!</p>
<p><em>Call us at 855-444-4777 to learn more about our packages!</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-2019-e-commerce-seo-checklist-for-small-business-owners-and-entrepreneurs/">The 2021 E-Commerce SEO Checklist for Small Business Owners and Entrepreneurs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/the-2019-e-commerce-seo-checklist-for-small-business-owners-and-entrepreneurs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
