<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>White Label SEO &#8211; Search Berg</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/category/white-label-seo/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 05:20:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>5 Things Our Client Dashboard Can Do For You!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-things-our-client-dashboard-can-do-for-you/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-things-our-client-dashboard-can-do-for-you/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 05:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Small Business SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White Label SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=658</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Searchberg&#8217;s client dashboard is designed exclusively for our clients, keeping all their SEO needs in mind. Through the client dashboard, our clients can easily monitor each and every aspect of their SEO marketing strategy.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-things-our-client-dashboard-can-do-for-you/">5 Things Our Client Dashboard Can Do For You!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="clear:both;"></div>
<p>Searchberg&#8217;s client dashboard is designed exclusively for our clients, keeping all their SEO needs in mind. Through the client dashboard, our clients can easily monitor each and every aspect of their SEO marketing strategy.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-659" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/searchberg-infograph-may.jpg" alt="" width="690" height="7132" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-things-our-client-dashboard-can-do-for-you/">5 Things Our Client Dashboard Can Do For You!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/5-things-our-client-dashboard-can-do-for-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How SearchBerg’s White Label SEO Services Can Help Agencies Establish Themselves and Build Their Brand</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-searchbergs-white-label-seo-services-can-help-agencies-establish-themselves-and-build-their-brand/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-searchbergs-white-label-seo-services-can-help-agencies-establish-themselves-and-build-their-brand/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 15:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[White Label SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=613</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Wondering how you can steadily deliver quality SEO to hundreds of clients simultaneously and deliver results that are in line with their expectations? In this blog post, we talk about SearchBerg’shighly transparent and effective White Label SEO services, designed from the ground up for your clients! The SEO industry today has evolved beyond just links [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-searchbergs-white-label-seo-services-can-help-agencies-establish-themselves-and-build-their-brand/">How SearchBerg’s White Label SEO Services Can Help Agencies Establish Themselves and Build Their Brand</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><em>Wondering how you can steadily deliver quality SEO to hundreds of clients simultaneously and deliver results that are in line with their expectations? In this blog post, we talk about SearchBerg’shighly transparent and effective White Label SEO services, designed from the ground up for your clients!</em></p>
<p>The SEO industry today has evolved beyond just links and rankings. It’s more about determining what constitutes a positive user experience for the visitor to a site and then building the SEO strategy around it. There is more emphasis on content; even more so on white-hat link building strategies that deliver long-term results. Then there is promotional content such as PR and videos that are most eagerly sought out by many companies. And let’s not forget social media without which no company can establish a solid online foothold in their respective niche. And once you get all those right, other elements come into play such as responsive website design, and mobile friendly usability. In other words, the requirements have changed, user demands have increased and the workload associated with delivering viable SEO solutions has literally quintupled. This can be a lot of many web design companies or SEO agencies to handle and this is where White-Label SEO services can make all the difference and give you the edge over your competitors.</p>
<h2><strong>White Label SEO Services Is the Answer</strong></h2>
<p>So what do you do when work piles up or when you are faced with client requirements you cannot specifically handle yet you still want to keep them as your clients. The answer is that you partner up! You team up with another SEO agency that offers White Label SEO Services and you forward all client work to them. All work done is then forwarded to you which you, in turn, can forward to your clients. This is the essence of White Label SEO; getting another SEO company to do all the work for you all the while you keeping and retaining your client. This approach can help you establish your company and refine your brand image.</p>
<h2><strong>Why Do You Need White Label SEO Services?</strong></h2>
<p>Let’s face it; with everything else on your plate, hiring and maintaining a proper in-house SEO team comprising of writers, SEOs, designers, developers and link builders is a big challenge and an enormous financial undertaking for any company. And then there is the challenge of putting together a proper workspace; an office with the right amenities such as furniture, phone lines, laptops, high-speed internet, Admin and HR departments and much more. This is a huge investment of both money and time and it generally takes years to eventually pay off. Signing up for White Label Services is a quick, <strong>instantaneous</strong>, solution to your worries.</p>
<h2><strong>Why SearchBerg White Label SEO</strong></h2>
<p>As a leading White Label SEO service provider, SearchBergoffersWeb and SEO agencies a highly affordable alternative to outsourcing your SEO promotions. We do it all. Content Marketing, Pay Per Click Advertising, Reputation and Brand Management, Social Marketing; you name it. SearchBerg is a complete SEO Solutions provider. We even assist in Web Design and Development projects which make us extremely versatile to handle practically any kind of project our partner-clients forward us.</p>
<p>We send you unbranded results and reports which you can modify with your name and logo and forward it to your clients. We take care of things at the backend and you get to build your brand and establish your company as a professional SEO Agency —that’s what quality White Label SEO services are all about!</p>
<h2><strong>What You Get As an Agency Client</strong></h2>
<p>The quality of Service. Transparent reporting. Prompt Communication. Weekly and monthly activity sheets and reports. These are just a few of the things you can expect from as our White Label SEO Agency client. SearchBerg has over 3000+ highly satisfied clients and has completed well over 10,000+ projects, which makes us a highly trusted name in the SEO industry.</p>
<p>Over the years, we have partnered with countless number of agencies struggling to meet client expectations and enhance their brand image in the process. Here are a few standout features we offer that keep them coming back:</p>
<ul>
<li>Highly customized White Label SEO packages right according to your needs</li>
<li>A completely content driven approach</li>
<li>Solid results that develop a base of repeat clients</li>
<li>Unparalleled opportunities to strengthen your brand image</li>
<li>A customizable dashboard (With no signs of our logos)</li>
<li>24/7 support</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Agency Dashboard</strong></h2>
<p>An integral part of White Label SEO services is having access to a single platform to meet all client needs and expectations. You need to have access to all performance indicators in a single place, telling you of the progress and what you should practically expect.</p>
<p>Our new and improved agency dashboard allows you to monitor all of your client’s progress from one platform. You no longer need to browse around pages to analyze track records of clients. With a few simple clicks, you can monitor all client activity from a single panel. The enhanced tools also allow you to add/remove or manage clients with ease. There is practically no limit to the number of clients you can configure on your dashboard.</p>
<p>Here is a quick insight into salient agency dashboard features:</p>
<ul>
<li>Real-time web traffic updates</li>
<li>Keyword rankings</li>
<li>Social media reports and updates</li>
<li>HTML, Hosting, Domain, Analytics and inbound link analysis</li>
<li>Reputation management briefs</li>
</ul>
<p>From making sure that your clients get timely responses from your end to helping you gauge how far you’ve come with our services, the agency dashboard is your one-stop shop to all that you need to know. With our White Label SEO services, every day you get another step closer to becoming the next big SEO agency.</p>
<h2><strong>What Your Clients Get</strong></h2>
<p>Comprehensive reporting and analysis, responsive communications, and a result oriented performance delivery platform are some of the most important aspects of our White Label SEO services.</p>
<p>We understand that meeting client deadlines, answering their questions and keeping them informed is part of the process to becoming a reliable SEO agency.</p>
<p>Why not give them access to a dashboard with your logo and brand name on it, to provide them with all they need to do know about their projects? We make it possible.</p>
<p>When you choose our services, here is what your clients get:</p>
<ul>
<li>A client-oriented dashboard with your logo on it</li>
<li>Original and realistically valuable content</li>
<li>Content strategies backed by in-depth market and target audience analysis</li>
<li>Comprehensive and timely reporting</li>
<li>Highly affordable pricing</li>
<li>Zero-setup fees/no obligations</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>What You Need To Do</strong></h2>
<p>Call us! You can reach us at 855 444 4777 and speak directly with our Sales department or you can fill out a form and inquire about White Label SEO through a query. We will send a detailed proposal along with work samples for your satisfaction. Our services have helped a significant number of SEO agencies gain a head start and pave the path to a successful digital future.</p>
<p>Take the first step towards establishing your company’s online foothold in the Digital Marketing arena;Become a White Label Partner with SearchBerg and start working on strengthening your brand and increasing your clientele.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-searchbergs-white-label-seo-services-can-help-agencies-establish-themselves-and-build-their-brand/">How SearchBerg’s White Label SEO Services Can Help Agencies Establish Themselves and Build Their Brand</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-searchbergs-white-label-seo-services-can-help-agencies-establish-themselves-and-build-their-brand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SearchBerg Completes 10,000 Projects!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/searchberg-completes-10000-projects/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/searchberg-completes-10000-projects/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 09:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Small Business SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White Label SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=608</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We, at SearchBerg, have some great news to share with our fans, followers and clients. This month, SearchBerg successfully completed 10,000 projects! We couldn’t be happier on reaching this monumental achievement. This is a significant milestone for us. It says a lot about how far SearchBerg has come as a SEO services provider not just [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/searchberg-completes-10000-projects/">SearchBerg Completes 10,000 Projects!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We, at SearchBerg, have some great news to share with our fans, followers and clients.</p>
<p>This month, SearchBerg successfully completed <strong>10,000 projects</strong>! We couldn’t be happier on reaching this monumental achievement. This is a significant milestone for us. It says a lot about how far SearchBerg has come as a SEO services provider not just in the United States but globally, around the world.</p>
<p>We believe that the ultimate measure of any SEO company is determined by the breadth of the <strong><u>results</u></strong> they deliver. And that is what we have worked so hard to achieve for our clients. Quality of service matters; transparent reporting is a must. Both are part of our business model. Yet at the end of the day, it is the <em><u>results</u></em> that essentially decide whether a client should continue with their SEO campaign. Our results-driven, white-hat SEO strategies are the reason why SearchBerg enjoys a high client retention ratio. And successfully completing 10,000 projects is proof that our strategies work and that they deliver.</p>
<p>From humble beginnings on E-lance in 2010 to 10,000 projects in 2016, it has been a long journey for SearchBerg with ups and downs along the way. We learned from our mistakes and we amplified what clients liked about our work. Today, SearchBerg is a complete SEO services provider, offering not just SEO, but also other financially lucrative online marketing services such as Paid Advertising (PPC), Social Media Marketing, Content Marketing and Brand Management.</p>
<p>We want to take this opportunity to thank everyone who supported us in our journey to 10,000. A very sincerely thank all our clients all over the world, in Europe, Asia, and the Continental US, who stayed with us through thick and thin. Their positive feedback and even criticism, made us the company we are today.</p>
<p>Thank you once again, and we look forward to reaching more milestones in the coming months!</p>
<p>Team SearchBerg</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/searchberg-completes-10000-projects/">SearchBerg Completes 10,000 Projects!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/searchberg-completes-10000-projects/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Link Building Services for 2016 and Beyond!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/link-building-services-for-2016-and-beyond/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/link-building-services-for-2016-and-beyond/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 12:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[White Label SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Search Engine Optimization is part science; part art. The science part is fairly straightforward. It is also the part that is easier for website SEO experts to control and master. Things like creating original, link-worthy, viral content;conforming to Google guidelines; practicing white-hat link building techniques; focusing on relevancy and on providing a positive user experience [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/link-building-services-for-2016-and-beyond/">Link Building Services for 2016 and Beyond!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Search Engine Optimization is part science; part art. The science part is fairly straightforward. It is also the part that is easier for <strong>website SEO experts</strong> to control and master. Things like creating original, link-worthy, viral content;conforming to Google guidelines; practicing white-hat link building techniques; focusing on relevancy and on providing a positive user experience and so on. Elements of On-page optimization are all part of science.</p>
<p><strong>Off-page optimization is the art.</strong></p>
<p>This part is not so straightforward; not so easy to master and it eventually comes down to how creative the SEO is. It is also the part that <u>never ends</u> until unless you are ranking #1 for every single keyword you are targeting.This part is tough, but the link building possibilities are also endless which is why Off-page Optimization will be the topic of today’s post as we focus on the art of building links. We highlight some very popular, useful and result-driven link building services that should be a top priority for all businesses seeking to enhance online presence and visibility in 2016 and beyond!</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Check out our infographic on the<strong> <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/impact-of-seo-services-on-small-businesses/">Impact of SEO Services on Small Businesses</a>.</strong></p>
<h3><strong>Content Marketing</strong></h3>
<p>After Panda and Penguin, Content has come under a whole new spotlight. There are rewards for investing in quality and presentation. Writing a lengthy post on a good topic is great. But if that post is not supplemented with proper images, graphics, statistics or any type of relevant visual material, your content will only look like random boring text.</p>
<p>Viewer intent is paramount in content marketing. Figuring out what people are searching for is one thing. Presenting it is another. The first part involves proper research to come up with list of topics that would make great articles pieces or blog posts. The other part is writing them well and that entails asking questions. Should it be an opinion piece or a stat’s based informative piece? Will it include stats or reference to other websites supplementing the point being made in the post?</p>
<p>Having a blog on your website is a huge plus. For some industries, it is actually required in order to portray a professional and strong brand image. Blogs are great way to get your website indexed frequently. Thus content creation is a great link building strategy to rank higher for target keywords.</p>
<h3><strong>Guest Posts</strong></h3>
<p>Matt Cutts made headlines last year when he specifically stated, “<a href="https://www.mattcutts.com/blog/guest-blogging/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Stick a fork in it, Guest Posts are done!</a>” However the fact of the matter is that guest posts remain a popular choice among who people who want to build “natural, relevant” links to their website. That particular comment from Matt Cutts was more in response to people abusing the guest post strategy by submitting lengthy irrelevant, low quality content on sites that would literally accept any content for a backlink without checking for authenticity, relevancy, and quality.</p>
<p>The truth is that authority sites that focus on their respective areas of expertise are enjoying a higher standing in Google. They are top ranked for their brand, their keywords and their traffic is increasing as their readership increases. Take websites like Search Engine Land and Moz for example. They specialize in content specifically written for Search Engine Optimization, PPC, and all matters associated with digital marketing.They are regarded as an <u>authority sites</u>. People from all over the world contribute via guest post at these forums every day and the website continues to enjoy high rankings.</p>
<p>Bottom line,writing <u>quality guest post</u> is still a great link building strategy. It yields a high value link from an authority sites and overtime creates a mental perception of authority, and leadership among the target audience. Businesses should seriously look into exploring this option for their SEO.</p>
<h3><strong>Social Media Platforms</strong></h3>
<p>The more reachable you are online, the more rewarding the user experience and thus more traffic, more domain authority and more rankings. There was a time when social media used to be a hip thing to do. Now it is a must-do thing. Platforms like Facebook, Twitter and Google+ are some of the top options to explore. However depending on your industry, there are other platforms where you can capitalize on as well such as Instagram and Pinterest. These are great platforms to sport your merchandise or showcase your services.</p>
<p>And let’s not forget Youtube and Vimeo. People respond to visuals, and videos are a great way to get your message across to your target audience. People would rather watch a one minute video than read through lengthy dull text. And besides, it is a proven fact that short version videos tend to have a bigger, longer lasting impact on viewers than text. Creating videos of your business is an excellent way to build your brand, interact with clients, and get a reliable backlink in the process.</p>
<p>These are some popular link building services that you can surely add to your digital marketing strategy for 2016. The main thing to take from this post is that SEO is still alive and in demand. It has taken more of a content-centric form than ever but there are still many ways to build authority links rather than directly submissions. Try the above mentioned strategies and see how the results pan out for your website.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/link-building-services-for-2016-and-beyond/">Link Building Services for 2016 and Beyond!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/link-building-services-for-2016-and-beyond/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2015’s Most Noteworthy SEO Updates From Google, And How They Matter In 2016</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/2015s-most-noteworthy-seo-updates-from-google-and-how-they-matter-in-2016/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/2015s-most-noteworthy-seo-updates-from-google-and-how-they-matter-in-2016/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 14:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Small Business SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White Label SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=548</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>2015 was a big year for Search because many game changing events took place that redefined how websites interact with their customers and end-users. In today’s post, we will look at some of these events and why they will be even more important going into 2016. Google’s approach is very methodical when it comes to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/2015s-most-noteworthy-seo-updates-from-google-and-how-they-matter-in-2016/">2015’s Most Noteworthy SEO Updates From Google, And How They Matter In 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>2015 was a big year for Search because many game changing events took place that redefined how websites interact with their customers and end-users. In today’s post, we will look at some of these events and why they will be even more important going into 2016.</p>
<p>Google’s approach is very methodical when it comes to changes to its ranking algorithm. Every move it makes has a reason and a long term effect behind it. Mentioned below are twomost important events of 2015 that redesigned how companies went about SEO for their business.</p>
<p><strong>The Mobilegeddon Update</strong></p>
<p>With the continuing rise of mobile internet users, many companies were quick to evolve accordingly with the new paradigm shift and immediately designed a mobile friendly version of their website in addition to the standard one. Others ignored it and instead focused solely on traditional SEO. Google’s Mobile Friendly update changed all that.</p>
<p>On April 22, 2015, Google announced that it will rank mobile search results differently for sites that are mobile friendly. Before this update, mobile rankings for keywords were the same as the organic rankings; The only benefit of having a mobile website was having one additional portal to display your website and having some form of mobile presence. With this update Google started rewarding sites that for having mobile presence and many others were forced to create a mobile friendly version in order to capitalize on the mobile traffic.</p>
<p>Having a mobile friendly version is no longer an option today. It is mandatory. Most clients who initiate SEO for their website start things off with a mobile friendly version first so that the proper foundation for SEO is set in place before the actual work can begin. It is a smart move that pays for itself in the coming month.</p>
<p><strong>Panda 4.2 Update</strong></p>
<p>Panda stunned everyone when it went live in 2011. So many top rankings websites disappeared completely. While many unknowns rose to the top; all in a matter of hours for most websites. The idea behind Panda was to eliminate the negative user experience; encourage white-hat <a href="http://www.searchberg.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>SEO services</strong></a> and set an example for companies who opt for shady link building to gain quick rankings or traffic.</p>
<p>Google has been rolling out different versions of Panda ever since 2011. Last year in July, 2015 Panda 4.2 was rolled out. Though regarded more of a refresh rather than an update, Panda 4.2 affected 2 to 3% of overall queries and didn’t cause ripples like the first update. This is because many websites have completely abandoned black hat SEO and are opting for long term natural SEO for their website. All Panda update are essentially a re-implementation of the same processes that were introduced in the original Panda update.</p>
<p>Moving on to 2016, the need for natural SEO, relevant link building, and original content will only continue to grow more and more importantly. With a majority of the SEO strategy being content driven, being mindful of Panda will continue to be a top SEO priority. That means less content scrapping and more original content development, less spammy links and more relative authoritative links; less posting on low quality sites and more interaction on relevant high quality websites.</p>
<p><strong>RankBrain</strong></p>
<p>Google made a major announcement regarding their ranking algorithm in October 2015. This was a very unusual move by Google as the company rarely make major announcements, especially when it comes to the ranking algorithm.</p>
<p>The update called RankBrain revealed that machine learning will become a part of the Google ranking algorithm. This is a process where a computer teaches itself rather than receiving input from humans or through detailed programming. It is Artificial Intelligence at its peak. RankBrain recognizes patterns between unconnected search terms in order to understand how they are actually similar to one another. In this case, RankBrainwould be used to sort through the billions of pages in the Google Index against the 7 billion daily Google searches and display the best possible results. For businesses that means quality content will always win and natural, long term SEO strategies will always outlast, grey-hat or black hat techniques. Rightfully so, The RankBrainis regarded as an extension to the Google Hummingbird, another update from the previous year.</p>
<p>So what were the take home lessons of 2015?</p>
<ul>
<li>Have a mobile friendly website ready</li>
<li>Only follow white-hate SEO that is spearheaded by original, high quality, relevant content</li>
<li>RankBrain will play a crucial role in refining search queries</li>
</ul>
<p>As we start 2016, these points should be at the top of the list for any business that is serious about capturing the only market and more importantly, sustaining it for the long run so that they can build upon it and increased their online presence and visibility. We at SearchBerg Labs, would surely recommend that all businesses add these two approaches in their online business model if they are to succeed commercially in 2016.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/2015s-most-noteworthy-seo-updates-from-google-and-how-they-matter-in-2016/">2015’s Most Noteworthy SEO Updates From Google, And How They Matter In 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/2015s-most-noteworthy-seo-updates-from-google-and-how-they-matter-in-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get 2016 Off To A Blazing Start!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/get-2016-off-to-a-blazing-start/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/get-2016-off-to-a-blazing-start/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 15:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[White Label SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[infographics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hey there digital marketers, don’t let your content slip up this year. We tell you the top priorities for all content specialists! Invest some time and energy into these 4 resolutions and don’t listen to the cynics. Remember: People who make resolutions are 10 times more likely to achieve their goals than people who don’t [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/get-2016-off-to-a-blazing-start/">Get 2016 Off To A Blazing Start!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey there digital marketers, don’t let your content slip up this year. We tell you the top priorities for all content specialists! Invest some time and energy into these 4 resolutions and don’t listen to the cynics. Remember: People who make resolutions are 10 times more likely to achieve their goals than people who don’t bother with them.</p>
<p>What do you say? Let’s hit the ground running and be a better digital marketer in 2016!</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-541" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/SB-Blog-Graphic.jpg" alt="SB Blog Graphic" width="800" height="1200" /></p>
<style>
.post-540 .vw-featured-image {display:none;}
</style>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/get-2016-off-to-a-blazing-start/">Get 2016 Off To A Blazing Start!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/get-2016-off-to-a-blazing-start/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Search Berg.com &#8211; Offering SEO Services in Austin</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/searchberg-com-offering-seo-services-in-austin/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/searchberg-com-offering-seo-services-in-austin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 07:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[White Label SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We hope you have got the whole picture of why Search Berg is one of the best Austin SEO companies and how you can avail our services to dominate the local Austin SERPs with your business keywords.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/searchberg-com-offering-seo-services-in-austin/">Search Berg.com &#8211; Offering SEO Services in Austin</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-500 size-full" src="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/searchberg.png" alt="searchberg" width="1400" height="4450" /></p>
<p>We hope you have got the whole picture of why Search Berg is one of the best <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/seo-austin.html">Austin SEO companies</a> and how you can avail our services to dominate the local Austin SERPs with your business keywords.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/searchberg-com-offering-seo-services-in-austin/">Search Berg.com &#8211; Offering SEO Services in Austin</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/searchberg-com-offering-seo-services-in-austin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Insane Social Media Tips to Your Audience&#8217;s Heart!</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/insane-social-media-tips-to-your-audiences-heart/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/insane-social-media-tips-to-your-audiences-heart/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 13:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[White Label SEO]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=496</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Social media offers today’s businesses never-before-seen-opportunities to engage their audience. But cashing on this huge potential can be a daunting task. Fresh, high quality, relevant and relatable content is the key to social media marketing success. And that is why running an SMM campaign is the biggest challenge for today’s businesses. You will have to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/insane-social-media-tips-to-your-audiences-heart/">Insane Social Media Tips to Your Audience&#8217;s Heart!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Social media offers today’s businesses never-before-seen-opportunities to engage their audience. But cashing on this huge potential can be a daunting task.</p>
<p>Fresh, high quality, relevant and relatable content is the key to social media marketing success. And that is why running an <a href="http://www.searchberg.com/blog/effective-social-media-management-for-enhanced-seo-results/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SMM campaign</a> is the biggest challenge for today’s businesses. You will have to keep thinking up new ideas, always be on your toes about responding to comments and queries, and also continue to offer value to your audience. Your content offerings have to be representative of your uniqueness and be compelling to the core.</p>
<h2>Rise Above All The Noise, Statistics and Misinformation!</h2>
<p>Social media is new and therefore scary, and the abundance of SMM gurus out there makes it feel like you will need specialized help to make it through your SMM experience unscathed. We beg to differ. Just like all your organization’s other functions, you will be better off by getting to know your SMM more thoroughly.</p>
<p>Here we bring you some good, old-fashioned advice and tactics that rise above the wild claims and statistics, offering you evergreen guidance on acing social media. We’ll start with the very basics and then cover some advanced pointers to ensure a more holistic social media experience for your audience.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;">Tried-And-Tested Best Practices for Building and Retaining an Audience on Social Media</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Know Your Audience</strong><br />
Profiling your target market makes it easier to agree on a tone of voice and the type of content your audience will appreciate. Also invest some time and money in learning their social media proclivities and content consumption habits. Now you know exactly who you are trying to attract, and not just posting for a faceless mass, hoping and shooting in the dark.</li>
<li><strong>Be Human</strong><br />
Social media is all about the ‘social’. So try your best to keep your posts, tweets and shares as interactive as possible. When your audience looks your brand up, they aren’t exactly expecting to see tons of research and content. What they are really searching for is a clue to your brand’s personality online. So be a little selective of your messages and let your brand boast customer service and satisfaction.</li>
<li><strong>Be Trustworthy</strong><br />
People trust, and respect content that comes along with the right references. For example, if you are mentioning health-related facts, you will do good to back it up with authentic references. Information from qualified doctors will always take precedence over that from drug or insurance companies or even other patients. Social media gives you the power to command trust, so use it wisely.</li>
<li><strong>Pick Your Social Platform Wisely</strong><br />
Pinterest, YouTube, Instagram, Facebook, Twitter and many others. If you are a small business, it is a good idea to stick to only two of those, at least for the first few months. Start by creating a strong presence on platforms that your audience most associates with. Find out which social media sites your competitors are most active on. Observe them and fire up your own account once you’re ready.</li>
<li><strong>Social Is Not a Hard Sell</strong><br />
We can’t stress this point enough. Social channels are not the place for you to force your brand message. It is where you inform, educate and interact, so leave the overly promotional copy for your website and product landing pages. We know how remarkable your product/service is, but saying it out loud every time you share something is a surefire way of losing followers. Make it a philosophy to share more and sell less… a lot less.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing Goes Beyond 9-5</strong><br />
Success on social media is a 24/7 pursuit. The better your profiling, the surer you’ll be of when your audience comes online. Social media management tools like HootSuite can let you schedule posts in advance and update your pages according to your SMM plan. Be active different times in a day just so you can cast a wider net, and catch as much attention as possible.</li>
<li><strong>Be Ready To Pay and Play</strong><br />
While posting on social media is pretty much free, generic posts by themselves only reach about 16% followers. And if that figure is unacceptable for you, then you can pay to promote your page and certifiably expand the reach of your posts.</li>
</ol>
<p>You may also choose to invest in social media marketing software, like the one mentioned earlier i.e. HootSuite. These smart little programs can help share your content across social media, as and when you want them to.</p>
<h2>Are You Ready To Put Social Media To Work For You?</h2>
<p>Give some thought to your goals and the value they bring your followers. Adapt an approach that’s completely in sync with what your audience values. Then keep an eye on it and tweak your SMM strategy as and when needed to ensure that it yields the results you need. Social media can help increase your reach and grow your prospective clientele easily and swiftly.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/insane-social-media-tips-to-your-audiences-heart/">Insane Social Media Tips to Your Audience&#8217;s Heart!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/insane-social-media-tips-to-your-audiences-heart/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
