<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Facebook Marketing &#8211; Search Berg</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/category/facebook-marketing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 09:42:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to Get More Likes on Facebook in 2020</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-likes-on-facebook-in-2020/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-likes-on-facebook-in-2020/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Tylor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 09:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Facebook Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=2187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Contents Why Do Facebook Likes Matter? 13 Ways to Get More Facebook Likes Make Your Facebook Page Super Easy to Find! Share Engaging, Data-Driven Content Make Sure Your Facebook Profile Stands Out Shift Your Focus to Shareability Get to Know the Best Posting Times Leverage the 80/20 Rule Get Creative With Your Calls-to-Action (CTAs) Giveaways [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-likes-on-facebook-in-2020/">How to Get More Likes on Facebook in 2020</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Contents</h2>
<p><a href="#_Toc52223224">Why Do Facebook Likes Matter?</a></p>
<p><a href="#_Toc52223225">13 Ways to Get More Facebook Likes</a></p>
<ol>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223226"> Make Your Facebook Page Super Easy to Find!</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223227"> Share Engaging, Data-Driven Content</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223228"> Make Sure Your Facebook Profile Stands Out</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223229"> Shift Your Focus to Shareability</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223230"> Get to Know the Best Posting Times</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223231"> Leverage the 80/20 Rule</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223232"> Get Creative With Your Calls-to-Action (CTAs)</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223233"> Giveaways and Contests Are a Big Yes!</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223234"> Facebook Ads: Get 1000+ likes on Facebook</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223235"> Add Social Media Links to Your Website and Blog</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223236"> Engage, Engage, Engage!</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223237"> Create a Customer Lookalike Audience</a></li>
<li><a href="#_Toc52223238"> Create More Image and Video Content </a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#_Toc52223239">Final Thoughts on How to Get More Likes and Followers on Facebook Posts! </a></p>
<p>Want to increase likes on Facebook?</p>
<p>Since its inception in 2004, Facebook has continued to grow exponentially and dominate the digital marketing landscape. With <strong><u>over 2.7 billion monthly users</u></strong>, the powerful platform is the world’s third-most visited website.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/264810/number-of-monthly-active-facebook-users-worldwide/" rel="nofollow"><img class="aligncenter" style="width: 100%; height: auto !important; max-width: 1000px; -ms-interpolation-mode: bicubic;" src="https://www.statista.com/graphic/1/264810/number-of-monthly-active-facebook-users-worldwide.jpg" alt="Statistic: Number of monthly active Facebook users worldwide as of 2nd quarter 2020 (in millions) | Statista" /></a><br />
Find more statistics at <a href="https://www.statista.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Statista</a></p>
<p>In fact, a whopping <strong><u>74% of Americans</u></strong> use the social networking site regularly. And <strong><u>over 90 million small businesses</u></strong> use Facebook to increase their reach, get their phones ringing, and bag impressive sales.</p>
<p>While there’s a lot that goes into using Facebook to your advantage, there’s one key feature that stands out: Facebook likes.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc52223224"></a>Why Do Facebook Likes Matter?</h2>
<p>We won’t beat around the bush: Facebook’s organic reach has been on the decline for a few years now.</p>
<p>It’s a bitter pill to swallow. And while we’d love nothing more than to create a Facebook page and watch the dough roll in, that’s not quite how things work anymore. As the competition becomes more cut-throat, resting on your laurels isn’t an option.</p>
<p>If you’re looking to maximize reach and conversions, you need to set yourself apart from the crowd.</p>
<p>This is where Facebook steps in. As you get more likes on your Facebook page, posts, comments, and activity, you catch the eye of the sole entity that matters most here: <strong><u>the Facebook algorithm</u></strong>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2189 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog1-1.jpg" alt="Facebook Algorithmn" width="700" height="480" /></p>
<p>Since the popularity of your posts is a key <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-8-google-ranking-factors-for-2020/">ranking signal</a>, you’ll manage to break into your target audience’s feed and earn more conversions.</p>
<p>In short, as you get more likes on Facebook, your business will become more visible on the mega platform. The outcome? Impressive sales and sustained business growth in the long run.</p>
<p>In this post, we wanted to address top strategies and tips on how to increase likes on Facebook in 2020.</p>
<h2 style="text-align: center;"><a name="_Toc52223225"></a>13 Ways to Get More Facebook Likes</h2>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223226"></a>1. Make Your Facebook Page Super Easy to Find!</h3>
<p>We’re going to start off with the easy stuff: people cannot find you if you’re not easy to find! And we cannot emphasize this enough!</p>
<ul>
<li>Choose a simple Facebook page name. Don’t add unnecessary keywords.</li>
<li>How to get more likes on your page using your blog? Add Facebook follow and Like buttons to your website or blog. This can direct traffic to your Facebook page.</li>
<li>Embed a FB post on your website</li>
<li>Promote your page on other channels like LinkedIn, YouTube, Twitter, and vice-versa.</li>
<li>Create a promotional video promoting your Facebook page</li>
</ul>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223227"></a>2. Share Engaging, Data-Driven Content</h3>
<p>Take a quick guess at how many images are uploaded on Facebook every day.</p>
<p>100 million? Far off.</p>
<p>200 million? Nope.</p>
<p>300 million? You’re in the right ballpark.</p>
<p><strong><u>350 million</u></strong>, to be precise.</p>
<p>And this figure only covers image-based posts. You can only imagine how many text-based posts are shared on the mega platform each day!</p>
<p>In short, there is an abundance of content on Facebook. If your posts are unengaging and lack value, they’ll get a couple of likes at best.</p>
<p><em>“How do I get more likes on my Facebook posts?” Or “how to get more likes on my Facebook business page?”</em></p>
<p>You think outside the box. Sharing <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-content-driven-seo-is-the-ultimate-digital-marketing-strategy-for-2020/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">value-added, data-driven, and proven content</a> is a great way to compel your target audience to engage with your posts.</p>
<p>Instead of adopting a generic Facebook content marketing approach, <strong><u>pull out all the stops</u></strong>.</p>
<p>Actively share value-added blogs, engaging infographics, conversion-focused videos, and other types of high-quality content to prompt action. You don’t necessarily have to include media in your posts each time; you can also share text-based posts so long as they’re brimming with value.</p>
<p>Once you put your strategy to the test, keep a close eye on which posts are performing better than the others. This is a great way to replicate strategies that generate great results.</p>
<p>For instance, you’ll notice that Starbucks periodically shares inspiring stories from their customers.</p>
<p>Here’s a glimpse:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FStarbucks%2Fposts%2F10158353973898057&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=735&amp;appId" width="552" height="735" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FStarbucks%2Fposts%2F10158385056388057&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=716&amp;appId" width="552" height="716" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></p>
<p>If you take a closer look at post engagement, you’ll notice that each post has garnered 10K and 6.5K likes respectively. In fact, the posts have also earned a substantial number of comments and shares.</p>
<p>This is a masterclass in reusing the same strategy because of impressive results.</p>
<p>If certain posts outperform others, don’t consider it an accomplishment and call it a day. Instead, consider it an accomplishment and actively work towards incorporating similar themes into upcoming posts to maintain high levels of engagement.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223228"></a>3. Make Sure Your Facebook Profile Stands Out</h3>
<p>While your Facebook posts may be engaging, if you’ve let your Facebook page collect dust over the years, you may want to step back and re-strategize.</p>
<p>An off-putting or outdated Facebook page is a recipe for disaster. As potential customers visit your page to engage with more posts, they’re very likely to bounce if your cover photo doesn’t look the part or your profile photo is pixelated.</p>
<p>Over time, you may lose likes and notice a drop in conversions.</p>
<p>Here’s how you can revamp your Facebook page.</p>
<p>Start by focusing on the images. Engage customers by striking the perfect aesthetic balance between your profile photo and cover photo. We suggest keeping the profile photo simple, clean, and classic while leaving ample room for experimentation with your cover photo.</p>
<p>HP’s Facebook page is the embodiment of this delicate ratio:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2190 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog.png" alt="HP" width="931" height="479" /></p>
<p>If you keep up with their page, you’ll notice that they periodically change their cover photo to ensure relevance. This is a great way to add a unique touch of novelty to your page to prompt more likes.</p>
<p>Use high-quality, creative, and aesthetically pleasing images to do the trick.</p>
<p>Once you’ve taken care of the images, shift your focus to the “About” section. Keep it concise and engaging. Moreover, fill out each section to ensure comprehensiveness.</p>
<p>Wayfair’s succinct and feel-good “About” section checks off all the boxes:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2191" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-1.png" alt="about" width="349" height="496" /></p>
<p>As you get more likes on your Facebook page, your posts will reach a wide demographic. Not only will you notice a boost in revenue, but your brand identity will also crystallize over time.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style1">
<div class="inner">
<h3>Is your Facebook page lacking the wow factor?<br />
Our Facebook marketing experts can help!</h3>
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/facebook-advertising/" rel="nofollow">Click here to revamp and optimize your page!</a></p>
</div>
</div>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223229"></a>4. Shift Your Focus to Shareability</h3>
<p><em>“How can I increase my Facebook likes automatically?”</em></p>
<p>If you’ve found yourself pondering this question, you’re one of the millions of business owners and marketers who are looking to get the ball rolling without going to great lengths.</p>
<p>Well, there <em>is</em> a way to go about this.</p>
<p>It’s called <strong>shareability</strong></p>
<div class="pro-tip">
<div class="left">
<h3>When it comes to maximizing Facebook likes,</h3>
<p>creating shareable content is your best bet. If your post resonates with your followers, they’re more likely to share it on their timeline or send it to their friends/family.</p>
</div>
<div class="right"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2217" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/cta-icon1.png" alt="" width="143" height="137" /></div>
</div>
<p>This is equivalent to winning the lottery in the world of digital marketing. In short, your post has a fair shot at going viral.</p>
<p><a href="https://buzzsumo.com/blog/facebook-engagement-guide/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">According to Buzzsumo</a>, the most viral Facebook posts of 2017 were:</p>
<ul>
<li>Practical tips and hacks</li>
<li>Inspiring content</li>
<li>Food and recipes posts</li>
<li>Cute animals</li>
<li>Music videos</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>As the shares and likes continue to snowball, your follower count and sales will go up.</p>
<p>Let’s get back to the crux of the argument: <em>how do you create shareable content</em>?</p>
<p>It’s simple. <strong><u>You focus on trends</u></strong>.</p>
<p>One of the most common themes among all viral Facebook posts is relevance. They’re carefully formulated with the ongoing landscape in mind.</p>
<p>From using the right pop culture references to incorporating trending holidays, viral posts rely on relevance to prompt clicks and shares.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Ftarget%2Fposts%2F10158914913043120&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=590&amp;appId" width="552" height="590" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" align="center"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></p>
<p>Target’s recent Fall-friendly Facebook posts pack the power of relevance in abundance: they’re creative, unique, and a visual treat.</p>
<p>If you take a quick look at the comments, you’ll notice that people have actively interacted with the post and shared their own variations of fall-friendly décor.</p>
<p>With over 15K likes and 4.6K shares, the post checks off all the boxes of high-quality, shareable, and out-of-the-box content.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223230"></a>5. Get to Know the Best Posting Times</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2194 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog1-2.jpg" alt="The best time to post on Facebook" width="701" height="451" /></p>
<p>You’ve probably heard about the importance of posting at the right time numerous times.</p>
<p>You’ve <em>also</em> probably rolled your eyes and never given it another thought because of how preposterous it sounds.</p>
<p>We’ll be the first ones to admit that it doesn’t sound like something that can substantially impact the number of Facebook likes your posts get. However, once you scratch the surface, you quickly realize that it’s a game changer. In fact, that would be an understatement.</p>
<p>Depending on your business, your target audience is most likely active on Facebook during certain hours of the day. Delve deep into your demographics to determine peak activity hours.</p>
<p>While optimal posting times largely vary, posting between <strong><u>12 to 3 pm on weekdays</u></strong> and <strong><u>12 to 1 pm on weekends</u></strong> will yield great results if you’re new to this.</p>
<p>Of course, calibrate and recalibrate posting times until you find the perfect mix that yields optimal likes.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223231"></a>6. Leverage the 80/20 Rule</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-2195 size-full" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-4.png" alt="The type of content to post on Facebook" width="700" height="480" /></p>
<p>Sure, posting content that largely revolves around your brand may sound tempting. In fact, it may also sound like the only option you have.</p>
<p>However, excessive branding doesn’t go down too well with most audiences.</p>
<p>If your posts are solely centered on your products/services, sales, special offers, and the like, your customers may get bored. Instead, use the 80/20 rule to maintain a balance and prompt more likes.</p>
<p>80% of your posts should comprise brand-related content whereas the remaining 20% should feature your customers, relevant industry updates, etc.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223232"></a>7. Get Creative With Your Calls-to-Action (CTAs)</h3>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fwatch%2F%3Fv%3D552249608923213&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=734&amp;height=502&amp;appId" width="734" height="502" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"><span data-mce-type="bookmark" style="display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;" class="mce_SELRES_start">﻿</span></iframe></p>
<p>Using the same ol’ CTAs is a surefire way to watch your Facebook likes take a dip. Not only will they fail to prompt action, but the lack of creativity will also keep you from maximizing audience engagement.</p>
<p>Master the art of creating <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbescoachescouncil/2018/12/26/why-your-call-to-action-needs-to-be-clear-and-compelling/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">compelling, action-oriented, and concise CTAs</a> that carry a hint of urgency.</p>
<p>Instead of opting for a generic “Call us for more info,” think outside the box.</p>
<p>“Ready to get piping hot pizza delivered to your home? Our speedy delivery services are a call away!” is <em>twice</em> as engaging and actionable.</p>
<p>Let your creative juices run wild!</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223233"></a>8. Giveaways and Contests Are a Big Yes!</h3>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/post.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FHelloFreshus%2Fphotos%2Fa.499635223397667%2F2361316220562882%2F&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=552&amp;height=659&amp;appId" width="552" height="659" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>Who doesn’t love a good giveaway/contest? While there may be a couple naysayers, surprises are <em>a big hit</em> on Facebook.</p>
<p>Engage and convert your audience by posting exciting giveaways and contests.</p>
<p>You can offer your products/services, special discounts, or customized packages.</p>
<div class="pro-tip">
<div class="left">
<h3>As part of the rules,</h3>
<p>ask your audience to follow your page, like that particular post, like the last five posts on your page, and tag 3–5 friends.</p>
</div>
<div class="right"><img loading="lazy" class="alignright size-full wp-image-2218" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/cta-icon2.png" alt="" width="168" height="113" /></div>
</div>
<p>Of course, you can get creative with the rules and add/remove as you’d like. However, don’t sideline the importance of requesting likes.</p>
<p>We also suggest getting creative with the countless features on Facebook. From posting polls to engaging your audience with Facebook Live, experiment with different elements to drive more likes and get your page seen by more people.</p>
<p>If you’re willing to go the extra mile, share links to scheduled Facebook Live sessions or exclusive Facebook giveaways on other social media pages, including Twitter, Instagram, Pinterest, Snapchat, etc. This is a great way to generate more buzz around your products/services, major brand events, or anything else that you’d like to showcase!</p>
<p>Ultimately, these strategies will help you get more likes on your Facebook page and increase followers.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223234"></a>9. Facebook Ads: Get 1000+ likes on Facebook</h3>
<p>An average Facebook user clicks on an astounding <strong><u>11 ads per month</u></strong>. When it comes to maximizing Facebook likes, leveraging Facebook ads is your best bet.</p>
<p>As Facebook ads continue to grow in popularity, more brands are jumping on the bandwagon to maximize reach and engagement, get 1000+ likes on Facebook, and establish a winning brand identity.</p>
<p>Here’s how you can kick things off. Consult <strong><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/facebook-advertising/">Facebook marketing experts</a></strong> to determine the right ads for your business. Depending on your business model, demographic, and project scope, they’ll help you choose between video ads, photo ads, slideshow ads, canvas ads, carousel ads, and dynamic product/service ads.</p>
<p>They’ll also optimize your ad schedule and ad placement to ensure maximum engagement and yield impressive results.</p>
<p>Facebook marketing specialists are adept at A/B testing your ideas to determine what works best and maximize conversion. From monitoring and analyzing Facebook Insights to overseeing each aspect of your business page, they’ll make sure you get more likes on Facebook and consistently engage a wide audience.</p>
<div class="blog-cta style1">
<div class="inner">
<h3>Want more likes on your Facebook page and posts? We can make it happen!</h3>
<p><a class="btn" href="https://www.searchberg.com/facebook-advertising/">Click here to sign up</a></p>
<p>for our Facebook advertising services starting from $199!</p>
</div>
</div>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223235"></a>10. Add Social Media Links to Your Website and Blog</h3>
<p>Have a great website? Great! A Facebook page? Even better! But are you linking the two?</p>
<p>Most business owners forget to add their social media links on their website. These links could be in your header, footer or in the sidebar, depending on your website’s theme.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2198" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-7-1024x541.png" alt="Adding Social Media Links to Your Website" width="1024" height="541" /></p>
<p>Another great recommendation is to add your social sharing icons—like Facebook follow and Like buttons—on your blog posts. This increases the shareability of your content.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2199" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-8-1024x544.png" alt="Adding Social Media Links to Your Blog Posts" width="1024" height="544" /></p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223236"></a>11. Engage, Engage, Engage!</h3>
<p>Some of the biggest brands on Facebook don’t engage with their followers. With thousands of tags, mentions, posts, it’s hard to keep up. However, smaller businesses can really engage with the community.</p>
<p>It’s not just about replying about delivery times and work hours; CONNECT! Build relationships. It humanizes your brand. It makes the interaction memorable. And it engages.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2200" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-9-1024x605.png" alt="Engaging with followers on Facebook" width="1024" height="605" /></p>
<p>Don’t stop here; invest in community participation by joining relevant Facebook groups and commenting on topics that are in line with your products and services or business values.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223237"></a>12. Create a Customer Lookalike Audience</h3>
<p>According to Facebook for Businesses,</p>
<p>A Lookalike Audience is a way to reach new people who are likely to be interested in your business because they&#8217;re similar to your best existing customers.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2201" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/blog-10.png" alt="Create a Customer Lookalike Audience" width="778" height="344" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Source: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/learn/lessons/using-ads-manager-to-create-custom-lookalike-audiences?ref=ahc_lwe" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Facebook Business</a></strong></p>
<p>Using the list of people who already follow you, Facebook will analyze data and identify similarities in interests, demographics, etc., and then list an audience that shares these characteristics for targeted Facebook advertising.</p>
<h3><a name="_Toc52223238"></a>13. Create More Image and Video Content</h3>
<p>One study found that images received <a href="http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/33800/Photos-on-Facebook-Generate-53-More-Likes-Than-the-Average-Post-NEW-DATA.aspx" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">far more engagement</a>—53% more Likes, 104% more comments, and 84% more click-throughs—than an average post.</p>
<p>But here’s something better: video posts receive <strong>135% better organic reach</strong> than image posts.</p>
<p>Mic drop.</p>
<p>So, how do you leverage this?</p>
<ul>
<li>Identify the kind of images and videos your target audience would engage with.</li>
<li>With your videos, make an impact in the first 5 seconds.</li>
<li>Create immersive stories</li>
<li>Don’t forget to include a call to action!</li>
</ul>
<p>One last thing: another research indicates that Facebook native videos perform up to 4 times better than other video formats.</p>
<h2><a name="_Toc52223239"></a>Final Thoughts on How to Get More Likes and Followers on Facebook Posts</h2>
<p>Getting more likes, followers and shares on Facebook is proven to be a great way to get more traffic for your business, regardless of the industry you operate in.</p>
<p>We’ve highlighted 13 tactics on how to get Facebook likes, pretty much for free<em> and </em>FAST! Should you start with all these? Absolutely; if you can maintain that. If you can’t, that’s where we come in.</p>
<p>We help manage your Facebook page to get you more likes and followers! That includes creating a Facebook profile if you don’t already have one, scheduling posts, sharing content, analyzing metrics and engaging with your followers!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Call <a href="tel:855-444-4777">855-444-4777</a> now and fill out the form below and let’s get started on your <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/facebook-advertising/">Facebook marketing campaign</a>! </strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-likes-on-facebook-in-2020/">How to Get More Likes on Facebook in 2020</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/how-to-get-more-likes-on-facebook-in-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 10 Ways to Grow a Small Business Through Facebook</title>
		<link>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-ways-to-grow-a-small-business-through-facebook/</link>
					<comments>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-ways-to-grow-a-small-business-through-facebook/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jay Melendez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 13:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Facebook Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media Management]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.searchberg.com/blog/?p=1482</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The ongoing COVID-19 pandemic has inevitably transformed how business is done across the globe. A recent Goldman Sachs report revealed that over 96% of small business owners reported being impacted by the crisis. In addition, over 51% admitted that they would be forced to close their business within 0–3 months. As the ongoing lockdown demands a shift toward digitalization, many [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-ways-to-grow-a-small-business-through-facebook/">Top 10 Ways to Grow a Small Business Through Facebook</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The ongoing COVID-19 pandemic has inevitably transformed how business is done <strong>across the globe</strong>.</p>
<p><span id="more-1482"></span></p>
<p>A recent Goldman Sachs report revealed that over <u><a href="https://www.goldmansachs.com/citizenship/10000-small-businesses/US/no-time-to-waste/index.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">96%</a></u> of small business owners reported being impacted by the crisis. In addition, over <u><a href="https://www.goldmansachs.com/citizenship/10000-small-businesses/US/no-time-to-waste/index.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">51%</a></u> admitted that they would be <strong>forced to close</strong> their business within <strong>0–3 months</strong>.</p>
<p>As the ongoing lockdown demands a <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/2020/03/20/why-companies-turn-to-digital-marketing-to-survive-covid-19/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">shift toward digitalization</a></u>, many local offline businesses are struggling to undertake this massive transformation. However, it may be their only way to maintain (and boost) metrics, audience engagement, and audience retention.</p>
<p>According to Forbes, the <strong>COVID-19 pandemic has increased internet use</strong> by <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/markbeech/2020/03/25/covid-19-pushes-up-internet-use-70-streaming-more-than-12-first-figures-reveal/#3cbc21903104" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">70%</a></u>.</p>
<p>Brands that have successfully leveraged the power of digital marketing have managed to keep their business afloat and increase revenue sales.</p>
<p>While digital marketing comprises an eclectic blend of <strong>PPC marketing, reputation management, web design</strong> and <strong>development</strong>, and <strong>content production</strong>, there’s one key player that stands out for its unparalleled performance.</p>
<p>Research indicates that coronavirus has pushed Facebook usage through the roof. People are spending <u><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/24/21193094/facebook-coronavirus-covid-19-messaging-service-reliable-strain-outages" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">50%</a></u> more time on the popular social media application, thereby interacting with more digital marketing content and fueling conversion rates for online businesses.</p>
<p>A recent survey conducted in March revealed that over <u><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1106338/facebook-usage-increase-due-to-coronavirus-home-usa/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">63%</a></u> of Americans stated that they were <strong>expecting to use Facebook more during the pandemic</strong> to stay informed about recent developments. Not only has that estimate increased across the globe, but it has also helped a lot of small businesses gain greater visibility and boost their business.</p>
<p>If your business has been struggling to weather the COVID-19 storm, we’ve rounded up <strong><em><u>ten powerful ways to leverage Facebook</u> </em></strong>for greater audience reach, revenue sales, and brand identity during the ongoing crisis.</p>
<h2>1. Create a Separate Business Page</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1484" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/1-1.png" alt="" width="628" height="420" /></p>
<p>Facebook helps businesses grow.</p>
<p>Research indicates that there are currently <u><a href="https://expandedramblings.com/index.php/by-the-numbers-17-amazing-facebook-stats/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">over 65 million</a></u> active small business pages on Facebook. With the number expected to increase as the COVID-19 pandemic continues, <strong><u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/2010/08/17/internet-marketing-twitter-technology-facebook.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">creating a separate Facebook business page</a></u></strong> is a surefire way to <strong>boost audience engagement</strong> and <strong>retention</strong>.</p>
<p>The powerful tool helps small businesses centralize their audience, thereby strengthening brand identity and allowing you to reach a vast expanse of potential customers successfully. Instead of using conventional marketing strategies, marketing your target audience through a strong Facebook page will lower your marketing expenses. This is extremely beneficial for up-and-coming startups and small businesses that are actively on the lookout for cost-effective marketing strategies.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1488" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/5-1.png" alt="" width="629" height="471" /></p>
<p>Creating and running a <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/thesba/2014/05/05/5-content-tips-for-your-facebook-business-page/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Facebook business page</a></u> is free, so you don’t have to worry about investing in unpredictable marketing sources that may not deliver the expected results.</p>
<p>A Facebook business page is also extremely effective in <strong>boosting SEO</strong>, <strong>increasing website traffic</strong>, and <strong>increasing customer retention</strong>.</p>
<p>Target your <u>intended audience</u> based on <em>key demographics, interests</em>, and <em>location </em>to enhance localized engagement further.</p>
<p>These strategies will collectively help you establish a targeted social media presence and solid reputation.</p>
<p>As you continue to use the platform, you’ll also establish a strong sense of <strong>competitor strategies</strong>. As you analyze their <strong><u>performance, marketing tactics, content quality, and reputation management practices</u>,</strong> you’ll be able to <strong><u>tweak and polish your branding strategy accordingly.</u></strong></p>
<p>We recommend examining the <strong>Facebook business presence </strong>of small businesses and established corporations that fall within the same industry.</p>
<p>This will help you incorporate a unique and effective mesh of “glocal” (global and local) strategies that resonate with the intended audience.</p>
<h2>2. Post Empathetic and Crisis-Friendly Content That Resonates With Your Audience</h2>
<p>While the ongoing lockdown has necessitated the creation of a strong Facebook business page, many small businesses are struggling to use the platform in an <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/tracybrower/2020/03/16/the-coronavirus-makes-communication-more-important-than-ever-9-tips-for-communication-that-reassures-and-reengages-people/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">empathetic and crisis-friendly manner</a></u>.</p>
<p>While you may feel compelled to leverage the application by solely marketing your products/services, you may want to reevaluate your strategy.</p>
<p>The sensitive crisis demands a gradual departure from unadulterated branding. Instead, <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/jefffromm/2020/03/20/usefulness--speed-with-a-heavy-dose-of-empathy-will-build-brand-preference-during-covid-19/#f0199fd7831d" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">prioritize support and care</a></u> to make your audience feel comforted during a time of chaos and uncertainty.</p>
<p>Moving toward a humanized marketing approach—in contradistinction to an automatized marketing approach—will strengthen your brand identity.</p>
<p>Slack’s genuine, heartfelt, and altruistic check-ins are a great example of prioritizing audience health (physical, mental, and emotional) and wellness before promoting products/services:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1485" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/2-1.png" alt="" width="567" height="190" /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1486" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/3-1.png" alt="" width="595" height="198" /></p>
<p>We also love Foreo’s empathetic marketing approach that prioritizes care and follows it up with timely and appropriate product recommendations:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1487" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/4-1.png" alt="" width="499" height="554" /></p>
<p>Building an understanding and comforting Facebook presence will ultimately help you establish a strong brand identity and generate more sales.</p>
<p>We also recommend posting thoughtful and crisis-sensitive blogs, articles, press releases, guest posts, infographics, and videos to crystallize brand visibility and attract new audiences.</p>
<p>For more strategies on empathetic, crisis-friendly marketing practices, be sure to check out our blog <a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/6-digital-marketing-tips-for-small-businesses-struggling-to-navigate-covid-19/">8 Digital Marketing Tips For Small Businesses Struggling To Navigate COVID-19</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>3. Closely Monitor Insights to Improve Your Strategy Accordingly</h2>
<p>One of the most beneficial features of Facebook marketing is the ability it gives you to monitor insights closely.</p>
<p>As Facebook use continues to increase, small businesses are increasingly leveraging <u><a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/learn/facebook-audience-insights" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Audience Insights</a></u> to determine areas of improvement and connect with potential customers who may have been overlooked through conventional marketing strategies.</p>
<p>Access page summary data and scrutinize metrics to develop an understanding of what works and what doesn’t. As you browse through the posts with the highest organic reach and determine the most popular content style on your page, you’ll be able to realign your strategy without breaking a sweat successfully.</p>
<p>This tactic is essential for small business owners with a limited understanding of digital metrics and KPIs. The easy-to-use dashboard allows quick, accurate, and digestible statistics that’ll help you steer your business to success.</p>
<p>We also recommend benefiting from <strong><u><a href="https://developers.facebook.com/docs/analytics" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Facebook Analytics</a></u></strong><strong> </strong>to visualize and optimize the customer experience.</p>
<h2>4. Leverage Facebook Videos for Improved Audience Engagement and Retention</h2>
<p>While the lockdown has given people more free time than before, the average human attention span has remained constant. According to Time, humans have an average attention span of <u><a href="https://time.com/3858309/attention-spans-goldfish/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">8 seconds</a></u>—1 second less than that of a goldfish!</p>
<p>While image and text-based marketing content is effective, video content is <em>twice</em> as powerful. Research indicates that videos generate <u><a href="https://medium.com/@slicevideo/this-is-why-video-is-the-most-engaging-type-of-content-e5ca46d5cef1" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">1,200% more shares</a></u> than images and text combined. Moreover, Facebook videos enjoy <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/miketempleman/2017/09/06/17-stats-about-video-marketing/#17dcaa35567f" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">over 8 million</a></u> views per day!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1489" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/7-1.png" alt="" width="618" height="419" /></p>
<p>The way to use videos to engage an audience is by creating videos that:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Serve to inspire your viewers.</strong> This can be in the form of telling a story, sharing an inspirational quote related to your business and consumers. Having inspirational music in the background of such videos is a big plus because it helps audiences connect emotionally with your message.</li>
<li><strong>Educate them in some way. </strong>This can look like providing your audience with a hack that can help them do something better or teaching them something useful.</li>
<li><strong>Provide entertainment value.</strong> During the pandemic, stuck in their homes, the fact is that people are really, really bored.</li>
</ol>
<p>So <strong>free entertainment</strong> is a welcome and <strong>highly rewarded release</strong>.</p>
<p>This doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean you should whip out the <em>prank videos</em> and try to go viral just <em>for the sake of going viral. </em></p>
<p>Instead, you can create content with a <strong>business purpose</strong> in an entertaining way.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><strong>Are organized and systematic.</strong> You can do so by placing videos following a similar theme into a <strong>Facebook video playlist. </strong></li>
</ol>
<p>For example, say your company sells baking products, and you create videos like &#8220;Baking The Perfect Croissant&#8221;, and &#8220;Baking The Perfect Chocolate Cake&#8221;, you can combine these into a relevant playlist on Facebook entitled, let&#8217;s say, &#8220;Baking The Perfect Good.&#8221;</p>
<p>As the most viewed and shared form of content on Facebook, videos facilitate the buyer decision-making process by increasing reach, engagement, and retention.</p>
<p>Share effective, empathetic, and engaging <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/why-you-need-video-content-for-your-website-if-you-want-to-gain-new-customers-and-strengthen-your-brand-online/">video content</a></u> to promote your products/services.</p>
<h2>5. Don’t Abandon Your Facebook Page</h2>
<p>The initial boost in metrics and sales revenue can easily <em>induce complacency</em>, thereby preventing businesses from maintaining a <strong>consistent effort.</strong></p>
<p>While you may be tempted to relax after building some momentum and reduce Facebook interactivity to a lower frequency, it’s essential that you continue to post regularly. This will help you maintain the <strong>growth and visibility</strong> established for your business on the Facebook page in the initial months.</p>
<p>Instead, abandoning your page can wreak havoc on previous accomplishments and can gradually make your business disappear among the active competition.</p>
<p>Post <strong><u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2018/05/07/four-ways-to-engage-your-facebook-audience-in-2018/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">meaningful and compelling content</a></u></strong> that keeps audiences engaged. <strong>Celebrating powerful events</strong> is a great way to <strong>contribute to a good cause </strong>while concurrently <strong>maintaining your brand presence</strong>.</p>
<p>TOMS’ frequent posts commonly include heartfelt messages that commemorate annual days that carry <strong>social, economic, political</strong>, and <strong>cultural significance.</strong></p>
<p>For instance:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1490" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/8-1.png" alt="" width="495" height="475" /></p>
<p>Sharing <strong>strong messages</strong> on annual holidays and celebratory days will <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2018/04/03/want-to-keep-reaching-your-facebook-audience-11-tips-for-adjusting-your-strategy/#2693dca12845" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">help your brand stand out</a></u> while fighting the good fight. If you run out of ideas, share general posts with a slice of wit to keep engagement levels high!</p>
<p>Little Owl—an up-and-coming small eatery in New York—has established a strong reputation and presence owing to its frequent posts—many of which include re-shares when inspiration runs low!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1491" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/9-1.png" alt="" width="495" height="305" /></p>
<p>The <strong>consistency</strong> and <strong>continual empathy </strong>have helped them earn incredible ratings and attract cosmopolitan audiences across New York. Keeping yourself on the map by actively sharing and re-sharing content will also increase your brand’s overall SEO.</p>
<h2>6. Give Facebook Ads a Shot</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1492" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/10-1.png" alt="" width="628" height="420" /></p>
<p>As one of the most effective tools for small businesses, <strong><u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnhall/2018/07/29/3-strategies-that-will-make-your-facebook-ads-more-successful/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">Facebook Ads</a></u></strong> are a powerful way to increase revenue and brand awareness. With Facebook use at an all-time high, small businesses can <u><a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/boost/grants" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">effectively market their products/services</a></u> without worrying about engagement.</p>
<p>As the fastest and most cost-effective advertising strategy, Facebook Ads increase website traffic and dramatically lower cost per acquisition. According to research, over <u><a href="https://www.facebook.com/business/news/3-million-advertisers" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">3 million</a></u> businesses actively advertise on Facebook!</p>
<p><strong>Facebook’s Ad Manager</strong> facilitates campaign management, thereby making the process easier than alternative advertising strategies. With a few clicks, you can successfully run your ads across multiple platforms and receive extensive and robust analytics.</p>
<p>Facebook’s <strong>excellent targeting capabilities</strong> are extremely effective in helping small businesses micro-target their audience.</p>
<p>They do so by allowing you to tag not only specific demographics of users but also their exact interests. For example, if someone has liked a page related to your niche, you can literally ride off the coattails of this page&#8217;s audience to target them for your business.</p>
<p>For a Facebook ad to be successful, it needs to have three key components:</p>
<ol>
<li>Specific and <strong>accurate targeting</strong>. Picture hitting a bull&#8217;s eye in a sea of people with varied interests.</li>
<li><strong>Compelling words</strong> or <strong>copy</strong>.</li>
<li>A <strong>solid image or video</strong> to make your point and reel the <strong>casual scroller into being a customer</strong>.</li>
</ol>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Not only does this <u><a href="https://medium.com/marketing-and-entrepreneurship/these-are-9-reasons-why-you-should-use-facebook-ads-right-now-3fefbeef7ae5" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">increase conversions</a></u>, but it also reduces customer attrition (loss) as users that deviate from the target audience are gradually eliminated.</p>
<p>The platform’s rich payoff helps businesses <strong><u><a href="https://www.inc.com/larry-kim/9-important-reasons-you-need-to-use-facebook-ads-right-now-first-90-days.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">remarket to audiences</a></u></strong> and build a <strong><u>sustainable brand identity</u></strong>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>7. Collaborate With Similar Businesses to Increase Your Following</h2>
<p>Struggling to boost your following? Collaborating with businesses in the same industry is a great way to double or triple your following.</p>
<p>Ideal for small businesses, partnerships increase visibility within the same niche, thereby attracting potential customers with a strong intent to purchase.</p>
<p>For instance, if you own a small salon, we recommend partnering with local businesses that sell hair products or skin rejuvenation tools. Approach them with a cross-promotional offer to increase following and sales for your business. Similarly, they’ll also benefit from the collaboration, as your customers will visit their website and purchase their products/services.</p>
<p>While the clientele will be similar, the contrasting products/services will ensure that one business’s traffic isn’t transferred to the other. Instead, the mutual benefits will help each business enjoy greater audience reach and sales.</p>
<h2>8. Boost Post Views by Using Hashtags</h2>
<p>Using <strong>Facebook hashtags the right way</strong> is <u><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2018/12/26/how-to-optimize-hashtags-on-social-media/#47d556547a17" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">extremely effective</a></u> in organically boosting page views. A recent study revealed that Facebook posts with hashtags receive <u><a href="https://later.com/blog/ultimate-guide-to-using-instagram-hashtags/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">12.6%</a></u> more engagement than those without.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1493" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/11-1.png" alt="" width="626" height="132" /></p>
<p>Facebook brought in Hashtags <strong><u>to bring conversations regarding people, public events, and topics to the forefront. </u></strong>Meaning, the purpose of a hashtag is to get eyeballs on the conversation.</p>
<p>Each hashtag has its <strong>own unique URL</strong> and can be found using the Facebook search bar. You can research it by looking through the hashtag on Facebook. You can also click on a hashtag that is generated on another site such as LinkedIn or Instagram. Chances are, there will be a continuation of that hashtag on Facebook as well.</p>
<p>Once you find the trending topics in your niche/industry, <strong>participate</strong>!</p>
<p>Join the conversation, take a stance, and/or provide deeper insight/value into the topic.</p>
<p>This will help you stand out.</p>
<h2>9. Create a Private Group to Establish a Close Connection with Your Loyal Audience</h2>
<p>While this powerful strategy seems counterintuitive to many, it’s a great way to establish a strong connection with loyal customers. A private Facebook group increases personal engagement and helps frequent customers feel included in the brand’s decision-making process.</p>
<p>Whether you’re working on a new product or are considering releasing an in-demand service, a <strong>quick heads up to your customers</strong> can go a long way in increasing audience retention.</p>
<p>We recommend posting <strong>polls</strong>, <strong>updates</strong>, and <strong>behind-the-scenes images</strong> and <strong>videos</strong> to keep your audience engaged and entertained. In addition, ask for their <strong>feedback </strong>and announce <strong>special discounts</strong> to establish a connection that goes beyond a superficial buyer-seller relationship.</p>
<p>CJ’s Coffee Cafe’s lighthearted, fun, and rewarding poll is a great example of engaging with group members and incorporating a little giveaway at the end:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1494" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/12.png" alt="" width="495" height="437" /></p>
<p>Whether you follow a similar strategy or create a unique <strong>group atmosphere</strong> for your customers, <u>conscientiousness and dedication</u> will help create a <u>community</u>.</p>
<p>As the group members feel appreciated and involved, they’re also more likely to <strong>unknowingly market your products/services</strong> to friends and family, thereby boosting reach and engagement.</p>
<h2>10. Ask Professionals for Help!</h2>
<p>Now you know all the basics, you need to build a strong foundation to understand how to build your small business&#8217; Facebook page growth.</p>
<p>You understand the importance of creating a <strong>separate Facebook business page</strong>, having an <strong>empathetic</strong> and <strong>crisis-friendly</strong> tone in your <strong>brand messaging</strong>, <strong>monitoring insights</strong> to improve, using engaging <strong>Facebook videos</strong>, <strong>Facebook Ads</strong>, staying <strong>consistent</strong> in your <strong>content release frequency</strong>, <strong>Hashtags</strong>, <strong>collaborating</strong> with other small businesses, and the power of <strong>private groups/communities</strong>.</p>
<p>While this is critical information and certainly will put you on your path to success, it is by no means the end of your research phase entirely.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1495" src="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/13.png" alt="" width="628" height="134" /></p>
<p>You may come across many hiccups along the way that can easily be eliminated as a result of vast previous experience in this field of Digital Marketing.</p>
<p>As one of the leading digital marketing service providers in the U.S., we offer <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/social-media-management.html">expert Facebook management services</a></u> across the globe. Our experience has helped us complete <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/achievement-alert-search-berg-completes-20000-projects/">over 20,000 SEO projects</a></u> for a wide range of clients in varying industries.</p>
<p>We also offer award-winning <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/ppc-marketing.html">PPC marketing</a></u>, reputation management, <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/content-marketing.html">content marketing</a></u>, and web design and development services to help small businesses boost revenue and use Facebook to expand their business during the ongoing crisis. Our <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/money-back-guarantee.html">100% back money guarantee</a></u> ensures there are no contractual obligations that make small business owners feel hesitant.</p>
<p>Browse through our <u><a href="https://www.searchberg.com/how-it-works.html">3 phase SEO process</a></u> to get started!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-ways-to-grow-a-small-business-through-facebook/">Top 10 Ways to Grow a Small Business Through Facebook</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.searchberg.com/blog">Search Berg</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.searchberg.com/blog/top-10-ways-to-grow-a-small-business-through-facebook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
